<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5504"><akn:num>5504</akn:num><akn:heading>Model intermodal transportation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5504. Model intermodal transportation plans(a) Grants.—The Secretary of Transportation shall make grants to States to develop model State intermodal transportation plans that are consistent with the policy set forth in section 302(e) of this title. The model plans shall include systems for collecting data related to intermodal transportation.

(b) Distribution.—The Secretary shall award grants to States under this section that represent a variety of geographic regions and transportation needs, patterns, and modes.

(c) Plan Submission.—As a condition to a State receiving a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require that the State provide assurances that the State will submit to the Secretary a State intermodal transportation plan not later than 18 months after the date of receipt of the grant.

(d) Grant Amounts.—The Secretary shall reserve, from amounts deducted under section 104(a) of title 23, $3,000,000 to make grants under this section. The total amount that a State may receive in grants under this section may not be more than $500,000.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 850.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


550449:301 (note).Dec. 18, 1991, Pub. L. 102–240, § 5003, 105 Stat. 2159.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall make grants to States to develop model State intermodal transportation plans that are consistent with the policy set forth in section 302(e) of this title. The model plans shall include systems for collecting data related to intermodal transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall award grants to States under this section that represent a variety of geographic regions and transportation needs, patterns, and modes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan Submission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) As a condition to a State receiving a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require that the State provide assurances that the State will submit to the Secretary a State intermodal transportation plan not later than 18 months after the date of receipt of the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall reserve, from amounts deducted under section 104(a) of title 23, $3,000,000 to make grants under this section. The total amount that a State may receive in grants under this section may not be more than $500,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>