<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5506"><akn:num>5506</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced transportation research initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5506. Advanced transportation research initiative(a) Definition of Eligible Entity.—In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(1) a State agency;

(2) a local government agency;

(3) an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1002)), including a university transportation center established under section 5505;

(4) a nonprofit organization, including a nonprofit research organization; and

(5) a private sector organization working in collaboration with an entity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4).


(b) Pilot Program.—The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish an advanced transportation research pilot program under which the Secretary—(1) shall establish a process for eligible entities to submit to the Secretary unsolicited research proposals; and

(2) may enter into arrangements with 1 or more eligible entities to fund research proposed under paragraph (1), in accordance with this section.


(c) Eligible Research.—The Secretary may enter into an arrangement with an eligible entity under this section to fund research that—(1) addresses—(A) a research need identified by—(i) the Secretary; or

(ii) the Administrator of a modal administration of the Department of Transportation; or


(B) an issue that the Secretary determines to be important; and


(2) is not duplicative of—(A) any other Federal research project; or

(B) any project for which funding is provided by another Federal agency.



(d) Project Review.—The Secretary shall—(1) review each research proposal submitted under the pilot program established under subsection (b); and

(2)(A) if funding is denied for the research proposal—(i) provide to the eligible entity that submitted the proposal a written notice of the denial that, as applicable—(I) explains why the research proposal was not selected, including whether the research proposal fails to cover an area of need; and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Eligible Entity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish an advanced transportation research pilot program under which the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Research.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may enter into an arrangement with an eligible entity under this section to fund research that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review, Evaluation, and Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not less frequently than biennially, in accordance with the plan developed under section 6503, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Certain Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Of any amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use not more than 1.5 percent for coordination, evaluation, and oversight activities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5506_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>