<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5564"><akn:num>5564</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim preservation of certain rail passenger terminals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5564. Interim preservation of certain rail passenger terminals(a) General Grant Authority.—Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance to a responsible person (including a governmental authority) to preserve a rail passenger terminal under section 5562(a)(2) of this title. To receive assistance under this section, the person must be qualified, prepared, committed, and authorized by law to maintain (and prevent the demolition, dismantling, or further deterioration of) the terminal until plans for its reuse are prepared.

(b) Grant Requirements.—The Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance under this section only if—(1) the Secretary decides the rail passenger terminal has a reasonable likelihood of being converted to, or conditioned for reuse as, an intermodal transportation terminal, a civic or cultural activities center, or both; and

(2) planning activity directed toward conversion or reuse has begun and is proceeding in a competent way.


(c) Maximizing Preservation of Terminals.—(1) Amounts appropriated to carry out this section and section 5562(a)(2) of this title shall be expended in the way most likely to maximize the preservation of rail passenger terminals that are—(A) reasonably capable of conversion to intermodal transportation terminals;

(B) listed in the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior; or

(C) recommended (on the basis of architectural integrity and quality) by the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation or the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts.


(2) The Secretary of Transportation may not make a grant under this section for more than 80 percent of the total cost of maintaining the terminal for an interim period of not more than 5 years.


(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(d), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 852.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Grant Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance to a responsible person (including a governmental authority) to preserve a rail passenger terminal under section 5562(a)(2) of this title. To receive assistance under this section, the person must be qualified, prepared, committed, and authorized by law to maintain (and prevent the demolition, dismantling, or further deterioration of) the terminal until plans for its reuse are prepared.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation may make a grant of financial assistance under this section only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximizing Preservation of Terminals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>