<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5903"><akn:num>5903</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5903. Prohibitions(a) Providing Erroneous Information.—A person, To 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. whom section 5902(b) applies, tendering a loaded container or trailer may not provide erroneous information in a certification required by section 5902(b) of this title.

(b) Transporting Prior to Receiving Certification.—(1) Presumption.—If no certification is received by a motor carrier before or when a loaded intermodal container or trailer is tendered to it, the motor carrier may presume that the gross cargo weight of the container or trailer is less than 29,001 pounds.

(2) Copy of certification not required to accompany container or trailer.—Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, a copy of the certification required by section 5902(b) is not required to accompany the intermodal container or trailer.


(c) Unlawful Coercion.—(1) A person may not coerce or attempt to coerce a person participating in intermodal transportation to transport a loaded container or trailer having an actual gross cargo weight of more than 29,000 pounds before the certification required by section 5902(b) of this title is provided.

(2) A person, knowing that the weight of a loaded container or trailer or the weight of a tractor-trailer combination carrying the container or trailer is more than the weight allowed by applicable State law, may not coerce or attempt to coerce a carrier to transport the container or trailer or to operate the tractor-trailer combination in violation of that State law.


(d) Notice to Leased Operators.—(1) In general.—If a motor carrier knows that the gross cargo weight of an intermodal container or trailer subject to the certification requirements of section 5902(b) would result in a violation of applicable State gross vehicle weight laws, then—(A) the motor carrier shall give notice to the operator of a vehicle which is leased by the vehicle operator to a motor carrier that transports an intermodal contai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providing Erroneous Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A person, To 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. whom section 5902(b) applies, tendering a loaded container or trailer may not provide erroneous information in a certification required by section 5902(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transporting Prior to Receiving Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful Coercion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Leased Operators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>