<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60117"><akn:num>60117</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60117. Administrative(a) General Authority.—To carry out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may conduct investigations, make reports, issue subpenas, conduct hearings, require the production of records, take depositions, and conduct research, testing, development, demonstration, and training activities and promotional activities relating to prevention of damage to pipeline facilities. The Secretary may not charge a tuition-type fee for training State or local government personnel in the enforcement of regulations prescribed under this chapter.

(b) Enforcement Procedures.—(1) Process.—In implementing enforcement procedures under this chapter and part 190 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), the Secretary shall—(A) allow the respondent to request the use of a consent agreement and consent order to resolve any matter of fact or law asserted;

(B) allow the respondent and the agency to convene 1 or more meetings—(i) for settlement or simplification of the issues; or

(ii) to aid in the disposition of issues;


(C) require that the case file in an enforcement proceeding include all agency records pertinent to the matters of fact and law asserted;

(D) allow the respondent to reply to each post-hearing submission of the agency;

(E) allow the respondent to request that a hearing be held, and an order be issued, on an expedited basis;

(F) require that the agency have the burden of proof, presentation, and persuasion in any enforcement matter;

(G) require that any order contain findings of relevant fact and conclusions of law;

(H) require the Office of Pipeline Safety to file a post-hearing recommendation not later than 30 days after the deadline for any post-hearing submission of a respondent;

(I) require an order on a petition for reconsideration to be issued not later than 120 days after the date on which the petition is filed; and

(J) allow an operator to request that an issue of controversy or uncertainty be addressed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To carry out this chapter, the Secretary of Transportation may conduct investigations, make reports, issue subpenas, conduct hearings, require the production of records, take depositions, and conduct research, testing, development, demonstration, and training activities and promotional activities relating to prevention of damage to pipeline facilities. The Secretary may not charge a tuition-type fee for training State or local government personnel in the enforcement of regulations prescribed under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records, Reports, and Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To enable the Secretary to decide whether a person owning or operating a pipeline facility is complying with this chapter and standards prescribed or orders issued under this chapter, the person shall— The Secretary may require owners and operators of gathering lines to provide the Secretary information pertinent to the Secretary’s ability to make a determination as to whether and to what extent to regulate gathering lines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entry and Inspection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An officer, employee, or agent of the Department of Transportation designated by the Secretary, on display of proper credentials to the individual in charge, may enter premises to inspect the records and property of a person at a reasonable time and in a reasonable way to decide whether a person is complying with this chapter and standards prescribed or orders issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information related to a confidential matter referred to in section 1905 of title 18 that is obtained by the Secretary or an officer, employee, or agent in carrying out this section may be disclosed only to another officer or employee concerned with carrying out this chapter or in a proceeding under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Accident Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing Facilities Involved in Accidents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may require testing of a part of a pipeline facility subject to this chapter that has been involved in or affected by an accident only after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providing Safety Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) On request, the Secretary shall provide the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or appropriate State authority with information the Secretary has on the safety of material, operations, devices, or processes related to pipeline transportation or operating a pipeline facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60117_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>