<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60112"><akn:num>60112</akn:num><akn:heading>Pipeline facilities hazardous to life and property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60112. Pipeline facilities hazardous to life and property(a) General Authority.—After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary of Transportation may decide that a pipeline facility is hazardous if the Secretary decides that—(1) operation of the facility is or would be hazardous to life, property, or the environment; or

(2) the facility is or would be constructed or operated, or a component of the facility is or would be constructed or operated, with equipment, material, or a technique that the Secretary decides is hazardous to life, property, or the environment.


(b) Considerations.—In making a decision under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall consider, if relevant—(1) the characteristics of the pipe and other equipment used in the pipeline facility, including the age, manufacture, physical properties, and method of manufacturing, constructing, or assembling the equipment;

(2) the nature of the material the pipeline facility transports, the corrosive and deteriorative qualities of the material, the sequence in which the material are 11 So in original. Probably should be “is”. transported, and the pressure required for transporting the material;

(3) the aspects of the area in which the pipeline facility is located, including climatic and geologic conditions and soil characteristics;

(4) the proximity of the area in which the hazardous liquid pipeline facility is located to environmentally sensitive areas;

(5) the population density and population and growth patterns of the area in which the pipeline facility is located;

(6) any recommendation of the National Transportation Safety Board made under another law; and

(7) other factors the Secretary considers appropriate.


(c) Opportunity for State Comment.—The Secretary shall provide, to any appropriate official of a State in which a pipeline facility is located and about which a proceeding has begun under this section, notice and an opportunity to comment on an agreement the Sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) After notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary of Transportation may decide that a pipeline facility is hazardous if the Secretary decides that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In making a decision under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall consider, if relevant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for State Comment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall provide, to any appropriate official of a State in which a pipeline facility is located and about which a proceeding has begun under this section, notice and an opportunity to comment on an agreement the Secretary proposes to make to resolve the proceeding. State comment shall incorporate comments of affected local officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corrective Action Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Notice and Hearing in Emergency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may waive the requirements for notice and an opportunity for a hearing under this section and issue expeditiously an order under this section if the Secretary decides failure to issue the order expeditiously will result in likely serious harm to life, property, or the environment. An order under this subsection shall provide an opportunity for a hearing as soon as practicable after the order is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>