<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60115"><akn:num>60115</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical safety standards committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60115. Technical safety standards committees(a) Organization.—The Technical Pipeline Safety Standards Committee and the Technical Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Safety Standards Committee are committees in the Department of Transportation. The committees referred to in the preceding sentence shall serve as peer review committees for carrying out this chapter. Peer reviews conducted by the committees shall be treated for purposes of all Federal laws relating to risk assessment and peer review (including laws that take effect after the date of the enactment of the Accountable Pipeline Safety and Partnership Act of 1996) as meeting any peer review requirements of such laws.

(b) Composition and Appointment.—(1) The Technical Pipeline Safety Standards Committee is composed of 15 members appointed by the Secretary of Transportation after consulting with public and private agencies concerned with the technical aspect of transporting gas or operating a gas pipeline facility. Each member must be experienced in the safety regulation of transporting gas and of gas pipeline facilities or technically qualified, by training, experience, or knowledge in at least one field of engineering applicable to transporting gas or operating a gas pipeline facility, to evaluate gas pipeline safety standards or risk management principles.

(2) The Technical Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Safety Standards Committee is composed of 15 members appointed by the Secretary after consulting with public and private agencies concerned with the technical aspect of transporting hazardous liquid or operating a hazardous liquid pipeline facility. Each member must be experienced in the safety regulation of transporting hazardous liquid and of hazardous liquid pipeline facilities or technically qualified, by training, experience, or knowledge in at least one field of engineering applicable to transporting hazardous liquid or operating a hazardous liquid pipeline facility, to evaluate hazardous liquid pipeline safety</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Technical Pipeline Safety Standards Committee and the Technical Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Safety Standards Committee are committees in the Department of Transportation. The committees referred to in the preceding sentence shall serve as peer review committees for carrying out this chapter. Peer reviews conducted by the committees shall be treated for purposes of all Federal laws relating to risk assessment and peer review (including laws that take effect after the date of the enactment of the Accountable Pipeline Safety and Partnership Act of 1996) as meeting any peer review requirements of such laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and Appointment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee Reports on Proposed Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed Committee Standards and Policy Development Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each committee shall meet with the Secretary at least up to 4 times annually. Each committee proceeding shall be recorded. The record of the proceeding shall be available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60115_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A member of a committee under this section is entitled to expenses under section 5703 of title 5. A payment under this subsection does not make a member an officer or employee of the Government. This subsection does not apply to members regularly employed by the Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>