<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60116"><akn:num>60116</akn:num><akn:heading>Public education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60116. Public education programs(a) In General.—Each owner or operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility shall carry out a continuing program to educate the public on the use of a one-call notification system prior to excavation and other damage prevention activities, the possible hazards associated with unintended releases from the pipeline facility, the physical indications that such a release may have occurred, what steps should be taken for public safety in the event of a pipeline release, and how to report such an event.

(b) Modification of Existing Programs.—Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of the Pipeline Safety Improvement Act of 2002, each owner or operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility shall review its existing public education program for effectiveness and modify the program as necessary. The completed program shall include activities to advise affected municipalities, school districts, businesses, and residents of pipeline facility locations. The completed program shall be submitted to the Secretary or, in the case of an intrastate pipeline facility operator, the appropriate State agency, and shall be periodically reviewed by the Secretary or, in the case of an intrastate pipeline facility operator, the appropriate State agency.

(c) Standards.—The Secretary may issue standards prescribing the elements of an effective public education program. The Secretary may also develop material for use in the program.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1321; Pub. L. 104–304, § 11, Oct. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 3802; Pub. L. 107–355, § 5, Dec. 17, 2002, 116 Stat. 2988.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6011649 App.:1685(a).Aug. 12, 1968, Pub. L. 90–481, 82 Stat. 720, § 18(a); added Oct. 11, 1976, Pub. L. 94–477, § 8, 90 Stat. 2075; Nov. 30, 1979, Pub. L. 96–129, § 104(b), 93 Stat. 992; Oct. 24, 1992, Pub. L. 102–508, § 115(a)(1), 106 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each owner or operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility shall carry out a continuing program to educate the public on the use of a one-call notification system prior to excavation and other damage prevention activities, the possible hazards associated with unintended releases from the pipeline facility, the physical indications that such a release may have occurred, what steps should be taken for public safety in the event of a pipeline release, and how to report such an event.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of Existing Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of the Pipeline Safety Improvement Act of 2002, each owner or operator of a gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facility shall review its existing public education program for effectiveness and modify the program as necessary. The completed program shall include activities to advise affected municipalities, school districts, businesses, and residents of pipeline facility locations. The completed program shall be submitted to the Secretary or, in the case of an intrastate pipeline facility operator, the appropriate State agency, and shall be periodically reviewed by the Secretary or, in the case of an intrastate pipeline facility operator, the appropriate State agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may issue standards prescribing the elements of an effective public education program. The Secretary may also develop material for use in the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>