<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60126" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60126/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60126/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60126"><akn:num>60126</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60126. Risk management(a) Risk Management Program Demonstration Projects.—(1) In general.—The Secretary shall establish risk management demonstration projects—(A) to demonstrate, through the voluntary participation by owners and operators of gas pipeline facilities and hazardous liquid pipeline facilities, the application of risk management; and

(B) to evaluate the safety and cost-effectiveness of the program.


(2) Exemptions.—In carrying out a demonstration project under this subsection, the Secretary, by order—(A) may exempt an owner or operator of the pipeline facility covered under the project (referred to in this subsection as a “covered pipeline facility”), from the applicability of all or a portion of the requirements under this chapter that would otherwise apply to the covered pipeline facility; and

(B) shall exempt, for the period of the project, an owner or operator of the covered pipeline facility, from the applicability of any new standard that the Secretary promulgates under this chapter during the period of that participation, with respect to the covered facility.



(b) Requirements.—In carrying out a demonstration project under this section, the Secretary shall—(1) invite owners and operators of pipeline facilities to submit risk management plans for timely approval by the Secretary;

(2) require, as a condition of approval, that a risk management plan submitted under this subsection contain measures that are designed to achieve an equivalent or greater overall level of safety than would otherwise be achieved through compliance with the standards contained in this chapter or promulgated by the Secretary under this chapter;

(3) provide for—(A) collaborative government and industry training;

(B) methods to measure the safety performance of risk management plans;

(C) the development and application of new technologies;

(D) the promotion of community awareness concerning how the overall level of safety will be maintained or enhanced by the demon</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60126_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk Management Program Demonstration Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60126_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out a demonstration project under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60126_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergencies and Revocations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nothing in this section diminishes or modifies the Secretary’s authority under this title to act in case of an emergency. The Secretary may revoke any exemption granted under this section for substantial noncompliance with the terms and conditions of an approved risk management plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60126_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by State Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out this section, the Secretary may provide for consultation by a State that has in effect a certification under section 60105. To the extent that a demonstration project comprises an intrastate natural gas pipeline or an intrastate hazardous liquid pipeline facility, the Secretary may make an agreement with the State agency to carry out the duties of the Secretary for approval and administration of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60126_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than March 31, 2000, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a report on the results of the demonstration projects carried out under this section that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>