<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60127" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60127/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60127/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60127"><akn:num>60127</akn:num><akn:heading>Population encroachment and rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60127. Population encroachment and rights-of-way(a) Study.—The Secretary of Transportation, in conjunction with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies and State and local governments, shall undertake a study of land use practices, zoning ordinances, and preservation of environmental resources with regard to pipeline rights-of-way and their maintenance.

(b) Purpose of Study.—The purpose of the study shall be to gather information on land use practices, zoning ordinances, and preservation of environmental resources—(1) to determine effective practices to limit encroachment on existing pipeline rights-of-way;

(2) to address and prevent the hazards and risks to the public, pipeline workers, and the environment associated with encroachment on pipeline rights-of-way;

(3) to raise the awareness of the risks and hazards of encroachment on pipeline rights-of-way; and

(4) to address how to best preserve environmental resources in conjunction with maintaining pipeline rights-of-way, recognizing pipeline operators’ regulatory obligations to maintain rights-of-way and to protect public safety.


(c) Considerations.—In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consider, at a minimum, the following:(1) The legal authority of Federal agencies and State and local governments in controlling land use and the limitations on such authority.

(2) The current practices of Federal agencies and State and local governments in addressing land use issues involving a pipeline easement.

(3) The most effective way to encourage Federal agencies and State and local governments to monitor and reduce encroachment upon pipeline rights-of-way.


(d) Report.—(1) In general.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall publish a report identifying practices, laws, and ordinances that are most successful in addressing issues of encroachment and maintenance on pipeline rights-of-way so as to more eff</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60127_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation, in conjunction with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies and State and local governments, shall undertake a study of land use practices, zoning ordinances, and preservation of environmental resources with regard to pipeline rights-of-way and their maintenance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60127_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Study.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purpose of the study shall be to gather information on land use practices, zoning ordinances, and preservation of environmental resources—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60127_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consider, at a minimum, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60127_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>