<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60131" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60131/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60131/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60131"><akn:num>60131</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification of pipeline qualification programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60131. Verification of pipeline qualification programs(a) In General.—Subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall require the operator of a pipeline facility to develop and adopt a qualification program to ensure that the individuals who perform covered tasks are qualified to conduct such tasks.

(b) Standards and Criteria.—(1) Development.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall ensure that the Department of Transportation has in place standards and criteria for qualification programs referred to in subsection (a).

(2) Contents.—The standards and criteria shall include the following:(A) The establishment of methods for evaluating the acceptability of the qualifications of individuals described in subsection (a).

(B) A requirement that pipeline operators develop and implement written plans and procedures to qualify individuals described in subsection (a) to a level found acceptable using the methods established under subparagraph (A) and evaluate the abilities of individuals described in subsection (a) according to such methods.

(C) A requirement that the plans and procedures adopted by a pipeline operator under subparagraph (B) be reviewed and verified under subsection (e).



(c) Development of Qualification Programs by Pipeline Operators.—The Secretary shall require each pipeline operator to develop and adopt, not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, a qualification program that complies with the standards and criteria described in subsection (b).

(d) Elements of Qualification Programs.—A qualification program adopted by an operator under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:(1) A method for examining or testing the qualifications of individuals described in subsection (a). The method may include written examination, oral examination, observation during on-the-job performance, on-the-job training, simulations, and ot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to the requirements of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall require the operator of a pipeline facility to develop and adopt a qualification program to ensure that the individuals who perform covered tasks are qualified to conduct such tasks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of Qualification Programs by Pipeline Operators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall require each pipeline operator to develop and adopt, not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, a qualification program that complies with the standards and criteria described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of Qualification Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A qualification program adopted by an operator under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and Verification of Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intrastate Pipeline Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In the case of an intrastate pipeline facility operator, the duties and powers of the Secretary under this section with respect to the qualification program of the operator shall be vested in the appropriate State regulatory agency, consistent with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Task Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “covered task”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60131_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the status and results to date of the personnel qualification regulations issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>