<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60134"><akn:num>60134</akn:num><akn:heading>State damage prevention programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60134. State damage prevention programs(a) In General.—The Secretary may make a grant to a State authority (including a municipality with respect to intrastate gas pipeline transportation) to assist in improving the overall quality and effectiveness of a damage prevention program of the State authority under subsection (e) if the State authority—(1) has in effect an annual certification under section 60105 or an agreement under section 60106;

(2)(A) has in effect an effective damage prevention program that meets the requirements of subsection (b); or

(B) demonstrates that it has made substantial progress toward establishing such a program, and that such program will meet the requirements of subsection (b); and


(3) does not provide any exemptions to municipalities, State agencies, or their contractors from the one-call notification system requirements of the program.


(b) Damage Prevention Program Elements.—An effective damage prevention program includes the following elements:(1) Participation by operators, excavators, and other stakeholders in the development and implementation of methods for establishing and maintaining effective communications between stakeholders from receipt of an excavation notification until successful completion of the excavation, as appropriate.

(2) A process for fostering and ensuring the support and partnership of stakeholders, including excavators, operators, locators, designers, and local government in all phases of the program.

(3) A process for reviewing the adequacy of a pipeline operator’s internal performance measures regarding persons performing locating services and quality assurance programs.

(4) Participation by operators, excavators, and other stakeholders in the development and implementation of effective employee training programs to ensure that operators, the one-call center, the enforcing agency, and the excavators have partnered to design and implement training for the employees of operators, excavators, and loc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may make a grant to a State authority (including a municipality with respect to intrastate gas pipeline transportation) to assist in improving the overall quality and effectiveness of a damage prevention program of the State authority under subsection (e) if the State authority—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damage Prevention Program Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An effective damage prevention program includes the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors to Consider.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall take into consideration the commitment of each State to ensuring the effectiveness of its damage prevention program, including legislative and regulatory actions taken by the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If a State authority files an application for a grant under this section not later than September 30 of a calendar year and demonstrates that the Governor (or chief executive) of the State has designated it as the appropriate State authority to receive the grant, the Secretary shall review the State’s damage prevention program to determine its effectiveness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A grant under this section to a State authority may only be used to pay the cost of the personnel, equipment, and activities that the State authority reasonably requires for the calendar year covered by the grant to develop or carry out its damage prevention program in accordance with subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A grant made under this section is not subject to the section 60107(a) limitation on the maximum percentage of funds to be paid by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funds provided to carry out this section may not be used for lobbying or in direct support of litigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damage Prevention Process Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “damage prevention process” means a process that incorporates the principles described in sections 60114(b), 60114(d), and 60114(e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60134_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to provide grants under this section $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2023. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>