<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60130" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60130/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60130/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60130"><akn:num>60130</akn:num><akn:heading>Pipeline safety information grants to communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60130. Pipeline safety information grants to communities(a) Grant Authority.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Transportation may make grants for technical assistance to local communities, Indian Tribes, and groups of individuals (not including for-profit entities) relating to the safety of pipeline facilities in local communities, other than facilities regulated under Public Law 93–153 (43 U.S.C. 1651 et seq.). No grants may be awarded under section 60114(g) until the Secretary has established competitive procedures for awarding grants under this section and criteria for selecting grant recipients. Except as provided in subsection (c)(2), the amount of any grant under this section may not exceed $100,000 for a single grant recipient. The Secretary shall establish appropriate procedures to ensure the proper use of funds provided under this section.

(2) Demonstration grants.—At least the first 3 grants awarded under this section shall be demonstration grants for the purpose of demonstrating and evaluating the utility of grants under this section. Each such demonstration grant shall not exceed $25,000.

(3) Dissemination of technical findings.—Each recipient of a grant under this section shall ensure that—(A) the technical findings made possible by the grants are made available to the relevant operators; and

(B) open communication between the grant recipients, local operators, local communities, and other interested parties is encouraged.



(b) Prohibited Uses.—Funds provided under this section to grant recipients and their contractors may not be used for lobbying, for direct advocacy for or against a pipeline construction or expansion project, or in direct support of litigation.

(c) Funding.—(1) In general.—Subject to paragraph (2), out of amounts made available under section 2(b) of the PIPES Act of 2016 (Public Law 114–183; 130 Stat. 515), the Secretary shall use $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2023 to carry out this section.

(2) Improving te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60130_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60130_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funds provided under this section to grant recipients and their contractors may not be used for lobbying, for direct advocacy for or against a pipeline construction or expansion project, or in direct support of litigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60130_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60130_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>