<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60139" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60139/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/60139/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60139"><akn:num>60139</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum allowable operating pressure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60139. Maximum allowable operating pressure(a) Verification of Records.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Transportation shall require each owner or operator of a pipeline facility to conduct, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, a verification of the records of the owner or operator relating to the interstate and intrastate gas transmission pipelines of the owner or operator in class 3 and class 4 locations and class 1 and class 2 high-consequence areas.

(2) Purpose.—The purpose of the verification shall be to ensure that the records accurately reflect the physical and operational characteristics of the pipelines described in paragraph (1) and confirm the established maximum allowable operating pressure of the pipelines.

(3) Elements.—The verification process under this subsection shall include such elements as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(b) Reporting.—(1) Documentation of certain pipelines.—Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, each owner or operator of a pipeline facility shall identify and submit to the Secretary documentation relating to each pipeline segment of the owner or operator described in subsection (a)(1) for which the records of the owner or operator are insufficient to confirm the established maximum allowable operating pressure of the segment.

(2) Exceedances of maximum allowable operating pressure.—If there is an exceedance of the maximum allowable operating pressure with respect to a gas transmission pipeline of an owner or operator of a pipeline facility that exceeds the build-up allowed for operation of pressure-limiting or control devices, the owner or operator shall report the exceedance to the Secretary and appropriate State authorities on or before the 5th day following the date on which the exceedance occurs.


(c) Determination of Maximum Allowable Operating Pressure.—(1) In general.—In the case of a transmission line of an owner or operator of a pipeline facil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60139_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification of Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60139_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60139_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Maximum Allowable Operating Pressure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60139_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60139_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-consequence Area Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the term “high-consequence area” means an area described in section 60109(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>