<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1331"><akn:num>1331</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1331. Definitions
In this subchapter:(a) Outer Continental Shelf.—The term “outer Continental Shelf” means—(1) all submerged lands lying seaward and outside of the area of lands beneath navigable waters as defined in section 1301 of this title, and of which the subsoil and seabed appertain to the United States and are subject to its jurisdiction and control or within the exclusive economic zone of the United States and adjacent to any territory of the United States; and

(2) does not include any area conveyed by Congress to a territorial government for administration;


(b) Secretary.—The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, except that with respect to functions under this subchapter transferred to, or vested in, the Secretary of Energy or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission by or pursuant to the Department of Energy Organization Act (42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.), the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy, or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, as the case may be.

(c) Lease.—The term “lease” means any form of authorization which is issued under section 1337 of this title or maintained under section 1335 of this title and which authorizes exploration for, and development and production of, minerals.

(d) Person.—The term “person” includes, in addition to a natural person, an association, a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a private, public, or municipal corporation.

(e) Coastal zone.—The term “coastal zone” means the coastal waters (including the lands therein and thereunder) and the adjacent shorelands (including the waters therein and thereunder), strongly influenced by each other and in proximity to the shorelines of the several coastal States, and includes islands, transition and intertidal areas, salt marshes, wetlands, and beaches, which zone extends seaward to the outer limit of the United States territorial sea and extends inland from the shorelines to the extent necessary to control shorelands, the uses of whi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outer Continental Shelf.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The term “outer Continental Shelf” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, except that with respect to functions under this subchapter transferred to, or vested in, the Secretary of Energy or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission by or pursuant to the Department of Energy Organization Act (42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.), the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy, or the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “lease” means any form of authorization which is issued under section 1337 of this title or maintained under section 1335 of this title and which authorizes exploration for, and development and production of, minerals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “person” includes, in addition to a natural person, an association, a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a private, public, or municipal corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal zone.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “coastal zone” means the coastal waters (including the lands therein and thereunder) and the adjacent shorelands (including the waters therein and thereunder), strongly influenced by each other and in proximity to the shorelines of the several coastal States, and includes islands, transition and intertidal areas, salt marshes, wetlands, and beaches, which zone extends seaward to the outer limit of the United States territorial sea and extends inland from the shorelines to the extent necessary to control shorelands, the uses of which have a direct and significant impact on the coastal waters, and the inward boundaries of which may be identified by the several coastal States, pursuant to the authority of section 1454(b)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 16.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affected State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “affected State” means, with respect to any program, plan, lease sale, or other activity, proposed, conducted, or approved pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter, any State—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marine environment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The term “marine environment” means the physical, atmospheric, and biological components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the productivity, state, condition, and quality of the marine ecosystem, including the waters of the high seas, the contiguous zone, transitional and intertidal areas, salt marshes, and wetlands within the coastal zone and on the outer Continental Shelf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal environment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The term “coastal environment” means the physical atmospheric, and biological components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the productivity, state, condition, and quality of the terrestrial ecosystem from the shoreline inward to the boundaries of the coastal zone.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Human environment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The term “human environment” means the physical, social, and economic components, conditions, and factors which interactively determine the state, condition, and quality of living conditions, employment, and health of those affected, directly or indirectly, by activities occurring on the outer Continental Shelf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The term “Governor” means the Governor of a State, or the person or entity designated by, or pursuant to, State law to exercise the powers granted to such Governor pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>