<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1334" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1334/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1334/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1334"><akn:num>1334</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of leasing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1334. Administration of leasing(a) Rules and regulations; amendment; cooperation with State agencies; subject matter and scope of regulationsThe Secretary shall administer the provisions of this subchapter relating to the leasing of the outer Continental Shelf, and shall prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out such provisions. The Secretary may at any time prescribe and amend such rules and regulations as he determines to be necessary and proper in order to provide for the prevention of waste and conservation of the natural resources of the outer Continental Shelf, and the protection of correlative rights therein, and, notwithstanding any other provisions herein, such rules and regulations shall, as of their effective date, apply to all operations conducted under a lease issued or maintained under the provisions of this subchapter. In the enforcement of safety, environmental, and conservation laws and regulations, the Secretary shall cooperate with the relevant departments and agencies of the Federal Government and of the affected States. In the formulation and promulgation of regulations, the Secretary shall request and give due consideration to the views of the Attorney General with respect to matters which may affect competition. In considering any regulations and in preparing any such views, the Attorney General shall consult with the Federal Trade Commission. The regulations prescribed by the Secretary under this subsection shall include, but not be limited to, provisions—(1) for the suspension or temporary prohibition of any operation or activity, including production, pursuant to any lease or permit (A) at the request of a lessee, in the national interest, to facilitate proper development of a lease or to allow for the construction or negotiation for use of transportation facilities, or (B) if there is a threat of serious, irreparable, or immediate harm or damage to life (including fish and other aquatic life), to property, to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations; amendment; cooperation with State agencies; subject matter and scope of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations; amendment; cooperation with State agencies; subject matter and scope of regulations The Secretary shall administer the provisions of this subchapter relating to the leasing of the outer Continental Shelf, and shall prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out such provisions. The Secretary may at any time prescribe and amend such rules and regulations as he determines to be necessary and proper in order to provide for the prevention of waste and conservation of the natural resources of the outer Continental Shelf, and the protection of correlative rights therein, and, notwithstanding any other provisions herein, such rules and regulations shall, as of their effective date, apply to all operations conducted under a lease issued or maintained under the provisions of this subchapter. In the enforcement of safety, environmental, and conservation laws and regulations, the Secretary shall cooperate with the relevant departments and agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with regulations as condition for issuance, continuation, assignment, or other transfer of leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance with regulations as condition for issuance, continuation, assignment, or other transfer of leases The issuance and continuance in effect of any lease, or of any assignment or other transfer of any lease, under the provisions of this subchapter shall be conditioned upon compliance with regulations issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of nonproducing lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cancellation of nonproducing lease Whenever the owner of a nonproducing lease fails to comply with any of the provisions of this subchapter, or of the lease, or of the regulations issued under this subchapter, such lease may be canceled by the Secretary, subject to the right of judicial review as provided in this subchapter, if such default continues for the period of thirty days after mailing of notice by registered letter to the lease owner at his record post office address.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of producing lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cancellation of producing lease Whenever the owner of any producing lease fails to comply with any of the provisions of this subchapter, of the lease, or of the regulations issued under this subchapter, such lease may be forfeited and canceled by an appropriate proceeding in any United States district court having jurisdiction under the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pipeline rights-of-way; forfeiture of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pipeline rights-of-way; forfeiture of grant Rights-of-way through the submerged lands of the outer Continental Shelf, whether or not such lands are included in a lease maintained or issued pursuant to this subchapter, may be granted by the Secretary for pipeline purposes for the transportation of oil, natural gas, sulphur, or other minerals, or under such regulations and upon such conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary, or where appropriate the Secretary of Transportation, including (as provided in section 1347(b) of this title) assuring maximum environmental protection by utilization of the best available and safest technologies, including the safest practices for pipeline burial and upon the express condition that oil or gas pipelines shall transport or purchase without discrimination, oil or natural gas produced from submerged lands or outer Continental Shelf lands in the vicinity of the pipelines in such proportionate amounts as the Federal Energy Regulatory Commissio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive principles governing pipeline operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Competitive principles governing pipeline operation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates of production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rates of production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal action affecting outer Continental Shelf; notification; recommended changes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal action affecting outer Continental Shelf; notification; recommended changes The head of any Federal department or agency who takes any action which has a direct and significant effect on the outer Continental Shelf or its development shall promptly notify the Secretary of such action and the Secretary shall thereafter notify the Governor of any affected State and the Secretary may thereafter recommend such changes in such action as are considered appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flaring of natural gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Flaring of natural gas After September 18, 1978, no holder of any oil and gas lease issued or maintained pursuant to this subchapter shall be permitted to flare natural gas from any well unless the Secretary finds that there is no practicable way to complete production of such gas, or that such flaring is necessary to alleviate a temporary emergency situation or to conduct testing or work-over operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1334_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative development of common hydro­carbon-bearing areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative development of common hydro­carbon-bearing areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>