<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1340" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1340/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1340/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1340"><akn:num>1340</akn:num><akn:heading>Geological and geophysical explorations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1340. Geological and geophysical explorations(a) Approved exploration plans(1) Any agency of the United States and any person authorized by the Secretary may conduct geological and geophysical explorations in the outer Continental Shelf, which do not interfere with or endanger actual operations under any lease maintained or granted pursuant to this subchapter, and which are not unduly harmful to aquatic life in such area.

(2) The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply to any person conducting explorations pursuant to an approved exploration plan on any area under lease to such person pursuant to the provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Oil and gas explorationExcept as provided in subsection (f) of this section, beginning ninety days after September 18, 1978, no exploration pursuant to any oil and gas lease issued or maintained under this subchapter may be undertaken by the holder of such lease, except in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(c) Plan approval; State concurrence; plan provisions(1) Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, prior to commencing exploration pursuant to any oil and gas lease issued or maintained under this subchapter, the holder thereof shall submit an exploration plan to the Secretary for approval. Such plan may apply to more than one lease held by a lessee in any one region of the outer Continental Shelf, or by a group of lessees acting under a unitization, pooling, or drilling agreement, and shall be approved by the Secretary if he finds that such plan is consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, regulations prescribed under this subchapter, including regulations prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (8) of section 1334(a) of this title, and the provisions of such lease. The Secretary shall require such modifications of such plan as are necessary to achieve such consistency. The Secretary shall approve such plan, as submitted or modified, within thirty days of its subm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved exploration plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approved exploration plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil and gas exploration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Oil and gas exploration Except as provided in subsection (f) of this section, beginning ninety days after September 18, 1978, no exploration pursuant to any oil and gas lease issued or maintained under this subchapter may be undertaken by the holder of such lease, except in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan approval; State concurrence; plan provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan approval; State concurrence; plan provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drilling permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Drilling permit The Secretary may, by regulation, require any lessee operating under an approved exploration plan to obtain a permit prior to drilling any well in accordance with such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan revisions; conduct of exploration activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan revisions; conduct of exploration activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drilling permits issued and exploration plans approved within 90-day period after September 18, 1978</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Drilling permits issued and exploration plans approved within 90-day period after</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations requisite to issuance of permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Determinations requisite to issuance of permits Any permit for geological explorations authorized by this section shall be issued only if the Secretary determines, in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1340_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands beneath navigable waters adjacent to Phillip Burton Wilderness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Lands beneath navigable waters adjacent to Phillip Burton Wilderness The Secretary shall not issue a lease or permit for, or otherwise allow, exploration, development, or production activities within fifteen miles of the boundaries of the Phillip Burton Wilderness as depicted on a map entitled “Wilderness Plan, Point Reyes National Seashore”, numbered 612–90,000–B and dated September 1976, unless the State of California issues a lease or permit for, or otherwise allows, exploration, development, or production activities on lands beneath navigable waters (as such term is defined in section 1301 of this title) of such State which are adjacent to such Wilderness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>