<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1344"><akn:num>1344</akn:num><akn:heading>Outer Continental Shelf leasing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1344. Outer Continental Shelf leasing program(a) Schedule of proposed oil and gas lease salesThe Secretary, pursuant to procedures set forth in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, shall prepare and periodically revise, and maintain an oil and gas leasing program to implement the policies of this subchapter. The leasing program shall consist of a schedule of proposed lease sales indicating, as precisely as possible, the size, timing, and location of leasing activity which he determines will best meet national energy needs for the five-year period following its approval or reapproval. Such leasing program shall be prepared and maintained in a manner consistent with the following principles:(1) Management of the outer Continental Shelf shall be conducted in a manner which considers economic, social, and environmental values of the renewable and nonrenewable resources contained in the outer Continental Shelf, and the potential impact of oil and gas exploration on other resource values of the outer Continental Shelf and the marine, coastal, and human environments.

(2) Timing and location of exploration, development, and production of oil and gas among the oil- and gas-bearing physiographic regions of the outer Continental Shelf shall be based on a consideration of—(A) existing information concerning the geographical, geological, and ecological characteristics of such regions;

(B) an equitable sharing of developmental benefits and environmental risks among the various regions;

(C) the location of such regions with respect to, and the relative needs of, regional and national energy markets;

(D) the location of such regions with respect to other uses of the sea and seabed, including fisheries, navigation, existing or proposed sealanes, potential sites of deepwater ports, and other anticipated uses of the resources and space of the outer Continental Shelf;

(E) the interest of potential oil and gas producers in the development of oil and gas resources as indicated</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule of proposed oil and gas lease sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Schedule of proposed oil and gas lease sales The Secretary, pursuant to procedures set forth in subsections (c) and (d) of this section, shall prepare and periodically revise, and maintain an oil and gas leasing program to implement the policies of this subchapter. The leasing program shall consist of a schedule of proposed lease sales indicating, as precisely as possible, the size, timing, and location of leasing activity which he determines will best meet national energy needs for the five-year period following its approval or reapproval. Such leasing program shall be prepared and maintained in a manner consistent with the following principles:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimates of appropriations and staff required for management of leasing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Estimates of appropriations and staff required for management of leasing program The leasing program shall include estimates of the appropriations and staff required to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suggestions from Federal agencies and affected State and local governments; submission of proposed program to Governors of affected States and Congress; publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suggestions from Federal agencies and affected State and local governments; submission of proposed program to Governors of affected States and Congress; publication in Federal Register</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comments by Attorney General on anticipated effect on competition; comments by State or local governments; submission of program to President and Congress; issuance of leases in accordance with program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Comments by Attorney General on anticipated effect on competition; comments by State or local governments; submission of program to President and Congress; issuance of leases in accordance with program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review, revision, and reapproval of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review, revision, and reapproval of program The Secretary shall review the leasing program approved under this section at least once each year. He may revise and reapprove such program, at any time, and such revision and reapproval, except in the case of a revision which is not significant, shall be in the same manner as originally developed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural regulations for management of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedural regulations for management of program The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish procedures for— Such procedures shall be applicable to any significant revision or reapproval of the leasing program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information from public and private sources; confidentiality of classified or privileged data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information from public and private sources; confidentiality of classified or privileged data The Secretary may obtain from public sources, or purchase from private sources, any survey, data, report, or other information (including interpretations of such data, survey, report, or other information) which may be necessary to assist him in preparing any environmental impact statement and in making other evaluations required by this subchapter. Data of a classified nature provided to the Secretary under the provisions of this subsection shall remain confidential for such period of time as agreed to by the head of the department or agency from whom the information is requested. The Secretary shall maintain the confidentiality of all privileged or proprietary data or information for such period of time as is provided for in this subchapter, established by regulation, or agreed to by the parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information from all Federal departments and agencies; confidentiality of privileged or proprietary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Information from all Federal departments and agencies; confidentiality of privileged or proprietary information The heads of all Federal departments and agencies shall provide the Secretary with any nonpriviledged 11 So in original. Probably should be “nonprivileged”. or nonproprietary information he requests to assist him in preparing the leasing program and may provide the Secretary with any privileged or proprietary information he requests to assist him in preparing the leasing program. Privileged or proprietary information provided to the Secretary under the provisions of this subsection shall remain confidential for such period of time as agreed to by the head of the department or agency from whom the information is requested. In addition, the Secretary shall utilize the existing capabilities and resources of such Federal departments and agencies by appropriate agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application This section shall not apply to the scheduling of any lease sale in an area of the outer Continental Shelf that is adjacent to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>