<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1348" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1348/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1348/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1348"><akn:num>1348</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of safety and environmental regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1348. Enforcement of safety and environmental regulations(a) Utilization of Federal departments and agenciesThe Secretary, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, and the Secretary of the Army shall enforce safety and environmental regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter. Each such Federal department may by agreement utilize, with or without reimbursement, the services, personnel, or facilities of other Federal departments and agencies for the enforcement of their respective regulations.


(b) Duties of holders of lease or permitIt shall be the duty of any holder of a lease or permit under this subchapter to—(1) maintain all places of employment within the lease area or within the area covered by such permit in compliance with occupational safety and health standards and, in addition, free from recognized hazards to employees of the lease holder or permit holder or of any contractor or subcontractor operating within such lease area or within the area covered by such permit on the outer Continental Shelf;

(2) maintain all operations within such lease area or within the area covered by such permit in compliance with regulations intended to protect persons, property, and the environment on the outer Continental Shelf; and

(3) allow prompt access, at the site of any operation subject to safety regulations, to any inspector, and to provide such documents and records which are pertinent to occupational or public health, safety, or environmental protection, as may be requested.


(c) Onsite inspection of facilitiesThe Secretary and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall individually, or jointly if they so agree, promulgate regulations to provide for—(1) scheduled onsite inspection, at least once a year, of each facility on the outer Continental Shelf which is subject to any environmental or safety regulation promulgated pursuant to this subchapter, which inspection shall include all safety </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of Federal departments and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Utilization of Federal departments and agencies The Secretary, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, and the Secretary of the Army shall enforce safety and environmental regulations promulgated pursuant to this subchapter. Each such Federal department may by agreement utilize, with or without reimbursement, the services, personnel, or facilities of other Federal departments and agencies for the enforcement of their respective regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of holders of lease or permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of holders of lease or permit It shall be the duty of any holder of a lease or permit under this subchapter to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Onsite inspection of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Onsite inspection of facilities The Secretary and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall individually, or jointly if they so agree, promulgate regulations to provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation and report on major fires, oil spills, death, or serious injury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Investigation and report on major fires, oil spills, death, or serious injury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of allegations of violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review of allegations of violations The Secretary, or, in the case of occupational safety and health, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, may review any allegation from any person of the existence of a violation of a safety regulation issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1348_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summoning of witnesses and production of evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Summoning of witnesses and production of evidence In any investigation conducted pursuant to this section, the Secretary or the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall have power to summon witnesses and to require the production of books, papers, documents, and any other evidence. Attendance of witnesses or the production of books, papers, documents, or any other evidence shall be compelled by a similar process, as in the district courts of the United States. Such Secretary, or his designee, shall administer all necessary oaths to any witnesses summoned before such investigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>