<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1353" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1353/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1353/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1353"><akn:num>1353</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal purchase and disposition of oil and gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1353. Federal purchase and disposition of oil and gas(a) Payment of royalties or net profit shares in oil and gas; purchase of oil and gas by United States; transfer of title to Federal agencies(1) Except as may be necessary to comply with the provisions of sections 1335 and 1336 of this title, all royalties or net profit shares, or both, accruing to the United States under any oil and gas lease issued or maintained in accordance with this subchapter, shall, on demand of the Secretary, be paid in oil or gas.

(2) The United States shall have the right to purchase not to exceed 16⅔ per centum by volume of the oil and gas produced pursuant to a lease issued or maintained in accordance with this subchapter, at the regulated price, or, if no regulated price applies, at the fair market value at the well head of the oil and gas saved, removed, or sold, except that any oil or gas obtained by the United States as royalty or net profit share shall be credited against the amount that may be purchased under this subsection.

(3) Title to any royalty, net profit share, or purchased oil or gas may be transferred, upon request, by the Secretary to the Secretary of Defense, to the Administrator of the General Services Administration, or to the Secretary of Energy, for disposal within the Federal Government.


(b) Sale of oil by United States to public; disposition of oil to small refiners; application of other laws(1) The Secretary, except as provided in this subsection, may offer to the public and sell by competitive bidding for not more than its regulated price, or, if no regulated price applies, not less than its fair market value, any part of the oil (A) obtained by the United States pursuant to any lease as royalty or net profit share, or (B) purchased by the United States pursuant to subsection (a)(2) of this section.

(2) Whenever, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary determines that small refiners do not have access to adequate supplies of oil a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of royalties or net profit shares in oil and gas; purchase of oil and gas by United States; transfer of title to Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment of royalties or net profit shares in oil and gas; purchase of oil and gas by United States; transfer of title to Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of oil by United States to public; disposition of oil to small refiners; application of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sale of oil by United States to public; disposition of oil to small refiners; application of other laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of gas by United States to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale of gas by United States to public</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase by lessee of Federal oil or gas for which no bids received</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Purchase by lessee of Federal oil or gas for which no bids received The lessee shall take any Federal oil or gas for which no acceptable bids are received, as determined by the Secretary, and which is not transferred pursuant to subsection (a)(3) of this section, and shall pay to the United States a cash amount equal to the regulated price, or, if no regulated price applies, the fair market value of the oil or gas so obtained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1353_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of oil and gas in time of war</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Purchase of oil and gas in time of war Nothing in this section shall prohibit the right of the United States to purchase any oil or gas produced on the outer Continental Shelf as provided by section 1341(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>