<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1356b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1356b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1356b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1356b"><akn:num>1356b</akn:num><akn:heading>Transboundary hydrocarbon agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1356b. Transboundary hydrocarbon agreements(a) AuthorizationAfter December 26, 2013, the Secretary may implement the terms of any transboundary hydrocarbon agreement for the management of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs entered into by the President and approved by Congress. In implementing such an agreement, the Secretary shall protect the interests of the United States to promote domestic job creation and ensure the expeditious and orderly development and conservation of domestic mineral resources in accordance with all applicable United States laws governing the exploration, development, and production of hydrocarbon resources on the Outer Continental Shelf.


(b) Submission to Congress(1) In generalNo later than 180 days after all parties to a transboundary hydrocarbon agreement have agreed to its terms, a transboundary hydrocarbon agreement that does not constitute a treaty in the judgment of the President shall be submitted by the Secretary to—(A) the Speaker of the House of Representatives;

(B) the Majority Leader of the Senate;

(C) the Chair of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and

(D) the Chair of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.


(2) Contents of submissionThe submission shall include—(A) any amendments to this subchapter or other Federal law necessary to implement the agreement;

(B) an analysis of the economic impacts such agreement and any amendments necessitated by the agreement will have on domestic exploration, development, and production of hydrocarbon resources on the Outer Continental Shelf; and

(C) a detailed description of any regulations expected to be issued by the Secretary to implement the agreement.



(c) Implementation of specific transboundary agreement with MexicoThe Secretary may take actions as necessary to implement the terms of the Agreement between the United States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1356b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization After December 26, 2013, the Secretary may implement the terms of any transboundary hydrocarbon agreement for the management of transboundary hydrocarbon reservoirs entered into by the President and approved by Congress. In implementing such an agreement, the Secretary shall protect the interests of the United States to promote domestic job creation and ensure the expeditious and orderly development and conservation of domestic mineral resources in accordance with all applicable United States laws governing the exploration, development, and production of hydrocarbon resources on the Outer Continental Shelf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1356b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1356b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of specific transboundary agreement with Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation of specific transboundary agreement with Mexico The Secretary may take actions as necessary to implement the terms of the Agreement between the United States of America and the United Mexican States Concerning Transboundary Hydrocarbon Reservoirs in the Gulf of Mexico, signed at Los Cabos, February 20, 2012, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1356b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Savings provisions Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>