<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1453" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1453/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1453/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1453"><akn:num>1453</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Secretaries of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1453. Assistant Secretaries of the Interior
There shall be in the Department of the Interior two Assistant Secretaries of the Interior who shall be without numerical distinction of rank and who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.
(R.S. § 438; Mar. 3, 1885, ch. 360, 23 Stat. 497; Mar. 3, 1917, ch. 163, § 1, 39 Stat. 1102; Feb. 29, 1944, ch. 72, 58 Stat. 107.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Act Feb. 29, 1944, provided that the Assistant Secretaries shall be without numerical distinction of rank.
R.S. § 438 derived from acts Mar. 14, 1862, ch. 41, § 6, 12 Stat. 369; Mar. 3, 1873, ch. 226, § 1, 17 Stat. 486.
Section was formerly classified to section 482 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
Functions, powers, and duties of Office of Audit and Investigation in Department of the Interior transferred to Office of Inspector General in Department of the Interior, as established by section 9(a)(1)(F) of the Inspector General Act of 1978, Pub. L. 95–452, formerly set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. See section 422(a)(1)(H) of Title 5.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. May 24, 1950, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262, set out under section 1451 of this title.

Administrative Assistant SecretaryAn Administrative Assistant Secretary of the Interior, to be appointed, with the approval of the President, by the Secretary of the Interior under the classified civil service, to perform such duties as the Secretary of the Interior shall prescribe, and to receive compensation at the rate of $</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>