<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1474b"><akn:num>1474b</akn:num><akn:heading>Natural Resource Damage Assessment and Restoration Fund; availability of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1474b. Natural Resource Damage Assessment and Restoration Fund; availability of assessments
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in fiscal year 1991 and thereafter, sums provided by any party, including sums provided in advance or as a reimbursement for natural resource damage assessments, may be credited to this appropriation and shall remain available until expended.
(Pub. L. 102–154, title I, Nov. 13, 1991, 105 Stat. 994.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis appropriation, referred to in text, probably means appropriations under the heading “natural resource damage assessment and restoration fund” of the annual Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Investment of Exxon Valdez Oil Spill Court Recovery in High Yield Investments and in Marine ResearchPub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(3) [title III, § 350], Nov. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 1535, 1501A–207, provided that:
“(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to the provisions of paragraphs (5) and (7), upon the joint motion of the United States and the State of Alaska and the issuance of an appropriate order by the United States District Court for the District of Alaska, the joint trust funds, or any portion thereof, including any interest accrued thereon, previously received or to be received by the United States and the State of Alaska pursuant to the Agreement and Consent Decree issued in United States v. Exxon Corporation, et al. (No. A91–082 CIV) and State of Alaska v. Exxon Corporation, et al. (No. A91–083 CIV) (hereafter referred to as the ‘Consent Decree’), may be deposited in—“(A) the Natural Resource Damage Assessment and Restoration Fund (hereafter referred to as the ‘Fund’) established in title I of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1992 (Public Law 102–154; 43 U.S.C. 1474b);

“(B) accounts outside the United States Treasury (hereafter referred to as ‘outside accounts’)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>