<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1474d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1474d"><akn:num>1474d</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1474d. Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund(a) FundOne half of the amounts awarded by the Supreme Court to the United States in the case of United States of America v. State of Alaska (117 S.Ct. 1888) shall be deposited in a fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the “Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”).


(b) Investments(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall invest amounts in the Fund in interest bearing obligations of the United States.


(2) Acquisition of obligationsFor the purpose of investments under paragraph (1), obligations may be acquired—(A) on original issue at the issue price; or

(B) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price.


(3) Sale of obligationsAny obligations acquired by the Fund may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price.


(4) Credits to FundThe interest earned from investments of the Fund shall be covered into and form a part of the Fund.



(c) Transfer and availability of amounts earnedEach year, interest earned and covered into the Fund in the previous fiscal year shall be made available as follows:(1) To the extent provided in the subsequent appropriations Acts, 80 percent of such amounts shall be made available to be equally divided among the Directors of the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Chief of the Forest Service for high priority deferred maintenance and modernization of facilities that directly enhance the experience of visitors, including natural, cultural, recreational, and historic resources protection projects in National Parks, National Wildlife Refuges, and the public lands respectively as provided in subsection (d) and for payment to the State of Louisiana and its lessees for oil and gas drainage in the West Delta field. The Secretary shall submit with the annual budget submission to Congress a list of high priority </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fund One half of the amounts awarded by the Supreme Court to the United States in the case of United States of America v. State of Alaska (117 S.Ct. 1888) shall be deposited in a fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the “Environmental Improvement and Restoration Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer and availability of amounts earned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer and availability of amounts earned Each year, interest earned and covered into the Fund in the previous fiscal year shall be made available as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects A project referred to in subsection (c)(1) shall be consistent with the laws governing the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, the public lands and Forest Service lands and management plan for such unit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marine research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Marine research activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>