<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_155"><akn:num>155</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal, reservation, or restriction of public lands for defense purposes; “public lands” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 155. Withdrawal, reservation, or restriction of public lands for defense purposes; “public lands” defined; exception
Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, except in time of war or national emergency hereafter declared by the President or the Congress, on and after February 28, 1958 the provisions hereof shall apply to the withdrawal and reservation for, restriction of, and utilization by, the Department of Defense for defense purposes of the public lands of the United States, including public lands in the Territories of Alaska and Hawaii: Provided, That—(1) for the purposes of this Act, the term “public lands” shall be deemed to include, without limiting the meaning thereof, Federal lands and waters of the Outer Continental Shelf, as defined in section 1331 of this title, and Federal lands and waters off the coast of the Territories of Alaska and Hawaii;

(2) nothing in this Act shall be deemed to be applicable to the withdrawal or reservation of public lands specifically as naval petroleum, naval oil shale, or naval coal reserves;

(3) nothing in this Act shall be deemed to be applicable to the warning areas over the Federal lands and waters of the Outer Continental Shelf and Federal lands and waters off the coast of the Territory of Alaska reserved for use of the military departments prior to August 7, 1953, and

(4) nothing in this section, section 156, or section 157 of this title shall be deemed to be applicable either to those reservations or withdrawals which expired due to the ending of the unlimited national emergency of May 27, 1941, and which subsequent to such expiration have been and are now used by the military departments with the concurrence of the Department of the Interior, or to the withdrawal of public domain lands of the Marine Corps Training Center, Twentynine Palms, California, and the naval gunnery ranges in the State of Nevada designated as Basic Black Rock and Basic Sahwave Mountain.

(Pub. L. 85–337, § 1, Feb. 28, 1958, 72 Stat. 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) for the purposes of this Act, the term “public lands” shall be deemed to include, without limiting the meaning thereof, Federal lands and waters of the Outer Continental Shelf, as defined in section 1331 of this title, and Federal lands and waters off the coast of the Territories of Alaska and Hawaii;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) nothing in this Act shall be deemed to be applicable to the withdrawal or reservation of public lands specifically as naval petroleum, naval oil shale, or naval coal reserves;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) nothing in this Act shall be deemed to be applicable to the warning areas over the Federal lands and waters of the Outer Continental Shelf and Federal lands and waters off the coast of the Territory of Alaska reserved for use of the military departments prior to August 7, 1953, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) nothing in this section, section 156, or section 157 of this title shall be deemed to be applicable either to those reservations or withdrawals which expired due to the ending of the unlimited national emergency of May 27, 1941, and which subsequent to such expiration have been and are now used by the military departments with the concurrence of the Department of the Interior, or to the withdrawal of public domain lands of the Marine Corps Training Center, Twentynine Palms, California, and the naval gunnery ranges in the State of Nevada designated as Basic Black Rock and Basic Sahwave Mountain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>