<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1552" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1552/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1552/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1552"><akn:num>1552</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for long-range operation of reservoirs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1552. Criteria for long-range operation of reservoirs(a) Promulgation by Secretary; order of prioritiesIn order to comply with and carry out the provisions of the Colorado River Compact, the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact, and the Mexican Water Treaty, the Secretary shall propose criteria for the coordinated long-range operation of the reservoirs constructed and operated under the authority of the Colorado River Storage Project Act [43 U.S.C. 620 et seq.], the Boulder Canyon Project Act [43 U.S.C. 617 et seq.], and the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act [43 U.S.C. 618 et seq.]. To effect in part the purposes expressed in this paragraph, the criteria shall make provision for the storage of water in storage units of the Colorado River storage project and releases of water form Lake Powell in the following listed order of priority:(1) releases to supply one-half the deficiency described in article III(c) of the Colorado River Compact, if any such deficiency exists and is chargeable to the States of the Upper Division, but in any event such releases, if any, shall not be required in any year that the Secretary makes the determination and issues the proclamation specified in section 1512 of this title;

(2) releases to comply with article III(d) of the Colorado River Compact, less such quantities of water delivered into the Colorado River below Lee Ferry to the credit of the States of the Upper Division from other sources; and

(3) storage of water not required for the releases specified in clauses (1) and (2) of this subsection to the extent that the Secretary, after consultation with the Upper Colorado River Commission and representatives of the three Lower Division States and taking into consideration all relevant factors (including, but not limited to, historic stream-flows, the most critical period of record, and probabilities of water supply), shall find this to be reasonably necessary to assure deliveries under clauses (1) and (2) without impairment of an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1552_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation by Secretary; order of priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promulgation by Secretary; order of priorities In order to comply with and carry out the provisions of the Colorado River Compact, the Upper Colorado River Basin Compact, and the Mexican Water Treaty, the Secretary shall propose criteria for the coordinated long-range operation of the reservoirs constructed and operated under the authority of the Colorado River Storage Project Act [43 U.S.C. 620 et seq.], the Boulder Canyon Project Act [43 U.S.C. 617 et seq.], and the Boulder Canyon Project Adjustment Act [43 U.S.C. 618 et seq.]. To effect in part the purposes expressed in this paragraph, the criteria shall make provision for the storage of water in storage units of the Colorado River storage project and releases of water form Lake Powell in the following listed order of priority:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1552_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal of criteria for review and comment; publication; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submittal of criteria for review and comment; publication; report to Congress Not later than January 1, 1970, the criteria proposed in accordance with the foregoing subsection (a) of this section shall be submitted to the Governors of the seven Colorado River Basin States and to such other parties and agencies as the Secretary may deem appropriate for their review and comment. After receipt of comments on the proposed criteria, but not later than July 1, 1970, the Secretary shall adopt appropriate criteria in accordance with this section and publish the same in the Federal Register. Beginning January 1, 1972, and yearly thereafter, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress and to the Governors of the Colorado River Basin States a report describing the actual operation under the adopted criteria for the preceding compact water year and the projected operation for the current year. As a result of actual operating experience or unforeseen circumstances, the Secretary may thereafter</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1552_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powerplant operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powerplant operations Section 7 of the Colorado River Storage Project Act [43 U.S.C. 620f] shall be administered in accordance with the foregoing criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>