<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1595" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1595/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1595/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1595"><akn:num>1595</akn:num><akn:heading>Salinity control units; authority and functions of the Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1595. Salinity control units; authority and functions of the Secretary of the Interior(a) Allocation of costsThe Secretary shall allocate the total costs (excluding costs borne by non-Federal participants) of the on-farm measures authorized by section 1592(c) of this title, of all measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by section 1592(a) of this title, as follows:(1) Nonreimbursable costs; reimbursable costs(A) Nonreimbursable costs(i) In generalIn recognition of Federal responsibility for the Colorado River as an interstate stream and for international comity with Mexico, Federal ownership of the land of the Colorado River Basin from which most of the dissolved salts originate, and the policy established in the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.) and except as provided in clause (ii), the following shall be nonreimbursable:(I) 75 percent of the total costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by section 1592(a)(1) of this title, including 90 percent of—(aa) the costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by that section; and

(bb) the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.


(II) 75 percent of the total costs of construction and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by section 1592(a)(2) of this title, including 100 percent of—(aa) the costs of operation and maintenance of each unit or separable feature of a unit authorized by that section; and

(bb) the total costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of the associated measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone.


(III) 75 percent of the total costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature of a unit author</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocation of costs The Secretary shall allocate the total costs (excluding costs borne by non-Federal participants) of the on-farm measures authorized by section 1592(c) of this title, of all measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by section 1592(a) of this title, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs payable from Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Costs payable from Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs payable from Upper Colorado River Basin Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Costs payable from Upper Colorado River Basin Fund Costs of construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of each unit or separable feature thereof authorized by section 1592(a) of this title, costs of construction, operation, and maintenance of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and costs of implementation of the on-farm measures authorized by section 1592(c) of this title allocated for repayment by the upper basin under subsection (a)(2) shall be paid in accordance with section 620d(d)(5) of this title from the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund within the limit of the funds made available under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Upward adjustment of rates for electrical energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Upward adjustment of rates for electrical energy The Secretary is authorized to make upward adjustments in rates charged for electrical energy under all contracts administered by the Secretary under the Colorado River Storage Project Act (70 Stat. 105; 43 U.S.C. 620) as soon as practicable and to the extent necessary to cover the costs allocated to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund under subsection (a)(2) and in conformity with subsection (a)(3), subsection (a)(4) and subsection (a)(5): Provided, That revenues derived from said rate adjustments shall be available solely for the construction, operation, maintenance, and replacement of salinity control units, for the construction, operation, and maintenance of measures to replace incidental fish and wildlife values foregone, and for the implementation of on-farm measures in the Colorado River Basin herein authorized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1595_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Up-front cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Up-front cost share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>