<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1606"><akn:num>1606</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1606. Regional Corporations(a) Division of Alaska into twelve geographic regions; common heritage and common interest of region; area of region commensurate with operations of Native association; boundary disputes, arbitrationFor purposes of this chapter, the State of Alaska shall be divided by the Secretary within one year after December 18, 1971, into twelve geographic regions, with each region composed as far as practicable of Natives having a common heritage and sharing common interests. In the absence of good cause shown to the contrary, such regions shall approximate the areas covered by the operations of the following existing Native associations:(1) Arctic Slope Native Association (Barrow, Point Hope);

(2) Bering Straits Association (Seward Peninsula, Unalakleet, Saint Lawrence Island);

(3) Northwest Alaska Native Association (Kotzebue);

(4) Association of Village Council Presidents (southwest coast, all villages in the Bethel area, including all villages on the Lower Yukon River and the Lower Kuskokwim River);

(5) Tanana Chiefs’ Conference (Koyukuk, Middle and Upper Yukon Rivers, Upper Kuskokwim, Tanana River);

(6) Cook Inlet Association (Kenai, Tyonek, Eklutna, Iliamna);

(7) Bristol Bay Native Association (Dillingham, Upper Alaska Peninsula);

(8) Aleut League (Aleutian Islands, Pribilof Islands and that part of the Alaska Peninsula which is in the Aleut League);

(9) Chugach Native Association (Cordova, Tatitlek, Port Graham, English Bay, Valdez, and Seward);

(10) Tlingit-Haida Central Council (southeastern Alaska, including Metlakatla);

(11) Kodiak Area Native Association (all villages on and around Kodiak Island); and

(12) Copper River Native Association (Copper Center, Glennallen, Chitina, Mentasta).


Any dispute over the boundaries of a region or regions shall be resolved by a board of arbitrators consisting of one person selected by each of the Native associations involved, and an additional one or two persons, whichever is needed to make</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Division of Alaska into twelve geographic regions; common heritage and common interest of region; area of region commensurate with operations of Native association; boundary disputes, arbitration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Division of Alaska into twelve geographic regions; common heritage and common interest of region; area of region commensurate with operations of Native association; boundary disputes, arbitration For purposes of this chapter, the State of Alaska shall be divided by the Secretary within one year after December 18, 1971, into twelve geographic regions, with each region composed as far as practicable of Natives having a common heritage and sharing common interests. In the absence of good cause shown to the contrary, such regions shall approximate the areas covered by the operations of the following existing Native associations: Any dispute over the boundaries of a region or regions shall be resolved by a board of arbitrators consisting of one person selected by each of the Native associations involved, and an additional one or two persons, whichever is needed to make an odd number of arbitrators, such additional person or persons to be selected by the arbitrators selected by the Nativ</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Region mergers; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Region mergers; limitation The Secretary may, on request made within one year of December 18, 1971, by representative and responsible leaders of the Native associations listed in subsection (a), merge two or more of the twelve regions: Provided, That the twelve regions may not be reduced to less than seven, and there may be no fewer than seven Regional Corporations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of thirteenth region for nonresident Natives; majority vote; Regional Corporation for thirteenth region</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of thirteenth region for nonresident Natives; majority vote; Regional Corporation for thirteenth region If a majority of all eligible Natives eighteen years of age or older who are not permanent residents of Alaska elect, pursuant to section 1604(c) of this title, to be enrolled in a thirteenth region for Natives who are non-residents of Alaska, the Secretary shall establish such a region for the benefit of the Natives who elected to be enrolled therein, and they may establish a Regional Corporation pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation; business for profit; eligibility for benefits; provisions in articles for carrying out chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Incorporation; business for profit; eligibility for benefits; provisions in articles for carrying out chapter Five incorporators within each region, named by the Native association in the region, shall incorporate under the laws of Alaska a Regional Corporation to conduct business for profit, which shall be eligible for the benefits of this chapter so long as it is organized and functions in accordance with this chapter. The articles of incorporation shall include provisions necessary to carry out the terms of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original articles and bylaws: approval by Secretary prior to filing, submission for approval; amendments to articles: approval by Secretary; withholding approval in event of creation of inequities among Native individuals or groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Original articles and bylaws: approval by Secretary prior to filing, submission for approval; amendments to articles: approval by Secretary; withholding approval in event of creation of inequities among Native individuals or groups The original articles of incorporation and bylaws shall be approved by the Secretary before they are filed, and they shall be submitted for approval within eighteen months after December 18, 1971. The articles of incorporation may not be amended during the Regional Corporation’s first five years without the approval of the Secretary. The Secretary may withhold approval under this section if in his judgment inequities among Native individuals or groups of Native individuals would be created.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of directors; management; stockholders; provisions in articles or bylaws for number, term, and method of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Board of directors; management; stockholders; provisions in articles or bylaws for number, term, and method of election The management of the Regional Corporation shall be vested in a board of directors, all of whom, with the exception of the initial board, shall be stockholders over the age of eighteen. The number, terms, and method of election of members of the board of directors shall be fixed in the articles of incorporation or bylaws of the Regional Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Issuance of stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement Common Stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Settlement Common Stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain natural resource revenues; distribution among twelve Regional Corporations; computation of amount; subsection inapplicable to thirteenth Regional Corporation; exclusion from revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain natural resource revenues; distribution among twelve Regional Corporations; computation of amount; subsection inapplicable to thirteenth Regional Corporation; exclusion from revenues</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporate funds and other net income, distribution among: stockholders of Regional Corporations; Village Corporations and nonresident stockholders; and stockholders of thirteenth Regional Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Corporate funds and other net income, distribution among: stockholders of Regional Corporations; Village Corporations and nonresident stockholders; and stockholders of thirteenth Regional Corporation During the five years following December 18, 1971, not less than 10% of all corporate funds received by each of the twelve Regional Corporations under section 1605 of this title (Alaska Native Fund), and under subsection (i) (revenues from the timber resources and subsurface estate patented to it pursuant to this chapter), and all other net income, shall be distributed among the stockholders of the twelve Regional Corporations. Not less than 45% of funds from such sources during the first five-year period, and 50% thereafter, shall be distributed among the Village Corporations in the region and the class of stockholders who are not residents of those villages, as provided in subsection 22 So in original. to it. In the case of the thirteenth Regional Corporation, if organized, not less </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>