<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1610"><akn:num>1610</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1610. Withdrawal of public lands(a) Description of withdrawn public lands; exceptions; National Wildlife Refuge lands exception; time of withdrawal(1) The following public lands are withdrawn, subject to valid existing rights, from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining and mineral leasing laws, and from selection under the Alaska Statehood Act, as amended:(A) The lands in each township that encloses all or part of any Native village identified pursuant to subsection (b);

(B) The lands in each township that is contiguous to or corners on the township that encloses all or part of such Native village; and

(C) The lands in each township that is contiguous to or corners on a township containing lands withdrawn by paragraph (B) of this subsection.


The following lands are excepted from such withdrawal: lands in the National Park System and lands withdrawn or reserved for national defense purposes other than Naval Petroleum Reserve Numbered 4.

(2) All lands located within the townships described in subsection (a)(1) hereof that have been selected by, or tentatively approved to, but not yet patented to, the State under the Alaska Statehood Act are withdrawn, subject to valid existing rights, from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining and mineral leasing laws, and from the creation of third party interests by the State under the Alaska Statehood Act.

(3)(A) If the Secretary determines that the lands withdrawn by subsections (a)(1) and (2) hereof are insufficient to permit a Village or Regional Corporation to select the acreage it is entitled to select, the Secretary shall withdraw three times the deficiency from the nearest unreserved, vacant and unappropriated public lands. In making this withdrawal the Secretary shall, insofar as possible, withdraw public lands of a character similar to those on which the village is located and in order of their proximity to the center of the Native village:</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of withdrawn public lands; exceptions; National Wildlife Refuge lands exception; time of withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Description of withdrawn public lands; exceptions; National Wildlife Refuge lands exception; time of withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of Native villages subject to chapter; review; eligibility for benefits; expiration of withdrawals for villages; alternative eligibility; eligibility of unlisted villages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) List of Native villages subject to chapter; review; eligibility for benefits; expiration of withdrawals for villages; alternative eligibility; eligibility of unlisted villages NAME OF PLACE AND REGION Afognak, Afognak Island. Akhiok, Kodiak. Akiachak, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Akiak, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Akutan, Aleutian. Alakanuk, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Alatna, Koyukuk-Lower Yukon. Aleknagik, Bristol Bay. Allakaket, Koyukuk-Lower Yukon. Ambler, Bering Strait. Anaktuvuk, Pass, Arctic Slope. Andreafsey, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Aniak, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Anvik, Koyukuk-Lower Yukon. Arctic Village, Upper Yukon-Porcupine. Atka, Aleutian. Atkassok, Arctic Slope. Atmautlauk, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Barrow, Arctic Slope. Beaver, Upper Yukon-Porcupine. Belkofsky, Aleutian. Bethel, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Bill Moore’s, Southwest Coastal Lowland. Biorka, Aleutian. Birch Creek, Upper Yukon-Porcupine. Brevig Mission, Bering Strait. Buckland, Bering Strait. Candle, Be</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>