<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1612"><akn:num>1612</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1612. Surveys(a) Areas for conveyance to Village Corporations; monumentation of exterior boundaries; meanderable water boundaries exempt from requirement; land occupied as primary place of residence or business, or for other purposes and other patentable lands as subject to surveyThe Secretary shall survey the areas selected or designated for conveyance to Village Corporations pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. He shall monument only exterior boundaries of the selected or designated areas at angle points and at intervals of approximately two miles on straight lines. No ground survey or monumentation will be required along meanderable water boundaries. He shall survey within the areas selected or designated land occupied as a primary place of residence, as a primary place of business, and for other purposes, and any other land to be patented under this chapter.


(b) Withdrawals, selections, and conveyances pursuant to chapter: current plats of surveys or protraction diagrams; conformity to Land Survey SystemAll withdrawals, selections, and conveyances pursuant to this chapter shall be as shown on current plats of survey or protraction diagrams of the Bureau of Land Management, or protraction diagrams of the Bureau of the State where protraction diagrams of the Bureau of Land Management are not available, and shall conform as nearly as practicable to the United States Land Survey System.


(Pub. L. 92–203, § 13, Dec. 18, 1971, 85 Stat. 702.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Areas for conveyance to Village Corporations; monumentation of exterior boundaries; meanderable water boundaries exempt from requirement; land occupied as primary place of residence or business, or for other purposes and other patentable lands as subject to survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Areas for conveyance to Village Corporations; monumentation of exterior boundaries; meanderable water boundaries exempt from requirement; land occupied as primary place of residence or business, or for other purposes and other patentable lands as subject to survey The Secretary shall survey the areas selected or designated for conveyance to Village Corporations pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. He shall monument only exterior boundaries of the selected or designated areas at angle points and at intervals of approximately two miles on straight lines. No ground survey or monumentation will be required along meanderable water boundaries. He shall survey within the areas selected or designated land occupied as a primary place of residence, as a primary place of business, and for other purposes, and any other land to be patented under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawals, selections, and conveyances pursuant to chapter: current plats of surveys or protraction diagrams; conformity to Land Survey System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Withdrawals, selections, and conveyances pursuant to chapter: current plats of surveys or protraction diagrams; conformity to Land Survey System All withdrawals, selections, and conveyances pursuant to this chapter shall be as shown on current plats of survey or protraction diagrams of the Bureau of Land Management, or protraction diagrams of the Bureau of the State where protraction diagrams of the Bureau of Land Management are not available, and shall conform as nearly as practicable to the United States Land Survey System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>