<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1613"><akn:num>1613</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1613. Conveyance of lands(a) Native villages listed in section 1610 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreageImmediately after selection by a Village Corporation for a Native village listed in section 1610 of this title which the Secretary finds is qualified for land benefits under this chapter, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate in the number of acres shown in the following table:






If the village had on the 1970 censusenumeration date a Native populationbetween—It shall be entitled to a patent to an area of public lands equal to—


25 and 9969,120 acres.
100 and 19992,160 acres.
200 and 399115,200 acres.
400 and 599138,240 acres.
600 or more161,280 acres.



The lands patented shall be those selected by the Village Corporation pursuant to section 1611(a) of this title. In addition, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate in the lands selected pursuant to section 1611(b) of this title.


(b) Native villages listed in section 1615 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreageImmediately after selection by any Village Corporation for a Native village listed in section 1615 of this title which the Secretary finds is qualified for land benefits under this chapter, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate to 23,040 acres. The lands patented shall be the lands within the township or townships that enclose the Native village, and any additional lands selected by the Village Corporation from the surrounding townships withdrawn for the Native village by section 1615(a) of this title.


(c) Conveyance of certain land by Village Corporation(1) In generalEach patent issued pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) shall be subject to the requirements of this subsection. Upon receipt of a patent or patents:(A) The Village Corporation shall first convey to any Native or non-</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native villages listed in section 1610 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Native villages listed in section 1610 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreage Immediately after selection by a Village Corporation for a Native village listed in section 1610 of this title which the Secretary finds is qualified for land benefits under this chapter, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate in the number of acres shown in the following table:






If the village had on the 1970 censusenumeration date a Native populationbetween—It shall be entitled to a patent to an area of public lands equal to—


25 and 9969,120 acres.
100 and 19992,160 acres.
200 and 399115,200 acres.
400 and 599138,240 acres.
600 or more161,280 acres.



The lands patented shall be those selected by the Village Corporation pursuant to section 1611(a) of this title. In addition, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate in the lands selected pursuant to section 1611(b) of t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native villages listed in section 1615 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Native villages listed in section 1615 and qualified for land benefits; patents for surface estates; issuance; acreage Immediately after selection by any Village Corporation for a Native village listed in section 1615 of this title which the Secretary finds is qualified for land benefits under this chapter, the Secretary shall issue to the Village Corporation a patent to the surface estate to 23,040 acres. The lands patented shall be the lands within the township or townships that enclose the Native village, and any additional lands selected by the Village Corporation from the surrounding townships withdrawn for the Native village by section 1615(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of certain land by Village Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conveyance of certain land by Village Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of approximation with respect to acreage limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of approximation with respect to acreage limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surface and/or subsurface estates to Regional Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Surface and/or subsurface estates to Regional Corporations Immediately after selection by a Regional Corporation, the Secretary shall convey to the Regional Corporation title to the surface and/or the subsurface estates, as is appropriate, in the lands selected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patents to Village Corporations for surface estates and to Regional Corporations for subsurface estates; excepted lands; mineral rights, consent of Village Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Patents to Village Corporations for surface estates and to Regional Corporations for subsurface estates; excepted lands; mineral rights, consent of Village Corporations When the Secretary issues a patent to a Village Corporation for the surface estate in lands pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), he shall issue to the Regional Corporation for the region in which the lands are located a patent to the subsurface estate in such lands, except lands located in the National Wildlife Refuge System and lands withdrawn or reserved for national defense purposes, including Naval Petroleum Reserve Numbered 4, for which in lieu rights are provided for in section 1611(a)(1) of this title: Provided, That the right to explore, develop, or remove minerals from the subsurface estate in the lands within the boundaries of any Native village shall be subject to the consent of the Village Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valid existing rights preserved; saving provisions in patents; patentee rights; administration; proportionate rights of patentee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Valid existing rights preserved; saving provisions in patents; patentee rights; administration; proportionate rights of patentee All conveyances made pursuant to this chapter shall be subject to valid existing rights. Where, prior to patent of any land or minerals under this chapter, a lease, contract, permit, right-of-way, or easement (including a lease issued under section 6(g) of the Alaska Statehood Act) has been issued for the surface or minerals covered under such patent, the patent shall contain provisions making it subject to the lease, contract, permit, right-of-way, or easement, and the right of the lessee, contractee, permittee, or grantee to the complete enjoyment of all rights, privileges, and benefits thereby granted to him. Upon issuance of the patent, the patentee shall succeed and become entitled to any and all interests of the State or the United States as lessor, contractor, permitter, or grantor, in any such leases, contracts, permits, rights-of-way, or easement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1613_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for land conveyances; surface and subsurface estates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization for land conveyances; surface and subsurface estates The Secretary is authorized to withdraw and convey 2 million acres of unreserved and unappropriated public lands located outside the areas withdrawn by sections 1610 and 1615 of this title, and 11 So in original. Probably should be “as”. follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>