<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1615" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1615/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1615/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1615"><akn:num>1615</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal and selection of public lands; funds in lieu of acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1615. Withdrawal and selection of public lands; funds in lieu of acreage(a) Withdrawal of public lands; list of Native villagesAll public lands in each township that encloses all or any part of a Native village listed below, and in each township that is contiguous to or corners on such township, except lands withdrawn or reserved for national defense purposes, are hereby withdrawn, subject to valid existing rights, from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining and mineral leasing laws, and from selection under the Alaska Statehood Act, as amended:
Angoon, Southeast.
Craig, Southeast.
Hoonah, Southeast.
Hydaburg, Southeast.
Kake, Southeast.
Kasaan, Southeast.
Klawock, Southeast.
Saxman, Southeast.
Yakutat, Southeast.


(b) Native land selections; Village Corporations for listed Native villages; acreage; proximity of selections; conformity to Lands Survey SystemDuring a period of three years from December 18, 1971, each Village Corporation for the villages listed in subsection (a) shall select, in accordance with rules established by the Secretary, an area equal to 23,040 acres, which must include the township or townships in which all or part of the Native village is located, plus, to the extent necessary, withdrawn lands from the townships that are contiguous to or corner on such townships. All selections shall be contiguous and in reasonably compact tracts, except as separated by bodies of water, and shall conform as nearly as practicable to the United States Lands Survey System.


(c) Tlingit-Haida settlementThe funds appropriated by the Act of July 9, 1968 (82 Stat. 307), to pay the judgment of the Court of Claims in the case of The Tlingit and Haida Indians of Alaska, et al. against The United States, numbered 47,900, and distributed to the Tlingit and Haida Indians pursuant to the Act of July 13, 1970 (84 Stat. 431), are in lieu of the additional acreage to be conveyed to qualified villages listed in section 1610 of this tit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of public lands; list of Native villages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal of public lands; list of Native villages All public lands in each township that encloses all or any part of a Native village listed below, and in each township that is contiguous to or corners on such township, except lands withdrawn or reserved for national defense purposes, are hereby withdrawn, subject to valid existing rights, from all forms of appropriation under the public land laws, including the mining and mineral leasing laws, and from selection under the Alaska Statehood Act, as amended:
Angoon, Southeast.
Craig, Southeast.
Hoonah, Southeast.
Hydaburg, Southeast.
Kake, Southeast.
Kasaan, Southeast.
Klawock, Southeast.
Saxman, Southeast.
Yakutat, Southeast.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native land selections; Village Corporations for listed Native villages; acreage; proximity of selections; conformity to Lands Survey System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Native land selections; Village Corporations for listed Native villages; acreage; proximity of selections; conformity to Lands Survey System During a period of three years from December 18, 1971, each Village Corporation for the villages listed in subsection (a) shall select, in accordance with rules established by the Secretary, an area equal to 23,040 acres, which must include the township or townships in which all or part of the Native village is located, plus, to the extent necessary, withdrawn lands from the townships that are contiguous to or corner on such townships. All selections shall be contiguous and in reasonably compact tracts, except as separated by bodies of water, and shall conform as nearly as practicable to the United States Lands Survey System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tlingit-Haida settlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tlingit-Haida settlement The funds appropriated by the Act of July 9, 1968 (82 Stat. 307), to pay the judgment of the Court of Claims in the case of The Tlingit and Haida Indians of Alaska, et al. against The United States, numbered 47,900, and distributed to the Tlingit and Haida Indians pursuant to the Act of July 13, 1970 (84 Stat. 431), are in lieu of the additional acreage to be conveyed to qualified villages listed in section 1610 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of lands for selection for village of Klukwan; benefits under this chapter; existing entitlements; forest reserves; quitclaims to Chilkat Indian Village; location, character, and value of lands to be withdrawn; withdrawal and selection periods; nonwithdrawal of lands selected or nominated for selection by other Native Corporation or located on Admiralty Island</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withdrawal of lands for selection for village of Klukwan; benefits under this chapter; existing entitlements; forest reserves; quitclaims to Chilkat Indian Village; location, character, and value of lands to be withdrawn; withdrawal and selection periods; nonwithdrawal of lands selected or nominated for selection by other Native Corporation or located on Admiralty Island</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>