<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1620" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1620/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1620/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1620"><akn:num>1620</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1620. Taxation(a) Fund revenues exemption; investment income taxableRevenues originating from the Alaska Native Fund shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State, or local taxation at the time of receipt by a Regional Corporation, Village Corporation, or individual Native through dividend distributions (even if the Regional Corporation or Village Corporation distributing the dividend has not segregated revenue received from the Alaska Native Fund from revenue received from other sources) or in any other manner. This exemption shall not apply to income from the investment of such revenues.


(b) Shares of stock exemptionThe receipt of shares of stock in the Regional or Village Corporations by or on behalf of any Native shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State or local taxation.


(c) Land or land interests exemption; basis for sale or other disposition, adjustment; basis for interest in mine, well, other natural deposit, or block of timber, adjustmentThe receipt of land or any interest therein pursuant to this chapter or of cash in order to equalize the values of properties exchanged pursuant to section 1621(f) of this title shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State, or local taxation. The basis for determining gain or loss from the sale or other disposition of such land or interest in land for purposes of any Federal, State, or local tax imposed on or measured by income shall be the fair value of such land or interest in land at the time of receipt, adjusted as provided in section 1016 of title 26, as amended: Provided, however, That the basis of any such land or interest therein attributable to an interest in a mine, well, other natural deposit, or block of timber shall be not less than the fair value of such mine, well, natural deposit, or block of timber (or such interest therein as the Secretary shall convey) at the time of the first commercial development thereof, adjusted as provided in section 1016 of title 26. For purposes of this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund revenues exemption; investment income taxable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fund revenues exemption; investment income taxable Revenues originating from the Alaska Native Fund shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State, or local taxation at the time of receipt by a Regional Corporation, Village Corporation, or individual Native through dividend distributions (even if the Regional Corporation or Village Corporation distributing the dividend has not segregated revenue received from the Alaska Native Fund from revenue received from other sources) or in any other manner. This exemption shall not apply to income from the investment of such revenues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shares of stock exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Shares of stock exemption The receipt of shares of stock in the Regional or Village Corporations by or on behalf of any Native shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State or local taxation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land or land interests exemption; basis for sale or other disposition, adjustment; basis for interest in mine, well, other natural deposit, or block of timber, adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Land or land interests exemption; basis for sale or other disposition, adjustment; basis for interest in mine, well, other natural deposit, or block of timber, adjustment The receipt of land or any interest therein pursuant to this chapter or of cash in order to equalize the values of properties exchanged pursuant to section 1621(f) of this title shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State, or local taxation. The basis for determining gain or loss from the sale or other disposition of such land or interest in land for purposes of any Federal, State, or local tax imposed on or measured by income shall be the fair value of such land or interest in land at the time of receipt, adjusted as provided in section 1016 of title 26, as amended: Provided, however, That the basis of any such land or interest therein attributable to an interest in a mine, well, other natural deposit, or block of timber shall be not less than the fair value of such mine, well, natural deposit, or block of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Real property interests; exemption period for conveyance of interests not developed or leased or interests used solely for exploration, interests taxable; derivative revenues taxable; exchanges; simultaneous exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Real property interests; exemption period for conveyance of interests not developed or leased or interests used solely for exploration, interests taxable; derivative revenues taxable; exchanges; simultaneous exchanges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public lands status of real property interests exempt from real estate taxes for purposes of Federal highway and education laws; Federal fire protection services for real property interests without cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public lands status of real property interests exempt from real estate taxes for purposes of Federal highway and education laws; Federal fire protection services for real property interests without cost Real property interests conveyed pursuant to this chapter to a Native individual, Native group, corporation organized under section 1613(h)(3) of this title, or Village or Regional Corporation shall, so long as the fee therein remains not subject to State or local taxes on real estate, continue to be regarded as public lands for the purpose of computing the Federal share of any highway project pursuant to title 23, as amended and supplemented, for the purpose of the Johnson-O’Malley Act of April 16, 1934, as amended (25 U.S.C. 452),11 See References in Text note below. and for the purpose of Public Laws 815 and 874, 81st Congress (64 Stat. 967, 1100). So long as there are no substantial revenues from such lands they shall continue to receive wildland fire protection services from th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stocks of Regional and Village Corporations exempt from estate taxes; period of exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Stocks of Regional and Village Corporations exempt from estate taxes; period of exemption Until January 1, 1992, stock of any Regional Corporation organized pursuant to section 1606 of this title, including the right to receive distributions under subsection 1606(j) of this title, and stock of any Village Corporation organized pursuant to section 1607 of this title shall not be includable in the gross estate of a decedent under sections 2031 and 2033, or any successor provisions, of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource information or analysis; professional or technical services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Resource information or analysis; professional or technical services In the case of any Native Corporation established pursuant to this chapter, income for purposes of any form of Federal, State, or local taxation shall not be deemed to include the value of— This subsection shall be effective as of December 18, 1971, and, with respect to each Native Corporation, shall remain in full force and effect for a period of twenty years thereafter or until the Corporation has received conveyance of its full land entitlement, whichever first occurs. Except as set forth in this subsection and in subsection (d) hereof, all rents, royalties, profits, and other revenues or proceeds derived from real property interests selected and conveyed pursuant to sections 1611 and 1613 of this title shall be taxable to the same extent as such revenues or proceeds are taxable when received by a non-Native individual or corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date of incorporation as date of trade or business; ordinary and necessary expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Date of incorporation as date of trade or business; ordinary and necessary expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal Holding Company Act exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Personal Holding Company Act exemption No Corporation created pursuant to this chapter shall be considered to be a personal holding company within the meaning of section 542(a) of title 26 prior to January 1, 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1620_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder homesites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Shareholder homesites A real property interest distributed by a Native Corporation to a shareholder of such Corporation pursuant to a program to provide homesites to its shareholders, shall be deemed conveyed and received pursuant to this chapter: Provided, That alienability of the Settlement Common Stock of the Corporation has not been terminated pursuant to section 1629c of this title: Provided further, That the land received is restricted by covenant for a period not less than ten years to single-family (including traditional extended family customs) residential occupancy, and by such other covenants and retained interests as the Native Corporation deems appropriate: Provided further, That the land conveyed does not exceed one and one-half acres: Provided further, That if the shareholder receiving the homesite subdivides such homesite, he or she shall pay all Federal, State, and local taxes that would have been incurred but for this subsection together with simple interest at 6 </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>