<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1629g_1"><akn:num>1629g–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska Native Vietnam era veterans land allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1629g–1. Alaska Native Vietnam era veterans land allotment(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Available Federal land(A) In generalThe term “available Federal land” means Federal land in the State that—(i) is vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved and is identified as available for selection under subsection (b)(5); or

(ii) has been selected by, but not yet conveyed to—(I) the State, if the State agrees to voluntarily relinquish the selection of the Federal land for selection by an eligible individual; or

(II) a Regional Corporation or a Village Corporation, if the Regional Corporation or Village Corporation agrees to voluntarily relinquish the selection of the Federal land for selection by an eligible individual.



(B) ExclusionsThe term “available Federal land” does not include any Federal land in the State that is—(i)(I) a right-of-way of the TransAlaska Pipeline; or

(II) an inner or outer corridor of such a right-of-way;


(ii) withdrawn or acquired for purposes of the Armed Forces;

(iii) under review for a pending right-of-way for a natural gas corridor;

(iv) within the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge;

(v) within a unit of the National Forest System;

(vi) designated as wilderness by Congress;

(vii) within a unit of the National Park System, a National Preserve, or a National Monument;

(viii) within a component of the National Trails System;

(ix) within a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; or

(x) within the National Petroleum Reserve–Alaska.



(2) Eligible individualThe term “eligible individual” means an individual who, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (c)(1), is—(A) a Native veteran—(i) who served in the Armed Forces during the period between August 5, 1964, and December 31, 1971; and

(ii) has not received an allotment made pursuant to—(I) the Act of May 17, 1906 (34 Stat. 197, chapter 2469) (as in effect on December 17, 1971);

(II) section 1613(h)(5) of this title; or

(III) section 1629g of thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments for eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allotments for eligible individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of available Federal land in units of the National Wildlife Refuge System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification of available Federal land in units of the National Wildlife Refuge System</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation No Federal land may be identified for selection or made available for allotment within a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System unless it has been authorized by an Act of Congress subsequent to March 12, 2019. Further, any proposed conveyance of land within a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System must have been identified by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (c)(4) in the report to Congress required by subsection (c) and include patent provisions that the land remains subject to the laws and regulations governing the use and development of the Refuge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>