<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1629b"><akn:num>1629b</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for considering amendments and resolutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1629b. Procedures for considering amendments and resolutions(a) CoverageNotwithstanding any provision of the articles of incorporation and bylaws of a Native Corporation or of the laws of the State, except those related to proxy statements and solicitations that are not inconsistent with this section—(1) an amendment to the articles of incorporation of a Native Corporation authorized by subsections (g) and (h) of section 1606 of this title, subsection (d)(1)(B) of this section, or section 1629c of this title;

(2) a resolution authorized by section 1629d(a)(2) of this title;

(3) a resolution to establish a Settlement Trust; or

(4) a resolution to convey all or substantially all of the assets of a Native Corporation to a Settlement Trust pursuant to section 1629e(a)(1) of this title;


shall be considered in accordance with the provisions of this section.

(b) Basic procedure(1) An amendment or resolution described in subsection (a) may be approved by the board of directors of a Native Corporation in accordance with its bylaws. If the board approves the amendment or resolution, it shall direct that the amendment or resolution be submitted to a vote of the shareholders at the next annual meeting or at a special meeting (if the board, at its discretion, schedules such special meeting). One or more such amendments or resolutions may be submitted to the shareholders and voted upon at one meeting.

(2)(A) A written notice (including a proxy statement if required under applicable law), setting forth the amendment or resolution approved pursuant to paragraph (1) (and, at the discretion of the board, a summary of the changes to be effected) together with any amendment or resolution submitted pursuant to subsection (c) and the statements described therein shall be sent, not less than fifty days nor more than sixty days prior to the meeting of the shareholders, by first-class mail or hand-delivered to each shareholder of record entitled to vote at his or her address as it </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coverage Notwithstanding any provision of the articles of incorporation and bylaws of a Native Corporation or of the laws of the State, except those related to proxy statements and solicitations that are not inconsistent with this section— shall be considered in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basic procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder petitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Shareholder petitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Voting standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting power</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Voting power For the purposes of this section, the determination of total voting power of a Native Corporation shall include all outstanding shares of stock that carry voting rights except shares that are not permitted to vote on the amendment or resolution in question because of restrictions in the articles of incorporation of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantially all of the assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Substantially all of the assets For purposes of this section and section 1629e of this title, a Native Corporation shall be considered to be transferring all or substantially all of its assets to a Settlement Trust only if such assets represent two-thirds or more of the fair market value of the Native Corporation’s total assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>