<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1629g"><akn:num>1629g</akn:num><akn:heading>Open season for certain Alaska Native veterans for allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1629g. Open season for certain Alaska Native veterans for allotments(a) In general(1) During the eighteen month period following promulgation of implementing rules pursuant to subsection (e), a person described in subsection (b) shall be eligible for an allotment of not more than two parcels of federal 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. land totaling 160 acres or less under the Act of May 17, 1906 (chapter 2469; 34 Stat. 197), as such Act was in effect before December 18, 1971.

(2) Allotments may be selected only from lands that were vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved on the date when the person eligible for the allotment first used and occupied those lands.

(3) The Secretary may not convey allotments containing any of the following—(A) lands upon which a native or non-native campsite is located, except for a campsite used primarily by the person selecting the allotment;

(B) lands selected by, but not conveyed to, the State of Alaska pursuant to the Alaska Statehood Act or any other provision of law;

(C) lands selected by, but not conveyed to, a Village or Regional Corporation;

(D) lands designated as wilderness by statute;

(E) acquired lands;

(F) lands containing a building, permanent structure, or other development owned or controlled by the United States, another unit of government, or a person other than the person selecting the allotment;

(G) lands withdrawn or reserved for national defense purposes other than National Petroleum Reserve-Alaska;

(H) National Forest Lands; and

(I) lands selected or claimed, but not conveyed, under a public land law, including but not limited to the following:(1) Lands within a recorded mining claim.

(2) Home sites.

(3) Trade and Manufacturing sites.

(4) Reindeer sites or headquarters sites.

(5) Cemetery sites.



(4) A person who qualifies for an allotment on lands prohibited from conveyance by a provision of subsection (a)(3) may select an alternative allotment from the following lands located</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible person</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Study and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For the purposes of this section, the terms “veteran” and “Vietnam era” have the meanings given those terms by paragraphs (2) and (29), respectively, of section 101 of title 38.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations No later than 18 months after October 21, 1998, the Secretary of the Interior shall promulgate, after consultation with Alaska Natives groups, rules to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>