<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1629h"><akn:num>1629h</akn:num><akn:heading>Kake Tribal Corporation land transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1629h. Kake Tribal Corporation land transfer(a) In generalIf—(1) the State of Alaska relinquishes its selection rights under the Alaska Statehood Act (Public Law 85–508) to lands described in subsection (c)(2) of this section; and

(2) Kake Tribal Corporation and Sealaska Corporation convey all right, title, and interest to lands described in subsection (c)(1) to the City of Kake, Alaska,


then the Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as “Secretary”) shall, not later than 180 days thereafter, convey to Kake Tribal Corporation title to the surface estate in the land identified in subsection (c)(2) of this section, and convey to Sealaska Corporation title to the subsurface estate in such land.

(b) Effect on selection totals(1) Of the lands to which the State of Alaska relinquishes selection rights and which are conveyed to the City of Kake pursuant to subsection (a), 694.5 acres shall be charged against lands to be selected by the State of Alaska under section 6(a) of the Alaska Statehood Act and 694.5 acres against lands to be selected by the State of Alaska under section 6(b) of the Alaska Statehood Act.

(2) The land conveyed to Kake Tribal Corporation and to Sealaska Corporation under this section is, for all purposes, considered to be land conveyed under this chapter. However, the conveyance of such land to Kake Tribal Corporation shall not count against or otherwise affect the Corporation’s remaining entitlement under section 1615(b) of this title.


(c) Lands subject to exchange(1) The lands to be transferred to the City of Kake under subsection (a) are the surface and subsurface estate to approximately 1,430 acres of land owned by Kake Tribal Corporation and Sealaska Corporation, and depicted as “KTC Land to City of Kake” on the map entitled “Kake Land Exchange-2000”, dated May 2000.

(2) The lands subject to relinquishment by the State of Alaska and to conveyance to Kake Tribal Corporation and Sealaska Corporation under subsection (a) are the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If— then the Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as “Secretary”) shall, not later than 180 days thereafter, convey to Kake Tribal Corporation title to the surface estate in the land identified in subsection (c)(2) of this section, and convey to Sealaska Corporation title to the subsurface estate in such land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on selection totals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect on selection totals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands subject to exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lands subject to exchange</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, the lands described in subsection (c)(2) are withdrawn from all forms of location, entry, and selection under the mining and public land laws of the United States and from leasing under the mineral and geothermal leasing laws. This withdrawal expires 18 months after the effective date of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maps The maps referred to in this chapter shall be maintained on file in the Office of the Chief, United States Forest Service, the Office of the Secretary of the Interior, and the Office of the Petersburg Ranger District, Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Watershed management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Watershed management The United States Forest Service may cooperate with Kake Tribal Corporation and the City of Kake in developing a watershed management plan that provides for the protection of the watershed in the public interest. Grants may be made, and contracts and cooperative agreements may be entered into, to the extent necessary to assist the City of Kake and Kake Tribal Corporation in the preparation and implementation of a watershed management plan for the land within the City of Kake’s municipal watershed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date This section is effective upon the execution of one or more conservation easements that, subject to valid existing rights of third parties—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized such sums as may be necessary to carry out this chapter, including to compensate Kake Tribal Corporation for relinquishing its development rights pursuant to subsection (g)(2). No funds authorized under this section may be paid to Kake Tribal Corporation unless Kake Tribal Corporation is a party to the conservation easements described in subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>