<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1629e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1629e"><akn:num>1629e</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement Trust option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1629e. Settlement Trust option(a) Conveyance of corporate assets(1)(A) A Native Corporation may convey assets (including stock or beneficial interests therein) to a Settlement Trust in accordance with the laws of the State (except to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with this section and section 1629b of this title).

(B) The approval of the shareholders of the corporation in the form of a resolution shall be required to convey all or substantially all of the assets of the corporation to a Settlement Trust. A conveyance in violation of this clause shall be void ab initio and shall not be given effect by any court.


(2) No subsurface estate in land shall be conveyed to a Settlement Trust. A conveyance of title to, or any other interest in, subsurface estate in violation of this subparagraph shall be void ab initio and shall not be given effect by any court.

(3) Conveyances made pursuant to this subsection—(A) shall be subject to applicable laws respecting fraudulent conveyance and creditors rights; and

(B) shall give rise to dissenters rights to the extent provided under the laws of the State only if—(i) the rights of beneficiaries in the Settlement Trust receiving a conveyance are inalienable; and

(ii) a shareholder vote on such transfer is required by section 1629b(a)(4) of this title.



(4) The provisions of this subsection shall not prohibit a Native Corporation from engaging in any conveyance, reorganization, or transaction not otherwise prohibited under the laws of the State or the United States.


(b) Authority and limitations of a Settlement Trust(1) The purpose of a Settlement Trust shall be to promote the health, education, and welfare of its beneficiaries and preserve the heritage and culture of Natives. A Settlement Trust shall not—(A) operate as a business;

(B) alienate land or any interest in land received from the settlor Native Corporation (except if the recipient of the land is the settlor corporation or the land is conveyed for a h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of corporate assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conveyance of corporate assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and limitations of a Settlement Trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority and limitations of a Settlement Trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1629e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Savings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>