<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1635" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1635/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1635/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1635"><akn:num>1635</akn:num><akn:heading>State selections and conveyances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1635. State selections and conveyances(a) Omitted

(b) School lands settlement(1) In full and final settlement of any and all claims by the State of Alaska arising under the Act of March 4, 1915 (38 Stat. 1214), as confirmed and transferred in section 6(k) of the Alaska Statehood Act, the State is hereby granted seventy-five thousand acres which it shall be entitled to select until January 4, 1994, from vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved public lands. In exercising the selection rights granted herein, the State shall be deemed to have relinquished all claims to any right, title, or interest to any school lands which failed to vest under the above statutes at the time Alaska became a State (January 3, 1959), including lands unsurveyed on that date or surveyed lands which were within Federal reservations or withdrawals on that date.

(2) Except as provided herein, such selections shall be made in conformance with the provisions for selections under section 6(b) of the Alaska Statehood Act. Selections made under this subsection shall be in units of whole sections as shown on the official survey plats of the Bureau of Land Management, including protraction diagrams, unless part of the section is unavailable or the land is otherwise surveyed, or unless the Secretary waives the whole section requirement.

(3) Lands selected and conveyed to the State under this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of subsections (j) and (k) of section 6 of the Alaska Statehood Act.


(c) Prior tentative approvals(1) All tentative approvals of State of Alaska land selections pursuant to the Alaska Statehood Act are hereby confirmed, subject only to valid existing rights and Native selection rights under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.], and the United States hereby confirms that all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to such lands is deemed to have vested in the State of Alaska as of the date of tentative approval; except th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>School lands settlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) School lands settlement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior tentative approvals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prior tentative approvals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior State selections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prior State selections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Future “top filings”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Future “top filings” Subject to valid existing rights and Native selection rights under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.], the State, at its option, may file future selection applications and amendments thereto, pursuant to section 6(a) or (b) of the Alaska Statehood Act or subsection (b) of this section, for lands which are not, on the date of filing of such applications, available within the meaning of section 6(a) or (b) of the Alaska Statehood Act, other than lands within any conservation system unit or the National Petroleum Reserve—Alaska. Each such selection application, if otherwise valid, shall become an effective selection without further action by the State upon the date the lands included in such application become available within the meaning of subsection (a) or (b) of section 6 regardless of whether such date occurs before or after expiration of the State’s land selection rights. Selection applications heretofore filed by the State may </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to overselect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Right to overselect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of specified lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conveyance of specified lands In furtherance of the State’s entitlement to lands under section 6(b) of the Alaska Statehood Act, the United States hereby conveys to the State of Alaska all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to all vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved lands, including lands subject to subsection (e) of this section but which lie within those townships outside the boundaries of conservation system units, National Conservation Areas, National Recreation Areas, new national forests and forest additions, established, designated, or expanded by this Act, which are specified in the list entitled “State Selection Lands May 15, 1978”, dated July 24, 1978, submitted by the State of Alaska and on file in the office of the Secretary of the Interior. The denomination of lands in such list which are not, on December 2, 1980, available lands within the meaning of section 6(b) of the Alaska Statehood Act and this Act shall be treated as a future selection app</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of conveyances of specified lands tentative approvals; surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation of conveyances of specified lands tentative approvals; surveys</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Adjudication Nothing contained in this section shall relieve the Secretary of the duty to adjudicate conflicting claims regarding the lands specified in subsection (g) of this section, or otherwise selected under authority of the Alaska Statehood Act, subsection (b) of this section, or other law, prior to the issuance of tentative approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of land status outside units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Clarification of land status outside units As to lands outside the boundaries of a conservation system unit, National Recreation Areas, National Conservation Areas, new national forests and forest additions, the following withdrawals, classifications, or designations shall not, of themselves, remove the lands involved from the status of vacant, unappropriated, and unreserved lands for the purposes of subsection (d) or (g) of this section and future State selections pursuant to the Alaska Statehood Act or subsection (b) of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>