<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1714" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1714/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1714/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1714"><akn:num>1714</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawals of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1714. Withdrawals of lands(a) Authorization and limitation; delegation of authorityOn and after the effective date of this Act the Secretary is authorized to make, modify, extend, or revoke withdrawals but only in accordance with the provisions and limitations of this section. The Secretary may delegate this withdrawal authority only to individuals in the Office of the Secretary who have been appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(b) Application and procedures applicable subsequent to submission of application(1) Within thirty days of receipt of an application for withdrawal, and whenever he proposes a withdrawal on his own motion, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register stating that the application has been submitted for filing or the proposal has been made and the extent to which the land is to be segregated while the application is being considered by the Secretary. Upon publication of such notice the land shall be segregated from the operation of the public land laws to the extent specified in the notice. The segregative effect of the application shall terminate upon (a) rejection of the application by the Secretary, (b) withdrawal of lands by the Secretary, or (c) the expiration of two years from the date of the notice.

(2) The publication provisions of this subsection are not applicable to withdrawals under subsection (e) hereof.


(c) Congressional approval procedures applicable to withdrawals aggregating five thousand acres or more(1) On and after October 21, 1976, a withdrawal aggregating five thousand acres or more may be made (or such a withdrawal or any other withdrawal involving in the aggregate five thousand acres or more which terminates after such date of approval may be extended) only for a period of not more than twenty years by the Secretary on his own motion or upon request by a department or agency head. The Secretary shall notify both Houses of Congress of such a withdrawal no la</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization and limitation; delegation of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization and limitation; delegation of authority On and after the effective date of this Act the Secretary is authorized to make, modify, extend, or revoke withdrawals but only in accordance with the provisions and limitations of this section. The Secretary may delegate this withdrawal authority only to individuals in the Office of the Secretary who have been appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and procedures applicable subsequent to submission of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application and procedures applicable subsequent to submission of application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional approval procedures applicable to withdrawals aggregating five thousand acres or more</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Congressional approval procedures applicable to withdrawals aggregating five thousand acres or more</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawals aggregating less than five thousand acres; procedure applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withdrawals aggregating less than five thousand acres; procedure applicable A withdrawal aggregating less than five thousand acres may be made under this subsection by the Secretary on his own motion or upon request by a department or an agency head—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency withdrawals; procedure applicable; duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Emergency withdrawals; procedure applicable; duration When the Secretary determines, or when the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate notifies the Secretary, that an emergency situation exists and that extraordinary measures must be taken to preserve values that would otherwise be lost, the Secretary notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (c)(1) and (d) of this section, shall immediately make a withdrawal and file notice of such emergency withdrawal with both of those Committees. Such emergency withdrawal shall be effective when made but shall last only for a period not to exceed three years and may not be extended except under the provisions of subsection (c)(1) or (d), whichever is applicable, and (b)(1) of this section. The information required in subsection (c)(2) of this subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. shall be furnished the committees within three months</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of existing withdrawals and extensions; procedure applicable to extensions; duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review of existing withdrawals and extensions; procedure applicable to extensions; duration All withdrawals and extensions thereof, whether made prior to or after October 21, 1976, having a specific period shall be reviewed by the Secretary toward the end of the withdrawal period and may be extended or further extended only upon compliance with the provisions of subsection (c)(1) or (d), whichever is applicable, and only if the Secretary determines that the purpose for which the withdrawal was first made requires the extension, and then only for a period no longer than the length of the original withdrawal period. The Secretary shall report on such review and extensions to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Processing and adjudication of existing applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Processing and adjudication of existing applications All applications for withdrawal pending on October 21, 1976 shall be processed and adjudicated to conclusion within fifteen years of October 21, 1976, in accordance with the provisions of this section. The segregative effect of any application not so processed shall terminate on that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearing required for new withdrawals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Public hearing required for new withdrawals All new withdrawals made by the Secretary under this section (except an emergency withdrawal made under subsection (e) of this section) shall be promulgated after an opportunity for a public hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent for withdrawal of lands under administration of department or agency other than Department of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Consent for withdrawal of lands under administration of department or agency other than Department of the Interior In the case of lands under the administration of any department or agency other than the Department of the Interior, the Secretary shall make, modify, and revoke withdrawals only with the consent of the head of the department or agency concerned, except when the provisions of subsection (e) of this section apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1714_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other Federal laws withdrawing lands as limiting authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Applicability of other Federal laws withdrawing lands as limiting authority The Secretary shall not make, modify, or revoke any withdrawal created by Act of Congress; make a withdrawal which can be made only by Act of Congress; modify or revoke any withdrawal creating national monuments under chapter 3203 of title 54; or modify, or revoke any withdrawal which added lands to the National Wildlife Refuge System prior to October 21, 1976, or which thereafter adds lands to that System under the terms of this Act. Nothing in this Act is intended to modify or change any provision of the Act of February 27, 1976 (90 Stat. 199; 16 U.S.C. 668dd(a)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>