<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1731"><akn:num>1731</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau of Land Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1731. Bureau of Land Management(a) Director; appointment, qualifications, functions, and dutiesThe Bureau of Land Management established by Reorganization Plan Numbered 3, of 1946 shall have as its head a Director. Appointments to the position of Director shall hereafter be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director of the Bureau shall have a broad background and substantial experience in public land and natural resource management. He shall carry out such functions and shall perform such duties as the Secretary may prescribe with respect to the management of lands and resources under his jurisdiction according to the applicable provisions of this Act and any other applicable law.


(b) Statutory transfer of functions, powers and duties relating to administration of lawsSubject to the discretion granted to him by Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1950, the Secretary shall carry out through the Bureau all functions, powers, and duties vested in him and relating to the administration of laws which, on October 21, 1976, were carried out by him through the Bureau of Land Management established by section 403 of Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1946. The Bureau shall administer such laws according to the provisions thereof existing as of October 21, 1976, as modified by the provisions of this Act or by subsequent law.


(c) Associate Director, Assistant Directors, and other employees; appointment and compensationIn addition to the Director, there shall be an Associate Director of the Bureau and so many Assistant Directors, and other employees, as may be necessary, who shall be appointed by the Secretary subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter 3 11 So in original. Probably should be subchapter “III”. of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.


(d) Existing</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director; appointment, qualifications, functions, and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Director; appointment, qualifications, functions, and duties The Bureau of Land Management established by Reorganization Plan Numbered 3, of 1946 shall have as its head a Director. Appointments to the position of Director shall hereafter be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director of the Bureau shall have a broad background and substantial experience in public land and natural resource management. He shall carry out such functions and shall perform such duties as the Secretary may prescribe with respect to the management of lands and resources under his jurisdiction according to the applicable provisions of this Act and any other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory transfer of functions, powers and duties relating to administration of laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statutory transfer of functions, powers and duties relating to administration of laws Subject to the discretion granted to him by Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1950, the Secretary shall carry out through the Bureau all functions, powers, and duties vested in him and relating to the administration of laws which, on October 21, 1976, were carried out by him through the Bureau of Land Management established by section 403 of Reorganization Plan Numbered 3 of 1946. The Bureau shall administer such laws according to the provisions thereof existing as of October 21, 1976, as modified by the provisions of this Act or by subsequent law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Associate Director, Assistant Directors, and other employees; appointment and compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Associate Director, Assistant Directors, and other employees; appointment and compensation In addition to the Director, there shall be an Associate Director of the Bureau and so many Assistant Directors, and other employees, as may be necessary, who shall be appointed by the Secretary subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service, and shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter 3 11 So in original. Probably should be subchapter “III”. of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1731_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing regulations relating to administration of laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Existing regulations relating to administration of laws Nothing in this section shall affect any regulation of the Secretary with respect to the administration of laws administered by him through the Bureau on October 21, 1976.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>