<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1735" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1735/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1735/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1735"><akn:num>1735</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeitures and deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1735. Forfeitures and deposits(a) Credit to separate account in Treasury; appropriation and availabilityAny moneys received by the United States as a result of the forfeiture of a bond or other security by a resource developer or purchaser or permittee who does not fulfill the requirements of his contract or permit or does not comply with the regulations of the Secretary; or as a result of a compromise or settlement of any claim whether sounding in tort or in contract involving present or potential damage to the public lands shall be credited to a separate account in the Treasury and are hereby authorized to be appropriated and made available, until expended as the Secretary may direct, to cover the cost to the United States of any improvement, protection, or rehabilitation work on those public lands which has been rendered necessary by the action which has led to the forfeiture, compromise, or settlement.


(b) Expenditure of moneys collected administering Oregon and California Railroad and Coos Bay Wagon Road Grant landsAny moneys collected under this Act in connection with lands administered under the Act of August 28, 1937 (50 Stat. 874; 43 U.S.C. 1181a–1181j),11 See References in Text note below. shall be expended for the benefit of such land only.


(c) RefundsIf any portion of a deposit or amount forfeited under this Act is found by the Secretary to be in excess of the cost of doing the work authorized under this Act, the Secretary, upon application or otherwise, may cause a refund of the amount in excess to be made from applicable funds.


(Pub. L. 94–579, title III, § 305, Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2765.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsecs. (b) and (c), is Pub. L. 94–579, Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2743, known as the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
Act of August 28, 1937 (50 Stat. 874; 43 U.S.C. 1181a–1181j), referred to in subsec. (b), probably m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1735_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit to separate account in Treasury; appropriation and availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Credit to separate account in Treasury; appropriation and availability Any moneys received by the United States as a result of the forfeiture of a bond or other security by a resource developer or purchaser or permittee who does not fulfill the requirements of his contract or permit or does not comply with the regulations of the Secretary; or as a result of a compromise or settlement of any claim whether sounding in tort or in contract involving present or potential damage to the public lands shall be credited to a separate account in the Treasury and are hereby authorized to be appropriated and made available, until expended as the Secretary may direct, to cover the cost to the United States of any improvement, protection, or rehabilitation work on those public lands which has been rendered necessary by the action which has led to the forfeiture, compromise, or settlement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1735_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure of moneys collected administering Oregon and California Railroad and Coos Bay Wagon Road Grant lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expenditure of moneys collected administering Oregon and California Railroad and Coos Bay Wagon Road Grant lands Any moneys collected under this Act in connection with lands administered under the Act of August 28, 1937 (50 Stat. 874; 43 U.S.C. 1181a–1181j),11 See References in Text note below. shall be expended for the benefit of such land only.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1735_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Refunds If any portion of a deposit or amount forfeited under this Act is found by the Secretary to be in excess of the cost of doing the work authorized under this Act, the Secretary, upon application or otherwise, may cause a refund of the amount in excess to be made from applicable funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>