<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1748b"><akn:num>1748b</akn:num><akn:heading>Cohesive wildfire management strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1748b. Cohesive wildfire management strategy(a) Strategy requiredNot later than one year after October 30, 2009, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting jointly, shall submit to Congress a report that contains a cohesive wildfire management strategy, consistent with the recommendations described in recent reports of the Government Accountability Office regarding management strategies.


(b) Elements of strategyThe strategy required by subsection (a) shall provide for—(1) the identification of the most cost-effective means for allocating fire management budget resources;

(2) the reinvestment in non-fire programs by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture;

(3) employing the appropriate management response to wildfires;

(4) assessing the level of risk to communities;

(5) the allocation of hazardous fuels reduction funds based on the priority of hazardous fuels reduction projects;

(6) assessing the impacts of climate change on the frequency and severity of wildfire; and

(7) studying the effects of invasive species on wildfire risk.


(c) RevisionAt least once during each five-year period beginning on the date of the submission of the cohesive wildfire management strategy under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall revise the strategy to address any changes affecting the strategy, including changes with respect to landscape, vegetation, climate, and weather.


(Pub. L. 111–88, div. A, title V, § 503, Oct. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 2971.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Federal Land Assistance, Management, and Enhancement Act of 2009, also known as the FLAME Act of 2009, and also as part of the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2010, and not as part of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 which comprises this chapter.

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 13855. Promoting Active M</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Strategy required Not later than one year after October 30, 2009, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting jointly, shall submit to Congress a report that contains a cohesive wildfire management strategy, consistent with the recommendations described in recent reports of the Government Accountability Office regarding management strategies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements of strategy The strategy required by subsection (a) shall provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revision At least once during each five-year period beginning on the date of the submission of the cohesive wildfire management strategy under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall revise the strategy to address any changes affecting the strategy, including changes with respect to landscape, vegetation, climate, and weather.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>