<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1748a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1748a"><akn:num>1748a</akn:num><akn:heading>FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1748a. FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Funds(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Federal landThe term “Federal land” means—(A) public land, as defined in section 1702 of this title;

(B) units of the National Park System;

(C) refuges of the National Wildlife Refuge System;

(D) land held in trust by the United States for the benefit of Indian tribes or members of an Indian tribe; and

(E) land in the National Forest System, as defined in section 1609(a) of title 16.


(2) FLAME FundThe term “FLAME Fund” means a FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund established by subsection (b).


(3) Relevant congressional committeesThe term “relevant congressional committees” means the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.


(4) Secretary concernedThe term “Secretary concerned” means—(A) the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to—(i) Federal land described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of paragraph (1); and

(ii) the FLAME Fund established for the Department of the Interior; and


(B) the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to—(i) National Forest System land; and

(ii) the FLAME Fund established for the Department of the Agriculture.




(b) Establishment of FLAME FundsThere is established in the Treasury of the United States the following accounts:(1) The FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund for the Department of the Interior.

(2) The FLAME Wildfire Suppression Reserve Fund for the Department of Agriculture.


(c) Purpose of FLAME FundsThe FLAME Funds shall be available to cover the costs of large or complex wildfire events and as a reserve when amounts provided for wildfire suppression and Federal emergency response in the Wildland Fire Management appropriation accounts are exhausted.


(d) Funding(1) Credits to fundsA FLAME Fund</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of FLAME Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of FLAME Funds There is established in the Treasury of the United States the following accounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of FLAME Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose of FLAME Funds The FLAME Funds shall be available to cover the costs of large or complex wildfire events and as a reserve when amounts provided for wildfire suppression and Federal emergency response in the Wildland Fire Management appropriation accounts are exhausted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of FLAME Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of FLAME Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of anticipated and predicted activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of anticipated and predicted activities For fiscal year 2011 and subsequent fiscal years, the Secretary concerned shall request funds within the Wildland Fire Management appropriation account of that Secretary for regular wildfire suppression activities that do not meet the criteria specified in subsection (e)(2)(B)(i).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on other transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition on other transfers The Secretary concerned may not transfer funds from non-fire accounts to the Wildland Fire Management appropriation account of that Secretary unless amounts in the FLAME Fund of that Secretary and any amounts appropriated to that Secretary for the purpose of wildfire suppression will be exhausted within 30 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Accounting and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1748a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination of authority The authority of the Secretary concerned to use the FLAME Fund established for that Secretary shall terminate at the end of the third fiscal year in which no appropriations to, or withdrawals from, that FLAME Fund have been made for a period of three consecutive fiscal years. Upon termination of such authority, any amounts remaining in the affected FLAME Fund shall be transferred to, and made a part of, the Wildland Fire Management appropriation account of the Secretary concerned for wildland suppression activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>