<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1752" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1752/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1752/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1752"><akn:num>1752</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing leases and permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1752. Grazing leases and permits(a) Terms and conditionsExcept as provided in subsection (b) of this section, permits and leases for domestic livestock grazing on public lands issued by the Secretary under the Act of June 28, 1934 (48 Stat. 1269, as amended; 43 U.S.C. 315 et seq.) or the Act of August 28, 1937 (50 Stat. 874, as amended; 43 U.S.C. 1181a–1181j),11 See References in Text note below. or by the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to lands within National Forests in the sixteen contiguous Western States, shall be for a term of ten years subject to such terms and conditions the Secretary concerned deems appropriate and consistent with the governing law, including, but not limited to, the authority of the Secretary concerned to cancel, suspend, or modify a grazing permit or lease, in whole or in part, pursuant to the terms and conditions thereof, or to cancel or suspend a grazing permit or lease for any violation of a grazing regulation or of any term or condition of such grazing permit or lease.


(b) Terms of lesser durationPermits or leases may be issued by the Secretary concerned for a period shorter than ten years where the Secretary concerned determines that—(1) the land is pending disposal; or

(2) the land will be devoted to a public purpose prior to the end of ten years; or

(3) it will be in the best interest of sound land management to specify a shorter term: Provided, That the absence from an allotment management plan of details the Secretary concerned would like to include but which are undeveloped shall not be the basis for establishing a term shorter than ten years: Provided further, That the absence of completed land use plans or court ordered environmental statements shall not be the sole basis for establishing a term shorter than ten years unless the Secretary determines on a case-by-case basis that the information to be contained in such land use plan or court ordered environmental impact statement is necessary to determine whether a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Terms and conditions Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, permits and leases for domestic livestock grazing on public lands issued by the Secretary under the Act of June 28, 1934 (48 Stat. 1269, as amended; 43 U.S.C. 315 et seq.) or the Act of August 28, 1937 (50 Stat. 874, as amended; 43 U.S.C. 1181a–1181j),11 See References in Text note below. or by the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to lands within National Forests in the sixteen contiguous Western States, shall be for a term of ten years subject to such terms and conditions the Secretary concerned deems appropriate and consistent with the governing law, including, but not limited to, the authority of the Secretary concerned to cancel, suspend, or modify a grazing permit or lease, in whole or in part, pursuant to the terms and conditions thereof, or to cancel or suspend a grazing permit or lease for any violation of a grazing regulation or of any term or condition of such grazing permit or lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of lesser duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of lesser duration Permits or leases may be issued by the Secretary concerned for a period shorter than ten years where the Secretary concerned determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>First priority for renewal of expiring permit or lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) First priority for renewal of expiring permit or lease</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment management plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allotment management plan requirements All permits and leases for domestic livestock grazing issued pursuant to this section may incorporate an allotment management plan developed by the Secretary concerned. However, nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede any requirement for completion of court ordered environmental impact statements prior to development and incorporation of allotment management plans. If the Secretary concerned elects to develop an allotment management plan for a given area, he shall do so in careful and considered consultation, cooperation and coordination with the lessees, permittees, and landowners involved, the district grazing advisory boards established pursuant to section 1753 of this title, and any State or States having lands within the area to be covered by such allotment management plan. Allotment management plans shall be tailored to the specific range condition of the area to be covered by such plan, and shall be reviewed on a peri</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omission of allotment management plan requirements and incorporation of appropriate terms and conditions; reexamination of range conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Omission of allotment management plan requirements and incorporation of appropriate terms and conditions; reexamination of range conditions In all cases where the Secretary concerned has not completed an allotment management plan or determines that an allotment management plan is not necessary for management of livestock operations and will not be prepared, the Secretary concerned shall incorporate in grazing permits and leases such terms and conditions as he deems appropriate for management of the permitted or leased lands pursuant to applicable law. The Secretary concerned shall also specify therein the numbers of animals to be grazed and the seasons of use and that he may reexamine the condition of the range at any time and, if he finds on reexami­nation that the condition of the range requires adjustment in the amount or other aspect of grazing use, that the permittee or lessee shall adjust his use to the extent the Secretary concerned deems necessary. Such readjustment shall b</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment management plan applicability to non-Federal lands; appeal rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allotment management plan applicability to non-Federal lands; appeal rights Allotment management plans shall not refer to livestock operations or range improvements on non-Federal lands except where the non-Federal lands are intermingled with, or, with the consent of the permittee or lessee involved, associated with, the Federal lands subject to the plan. The Secretary concerned under appropriate regulations shall grant to lessees and permittees the right of appeal from decisions which specify the terms and conditions of allotment management plans. The preceding sentence of this subsection shall not be construed as limiting any other right of appeal from decisions of such officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of permit or lease; determination of reasonable compensation; notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cancellation of permit or lease; determination of reasonable compensation; notice Whenever a permit or lease for grazing domestic livestock is canceled in whole or in part, in order to devote the lands covered by the permit or lease to another public purpose, including disposal, the permittee or lessee shall receive from the United States a reasonable compensation for the adjusted value, to be determined by the Secretary concerned, of his interest in authorized permanent improvements placed or constructed by the permittee or lessee on lands covered by such permit or lease, but not to exceed the fair market value of the terminated portion of the permittee’s or lessee’s interest therein. Except in cases of emergency, no permit or lease shall be canceled under this subsection without two years’ prior notification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority and timing for completion of environmental analyses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Priority and timing for completion of environmental analyses The Secretary concerned, in the sole discretion of the Secretary concerned, shall determine the priority and timing for completing each required environmental analysis with respect to a grazing allotment, permit, or lease based on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of provisions to rights, etc., in or to public lands or lands in National Forests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Applicability of provisions to rights, etc., in or to public lands or lands in National Forests Nothing in this Act shall be construed as modifying in any way law existing on October 21, 1976, with respect to the creation of right, title, interest or estate in or to public lands or lands in National Forests by issuance of grazing permits and leases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>