<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1764" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1764/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1764/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1764"><akn:num>1764</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1764. General requirements(a) Boundary specifications; criteria; temporary use of additional landsThe Secretary concerned shall specify the boundaries of each right-of-way as precisely as is practical. Each right-of-way shall be limited to the ground which the Secretary concerned determines (1) will be occupied by facilities which constitute the project for which the right-of-way is granted, issued, or renewed, (2) to be necessary for the operation or maintenance of the project, (3) to be necessary to protect the public safety, and (4) will do no unnecessary damage to the environment. The Secretary concerned may authorize the temporary use of such additional lands as he determines to be reasonably necessary for the construction, operation, maintenance, or termination of the project or a portion thereof, or for access thereto.


(b) Terms and conditions of right-of-way or permitEach right-of-way or permit granted, issued, or renewed pursuant to this section shall be limited to a reasonable term in light of all circumstances concerning the project. In determining the duration of a right-of-way the Secretary concerned shall, among other things, take into consideration the cost of the facility, its useful life, and any public purpose it serves. The right-of-way shall specify whether it is or is not renewable and the terms and conditions applicable to the renewal.


(c) Applicability of regulations or stipulationsRights-of-way shall be granted, issued, or renewed pursuant to this subchapter under such regulations or stipulations, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter or any other applicable law, and shall also be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned may prescribe regarding extent, duration, survey, location, construction, maintenance, transfer or assignment, and termination.


(d) Submission of plan of construction, operation, and rehabilitation by new project applicants; plan requirementsThe Secretary concerned prior to granting </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary specifications; criteria; temporary use of additional lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Boundary specifications; criteria; temporary use of additional lands The Secretary concerned shall specify the boundaries of each right-of-way as precisely as is practical. Each right-of-way shall be limited to the ground which the Secretary concerned determines (1) will be occupied by facilities which constitute the project for which the right-of-way is granted, issued, or renewed, (2) to be necessary for the operation or maintenance of the project, (3) to be necessary to protect the public safety, and (4) will do no unnecessary damage to the environment. The Secretary concerned may authorize the temporary use of such additional lands as he determines to be reasonably necessary for the construction, operation, maintenance, or termination of the project or a portion thereof, or for access thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of right-of-way or permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions of right-of-way or permit Each right-of-way or permit granted, issued, or renewed pursuant to this section shall be limited to a reasonable term in light of all circumstances concerning the project. In determining the duration of a right-of-way the Secretary concerned shall, among other things, take into consideration the cost of the facility, its useful life, and any public purpose it serves. The right-of-way shall specify whether it is or is not renewable and the terms and conditions applicable to the renewal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of regulations or stipulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability of regulations or stipulations Rights-of-way shall be granted, issued, or renewed pursuant to this subchapter under such regulations or stipulations, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter or any other applicable law, and shall also be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned may prescribe regarding extent, duration, survey, location, construction, maintenance, transfer or assignment, and termination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of plan of construction, operation, and rehabilitation by new project applicants; plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission of plan of construction, operation, and rehabilitation by new project applicants; plan requirements The Secretary concerned prior to granting or issuing a right-of-way pursuant to this subchapter for a new project which may have a significant impact on the environment, shall require the applicant to submit a plan of construction, operation, and rehabilitation for such right-of-way which shall comply with stipulations or with regulations issued by that Secretary, including the terms and conditions required under section 1765 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory requirements for terms and conditions; revision and applicability of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulatory requirements for terms and conditions; revision and applicability of regulations The Secretary concerned shall issue regulations with respect to the terms and conditions that will be included in rights-of-way pursuant to section 1765 of this title. Such regulations shall be regularly revised as needed. Such regulations shall be applicable to every right-of-way granted or issued pursuant to this subchapter and to any subsequent renewal thereof, and may be applicable to rights-of-way not granted or issued, but renewed pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal or use of mineral and vegetative materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Removal or use of mineral and vegetative materials Mineral and vegetative materials, including timber, within or without a right-of-way, may be used or disposed of in connection with construction or other purposes only if authorization to remove or use such materials has been obtained pursuant to applicable laws or for emergency repair work necessary for those rights-of-way authorized under section 1761(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental payments; amount, waiver, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rental payments; amount, waiver, etc. The holder of a right-of-way shall pay in advance the fair market value thereof, as determined by the Secretary granting, issuing, or renewing such right-of-way. The Secretary concerned may require either annual payment or a payment covering more than one year at a time except that private individuals may make at their option either annual payments or payments covering more than one year if the annual fee is greater than one hundred dollars. The Secretary concerned may waive rentals where a right-of-way is granted, issued or renewed in consideration of a right-of-way conveyed to the United States in connection with a cooperative cost share program between the United States and the holder. The Secretary concerned may, by regulation or prior to promulgation of such regulations, as a condition of a right-of-way, require an applicant for or holder of a right-of-way to reimburse the United States for all reasonable administrative and other costs inc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damage or injury incurred by United States for use and occupancy of rights-of-way; indemnification of United States; no-fault liability; amount of damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Liability for damage or injury incurred by United States for use and occupancy of rights-of-way; indemnification of United States; no-fault liability; amount of damages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond or security requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Bond or security requirements Where he deems it appropriate, the Secretary concerned may require a holder of a right-of-way to furnish a bond, or other security, satisfactory to him to secure all or any of the obligations imposed by the terms and conditions of the right-of-way or by any rule or regulation of the Secretary concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for grant, issue, or renewal of right-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Criteria for grant, issue, or renewal of right-of-way The Secretary concerned shall grant, issue, or renew a right-of-way under this subchapter only when he is satisfied that the applicant has the technical and financial capability to construct the project for which the right-of-way is requested, and in accord with the requirements of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>