<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1784" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1784/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1784/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1784"><akn:num>1784</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands in Alaska; designation as wilderness; management by Bureau of Land Management pending Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1784. Lands in Alaska; designation as wilderness; management by Bureau of Land Management pending Congressional action
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, section 1782 of this title shall not apply to any lands in Alaska. However, in carrying out his duties under sections 1711 and 1712 of this title and other applicable laws, the Secretary may identify areas in Alaska which he determines are suitable as wilderness and may, from time to time, make recommendations to the Congress for inclusion of any such areas in the National Wilderness Preservation System, pursuant to the provisions of the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.]. In the absence of congressional action relating to any such recommendation of the Secretary, the Bureau of Land Management shall manage all such areas which are within its jurisdiction in accordance with the applicable land use plans and applicable provisions of law.
(Pub. L. 96–487, title XIII, § 1320, Dec. 2, 1980, 94 Stat. 2487.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Wilderness Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 88–577, Sept. 3, 1964, 78 Stat. 890, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of Title 16, Conservation. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1131 of Title 16 and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act, and not as part of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Kenai Natives Association Land ExchangePub. L. 104–333, div. I, title III, § 311, Nov. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 4139, as amended by Pub. L. 106–176, title I, § 105, Mar. 10, 2000, 114 Stat. 25, provided that:
“(a) Short Title.—This section may be cited as the ‘Kenai Natives Association Equity Act Amendments of 1996’.

“(b) Findings and Purpose.—“(1) Findings.—The Congress finds the following:“(A) The United States Fish and Wildlife Service </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>