<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1785" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1785/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1785/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1785"><akn:num>1785</akn:num><akn:heading>Fossil Forest Research Natural Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1785. Fossil Forest Research Natural Area(a) EstablishmentTo conserve and protect natural values and to provide scientific knowledge, education, and interpretation for the benefit of future generations, there is established the Fossil Forest Research Natural Area (referred to in this section as the “Area”), consisting of the approximately 2,770 acres in the Farmington District of the Bureau of Land Management, New Mexico, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Fossil Forest”, dated June 1983.


(b) Map and legal description(1) In generalAs soon as practicable after November 12, 1996, the Secretary of the Interior shall file a map and legal description of the Area with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives.


(2) Force and effectThe map and legal description described in paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act.


(3) Technical correctionsThe Secretary of the Interior may correct clerical, typographical, and cartographical errors in the map and legal description subsequent to filing the map pursuant to paragraph (1).


(4) Public inspectionThe map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior.



(c) Management(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall manage the Area—(A) to protect the resources within the Area; and

(B) in accordance with this Act, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), and other applicable provisions of law.


(2) Mining(A) WithdrawalSubject to valid existing rights, the lands within the Area are withdrawn from all forms of appropriation under the mining laws and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, and mineral material sales.


(B) Coal preference rights</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1785_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment To conserve and protect natural values and to provide scientific knowledge, education, and interpretation for the benefit of future generations, there is established the Fossil Forest Research Natural Area (referred to in this section as the “Area”), consisting of the approximately 2,770 acres in the Farmington District of the Bureau of Land Management, New Mexico, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Fossil Forest”, dated June 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1785_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Map and legal description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Map and legal description</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1785_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1785_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inventory Not later than 3 full fiscal years after November 12, 1996, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall develop a baseline inventory of all categories of fossil resources within the Area. After the inventory is developed, the Secretary shall conduct monitoring surveys at intervals specified in the management plan developed for the Area in accordance with subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1785_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>