<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1841"><akn:num>1841</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1841. Definitions
As used in this subchapter, the term—(1) “area affected by Outer Continental Shelf activities” means any geographic area:(A) which is under oil or gas lease on the Outer Continental Shelf;

(B) where Outer Continental Shelf exploration, development or production activities have been permitted, except geophysical activities;

(C) where pipeline rights-of-way have been granted; or

(D) otherwise impacted by such activities including but not limited to expired lease areas, relinquished rights-of-way and easements, Outer Continental Shelf supply vessel routes, or other areas as determined by the Secretary;


(2) “citizen of the United States” means any person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, any State, any agency of a State, or a group of States, or any corporation, partnership, or association organized under the laws of any State which has as its president or other chief executive officer and as its chairman of the board of directors, or holder of a similar office, a person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, and which has at least 75 per centum of the interest of 11 So in original. The “of” is probably unnecessary. therein owned by citizens of the United States. Seventy-five per centum of the interest in the corporation shall not be deemed to be owned by citizens of the United States—(A) if the title to 75 per centum of its stock is not vested in such citizens free from any trust or fiduciary obligation in favor of any person not a citizen of the United States;

(B) if 75 per centum of the voting power in such corporation is not vested in citizens of the United States;

(C) if through any contract or understanding it is so arranged that more than 25 per centum of the voting power may be exercised, directly or indirectly, in behalf of any person who is not a citizen of the United States; or

(D) if by any other means whatsoever control of any interest in the corporation in excess of 25 per</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “area affected by Outer Continental Shelf activities” means any geographic area:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “citizen of the United States” means any person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, any State, any agency of a State, or a group of States, or any corporation, partnership, or association organized under the laws of any State which has as its president or other chief executive officer and as its chairman of the board of directors, or holder of a similar office, a person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, and which has at least 75 per centum of the interest of 11 So in original. The “of” is probably unnecessary. therein owned by citizens of the United States. Seventy-five per centum of the interest in the corporation shall not be deemed to be owned by citizens of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “commercial fisherman” means any citizen of the United States who owns, operates, or derives income from being employed on a commercial fishing vessel;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) “commercial fishing vessel” means any vessel, boat, ship, or other craft which is (A) documented under the laws of the United States or, if under five net tons, registered under the laws of any State, and (B) used for, equipped to be used for, or of a type which is normally used for commercial purposes for the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish or the aiding or assisting of any activity related to the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish, including, but not limited to, preparation, supply, storage, refrigeration, transportation, or processing;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “fish” means finfish, mollusks, crustaceans, and all other forms of marine animal and plant life other than marine mammals, birds, and highly migratory species;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “fishing gear” means (A) any commercial fishing vessel, and (B) any equipment of such vessel, whether or not attached to such a vessel;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “Fund” means the Fishermen’s Contingency Fund established under section 1842 of this title; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce or the designee of such Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>