<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1864" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1864/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1864/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1864"><akn:num>1864</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of financial interests by officers and employees of Department of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1864. Disclosure of financial interests by officers and employees of Department of the Interior(a) Annual written statementEach officer or employee of the Department of the Interior who—(1) performs any function or duty under this chapter or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.], as amended by this Act; and

(2) has any known financial interest in any person who (A) applies for or receives any permit or lease under, or (B) is otherwise subject to the provisions of this chapter or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act [43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.],


shall, beginning on February 1, 1979, annually file with the Secretary of the Interior a written statement concerning all such interests held by such officer or employee during the preceeding 11 So in original. Probably should be “preceding”. calendar year. Such statement shall be available to the public.

(b) “Known financial interest” defined; enforcement; report to CongressThe Secretary of the Interior shall—(1) within ninety days after September 18, 1978—(A) define the term “known financial interest” for purposes of subsection (a) of this section; and

(B) establish the methods by which the requirement to file written statements specified in subsection (a) of this section will be monitored and enforced, including appropriate provisions for the filing by such officers and employees of such statements and the review by the Secretary of such statements; and


(2) report to the Congress on June 1 of each calendar year with respect to such disclosures and the actions taken in regard thereto during the preceding calendar year.


(c) Officers and employees in nonregulatory or nonpolicymaking positionsIn the rules prescribed in subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary may identify specific positions within the Department of the Interior which are of a nonregulatory or nonpolicymaking nature and provide that officers or employees occupying such positions shall be exempt from the requirements of this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual written statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual written statement Each officer or employee of the Department of the Interior who— shall, beginning on February 1, 1979, annually file with the Secretary of the Interior a written statement concerning all such interests held by such officer or employee during the preceeding 11 So in original. Probably should be “preceding”. calendar year. Such statement shall be available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Known financial interest” defined; enforcement; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Known financial interest” defined; enforcement; report to Congress The Secretary of the Interior shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees in nonregulatory or nonpolicymaking positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Officers and employees in nonregulatory or nonpolicymaking positions In the rules prescribed in subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary may identify specific positions within the Department of the Interior which are of a nonregulatory or nonpolicymaking nature and provide that officers or employees occupying such positions shall be exempt from the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalties Any officer or employee who is subject to, and knowingly violates, this section shall be fined not more than $2,500 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>