<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/1902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1902"><akn:num>1902</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1902. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(a) The terms “rangelands” or “public rangelands” means lands administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Land Management or the Secretary of Agriculture through the Forest Service in the sixteen contiguous Western States on which there is domestic livestock grazing or which the Secretary concerned determines may be suitable for domestic livestock grazing.

(b) The term “allotment management plan” is the same as defined in section 1702(k) of this title, except that as used in this chapter such term applies to the sixteen contiguous Western States.

(c) The term “grazing permit and lease” means any document authorizing use of public lands or lands in national forests in the sixteen contiguous Western States for the purpose of grazing domestic livestock.

(d) The term “range condition” means the quality of the land reflected in its ability in specific vegetative areas to support various levels of productivity in accordance with range management objectives and the land use planning process, and relates to soil quality, forage values (whether seasonal or year round), wildlife habitat, watershed and plant communities, the present state of vegetation of a range site in relation to the potential plant community for that site, and the relative degree to which the kinds, proportions, and amounts of vegetation in a plant community resemble that of the desired community for that site.

(e) The term “native vegetation” means those plant species, communities, or vegetative associations which are endemic to a given area and which would normally be identified with a healthy and productive range condition occurring as a result of the natural vegetative process of the area.

(f) The term “range improvement” means any activity or program on or relating to rangelands which is designed to improve production of forage; change vegetative composition; control patterns of use; provide water; stabilize soil and water condit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The terms “rangelands” or “public rangelands” means lands administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Land Management or the Secretary of Agriculture through the Forest Service in the sixteen contiguous Western States on which there is domestic livestock grazing or which the Secretary concerned determines may be suitable for domestic livestock grazing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “allotment management plan” is the same as defined in section 1702(k) of this title, except that as used in this chapter such term applies to the sixteen contiguous Western States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “grazing permit and lease” means any document authorizing use of public lands or lands in national forests in the sixteen contiguous Western States for the purpose of grazing domestic livestock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “range condition” means the quality of the land reflected in its ability in specific vegetative areas to support various levels of productivity in accordance with range management objectives and the land use planning process, and relates to soil quality, forage values (whether seasonal or year round), wildlife habitat, watershed and plant communities, the present state of vegetation of a range site in relation to the potential plant community for that site, and the relative degree to which the kinds, proportions, and amounts of vegetation in a plant community resemble that of the desired community for that site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “native vegetation” means those plant species, communities, or vegetative associations which are endemic to a given area and which would normally be identified with a healthy and productive range condition occurring as a result of the natural vegetative process of the area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “range improvement” means any activity or program on or relating to rangelands which is designed to improve production of forage; change vegetative composition; control patterns of use; provide water; stabilize soil and water conditions; and provide habitat for livestock and wildlife. The term includes, but is not limited to, structures, treatment projects, and use of mechanical means to accomplish the desired results.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The term “court ordered environmental impact statement” means any environmental statements which are required to be prepared by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to the final judgment or subsequent modification thereof as set forth on June 18, 1975, in the matter of Natural Resources Defense Council against Andrus.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The term “Secretary” unless specifically designated otherwise, means the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The term “sixteen contiguous Western States” means the States of Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Oregon, South Dakota, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>