<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2"><akn:num>2</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties concerning public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2. Duties concerning public lands
The Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate shall perform all executive duties appertaining to the surveying and sale of the public lands of the United States, or in anywise respecting such public lands, and, also, such as relate to private claims of land, and the issuing of patents for all grants of land under the authority of the Government.
(R.S. § 453; Feb. 18, 1875, ch. 80, § 1, 18 Stat. 317; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. July 16, 1946, 11 F.R. 7876, 60 Stat. 1100.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. § 453 derived from acts Apr. 25, 1812, ch. 68, § 1, 2 Stat. 716; July 4, 1836, ch. 352, § 1, 5 Stat. 107; June 6, 1874, ch. 223, 18 Stat. 62; Feb. 18, 1875, ch. 80, § 1, 18 Stat. 317.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Bureau of Land Management Drug Enforcement Supplemental AuthorityPub. L. 99–570, title V, subtitle C, as added by Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 6254(d)(3), Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4365, provided that:
“SEC. 5061. SHORT TITLE.“This subtitle may be cited as the ‘Bureau of Land Management Drug Enforcement Supplemental Authority Act’.


“SEC. 5062. BUREAU OF LAND MANAGEMENT AUTHORIZATION.“In order to improve Federal law enforcement activities relating to the use and production of narcotics and controlled substances on Bureau of Land Management public lands, from amounts appropriated there are made available to the Secretary of the Interior, in addition to sums made available under other authority of law, $1,500,000 for fiscal year 1989, and for each fiscal year thereafter, to be used for the employment and training of additional and existing personnel, for equipment and facilities to be used by such personnel, and for expenses related to such employment, training, equipment, and facilities.”





Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the In</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>