<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2007"><akn:num>2007</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2007. Decision of President(a) Decision concerning approval or disapproval of proposed systems(1) After reviewing all the information submitted to him concerning the various proposed crude oil transportation systems eligible for consideration under this chapter (including environmental impact statements, comments, reports, recommendations, and other information submitted to him at any time before he makes his decision) and after consulting the Secretaries of Energy, the Interior, and Transportation, the President shall decide which, if any, of such systems shall be approved for the purposes of section 2008 of this title (relating to procedures for waiver of law), section 2009 of this title (relating to expedited procedures for issuance of permits), section 2010 of this title (relating to negotiations with the Government of Canada), and section 2011 of this title (relating to judicial review). A decision approving a crude oil transportation system may include such modifications and alterations in such system as the President finds appropriate. The President shall issue his decision within 45 days after receiving recommendations and comments submitted to him under section 2005(c) of this title, except that the President, for such period as he deems necessary, but not to exceed 60 days, may delay his decision and its issuance if he determines that additional time is otherwise necessary to enable him to make a decision. If the President so delays his decision, he shall promptly notify the House of Representatives and the Senate of such delay and shall submit a full explanation of the basis for such delay.

(2) Any decision made under this subsection approving a system proposed under this chapter shall include a determination that construction and operation of such system is in the national interest and shall be based upon the criteria specified in subsection (b).


(b) Criteria(1) The criteria for making a decision under this subsection shall include findings of—(A) e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision concerning approval or disapproval of proposed systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Decision concerning approval or disapproval of proposed systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of findings and decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication of findings and decision The President shall make available to the public at the time of issuance of a decision under this section a written statement setting forth findings with respect to each of the criteria specified in subsection (b) and describing the nature and route of crude oil transportation systems, if any, which are approved in the decision. If the President’s decision is to approve a system, each statement shall set forth his reasons for approving such system over other proposed systems (if any) eligible for consideration under this chapter. Such statement along with notification of such decision shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>