<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2009" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2009/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2009/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009"><akn:num>2009</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedures for issuance of permits: enforcement of rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009. Expedited procedures for issuance of permits: enforcement of rights-of-way(a) Expedited procedures for approved systemsAfter issuance of a decision by the President approving any crude oil transportation system, all Federal officers and agencies shall expedite, to the maximum extent practicable, consistent with applicable provisions of law, all actions necessary to determine whether to issue, administer, or enforce rights-of-way across Federal lands and to issue Federal permits in connection with, or otherwise to authorize, construction and operation of such system. Any such action shall be consistent with applicable provisions of law. After taking any such action, such officer or agency shall publish notification of the taking of such action in the Federal Register.


(b) Expedited procedures for Long Beach-Midland projectAll decisions regarding issuance of Federal permits, rights-of-way, and leases and other Federal authorizations necessary for construction and operation of the Long Beach-Midland project shall be consistent with applicable provisions of Federal law, except that such decisions shall be made within 30 days after the date this chapter becomes effective. The President may extend the date by which such decisions, under the preceding sentence, are to be made to a date not later than 90 days after the effective date of this chapter. Notification of the making of such decisions shall be published in the Federal Register. Nothing in this section affects any decision made before November 9, 1978.


(c) Law governing rights-of-wayRights-of-way over any Federal land with respect to an approved crude oil transportation system or the Long Beach-Midland project shall be governed by the provisions of section 185 of title 30, other than subsection (w)(2) of such section.


(Pub. L. 95–617, title V, § 509, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3162.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date this chapter becomes effective and the effective date of this chapter, referre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedures for approved systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expedited procedures for approved systems After issuance of a decision by the President approving any crude oil transportation system, all Federal officers and agencies shall expedite, to the maximum extent practicable, consistent with applicable provisions of law, all actions necessary to determine whether to issue, administer, or enforce rights-of-way across Federal lands and to issue Federal permits in connection with, or otherwise to authorize, construction and operation of such system. Any such action shall be consistent with applicable provisions of law. After taking any such action, such officer or agency shall publish notification of the taking of such action in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedures for Long Beach-Midland project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expedited procedures for Long Beach-Midland project All decisions regarding issuance of Federal permits, rights-of-way, and leases and other Federal authorizations necessary for construction and operation of the Long Beach-Midland project shall be consistent with applicable provisions of Federal law, except that such decisions shall be made within 30 days after the date this chapter becomes effective. The President may extend the date by which such decisions, under the preceding sentence, are to be made to a date not later than 90 days after the effective date of this chapter. Notification of the making of such decisions shall be published in the Federal Register. Nothing in this section affects any decision made before November 9, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law governing rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Law governing rights-of-way Rights-of-way over any Federal land with respect to an approved crude oil transportation system or the Long Beach-Midland project shall be governed by the provisions of section 185 of title 30, other than subsection (w)(2) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>