<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2212"><akn:num>2212</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of water on temporary basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2212. Availability of water on temporary basis(a) General authorityIn order to mitigate losses and damages resulting from drought conditions, the Secretary may make available, by temporary contract, project and nonproject water, and may permit the use of facilities at Federal Reclamation projects for the storage or conveyance of project or nonproject water, for use both within and outside an authorized project service area.


(b) Special provisions applicable to temporary water supplies provided under this section(1) Temporary suppliesEach temporary contract for the supply of water entered into pursuant to this section shall terminate no later than two years from the date of execution or upon a determination by the Secretary that water supply conditions no longer warrant that such contracts remain in effect, whichever occurs first. The costs associated with any such contract shall be repaid within the term of the contract.


(2) Ownership and acreage limitationsLands not subject to Reclamation law that receive temporary irrigation water supplies under temporary contracts under this section shall not become subject to the ownership and acreage limitations or pricing provisions of Federal Reclamation law because of the delivery of such temporary water supplies. Lands that are subject to the ownership and acreage limitations of Federal Reclamation law shall not be exempted from those limitations because of the delivery of such temporary water supplies.


(3) Treatment under Reclamation Reform Act of 1982No temporary contract entered into by the Secretary under this section shall be treated as a “contract” as that term is used in sections 203(a) and 220 of the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (Public Law 97–293) [43 U.S.C. 390cc(a), 390tt].


(4) Amendments of existing contractsAny amendment to an existing contract to allow a contractor to carry out the provisions of this subchapter shall not be considered a new and supplemental benefit for purposes of the Reclamation R</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority In order to mitigate losses and damages resulting from drought conditions, the Secretary may make available, by temporary contract, project and nonproject water, and may permit the use of facilities at Federal Reclamation projects for the storage or conveyance of project or nonproject water, for use both within and outside an authorized project service area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provisions applicable to temporary water supplies provided under this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special provisions applicable to temporary water supplies provided under this section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contract price The price for project water, other than water purchased pursuant to section 2211(c) of this title, delivered under a temporary contract entered into by the Secretary under this section shall be at least sufficient to recover all Federal operation and maintenance costs and administrative costs, and an appropriate share of capital costs, including interest on such capital costs allocated to municipal and industrial water, except that, for project water delivered to nonproject landholdings, the price shall include full cost (as defined in section 202(3) of the Reclamation Reform Act of 1982 (Public Law 97–293; 96 Stat. 1263; 43 U.S.C. 390bb) [43 U.S.C. 390bb(3)]). For all contracts entered into by the Secretary under the authority of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fish and wildlife The Secretary may make water from Federal Reclamation projects and nonproject water available on a nonreimbursable basis for the purposes of protecting or restoring fish and wildlife resources, including mitigation losses, that occur as a result of drought conditions or the operation of a Federal Reclamation project during drought conditions. The Secretary may store and convey project and nonproject water for fish and wildlife purposes, and may provide conveyance of any such water for both State and Federal wildlife habitat and for habitat held in private ownership. The Secretary may make available water for these purposes outside the authorized project service area. Use of the Federal storage and conveyance facilities for these purposes shall be on a nonreimbursable basis. Water made available by the Secretary in 1991 from the Central Valley Project, California, to the Grasslands Water District for the purpose of fish and wildlife shall be nonreimbursable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonproject water</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonproject water The Secretary is authorized to store and convey nonproject water utilizing Federal Reclamation project facilities for use outside and inside the authorized project service area for municipal and industrial uses, fish and wildlife, and agricultural uses. Except in the case of water supplied for fish and wildlife, which shall be nonreimbursable, the Secretary shall charge the recipients of such water for such use of Federal Reclamation project facilities at a rate established pursuant to subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclamation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reclamation Fund The payment of capital costs attributable to the sale of project or nonproject water or the use of Federal Reclamation project facilities shall be covered into the Reclamation Fund and be placed to the credit of the project from which such water or use of such facilities is supplied.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>