<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2306"><akn:num>2306</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2306. Special provisions(a) In generalNothing in this chapter provides an exemption from any limitation on the acquisition of land or interest in land under any Federal law in effect on July 25, 2000.


(b) Other lawThis chapter shall not apply to land eligible for sale under—(1) Public Law 96–586 (commonly known as the “Santini-Burton Act”) (94 Stat. 3381);

(2) the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998 (Public Law 105–263; 112 Stat. 2343);

(3) the White Pine County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2006 (Public Law 109–432; 120 Stat. 3028);

(4) the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 (Public Law 108–424; 118 Stat. 2403);

(5) subtitle F of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (16 U.S.C. 1132 note; Public Law 111–11);

(6) subtitle O of title I of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (16 U.S.C. 460www note, 1132 note; Public Law 111–11);

(7) section 2601 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (Public Law 111–11; 123 Stat. 1108); or

(8) section 2606 of the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 (Public Law 111–11; 123 Stat. 1121).


(c) ExchangesNothing in this chapter precludes, preempts, or limits the authority to exchange land under authorities providing for the exchange of Federal lands, including but not limited to—(1) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); or

(2) the Federal Land Exchange Facilitation Act of 1988 (102 Stat. 1086) or the amendments made by that Act.


(d) No new right or benefitNothing in this chapter 11 See References in Text note below. creates a right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or any other person.


(Pub. L. 106–248, title II, § 207, July 25, 2000, 114 Stat. 617; Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title III, § 302(8), Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1076.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextPublic L</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Nothing in this chapter provides an exemption from any limitation on the acquisition of land or interest in land under any Federal law in effect on July 25, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other law This chapter shall not apply to land eligible for sale under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exchanges Nothing in this chapter precludes, preempts, or limits the authority to exchange land under authorities providing for the exchange of Federal lands, including but not limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No new right or benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No new right or benefit Nothing in this chapter 11 See References in Text note below. creates a right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by a party against the United States, its agencies, its officers, or any other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>