<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2606"><akn:num>2606</akn:num><akn:heading>Oregon and California Railroad revested lands and Coos Bay Wagon Road reconveyed lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2606. Oregon and California Railroad revested lands and Coos Bay Wagon Road reconveyed lands(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to the Oregon and California Railroad grant land revested in the United States by the Act of June 9, 1916 (39 Stat. 218, chapter 137), and the Coos Bay Wagon Road grant land reconveyed to the United States by the first section of the Act of February 26, 1919 (40 Stat. 1179, chapter 47), that is managed under the Act of August 28, 1937 (43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.), the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall not be required to engage in consultation under any law (including section 7 of Public Law 93–205 (16 U.S.C. 1536) and section 402.16 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), with respect to—(1) the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of critical habitat, pursuant to Public Law 93–205 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.), if a land use plan has been adopted by the Secretary of the Interior as of the date of listing or designation; and

(2) any provision of a land use plan adopted as described in paragraph (1).


(b) Effect of sectionNothing in this section affects any applicable requirement of the Secretary of the Interior to consult with the head of any other Federal department or agency—(1) regarding a project carried out, or proposed to be carried out, pursuant to Public Law 93–205 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.), including any requirement to consult regarding the consideration of the cumulative impacts of completed, ongoing, and planned projects; or

(2) with respect to the development of a new land use plan or the revision of or other significant change to an existing land use plan.


(Pub. L. 115–141, div. O, title II, § 209, Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1067.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextActs of June 9, 1916, and February 26, 1919, referred to in subsec. (a), are acts June 9, 1916, ch. 137, 39 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, with respect to the Oregon and California Railroad grant land revested in the United States by the Act of June 9, 1916 (39 Stat. 218, chapter 137), and the Coos Bay Wagon Road grant land reconveyed to the United States by the first section of the Act of February 26, 1919 (40 Stat. 1179, chapter 47), that is managed under the Act of August 28, 1937 (43 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.), the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall not be required to engage in consultation under any law (including section 7 of Public Law 93–205 (16 U.S.C. 1536) and section 402.16 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect of section Nothing in this section affects any applicable requirement of the Secretary of the Interior to consult with the head of any other Federal department or agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>