<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/2902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2902"><akn:num>2902</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2902. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Conveyed propertyThe term “conveyed property” means an eligible facility that has been conveyed to a qualifying entity under section 2903 of this title.


(2) Eligible facilityThe term “eligible facility” means a facility that meets the criteria for potential transfer established under section 2904(a) of this title.


(3) Facility(A) In generalThe term “facility” includes a dam or appurtenant works, canal, lateral, ditch, gate, control structure, pumping station, other infrastructure, recreational facility, building, distribution and drainage works, and associated land or interest in land or water.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “facility” does not include a Reclamation project facility, or a portion of a Reclamation project facility—(i) that is a reserved works as of March 12, 2019;

(ii) that generates hydropower marketed by a Federal power marketing administration; or

(iii) that is managed for recreation under a lease, permit, license, or other management agreement that does contribute to capital repayment.



(4) Project use powerThe term “project use power” means the electrical capacity, energy, and associated ancillary service components required to provide the minimum electrical service needed to operate or maintain Reclamation project facilities in accordance with the authorization for the Reclamation project.


(5) Qualifying entityThe term “qualifying entity” means an agency of a State or political subdivision of a State, a joint action or powers agency, a water users association, or an Indian Tribe or Tribal utility authority that—(A) as of the date of conveyance under this chapter, is the current operator of the eligible facility pursuant to a contract with Reclamation; and

(B) as determined by the Secretary, has the capacity to continue to manage the eligible facility for the same purposes for which the property has been managed under the reclamation laws.


(6) ReclamationThe term “Reclamation” means the Bureau of Re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyed property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Conveyed property The term “conveyed property” means an eligible facility that has been conveyed to a qualifying entity under section 2903 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible facility The term “eligible facility” means a facility that meets the criteria for potential transfer established under section 2904(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project use power</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Project use power The term “project use power” means the electrical capacity, energy, and associated ancillary service components required to provide the minimum electrical service needed to operate or maintain Reclamation project facilities in accordance with the authorization for the Reclamation project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Qualifying entity The term “qualifying entity” means an agency of a State or political subdivision of a State, a joint action or powers agency, a water users association, or an Indian Tribe or Tribal utility authority that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclamation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Reclamation The term “Reclamation” means the Bureau of Reclamation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclamation project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Reclamation project The term “Reclamation project” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserved works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Reserved works The term “reserved works” means any building, structure, facility, or equipment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>