<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/299" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/299/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/299/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_299"><akn:num>299</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of coal and mineral rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 299. Reservation of coal and mineral rights(a) General provisionsAll entries made and patents issued under the provisions of this subchapter shall be subject to and contain a reservation to the United States of all the coal and other minerals in the lands so entered and patented, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. The coal and other mineral deposits in such lands shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal and mineral land laws in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to locate and enter the coal or other mineral deposits, or having the right to mine and remove the same under the laws of the United States, shall have the right at all times to enter upon the lands entered or patented, as provided by this subchapter, for the purpose of prospecting for coal or other mineral therein, provided he shall not injure, damage, or destroy the permanent improvements of the entryman or patentee, and shall be liable to and shall compensate the entryman or patentee for all damages to the crops on such lands by reason of such prospecting. Any person who has acquired from the United States the coal or other mineral deposits in any such land, or the right to mine and remove the same, may reenter and occupy so much of the surface thereof as may be required for all purposes reasonably incident to the mining or removal of the coal or other minerals, first, upon securing the written consent or waiver of the homestead entryman or patentee; second, upon payment of the damages to crops or other tangible improvements to the owner thereof, where agreement may be had as to the amount thereof; or, third, in lieu of either of the foregoing provisions, upon the execution of a good and sufficient bond or undertaking to the United States for the use and benefit of the entryman or owner of the land, to secure the payment of such damages to the crops or tangible improvements of the entryman or ow</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General provisions All entries made and patents issued under the provisions of this subchapter shall be subject to and contain a reservation to the United States of all the coal and other minerals in the lands so entered and patented, together with the right to prospect for, mine, and remove the same. The coal and other mineral deposits in such lands shall be subject to disposal by the United States in accordance with the provisions of the coal and mineral land laws in force at the time of such disposal. Any person qualified to locate and enter the coal or other mineral deposits, or having the right to mine and remove the same under the laws of the United States, shall have the right at all times to enter upon the lands entered or patented, as provided by this subchapter, for the purpose of prospecting for coal or other mineral therein, provided he shall not injure, damage, or destroy the permanent improvements of the entryman or patentee, and shall be liable to and shall compensat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exploration; location of mining claims; notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exploration; location of mining claims; notices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consent Notwithstanding subsection (a) and any other provision of law, after the effective date of this subsection no person may engage in the conduct of mineral activities (other than those relating to exploration referred to in subsection (b)(1)B)) 11 So in original. Probably should be subsection “(b)(1)(B))”. on a mining claim located on lands subject to this subchapter without the written consent of the surface owner thereof unless the Secretary has authorized the conduct of such activities under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized mineral activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorized mineral activities The Secretary shall authorize a person to conduct mineral activities (other than those relating to exploration referred to in subsection (b)(1)(B)) on lands subject to this subchapter without the consent of the surface owner thereof if such person complies with the requirements of subsections (e) and (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Bond</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan of operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plan of operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fee The fee referred to in subsection (f)(1) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclamation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reclamation Lands affected by mineral activities under a plan of operations approved pursuant to subsection (f)(3) shall be reclaimed, to the maximum extent practicable, to a condition capable of supporting the uses to which such lands were capable of supporting prior to surface disturbance. Reclamation shall proceed as contemporaneously as practicable with the conduct of mineral activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Inspections Should any surface owner of land subject to this subchapter have reason to believe that they are or may be adversely affected by mineral activities due to any violation of the terms and conditions of a plan of operations approved under subsection (f), such surface owner may request an inspection of such lands. The Secretary shall determine within 10 days of the receipt of the request whether the request states a reason to believe that a violation exists, except in the event the surface owner alleges and provides reason to believe that an imminent danger exists, the 10-day period shall be waived and the inspection conducted immediately. When an inspection is conducted under this paragraph, the Secretary shall notify the surface owner and such surface owner shall be allowed to accompany the inspector on the inspection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>