<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3007"><akn:num>3007</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable energy fees on Federal land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3007. Renewable energy fees on Federal land(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Annual Adjustment FactorThe term “Annual Adjustment Factor” means 3 percent.


(2) Encumbrance FactorThe term “Encumbrance Factor” means—(A) 100 percent for a solar energy generation facility; and

(B) an amount determined by the Secretary, but not less than 10 percent for a wind energy generation facility.


(3) National Forest System(A) In generalThe term “National Forest System” means land of the National Forest System (as defined in section 1609(a) of title 16) administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.


(B) ExclusionThe term “National Forest System” does not include any forest reserve not created from the public domain.



(4) Per-Acre RateThe term “Per-Acre Rate”, with respect to a right-of-way, means the average of the per-acre pastureland rental rates published in the Cash Rents Survey by the National Agricultural Statistics Service for the State in which the right-of-way is located over the 5 calendar-year period preceding the issuance or renewal of the right-of-way.


(5) ProjectThe term “project” means a system described in section 2801.9(a)(4) of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on July 4, 2025).


(6) Public landThe term “public land” means—(A) public lands (as defined in section 1702 of this title); and

(B) National Forest System land.


(7) Renewable energy projectThe term “renewable energy project” means a project located on public land that uses wind or solar energy to generate energy.


(8) Right-of-wayThe term “right-of-way” has the meaning given the term in section 1702 of this title.


(9) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means—(A) the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land controlled or administered by the Secretary of the Interior; and

(B) the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land.



(b) Acreage rent for wind and solar rights-of-way(1) In generalPursuant to section 1764(g) of this title, the Secretary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acreage rent for wind and solar rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acreage rent for wind and solar rights-of-way</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capacity fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Capacity fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Late payment fee; termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Late payment fee; termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>