<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/31l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/31l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/31l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31l"><akn:num>31l</akn:num><akn:heading>Earth Mapping Resources Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31l. Earth Mapping Resources Initiative(a) Definition of critical mineralIn this section, the term “critical mineral” has the meaning given the term in section 1606(a) of title 30.


(b) EstablishmentThere is established within the United States Geological Survey an initiative, to be known as the “Earth Mapping Resources Initiative” (referred to in this section as the “Initiative”).


(c) PurposeThe purpose of the Initiative shall be to accelerate efforts to carry out the fundamental resources and mapping mission of the United States Geological Survey by—(1) providing integrated topographic, geologic, geochemical, and geophysical mapping;

(2) accelerating the integration and consolidation of geospatial and resource data; and

(3) providing interpretation of subsurface and above-ground mineral resources data.


(d) Cooperative agreements(1) In generalIn carrying out the Initiative, the Director of the United States Geological Survey may enter into cooperative agreements with State geological surveys.


(2) EffectNothing in paragraph (1) precludes the Director of the United States Geological Survey from using existing contracting authorities in carrying out the Initiative.



(e) Comprehensive mapping modernization(1) In generalNot later than 10 years after November 15, 2021, the Initiative shall complete an initial comprehensive national modern surface and subsurface mapping and data integration effort.


(2) ApproachIn carrying out paragraph (1) with regard to minerals, mineralization, and mineral deposits, the Initiative shall focus on the full range of minerals, using a whole ore body approach rather than a single commodity approach, to emphasize all of the recoverable critical minerals in a given surface or subsurface deposit.


(3) PriorityIn carrying out paragraph (1) with regard to minerals, mineralization, and mineral deposits, the Initiative shall prioritize mapping and assessing critical minerals.


(4) InclusionsIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Initia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of critical mineral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of critical mineral In this section, the term “critical mineral” has the meaning given the term in section 1606(a) of title 30.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established within the United States Geological Survey an initiative, to be known as the “Earth Mapping Resources Initiative” (referred to in this section as the “Initiative”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose The purpose of the Initiative shall be to accelerate efforts to carry out the fundamental resources and mapping mission of the United States Geological Survey by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive mapping modernization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Comprehensive mapping modernization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Availability The Initiative shall make the geospatial data and metadata gathered by the Initiative under subsection (e)(1) electronically publicly accessible on an ongoing basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of data sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Integration of data sources The Initiative shall integrate data sources, including data from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31l_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $320,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>