<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3203"><akn:num>3203</akn:num><akn:heading>Small water storage and groundwater storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3203. Small water storage and groundwater storage projects(a) Establishment of a competitive grant program for small water storage and groundwater storage projectsThe Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program, under which the non-Federal project sponsor of any project in a Reclamation State, including the State of Alaska or Hawaii, determined by the Secretary to be feasible under subsection (b)(2)(B) shall be eligible to apply for funding for the planning, design, and construction of the project.


(b) Eligibility and selection(1) Submission to the Secretary(A) In generalA non-Federal project sponsor described in subsection (a) may submit to the Secretary a proposal for a project eligible to receive a grant under this section in the form of a completed feasibility study.


(B) Eligible projectsA project shall be considered eligible for consideration for a grant under this section if the project—(i) has water storage capacity of not less than 200 acre-feet and not more than 30,000 acre-feet; and

(ii)(I) increases surface water or groundwater storage; or

(II) conveys water, directly or indirectly, to or from surface water or groundwater storage.



(C) GuidelinesNot later than 60 days after November 15, 2021, the Secretary shall issue guidelines for feasibility studies for small storage projects to provide sufficient information for the formulation of the studies.



(2) Review by the SecretaryThe Secretary shall review each feasibility study received under paragraph (1)(A) for the purpose of determining whether—(A) the feasibility study, and the process under which the study was developed, each comply with Federal laws (including regulations) applicable to feasibility studies of small storage projects;

(B) the project is technically and financially feasible, in accordance with—(i) the guidelines developed under paragraph (1)(C); and

(ii) the reclamation laws; and


(C) the project provides a Federal benefit, as determined by the Secretary.


(3) Sub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of a competitive grant program for small water storage and groundwater storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of a competitive grant program for small water storage and groundwater storage projects The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program, under which the non-Federal project sponsor of any project in a Reclamation State, including the State of Alaska or Hawaii, determined by the Secretary to be feasible under subsection (b)(2)(B) shall be eligible to apply for funding for the planning, design, and construction of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility and selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility and selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceiling on Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ceiling on Federal share The Federal share of the costs of each of the individual projects selected under this section shall not exceed the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Environmental laws In providing funding for a grant for a project under this section, the Secretary shall comply with all applicable environmental laws, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of authority The authority to carry out this section terminates on the date that is 5 years after November 15, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>