<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3205" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3205/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/3205/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3205"><akn:num>3205</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grant program for large-scale water recycling and reuse program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3205. Competitive grant program for large-scale water recycling and reuse program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(A) a State, Indian Tribe, municipality, irrigation district, water district, wastewater district, or other organization with water or power delivery authority;

(B) a State, regional, or local authority, the members of which include 1 or more organizations with water or power delivery authority; or

(C) an agency established under State law for the joint exercise of powers or a combination of entities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).


(2) Eligible projectThe term “eligible project” means a project described in subsection (c).


(3) ProgramThe term “program” means the grant program established under subsection (b).


(4) Reclamation StateThe term “Reclamation State” means a State or territory described in the first section of the Act of June 17, 1902 (43 U.S.C. 391; 32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093).



(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible entities on a competitive basis for the planning, design, and construction of large-scale water recycling and reuse projects that provide substantial water supply and other benefits to the Reclamation States in accordance with this section.


(c) Eligible projectA project shall be eligible for a grant under this section if the project—(1) reclaims and reuses—(A) municipal, industrial, domestic, or agricultural wastewater; or

(B) impaired groundwater or surface water;


(2) has a total estimated cost of $500,000,000 or more;

(3) is located in a Reclamation State;

(4) is constructed, operated, and maintained by an eligible entity; and

(5) provides a Federal benefit in accordance with the reclamation laws.


(d) Project evaluationThe Secretary may provide a grant to an eligible project under the program if—(1) the eligible entity determines through the preparation of a feasibility study or equivalent study, and the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible entities on a competitive basis for the planning, design, and construction of large-scale water recycling and reuse projects that provide substantial water supply and other benefits to the Reclamation States in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible project A project shall be eligible for a grant under this section if the project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project evaluation The Secretary may provide a grant to an eligible project under the program if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In providing grants to eligible projects under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible projects that meet 1 or more of the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental laws In providing a grant for an eligible project under the program, the Secretary shall comply with all applicable environmental laws, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Guidance Not later than 1 year after November 15, 2021, the Secretary shall issue guidance on the implementation of the program, including guidelines for the preparation of feasibility studies or equivalent studies by eligible entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3205_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of conveyance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Treatment of conveyance The Secretary shall consider the planning, design, and construction of a conveyance system for an eligible project to be eligible for grant funding under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>