<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390b–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390b–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390b–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390b_2"><akn:num>390b–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Leveraging Federal infrastructure for increased water supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390b–2. Leveraging Federal infrastructure for increased water supply(a) In generalAt the request of a non-Federal interest, the Secretary may review proposals to increase the quantity of available supplies of water at a Federal water resources development project through—(1) modification of the project;

(2) modification of how the project is managed; or

(3) accessing water released from the project.


(b) Proposals includedA proposal under subsection (a) may include—(1) increasing the storage capacity of the project;

(2) diversion of water released or withdrawn from the project—(A) to recharge groundwater;

(B) to aquifer storage and recovery; or

(C) to any other storage facility;


(3) construction of facilities for delivery of water from pumping stations constructed by the Secretary;

(4) construction of facilities to access water; and

(5) a combination of the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (4).


(c) ExclusionsThis section shall not apply to a proposal that—(1) reallocates existing water supply or hydropower storage; or

(2) reduces water available for any authorized project purpose.


(d) Other Federal projectsIn any case in which a proposal relates to a Federal project that is not operated by the Secretary, this section shall apply only to activities under the authority of the Secretary.


(e) Review process(1) NoticeOn receipt of a proposal submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide a copy of the proposal to each entity described in paragraph (2) and, if applicable, the Federal agency that operates the project, in the case of a project operated by an agency other than the Department of the Army.


(2) Public participationIn reviewing proposals submitted under subsection (a), and prior to making any decisions regarding a proposal, the Secretary shall comply with all applicable public participation requirements under law, including consultation with—(A) affected States;

(B) power marketing administrations, in the case of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general At the request of a non-Federal interest, the Secretary may review proposals to increase the quantity of available supplies of water at a Federal water resources development project through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proposals included A proposal under subsection (a) may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusions This section shall not apply to a proposal that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Federal projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other Federal projects In any case in which a proposal relates to a Federal project that is not operated by the Secretary, this section shall apply only to activities under the authority of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorities A proposal submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a) may be reviewed and approved, if applicable and appropriate, under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations The Secretary shall not approve a proposal submitted under subsection (a) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cost share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributed funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Contributed funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390b_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Assistance On request by a non-Federal interest, the Secretary may provide technical assistance in the development or implementation of a proposal under subsection (a), including assistance in obtaining necessary permits for construction, if the non-Federal interest contracts with the Secretary to pay all costs of providing the technical assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>