<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390g–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390g–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390g–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390g_9"><akn:num>390g–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Aquifer recharge flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390g–9. Aquifer recharge flexibility(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act”.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Reclamation.


(2) CommissionerThe term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of Reclamation.


(3) Eligible landThe term “eligible land”, with respect to a Reclamation project, means land that—(A) is authorized to receive water under State law; and

(B) shares an aquifer with land located in the service area of the Reclamation project.


(4) Net water storage benefitThe term “net water storage benefit” means an increase in the volume of water that is—(A) stored in 1 or more aquifers; and

(B)(i) available for use within the authorized service area of a Reclamation project; or

(ii) stored on a long-term basis to avoid or reduce groundwater overdraft.



(5) Reclamation facilityThe term “Reclamation facility” means each of the infrastructure assets that are owned by the Bureau at a Reclamation project.


(6) Reclamation projectThe term “Reclamation project” means any reclamation or irrigation project, including incidental features thereof, authorized by Federal reclamation law or the Act of August 11, 1939 (commonly known as the “Water Conservation and Utilization Act”) (53 Stat. 1418, chapter 717; 16 U.S.C. 590y et seq.), or constructed by the United States pursuant to such law, or in connection with which there is a repayment or water service contract executed by the United States pursuant to such law, or any project constructed by the Secretary through the Bureau for the reclamation of land.



(c) Flexibility to allow greater aquifer recharge in Western States(1) Use of Reclamation facilities(A) In generalThe Commissioner may allow the use of excess capacity in Reclamation facilities for aquifer recharge of non-Reclamation project water, subject to applicable rates, charges, and public participation requirements, on the condition that—(i) the use—(I) shall not be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390g_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390g_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390g_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibility to allow greater aquifer recharge in Western States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Flexibility to allow greater aquifer recharge in Western States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>