<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390h_13"><akn:num>390h–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390h–13. Authorization of appropriations(a) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes and provisions of sections 390h through 390h–12p of this title.


(b) Prerequisite cost-sharing agreement(1) Funds may not be appropriated for the construction of any project authorized by sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title until after—(A) an appraisal investigation and a feasibility study that complies with the provisions of sections 390h–1(b) or 390h–2(c) of this title, as the case may be, have been completed by the Secretary or the non-Federal project sponsor;

(B) the Secretary has determined that the non-Federal project sponsor is financially capable of funding the non-Federal share of the project’s costs; and

(C) the Secretary has approved a cost-sharing agreement with the non-Federal project sponsor which commits the non-Federal project sponsor to funding its proportionate share of the project’s construction costs on an annual basis.


(2) The requirements of paragraph (1) shall not apply to those projects authorized by sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title for which funds were appropriated prior to January 1, 1996.


(c) Congressional notificationThe Secretary shall notify the Committees on Resources and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Appropriations of the Senate within 30 days after the signing of a cost-sharing agreement pursuant to subsection (b) that such an agreement has been signed and that the Secretary has determined that the non-Federal project sponsor is financially capable of funding the project’s non-Federal share of the project’s costs.


(d) Ceiling on Federal share(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title and except as provided by paragraph (2), the Federal share of the costs of each of the individual projects authorized by sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title shall not exceed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes and provisions of sections 390h through 390h–12p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisite cost-sharing agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prerequisite cost-sharing agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Congressional notification The Secretary shall notify the Committees on Resources and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Appropriations of the Senate within 30 days after the signing of a cost-sharing agreement pursuant to subsection (b) that such an agreement has been signed and that the Secretary has determined that the non-Federal project sponsor is financially capable of funding the project’s non-Federal share of the project’s costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceiling on Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ceiling on Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>