<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390h–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390h_8"><akn:num>390h–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Lake Cheraw water reclamation and reuse study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390h–8. Lake Cheraw water reclamation and reuse study(a) General authorityThe Secretary is authorized, in cooperation with the State of Colorado and appropriate local and regional entities, to conduct a study to assess and develop means of reclaiming the waters of Lake Cheraw, Colorado, or otherwise ameliorating, controlling and mitigating potential negative impacts of pollution in the waters of Lake Cheraw on groundwater resources or the waters of the Arkansas River.


(b) Federal shareThe Federal share of the costs of the study authorized by this section shall not exceed 50 per centum of the total.


(c) ReportThe Secretary shall submit the report authorized by this section to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives not later than two years after appropriation of funds authorized by sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title.


(Pub. L. 102–575, title XVI, § 1610, Oct. 30, 1992, 106 Stat. 4667; Pub. L. 103–437, § 16(a)(2), Nov. 2, 1994, 108 Stat. 4594.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 103–437 substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” before “of the House”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority The Secretary is authorized, in cooperation with the State of Colorado and appropriate local and regional entities, to conduct a study to assess and develop means of reclaiming the waters of Lake Cheraw, Colorado, or otherwise ameliorating, controlling and mitigating potential negative impacts of pollution in the waters of Lake Cheraw on groundwater resources or the waters of the Arkansas River.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal share The Federal share of the costs of the study authorized by this section shall not exceed 50 per centum of the total.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390h_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report The Secretary shall submit the report authorized by this section to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives not later than two years after appropriation of funds authorized by sections 390h to 390h–39 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>