<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390jj" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390jj/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/390jj/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390jj"><akn:num>390jj</akn:num><akn:heading>Water conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390jj. Water conservation(a) Implementation of program by non-Federal recipientsThe Secretary shall, pursuant to his authorities under otherwise existing Federal reclamation law, encourage the full consideration and incorporation of prudent and responsible water conservation measures in the operations of non-Federal recipients of irrigation water from Federal reclamation projects, where such measures are shown to be economically feasible for such non-Federal recipients.


(b) Development of planEach district that has entered into a repayment contract or water service contract pursuant to Federal reclamation law or the Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended (43 U.S.C. 390b), shall develop a water conservation plan which shall contain definite goals, appropriate water conservation measures, and a time schedule for meeting the water conservation objectives.


(c) Coordination of ongoing programs; full public participationThe Secretary is authorized and directed to enter into memorandums of agreement with those Federal agencies having capability to assist in implementing water conservation measures to assure coordination of ongoing programs. Such memorandums should provide for involvement of non-Federal entities such as States, Indian tribes, and water user organizations to assure full public participation in water conservation efforts.


(Pub. L. 97–293, title II, § 210, Oct. 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 1268.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFederal reclamation law, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is defined in section 390aa of this title.
The Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended, referred to in subsec. (b), is title III of Pub. L. 85–500, July 3, 1958, 72 Stat. 319, which enacted section 390b of this title and enacted a provision set out as a note under section 390b of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 390b of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390jj_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of program by non-Federal recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation of program by non-Federal recipients The Secretary shall, pursuant to his authorities under otherwise existing Federal reclamation law, encourage the full consideration and incorporation of prudent and responsible water conservation measures in the operations of non-Federal recipients of irrigation water from Federal reclamation projects, where such measures are shown to be economically feasible for such non-Federal recipients.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390jj_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of plan Each district that has entered into a repayment contract or water service contract pursuant to Federal reclamation law or the Water Supply Act of 1958, as amended (43 U.S.C. 390b), shall develop a water conservation plan which shall contain definite goals, appropriate water conservation measures, and a time schedule for meeting the water conservation objectives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390jj_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of ongoing programs; full public participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination of ongoing programs; full public participation The Secretary is authorized and directed to enter into memorandums of agreement with those Federal agencies having capability to assist in implementing water conservation measures to assure coordination of ongoing programs. Such memorandums should provide for involvement of non-Federal entities such as States, Indian tribes, and water user organizations to assure full public participation in water conservation efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>