<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_416"><akn:num>416</akn:num><akn:heading>Laws applicable to withdrawn lands; restoration to entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 416. Laws applicable to withdrawn lands; restoration to entry
All lands entered and entries made under the homestead laws within areas so withdrawn during such withdrawal shall be subject to all the provisions, limitations, charges, terms, and conditions of this Act; that said surveys shall be prosecuted diligently to completion, and upon the completion thereof, and of the necessary maps, plans, and estimates of cost, the Secretary of the Interior shall determine whether or not said project is practicable and advisable, and if determined to be impracticable or unadvisable he shall thereupon restore said lands to entry.
(June 17, 1902, ch. 1093, § 3, 32 Stat. 388; Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 704(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2792.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is act June 17, 1902, popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 371 of this title and Tables.
Said surveys, referred to in text, mean the surveys for contemplated irrigation works authorized by section 411 of this title.

Codification
Section is comprised of part of section 3 of act June 17, 1902. Remainder of such section 3 is classified to sections 432 and 434 of this title.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–579 struck out provisions that the Secretary of the Interior withdraw from public entry lands required for irrigation works contemplated under the Act of June 17, 1902, prior to the giving of the public notice provided for in section 419 of this title, that he restore such withdrawn lands to public entry when he deemed such lands unnecessary for the purposes of such Act, and that he withdraw from entry, except under the homestead laws, any public lands believed to be susceptible of irrigation from said works prior to the beginning of surveys for any contemplated irrigation works.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>