<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/420" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/420/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/420/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_420"><akn:num>420</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of earth, timber, etc., from other public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 420. Use of earth, timber, etc., from other public lands
In carrying out the provisions of the national irrigation law approved June 17, 1902, and in constructing works thereunder, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to use and to permit the use by those engaged in the construction of works under said law, under rules and regulations to be prescribed by him, such earth, stone, and timber from the public lands of the United States as may be required in the construction of such works, and the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to permit the use of earth, stone, and timber from the national forests of the United States for the same purpose, under rules and regulations to be prescribed by him.
(Feb. 8, 1905, ch. 552, 33 Stat. 706; Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, 34 Stat. 1269.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe national irrigation law approved June 17, 1902, referred to in text, is act June 17, 1902, ch. 1093, 32 Stat. 388, popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 371 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Act Mar. 4, 1907 redesignated “forest reserves” as “national forests”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>