<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_502"><akn:num>502</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency fund to assure continuous operation of projects and project facilities governed by Federal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 502. Emergency fund to assure continuous operation of projects and project facilities governed by Federal reclamation law
In order to assure continuous operation of all projects and project facilities governed by the Federal reclamation law (Act of June 17, 1902, 32 Stat. 388, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), including any project and facilities constructed with funds provided by the Small Reclamation Projects Act (Act of August 6, 1956, 70 Stat. 1044, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto) [43 U.S.C. 422a et seq.] or with funds provided by the Distribution System Loans Act (Act of May 14, 1956, 69 Stat. 244, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), there is hereby authorized to be appropriated from the reclamation fund an emergency fund which shall be available for defraying expenses which the Commissioner of Reclamation determines are required to be incurred because of unusual or emergency conditions.
(June 26, 1948, ch. 676, § 1, 62 Stat. 1052; Pub. L. 97–275, Oct. 1, 1982, 96 Stat. 1185.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAct of June 17, 1902, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 371 of this title and Tables.
The Small Reclamation Projects Act, referred to in text, probably means the Small Reclamation Projects Act of 1956, act Aug. 6, 1956, ch. 972, 70 Stat. 1044, which is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 422a et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 422k of this title and Tables.
The Distribution System Loans Act (Act of May 14, 1956, 69 Stat. 244, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), referred to in text, probably means act July 4, 1955, ch. 271, 69 Stat. 244, which is classified generally to sections 421a to 421h of this title. Act May 14, 1956, ch. 268, 70 Stat. 1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>