<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/505a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/505a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/505a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_505a_1"><akn:num>505a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Asset Management Report enhancements for reserved works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 505a–1. Asset Management Report enhancements for reserved works(a) In generalNot later than 2 years after March 12, 2019, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an Asset Management Report that—(1) describes the efforts of the Bureau—(A) to maintain in a reliable manner all reserved works at Reclamation facilities; and

(B) to standardize and streamline data reporting and processes across regions and areas for the purpose of maintaining reserved works at Reclamation facilities; and


(2) expands on the information otherwise provided in an Asset Management Report, in accordance with subsection (b).


(b) Infrastructure maintenance needs assessment(1) In generalThe Asset Management Report submitted under subsection (a) shall include—(A) a detailed assessment of major repair and rehabilitation needs for all reserved works at all Reclamation projects; and

(B) to the maximum extent practicable, an itemized list of major repair and rehabilitation needs of individual Reclamation facilities at each Reclamation project.


(2) InclusionsTo the maximum extent practicable, the itemized list of major repair and rehabilitation needs under paragraph (1)(B) shall include—(A) a budget level cost estimate of the appropriations needed to complete each item; and

(B) an assignment of a categorical rating for each item, consistent with paragraph (3).


(3) Rating requirements(A) In generalThe system for assigning ratings under paragraph (2)(B) shall be—(i) consistent with existing uniform categorization systems to inform the annual budget process and agency requirements; and

(ii) subject to the guidance and instructions issued under subparagraph (B).


(B) GuidanceAs soon as practicable after March 12, 2019, the Secretary shall issue guidance that describes the applicability of the rating system applicable under paragraph (2)(B) to Reclamation facilities.



(4) Public availabilityExcept as provided in paragraph (5), the Secretary shall make publicly available, including on the inter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505a_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 2 years after March 12, 2019, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an Asset Management Report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505a_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Infrastructure maintenance needs assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Infrastructure maintenance needs assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505a_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Updates Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Asset Management Report is submitted under subsection (a) and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall update the Asset Management Report, subject to the requirements of section 505a–2(b)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505a_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation To the extent that such consultation would assist the Secretary in preparing the Asset Management Report under subsection (a) and updates to the Asset Management Report under subsection (c), the Secretary shall consult with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>