<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/54" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/54/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/54/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_54"><akn:num>54</akn:num><akn:heading>Completion of surveys; delivery to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 54. Completion of surveys; delivery to States
The Secretary of the Interior shall take all the necessary measures for the completion of the surveys in the several surveying districts, at the earliest periods compatible with the purposes contemplated by law; and whenever the surveys and records of any such district are completed, the Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate shall deliver over to the secretary of state of the respective States, including such surveys, or to such other officer as may be authorized to receive them, all the field notes, maps, records, and other papers appertaining to land titles within the same.
(R.S. § 2218; June 5, 1924, ch. 264, 43 Stat. 394; Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462, 43 Stat. 1144; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. July 16, 1946, 11 F.R. 7876, 60 Stat. 1100.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The original text of R.S. § 2218 provided for completion of surveys “in the several surveying-districts for which surveyors general have been, or may be, appointed” and also provided that “the surveyor general thereof shall be required to deliver over” all papers appertaining to land titles within the district, “and the office of surveyor general in every such district shall thereafter cease and be discontinued.” The references to the surveyors general were omitted in view of act Mar. 3, 1925 (classified to section 51 of this title) abolishing office of surveyor general and transferring its activities to the Field Surveying Service, under the jurisdiction of the U.S. Supervisor of Surveys. See, also, Transfer of Functions note below.
R.S. § 2207, formerly cited as a credit to this section, which provided for appointment of surveyors general, was superseded by act Mar. 3, 1925 (classified to section 51 of this title) and repealed by act Mar. 3, 1933, ch. 202, § 1, 47 Stat. 1429.
Act June 5, 1924, appropriated funds for use in making the surveys in twelve districts.
Act May 25, 1906, ch. 2554, 34 Stat. 199, provided for a survey,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>