<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/59" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/59/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/59/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_59"><akn:num>59</akn:num><akn:heading>Official papers in office of surveyor general in California; copies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 59. Official papers in office of surveyor general in California; copies
All official books, papers, instruments of writing, documents, archives, official seals, stamps, or dies, which have been authorized by law to be collected and deposited in the surveyor general’s office in California, shall be safely and securely kept by the Secretary of the Interior, or such officer as he may designate, in the archives of his office until disposed of as provided by law; and copies thereof, authenticated by the Secretary or such officer under his seal of office, shall be evidence in all cases where the originals would be evidence.
(R.S. § 2229; Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462, 43 Stat. 1144; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. July 16, 1946, 11 F.R. 7876, 60 Stat. 1100; Oct. 25, 1951, ch. 562, § 3(3), 65 Stat. 639.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. § 2229 derived from act May 18, 1858, ch. 39, § 1, 11 Stat. 289.

Amendments1951—Act Oct. 25, 1951, inserted “until disposed of as provided by law”.

Statutory Notes and Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. May 24, 1950, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262, set out under section 1451 of this title.
“Secretary of the Interior or such officer as he may designate” substituted for “Supervisor of Surveys” on authority on section 403 of Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1946. See note set out under section 1 of this title.
Previously, “Supervisor of Surveys” was substituted for “surveyor general” by act Mar. 3, 1925.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>