<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/593b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/593b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/593b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_593b"><akn:num>593b</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of additional works for irrigation purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 593b. Construction of additional works for irrigation purposes
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain under the provisions of the Federal reclamation laws (Act June 17, 1902, 32 Stat. 388, and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto), such additional works as he may deem necessary for irrigation purposes. Such irrigation works may be undertaken only after a report and findings thereon have been made by the Secretary of the Interior as provided in such Federal reclamation laws; and, within the limits of the water users’ repayment ability, such report may be predicated on allocation to irrigation of an appropriate portion of the cost of constructing said dam and reservoir. Said dam and reservoir and said irrigation works may be utilized for irrigation purposes only pursuant to the provisions of said Federal reclamation laws.
(June 5, 1944, ch. 234, § 3, 58 Stat. 271.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAct of June 17, 1902, referred to in text, is popularly known as the Reclamation Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 371 of this title and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Authorization of AppropriationsAct June 5, 1944, ch. 234, § 4, 58 Stat. 271, authorized appropriation of such sums as might be necessary to carry out the purpose of this section and section 593a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>