<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/617u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/617u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/617u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_617u"><akn:num>617u</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease of reserved lands in Boulder City, Nevada; disposition of revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 617u. Lease of reserved lands in Boulder City, Nevada; disposition of revenues
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and empowered, under such rules and regulations as he may prescribe, to establish rental rates for the lease of reserved lands of the United States situate within the exterior boundaries of Boulder City, Nevada, and, without prior advertising, to enter into leases therefor at not less than rates so established and for periods not exceeding fifty-three years from the date of such leases: Provided, That all revenues which may accrue to the United States under the provisions of such leases shall be deposited in the Treasury and credited to the Colorado River Dam fund established by section 617a of this title.
(June 18, 1940, ch. 395, 54 Stat. 437.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Boulder Canyon Project Act which comprises this subchapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Boulder City Act of 1958Public Law 85–900, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1726, provided for disposal of certain Federal property in Boulder City for purposes of establishment of a municipal corporation incorporated under laws of Nevada.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>