<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/619" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/619/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/619/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_619"><akn:num>619</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase in capacity of existing generating equipment at Hoover Powerplant; construction of Colorado</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 619. Increase in capacity of existing generating equipment at Hoover Powerplant; construction of Colorado River bridge crossing(a) Hoover Powerplant generating equipment; increase in capacity; improvement of appurtenances; authorization of SecretaryThe Secretary of the Interior is authorized to increase the capacity of existing generating equipment and appurtenances at Hoover Powerplant (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “uprating program”); and to improve parking, visitor facilities, and roadways and to provide additional elevators, and other facilities that will contribute to the safety and sufficiency of visitor access to Hoover Dam and Powerplant (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “visitor facilities program”).


(b) Construction of Colorado River bridge crossing; authorization of SecretaryThe Secretary of the Interior is authorized to construct a Colorado River bridge crossing, including suitable approach spans, immediately downstream from Hoover Dam for the purpose of alleviating traffic congestion and reducing safety hazards. This bridge shall not be a part of the Boulder Canyon project and shall neither be funded nor repaid from the Colorado River Dam Fund or the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund.


(Pub. L. 98–381, title I, § 101, Aug. 17, 1984, 98 Stat. 1333.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 98–381, Aug. 17, 1984, 98 Stat. 1333, which enacted this subchapter and sections 7274 and 7275 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and amended sections 617a, 617b, 618, 618a, 618e, 618k, and 1543 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2011 AmendmentPub. L. 112–72, § 1, Dec. 20, 2011, 125 Stat. 777, provided that: “This Act [amending section 619a of this title] may be cited as the ‘Hoover Power Allocation Act of 2011’.”


Short TitlePub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_619_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hoover Powerplant generating equipment; increase in capacity; improvement of appurtenances; authorization of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hoover Powerplant generating equipment; increase in capacity; improvement of appurtenances; authorization of Secretary The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to increase the capacity of existing generating equipment and appurtenances at Hoover Powerplant (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “uprating program”); and to improve parking, visitor facilities, and roadways and to provide additional elevators, and other facilities that will contribute to the safety and sufficiency of visitor access to Hoover Dam and Powerplant (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as “visitor facilities program”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_619_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of Colorado River bridge crossing; authorization of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction of Colorado River bridge crossing; authorization of Secretary The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to construct a Colorado River bridge crossing, including suitable approach spans, immediately downstream from Hoover Dam for the purpose of alleviating traffic congestion and reducing safety hazards. This bridge shall not be a part of the Boulder Canyon project and shall neither be funded nor repaid from the Colorado River Dam Fund or the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>