<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/620d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/620d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/620d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_620d"><akn:num>620d</akn:num><akn:heading>Upper Colorado River Basin Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 620d. Upper Colorado River Basin Fund(a) Authorization and availabilityThere is authorized a separate fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund (hereinafter referred to as the Basin Fund), which shall remain available until expended, as hereafter provided, for carrying out provisions of this chapter other than section 620g of this title.


(b) Crediting of appropriationsAll appropriations made for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, other than section 620g of this title shall be credited to the Basin Fund as advances from the general fund of the Treasury.


(c) Crediting and availability of revenuesAll revenues collected in connection with the operation of the Colorado River storage project and participating projects shall be credited to the Basin Fund, and shall be available, without further appropriation, for (1) defraying the costs of operation, maintenance, and replacements of, and emergency expenditures for, all facilities of the Colorado River storage project and participating projects, within such separate limitations as may be included in annual appropriation acts: Provided, That with respect to each participating project, such costs shall be paid from revenues received from each such project; (2) payment as required by subsection (d) of this section; and (3) payment as required by subsection (e) of this section. Revenues credited to the Basin Fund shall not be available for appropriation for construction of the units and participating projects authorized by or pursuant to this chapter.


(d) Payments of revenues in excess of operating needs to TreasuryRevenues in the Basin Fund in excess of operating needs shall be paid annually to the general fund of the Treasury to return—(1) the costs of each unit, participating project, or any separable feature thereof which are allocated to power pursuant to section 620e of this title, within a period not exceeding fifty years from the date of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization and availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization and availability There is authorized a separate fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund (hereinafter referred to as the Basin Fund), which shall remain available until expended, as hereafter provided, for carrying out provisions of this chapter other than section 620g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Crediting of appropriations All appropriations made for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, other than section 620g of this title shall be credited to the Basin Fund as advances from the general fund of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting and availability of revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Crediting and availability of revenues All revenues collected in connection with the operation of the Colorado River storage project and participating projects shall be credited to the Basin Fund, and shall be available, without further appropriation, for (1) defraying the costs of operation, maintenance, and replacements of, and emergency expenditures for, all facilities of the Colorado River storage project and participating projects, within such separate limitations as may be included in annual appropriation acts: Provided, That with respect to each participating project, such costs shall be paid from revenues received from each such project; (2) payment as required by subsection (d) of this section; and (3) payment as required by subsection (e) of this section. Revenues credited to the Basin Fund shall not be available for appropriation for construction of the units and participating projects authorized by or pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments of revenues in excess of operating needs to Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payments of revenues in excess of operating needs to Treasury Revenues in the Basin Fund in excess of operating needs shall be paid annually to the general fund of the Treasury to return—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment of excess revenues among States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Apportionment of excess revenues among States Revenues in the Basin Fund in excess of the amounts needed to meet the requirements of clause (1) of subsection (c) of this section, and to return to the general fund of the Treasury the costs set out in subsection (d) of this section, shall be apportioned among the States of the Upper Division in the following percentages: Colorado, 46 per centum; Utah, 21.5 per centum; Wyoming, 15.5 per centum; and New Mexico, 17 per centum: Provided, That prior to the application of such percentages, all revenues remaining in the Basin Fund from each participating project (or part thereof), herein or hereafter authorized, after payments, where applicable, with respect to such projects, to the general fund of the Treasury under subparagraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (d) of this section shall be apportioned to the State in which such participating project, or part thereof, is located.
Revenues so apportioned to each State shall be used only for </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of interest rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Determination of interest rate The interest rate applicable to each unit of the storage project and each participating project for purposes of computing interest during construction and interest on the unpaid balance shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, as of the beginning of the fiscal year in which construction is initiated, on the basis of the computed average interest rate payable by the Treasury upon its outstanding marketable public obligations, which are neither due nor callable for redemption for fifteen years from the date of issue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget to be submitted to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Budget to be submitted to Congress Business-type budgets shall be submitted to the Congress annually for all operations financed by the Basin Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>