<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/717...728" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/717...728/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/43/717...728/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_717___728"><akn:num>717...728</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2789</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 717 to 728. Repealed. Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 703(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2789

Section 717, R.S. § 2386, related to title to town lots subject to mineral rights.


Section 718, R.S. § 2387; acts Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 4, 26 Stat. 1097, authorized entry by town authorities of town sites in trust for occupants, under such regulations as may be prescribed by legislative authority of State or Territory in which the same may be situated.


Section 719, R.S. § 2388; acts Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 462, 43 Stat. 1144; 1946 Reorg. Plan No. 3, § 403, eff. July 16, 1946, 11 F.R. 7876, 60 Stat. 1100, related to procedure for entry by town authorities of town sites in trust for occupants.


Section 720, R.S. § 2389, authorized entry by town authorities of town sites in proportion to number of inhabitants.


Section 721, R.S. § 2391, made void acts of trustees not in conformity to regulations alluded to in section 718 of this title.


Section 722, R.S. § 2392, provided that no title was to be acquired under sections 711 to 715 and 717 to 721 of this title to any mine of gold, silver, cinnabar, or copper or to any valid mining claim or possession held under existing laws.


Section 723, R.S. § 2393, provided that provisions of sections 711 to 715 and 717 to 724 of this title were not to apply to military reservations or to other reservations made by the United States prior to Mar. 2, 1867, nor to reservations for lighthouses, customhouses, mints, or other public purposes, whether held under reservation through the Land Office by title derived from the Crown of Spain or otherwise.


Section 724, R.S. § 2394, authorized inhabitants of any town on public land to avail themselves of provisions of sections 718 to 720 of this title and required that they pay, in addition to minimum price of lands so entered, all costs of surveying and platting.


Section 725, act Mar. 3, 1877, ch. 113, § 1, 19 Stat. 392, related to requirements as to quantity of land excluded from homestead entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>