<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1011a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1011a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1011a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1011a"><akn:num>1011a</akn:num><akn:heading>Watershed agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1011a. Watershed agreements(a) Watershed restoration and enhancement agreementsFor fiscal year 2006 and each fiscal year thereafter, to the extent funds are otherwise available, appropriations for the Forest Service may be used by the Secretary of Agriculture for the purpose of entering into cooperative agreements with willing Federal, tribal, State and local governments, private and nonprofit entities and landowners for the protection, restoration and enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat, and other resources on public or private land, the reduction of risk from natural disaster where public safety is threatened, or a combination thereof or both that benefit these resources within the watershed.


(b) Direct and indirect watershed agreementsThe Secretary of Agriculture may enter into a watershed restoration and enhancement agreement—(1) directly with a willing private landowner; or

(2) indirectly through an agreement with a State, local or tribal government or other public entity, educational institution, or private nonprofit organization.


(c) Terms and conditionsIn order for the Secretary to enter into a watershed restoration and enhancement agreement—(1) the agreement shall—(A) include such terms and conditions mutually agreed to by the Secretary and the landowner, state 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. or local government, or private or nonprofit entity;

(B) improve the viability of and otherwise benefit the fish, wildlife, and other resources on national forests lands within the watershed;

(C) authorize the provision of technical assistance by the Secretary in the planning of management activities that will further the purposes of the agreement;

(D) provide for the sharing of costs of implementing the agreement among the Federal Government, the landowner(s), and other entities, as mutually agreed on by the affected interests; and

(E) ensure that any expenditure by the Secretary pursuant to the agreement is determined by the Secreta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1011a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Watershed restoration and enhancement agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Watershed restoration and enhancement agreements For fiscal year 2006 and each fiscal year thereafter, to the extent funds are otherwise available, appropriations for the Forest Service may be used by the Secretary of Agriculture for the purpose of entering into cooperative agreements with willing Federal, tribal, State and local governments, private and nonprofit entities and landowners for the protection, restoration and enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat, and other resources on public or private land, the reduction of risk from natural disaster where public safety is threatened, or a combination thereof or both that benefit these resources within the watershed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1011a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct and indirect watershed agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Direct and indirect watershed agreements The Secretary of Agriculture may enter into a watershed restoration and enhancement agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1011a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions In order for the Secretary to enter into a watershed restoration and enhancement agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1011a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicable law Chapter 63 of title 31 shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1011a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting requirements Not later than December 31, 1999, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House and Senate, which contains—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>