<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1161" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1161/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1161/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161"><akn:num>1161</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of fur seal rookeries and other Federal real and personal property on Pribilof Island</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161. Administration of fur seal rookeries and other Federal real and personal property on Pribilof Islands
The Secretary shall administer the fur seal rookeries and other Federal real and personal property on the Pribilof Islands, with the exception of lands purchased by the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service under section 1417 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (Public Law 96–487) or acquired or purchased by any other authority after October 14, 1983, and, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall ensure that activities on such property are consistent with the purposes of conserving, managing, and protecting the North Pacific fur seals and other wildlife and for other purposes consistent with that primary purpose.
(Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 201, Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1093; Pub. L. 98–129, § 2, Oct. 14, 1983, 97 Stat. 838; Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(4) [div. B, title I, § 144(e)(6)(B)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–248; Pub. L. 106–562, title I, § 106(b), Dec. 23, 2000, 114 Stat. 2799.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1417 of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 96–487, title XIV, § 1417, Dec. 2, 1980, 94 Stat. 2500, which is not classified to the Code.

Amendments2000—Pub. L. 106–554 and Pub. L. 106–562 amended text identically, substituting “on such property” for “on such Islands”.
1983—Pub. L. 98–129 substituted provisions enumerating the steps to be followed by the Secretary of Commerce in administering the fur seal rookeries and the Federal real and personal property on the Pribilof Islands for provisions which had provided that: “The Pribilof Islands shall continue to be administered as a special reservation by the Secretary of Commerce for the purposes of conserving, managing, and protecting the North Pacific fur seals and other wildlife, and for other purposes.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
PurposePub. L. 106–562, title I, § 102, Dec. 23, 2000,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>