<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1165" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1165/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1165/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1165"><akn:num>1165</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposal of Federal property on Pribilof Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1165. Disposal of Federal property on Pribilof Islands(a) to (d) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–562, title I, § 105(c), Dec. 23, 2000, 114 Stat. 2798, as amended by Pub. L. 114–120, title V, § 523(3)(B), Feb. 8, 2016, 130 Stat. 71

(e) TaxationThe grant, sale, transfer or conveyance of any real or personal property pursuant to this section shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State or local taxation. The basis for computing gain or loss on subsequent sale or disposition of such real or personal property for purposes of any Federal, State or local tax imposed on, or measured by revenue shall be the fair market value of such real or personal property at the time of receipt.


(f) Agreements with governmental agencies and third partiesIn carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements, including but not limited to land exchange agreements with other Departments and Agencies of both the State and Federal Governments, and with third parties, notwithstanding any provision of law relating to the transfer and disposal of Federal property to the contrary; except that the authority of the Secretary of the Interior regarding exchanges involving lands in the National Wildlife Refuge System on October 14, 1983, is not affected by this section.


(Pub. L. 89–702, title II, § 205, Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1094; Pub. L. 98–129, § 2, Oct. 14, 1983, 97 Stat. 839; Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(4) [div. B, title I, § 144(e)(4)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–245; Pub. L. 106–562, title I, §§ 104, 105(c)(1), Dec. 23, 2000, 114 Stat. 2796, 2798.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2000—Subsecs. (a), (b). Pub. L. 106–562, § 105(c)(1), as amended by Pub. L. 114–120, § 523(3)(B), struck out subsec. (a) which related to the submission to Congress of a property transfer document for property on the Pribilof Islands held by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and subsec. (b) which related to the contents of such document</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1165_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (d) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–562, title I, § 105(c), Dec. 23, 2000, 114 Stat. 2798, as amended by Pub. L. 114–120, title V, § 523(3)(B), Feb. 8, 2016, 130 Stat. 71</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) to (d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1165_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Taxation The grant, sale, transfer or conveyance of any real or personal property pursuant to this section shall not be subject to any form of Federal, State or local taxation. The basis for computing gain or loss on subsequent sale or disposition of such real or personal property for purposes of any Federal, State or local tax imposed on, or measured by revenue shall be the fair market value of such real or personal property at the time of receipt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1165_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with governmental agencies and third parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agreements with governmental agencies and third parties In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements, including but not limited to land exchange agreements with other Departments and Agencies of both the State and Federal Governments, and with third parties, notwithstanding any provision of law relating to the transfer and disposal of Federal property to the contrary; except that the authority of the Secretary of the Interior regarding exchanges involving lands in the National Wildlife Refuge System on October 14, 1983, is not affected by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>