<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1166" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1166/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1166/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1166"><akn:num>1166</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1166. Financial assistance(a) Grant authority(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall provide financial assistance to any city government, village corporation, or tribal council of St. George, Alaska, or St. Paul, Alaska.


(2) Use for matchingNotwithstanding any other provision of law relating to matching funds, funds provided by the Secretary as assistance under this subsection may be used by the entity as non-Federal matching funds under any Federal program that requires such matching funds.


(3) Restriction on useThe Secretary may not use financial assistance authorized by this chapter—(A) to settle any debt owed to the United States;

(B) for administrative or overhead expenses; or

(C) for contributions sought or required from any person for costs or fees to clean up any matter that was caused or contributed to by such person on or after March 15, 2000.


(4) Funding instruments and proceduresIn providing assistance under this subsection the Secretary shall transfer any funds appropriated to carry out this section to the Secretary of the Interior, who shall obligate such funds through instruments and procedures that are equivalent to the instruments and procedures required to be used by the Bureau of Indian Affairs pursuant to title IV of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5361 et seq.].


(5) Pro rata distribution of assistanceIn any fiscal year for which less than all of the funds authorized under subsection (c)(1) are appropriated, such funds shall be distributed under this subsection on a pro rata basis among the entities referred to in subsection (c)(1) in the same proportions in which amounts are authorized by that subsection for grants to those entities.



(b) Solid waste assistance(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall provide assistance to the State of Alaska for designing, locating, constructing, redeveloping, permitting, or certif</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solid waste assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Solid waste assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of assistance for lobbying activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on use of assistance for lobbying activities None of the funds authorized by this section may be available for any activity a purpose of which is to influence legislation pending before the Congress, except that this subsection shall not prevent officers or employees of the United States or of its departments, agencies, or commissions from communicating to Members of Congress, through proper channels, requests for legislation or appropriations that they consider necessary for the efficient conduct of public business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Immunity from liability Neither the United States nor any of its agencies, officers, or employees shall have any liability under this chapter or any other law associated with or resulting from the designing, locating, contracting for, redeveloping, permitting, certifying, operating, or maintaining any solid waste management facility on the Pribilof Islands as a consequence of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report on expenditures Each entity which receives assistance authorized under subsection (c) shall submit an audited statement listing the expenditure of that assistance to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, on the last day of fiscal years 2002, 2004, and 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1166_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional intent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Congressional intent Amounts authorized under subsection (c) are intended by Congress to be provided in addition to the base funding appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in fiscal year 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>