<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1244" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1244/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1244/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1244"><akn:num>1244</akn:num><akn:heading>National scenic and national historic trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1244. National scenic and national historic trails(a) Establishment and designation; administrationNational scenic and national historic trails shall be authorized and designated only by Act of Congress. There are hereby established the following National Scenic and National Historic Trails:(1) The Appalachian National Scenic Trail, a trail of approximately two thousand miles extending generally along the Appalachian Mountains from Mount Katahdin, Maine, to Springer Mountain, Georgia. Insofar as practicable, the right-of-way for such trail shall comprise the trail depicted on the maps identified as “Nationwide System of Trails, Proposed Appalachian Trail, NST–AT–101–May 1967”, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Director of the National Park Service. Where practicable, such rights-of-way shall include lands protected for it under agreements in effect as of October 2, 1968, to which Federal agencies and States were parties. The Appalachian Trail shall be administered primarily as a footpath by the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture.

(2) The Pacific Crest National Scenic Trail, a trail of approximately two thousand three hundred fifty miles, extending from the Mexican-California border northward generally along the mountain ranges of the west coast States to the Canadian-Washington border near Lake Ross, following the route as generally depicted on the map, identified as “Nationwide System of Trails, Proposed Pacific Crest Trail, NST–PC–103–May 1967” which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief of the Forest Service. The Pacific Crest Trail shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior.

(3) The Oregon National Historic Trail, a route of approximately two thousand miles extending from near Independence, Missouri, to the vicinity of Portland, Oregon, following a route as depicted on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and designation; administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and designation; administration National scenic and national historic trails shall be authorized and designated only by Act of Congress. There are hereby established the following National Scenic and National Historic Trails:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional national scenic or national historic trails; feasibility studies; consultations; submission of studies to Congress; scope of studies; qualifications for national historic trail designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional national scenic or national historic trails; feasibility studies; consultations; submission of studies to Congress; scope of studies; qualifications for national historic trail designation The Secretary of the Interior, through the agency most likely to administer such trail, and the Secretary of Agriculture where lands administered by him are involved, shall make such additional studies as are herein or may hereafter be authorized by the Congress for the purpose of determining the feasibility and desirability of designating other trails as national scenic or national historic trails. Such studies shall be made in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies administering lands through which such additional proposed trails would pass and in cooperation with interested interstate, State, and local governmental agencies, public and private organizations, and landowners and land users concerned. The feasibility of designating a trail shall be determined on the basi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Routes subject to consideration for designation as national scenic trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Routes subject to consideration for designation as national scenic trails The following routes shall be studied in accordance with the objectives outlined in subsection (b) of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trail advisory councils; establishment and termination; term and compensation; membership; chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Trail advisory councils; establishment and termination; term and compensation; membership; chairman The Secretary charged with the administration of each respective trail shall, within one year of the date of the addition of any national scenic or national historic trail to the System, and within sixty days of November 10, 1978, for the Appalachian and Pacific Crest National Scenic Trails, establish an advisory council for each such trail, each of which councils shall expire ten years from the date of its establishment, except that the Advisory Council established for the Iditarod Historic Trail shall expire twenty years from the date of its establishment. If the appropriate Secretary is unable to establish such an advisory council because of the lack of adequate public interest, the Secretary shall so advise the appropriate committees of the Congress. The appropriate Secretary shall consult with such council from time to time with respect to matters relating to the trail, includin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive national scenic trail plan; consultation; submission to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Comprehensive national scenic trail plan; consultation; submission to Congressional committees Within two complete fiscal years of the date of enactment of legislation designating a national scenic trail, except for the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail and the North Country National Scenic Trail, as part of the system, and within two complete fiscal years of November 10, 1978, for the Pacific Crest and Appalachian Trails, the responsible Secretary shall, after full consultation with affected Federal land managing agencies, the Governors of the affected States, the relevant advisory council established pursuant to subsection (d), and the Appalachian Trail Conference in the case of the Appalachian Trail, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, a comprehensive plan for the acquisition, management, development, and use of the trail, including but not limited to, the following i</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive national historic trail plan; consultation; submission to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Comprehensive national historic trail plan; consultation; submission to Congressional committees Within two complete fiscal years of the date of enactment of legislation designating a national historic trail or the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail or the North Country National Scenic Trail as part of the system, the responsible Secretary shall, after full consultation with affected Federal land managing agencies, the Governors of the affected States, and the relevant Advisory Council established pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, a comprehensive plan for the management, and use of the trail, including but not limited to, the following items:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1244_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of feasibility and suitability studies of existing national historic trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Revision of feasibility and suitability studies of existing national historic trails</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>