<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1250" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1250/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1250/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1250"><akn:num>1250</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer trails assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1250. Volunteer trails assistance(a) Volunteer planning, development, maintenance, and management of trails(1) In addition to the cooperative agreement and other authorities contained in this chapter, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the head of any Federal agency administering Federal lands, are authorized to encourage volunteers and volunteer organizations to plan, develop, maintain, and manage, where appropriate, trails throughout the Nation.

(2) Wherever appropriate in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, the Secretaries are authorized and encouraged to utilize section 102301 of title 54, the Volunteers in the Forests Act of 1972 11 See References in Text note below. [16 U.S.C. 558a et seq.], and 200305 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of title 54 (relating to the development of Statewide Comprehensive Outdoor Recreation Plans).


(b) Scope of volunteer workEach Secretary or the head of any Federal land managing agency may assist volunteers and volunteer organizations in planning, developing, maintaining, and managing trails. Volunteer work may include, but need not be limited to—(1) planning, developing, maintaining, or managing (A) trails which are components of the national trails system, or (B) trails which, if so developed and maintained, could qualify for designation as components of the national trails system; or

(2) operating programs to organize and supervise volunteer trail building efforts with respect to the trails referred to in paragraph (1), conducting trail-related research projects, or providing education and training to volunteers on methods of trails planning, construction, and maintenance.


(c) Use of Federal facilities, equipment, tools, and technical assistanceThe appropriate Secretary or the head of any Federal land managing agency may utilize and make available Federal facilities, equipment, tools, and technical assistance to volunteers and volunteer organizations, s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1250_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer planning, development, maintenance, and management of trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Volunteer planning, development, maintenance, and management of trails</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1250_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of volunteer work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of volunteer work Each Secretary or the head of any Federal land managing agency may assist volunteers and volunteer organizations in planning, developing, maintaining, and managing trails. Volunteer work may include, but need not be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1250_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Federal facilities, equipment, tools, and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of Federal facilities, equipment, tools, and technical assistance The appropriate Secretary or the head of any Federal land managing agency may utilize and make available Federal facilities, equipment, tools, and technical assistance to volunteers and volunteer organizations, subject to such limitations and restrictions as the appropriate Secretary or the head of any Federal land managing agency deems necessary or desirable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>