<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1271" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1271/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1271/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1271"><akn:num>1271</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1271. Congressional declaration of policy
It is hereby declared to be the policy of the United States that certain selected rivers of the Nation which, with their immediate environments, possess outstandingly remarkable scenic, recreational, geologic, fish and wildlife, historic, cultural, or other similar values, shall be preserved in free-flowing condition, and that they and their immediate environments shall be protected for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations. The Congress declares that the established national policy of dam and other construction at appropriate sections of the rivers of the United States needs to be complemented by a policy that would preserve other selected rivers or sections thereof in their free-flowing condition to protect the water quality of such rivers and to fulfill other vital national conservation purposes.
(Pub. L. 90–542, § 1(b), Oct. 2, 1968, 82 Stat. 906.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section consists of subsec. (b) of section 1 of Pub. L. 90–542. Subsecs. (a) and (c) of section 1 are classified to section 1272 of this title and as a note under this section, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2018 AmendmentPub. L. 115–229, § 1, Aug. 2, 2018, 132 Stat. 1629, provided that: “This Act [amending section 1274 of this title and enacting provisions classified as a note under section 1274 of this title] may be cited as the ‘East Rosebud Wild and Scenic Rivers Act’.”


Short Title of 2014 AmendmentPub. L. 113–244, § 1, Dec. 18, 2014, 128 Stat. 2864, provided that: “This Act [amending section 1274 of this title and section 615i of Title 43, Public Lands, and enacting provisions classified as a note under section 1274 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Crooked River Collaborative Water Security and Jobs Act of 2014’.”


Short Title of 2009 AmendmentPub. L. 111–11, title V, § 5002(a), Mar. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 1147, provided that: “This section [amending section 1274 of this title</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>