<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1274"><akn:num>1274</akn:num><akn:heading>Component rivers and adjacent lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1274. Component rivers and adjacent lands(a) DesignationThe following rivers and the land adjacent thereto are hereby designated as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system:(1) Clearwater, Middle Fork, Idaho—The Middle Fork from the town of Kooskia upstream to the town of Lowell; the Lochsa River from its junction with the Selway at Lowell forming the Middle Fork, upstream to the Powell Ranger Station; and the Selway River from Lowell upstream to its origin; to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.

(2) Eleventh Point, Missouri—The segment of the river extending downstream from Thomasville to State Highway 142; to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.

(3) Feather, California—The entire Middle Fork downstream from the confluence of its tributary streams one kilometer south of Beckwourth, California; to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture.

(4) Rio Grande, New Mexico—The segment extending from the Colorado State line downstream to the State Highway 96 crossing, and the lower four miles of the Red River; to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior.

(5) Rogue, oregon.—(A) In general.—The segment of the river extending from the mouth of the Applegate River downstream to the Lobster Creek Bridge, to be administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as agreed to by the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture or as directed by the President.

(B) Additions.—In addition to the segment described in subparagraph (A), there are designated the following segments in the Rogue River:(i) Kelsey creek.—The approximately 6.8-mile segment of Kelsey Creek from the Wild Rogue Wilderness boundary in T. 32 S., R. 9 W., sec. 25, Willamette Meridian, to the confluence with the Rogue River, as a wild river.

(ii) East fork kelsey creek.—(I) Scenic river.—The approximately 0.2-mile segment of East Fork Kelsey Creek from headwaters downstream to the Wild Rogue Wilderness boundary in T. 33 S., R. 8</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation The following rivers and the land adjacent thereto are hereby designated as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of boundaries; classification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of boundaries; classification The agency charged with the administration of each component of the national wild and scenic rivers system designated by subsection (a) of this section shall, within one year from the date of designation of such component under subsection (a) (except where a different date if 1616 So in original. Probably should be “is”. provided in subsection (a)), establish detailed boundaries therefor (which boundaries shall include an average of not more than 320 acres of land per mile measured from the ordinary high water mark on both sides of the river); and determine which of the classes outlined in section 1273(b) of this title best fit the river or its various segments.
Notice of the availability of the boundaries and classification, and of subsequent boundary amendments shall be published in the Federal Register and shall not become effective until ninety days after they have been forwarded to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the H</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public inspection of maps and descriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public inspection of maps and descriptions Maps of all boundaries and descriptions of the classifications of designated river segments, and subsequent amendments to such boundaries, shall be available for public inspection in the offices of the administering agency in the District of Columbia and in locations convenient to the designated river.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive management plan for protection of river values; review of boundaries, classifications, and plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Comprehensive management plan for protection of river values; review of boundaries, classifications, and plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>