<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1282" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1282/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1282/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1282"><akn:num>1282</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to State and local projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1282. Assistance to State and local projects(a) Assistance of Secretary of the InteriorThe Secretary of the Interior shall encourage and assist the States to consider, in formulating and carrying out their comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plans and proposals for financing assistance for State and local projects submitted pursuant to chapter 2003 of title 54),11 So in original. The closing parenthesis probably should not appear. needs and opportunities for establishing State and local wild, scenic and recreational river areas.


(b) Assistance of Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, or other Federal agency heads; use of Federal facilities, equipment, etc.; conditions on permits or other authorizations(1) The Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, or the head of any other Federal agency, shall assist, advise, and cooperate with States or their political subdivisions, landowners, private organizations, or individuals to plan, protect, and manage river resources. Such assistance, advice, and cooperation may be through written agreements or otherwise. This authority applies within or outside a federally administered area and applies to rivers which are components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and to other rivers. Any agreement under this subsection may include provisions for limited financial or other assistance to encourage participation in the acquisition, protection, and management of river resources.

(2) Wherever appropriate in furtherance of this chapter, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior are authorized and encouraged to utilize the following:(A) For activities on federally owned land, section 102301 of title 54 and the Volunteers in the Forest Act of 1972 (16 U.S.C. 558a–558d).22 See References in Text note below.

(B) For activities on all other lands, section 6 33 So in original. Probably should be “section 200305”. of chapter 2003 of title 54 (relating to the development of statewid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance of Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance of Secretary of the Interior The Secretary of the Interior shall encourage and assist the States to consider, in formulating and carrying out their comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plans and proposals for financing assistance for State and local projects submitted pursuant to chapter 2003 of title 54),11 So in original. The closing parenthesis probably should not appear. needs and opportunities for establishing State and local wild, scenic and recreational river areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance of Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, or other Federal agency heads; use of Federal facilities, equipment, etc.; conditions on permits or other authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance of Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, or other Federal agency heads; use of Federal facilities, equipment, etc.; conditions on permits or other authorizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>