<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1284" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1284/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1284/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1284"><akn:num>1284</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing State jurisdiction and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1284. Existing State jurisdiction and responsibilities(a) Fish and wildlifeNothing in this chapter shall affect the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the States with respect to fish and wildlife. Hunting and fishing shall be permitted on lands and waters administered as parts of the system under applicable State and Federal laws and regulations unless, in the case of hunting, those lands or waters are within a national park or monument. The administering Secretary may, however, designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting is permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment and shall issue appropriate regulations after consultation with the wildlife agency of the State or States affected.


(b) Compensation for water rightsThe jurisdiction of the States and the United States over waters of any stream included in a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall be determined by established principles of law. Under the provisions of this chapter, any taking by the United States of a water right which is vested under either State or Federal law at the time such river is included in the national wild and scenic rivers system shall entitle the owner thereof to just compensation. Nothing in this chapter shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to exemption from State water laws.


(c) Reservation of waters for other purposes or in unnecessary quantities prohibitedDesignation of any stream or portion thereof as a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall not be construed as a reservation of the waters of such streams for purposes other than those specified in this chapter, or in quantities greater than necessary to accomplish these purposes.


(d) State jurisdiction over included streamsThe jurisdiction of the States over waters of any stream included in a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall be unaffected by this chapter to t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fish and wildlife Nothing in this chapter shall affect the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the States with respect to fish and wildlife. Hunting and fishing shall be permitted on lands and waters administered as parts of the system under applicable State and Federal laws and regulations unless, in the case of hunting, those lands or waters are within a national park or monument. The administering Secretary may, however, designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting is permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment and shall issue appropriate regulations after consultation with the wildlife agency of the State or States affected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation for water rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation for water rights The jurisdiction of the States and the United States over waters of any stream included in a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall be determined by established principles of law. Under the provisions of this chapter, any taking by the United States of a water right which is vested under either State or Federal law at the time such river is included in the national wild and scenic rivers system shall entitle the owner thereof to just compensation. Nothing in this chapter shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to exemption from State water laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of waters for other purposes or in unnecessary quantities prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reservation of waters for other purposes or in unnecessary quantities prohibited Designation of any stream or portion thereof as a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall not be construed as a reservation of the waters of such streams for purposes other than those specified in this chapter, or in quantities greater than necessary to accomplish these purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State jurisdiction over included streams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State jurisdiction over included streams The jurisdiction of the States over waters of any stream included in a national wild, scenic or recreational river area shall be unaffected by this chapter to the extent that such jurisdiction may be exercised without impairing the purposes of this chapter or its administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate compacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interstate compacts Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to alter, amend, repeal, interpret, modify, or be in conflict with any interstate compact made by any States which contain any portion of the national wild and scenic rivers system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of access to streams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rights of access to streams Nothing in this chapter shall affect existing rights of any State, including the right of access, with respect to the beds of navigable streams, tributaries, or rivers (or segments thereof) located in a national wild, scenic or recreational river area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1284_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements and rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Easements and rights-of-way The Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, may grant easements and rights-of-way upon, over, under, across, or through any component of the national wild and scenic rivers system in accordance with the laws applicable to the national park system and the national forest system, respectively: Provided, That any conditions precedent to granting such easements and rights-of-way shall be related to the policy and purpose of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>