<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1285a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1285a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1285a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1285a"><akn:num>1285a</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease of Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1285a. Lease of Federal lands(a) Authority of Secretary; restrictive covenantsWhere appropriate in the discretion of the Secretary, he may lease federally owned land (or any interest therein) which is within the boundaries of any component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and which has been acquired by the Secretary under this chapter. Such lease shall be subject to such restrictive covenants as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Offer to prior ownerAny land to be leased by the Secretary under this section shall be offered first for such lease to the person who owned such land immediately before its acquisition by the United States.


(Pub. L. 90–542, § 14A, as added Pub. L. 95–625, title VII, § 764, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3534.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1285a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; restrictive covenants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; restrictive covenants Where appropriate in the discretion of the Secretary, he may lease federally owned land (or any interest therein) which is within the boundaries of any component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and which has been acquired by the Secretary under this chapter. Such lease shall be subject to such restrictive covenants as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1285a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offer to prior owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Offer to prior owner Any land to be leased by the Secretary under this section shall be offered first for such lease to the person who owned such land immediately before its acquisition by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>