<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1338a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1338a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1338a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1338a"><akn:num>1338a</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation of captured animals; procedures and prohibitions applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1338a. Transportation of captured animals; procedures and prohibitions applicable
In administering this chapter, the Secretary may use or contract for the use of helicopters or, for the purpose of transporting captured animals, motor vehicles. Such use shall be undertaken only after a public hearing and under the direct supervision of the Secretary or of a duly authorized official or employee of the Department. The provisions of section 47(a) of title 18 shall not be applicable to such use. Such use shall be in accordance with humane procedures prescribed by the Secretary. Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to limit the authority of the Secretary in the management of units of the National Park System, and the Secretary may, without regard either to the provisions of this chapter, or the provisions of section 47(a) of title 18, use motor vehicles, fixed-wing aircraft, or helicopters, or to contract for such use, in furtherance of the management of the National Park System, and section 47(a) of title 18 shall be applicable to such use.
(Pub. L. 92–195, § 9, as added Pub. L. 94–579, title IV, § 404, Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2775; amended Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title VIII, § 803(a), Nov. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 4186.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in last sentence, was in the original “this title”, and was translated as reading “this Act”, meaning the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act which enacted this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because that Act does not contain titles.

Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–333 inserted at end “Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed to limit the authority of the Secretary in the management of units of the National Park System, and the Secretary may, without regard either to the provisions of this chapter, or the provisions of section 47(a) of title 18, use motor vehicles, fixed-wing aircraft, or helicopters, or to contract for such use, in furtherance of the management of the N</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>