<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1371"><akn:num>1371</akn:num><akn:heading>Moratorium on taking and importing marine mammals and marine mammal products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1371. Moratorium on taking and importing marine mammals and marine mammal products(a) Imposition; exceptionsThere shall be a moratorium on the taking and importation of marine mammals and marine mammal products, commencing on the effective date of this chapter, during which time no permit may be issued for the taking of any marine mammal and no marine mammal or marine mammal product may be imported into the United States except in the following cases:(1) Consistent with the provisions of section 1374 of this title, permits may be issued by the Secretary for taking, and importation for purposes of scientific research, public display, photography for educational or commercial purposes, or enhancing the survival or recovery of a species or stock, or for importation of polar bear parts (other than internal organs) taken in sport hunts in Canada. Such permits, except permits issued under section 1374(c)(5) of this title, may be issued if the taking or importation proposed to be made is first reviewed by the Marine Mammal Commission and the Committee of Scientific Advisors on Marine Mammals established under subchapter III. The Commission and Committee shall recommend any proposed taking or importation, other than importation under section 1374(c)(5) of this title, which is consistent with the purposes and policies of section 1361 of this title. If the Secretary issues such a permit for importation, the Secretary shall issue to the importer concerned a certificate to that effect in such form as the Secretary of the Treasury prescribes, and such importation may be made upon presentation of the certificate to the customs officer concerned.

(2) Marine mammals may be taken incidentally in the course of commercial fishing operations and permits may be issued therefor under section 1374 of this title subject to regulations prescribed by the Secretary in accordance with section 1373 of this title, or in lieu of such permits, authorizations may be granted therefor under sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition; exceptions There shall be a moratorium on the taking and importation of marine mammals and marine mammal products, commencing on the effective date of this chapter, during which time no permit may be issued for the taking of any marine mammal and no marine mammal or marine mammal product may be imported into the United States except in the following cases:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions for Alaskan natives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions for Alaskan natives Except as provided in section 1379 of this title, the provisions of this chapter shall not apply with respect to the taking of any marine mammal by any Indian, Aleut, or Eskimo who resides in Alaska and who dwells on the coast of the North Pacific Ocean or the Arctic Ocean if such taking— Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, when, under this chapter, the Secretary determines any species or stock of marine mammal subject to taking by Indians, Aleuts, or Eskimos to be depleted, he may prescribe regulations upon the taking of such marine mammals by any Indian, Aleut, or Eskimo described in this subsection. Such regulations may be established with reference to species or stocks, geographical description of the area included, the season for taking, or any other factors related to the reason for establishing such regulations and consistent with the purposes of this chapter. Such regulations shall be prescribed after notice and hearin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taking in defense of self or others</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Taking in defense of self or others It shall not be a violation of this chapter to take a marine mammal if such taking is imminently necessary in self-defense or to save the life of a person in immediate danger, and such taking is reported to the Secretary within 48 hours. The Secretary may seize and dispose of any carcass.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good Samaritan exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Good Samaritan exemption It shall not be a violation of this chapter to take a marine mammal if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter not to apply to incidental takings by United States citizens employed on foreign vessels outside United States EEZ</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chapter not to apply to incidental takings by United States citizens employed on foreign vessels outside United States EEZ The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to a citizen of the United States who incidentally takes any marine mammal during fishing operations outside the United States exclusive economic zone (as defined in section 1802 of this title) when employed on a foreign fishing vessel of a harvesting nation which is in compliance with the International Dolphin Conservation Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1371_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of actions necessary for national defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption of actions necessary for national defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>