<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1374" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1374/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1374/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1374"><akn:num>1374</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1374. Permits(a) IssuanceThe Secretary may issue permits which authorize the taking or importation of any marine mammal. Permits for the incidental taking of marine mammals in the course of commercial fishing operations may only be issued as specifically provided for in sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 1371(a)(5) or 1416 of this title, or subsection (h) of this section.


(b) Requisite provisionsAny permit issued under this section shall—(1) be consistent with any applicable regulation established by the Secretary under section 1373 of this title, and

(2) specify—(A) the number and kind of animals which are authorized to be taken or imported,

(B) the location and manner (which manner must be determined by the Secretary to be humane) in which they may be taken, or from which they may be imported,

(C) the period during which the permit is valid, and

(D) any other terms or conditions which the Secretary deems appropriate.



In any case in which an application for a permit cites as a reason for the proposed taking the overpopulation of a particular species or population stock, the Secretary shall first consider whether or not it would be more desirable to transplant a number of animals (but not to exceed the number requested for taking in the application) of that species or stock to a location not then inhabited by such species or stock but previously inhabited by such species or stock.

(c) Importation for scientific research, public display, or enhancing survival or recovery of species or stock(1) Any permit issued by the Secretary which authorizes the taking or importation of a marine mammal for purposes of scientific research, public display, or enhancing the survival or recovery of a species or stock shall specify, in addition to the conditions required by subsection (b) of this section, the methods of capture, supervision, care, and transportation which must be observed pursuant to such taking or importation. Any person authorized t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance The Secretary may issue permits which authorize the taking or importation of any marine mammal. Permits for the incidental taking of marine mammals in the course of commercial fishing operations may only be issued as specifically provided for in sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 1371(a)(5) or 1416 of this title, or subsection (h) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisite provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requisite provisions Any permit issued under this section shall— In any case in which an application for a permit cites as a reason for the proposed taking the overpopulation of a particular species or population stock, the Secretary shall first consider whether or not it would be more desirable to transplant a number of animals (but not to exceed the number requested for taking in the application) of that species or stock to a location not then inhabited by such species or stock but previously inhabited by such species or stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation for scientific research, public display, or enhancing survival or recovery of species or stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Importation for scientific research, public display, or enhancing survival or recovery of species or stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application procedures; notice; hearing; review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application procedures; notice; hearing; review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification, suspension, and revocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Modification, suspension, and revocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Possession of permit by issuee or his agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Possession of permit by issuee or his agent Any permit issued under this section must be in the possession of the person to whom it is issued (or an agent of such person) during— A duplicate copy of the issued permit must be physically attached to the container, package, enclosure, or other means of containment, in which the marine mammal is placed for purposes of storage, transit, supervision, or care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fees The Secretary shall establish and charge a reasonable fee for permits issued under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1374_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>General permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) General permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>