<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1377" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1377/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1377/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1377"><akn:num>1377</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1377. Enforcement(a) Utilization of personnelExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Secretary shall enforce the provisions of this subchapter. The Secretary may utilize, by agreement, the personnel, services, and facilities of any other Federal agency for purposes of enforcing this subchapter.


(b) State officers and employeesThe Secretary may also designate officers and employees of any State or of any possession of the United States to enforce the provisions of this subchapter. When so designated, such officers and employees are authorized to function as Federal law enforcement agents for these purposes, but they shall not be held and considered as employees of the United States for the purposes of any laws administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.


(c) Warrants and other process for enforcementThe judges of the district courts of the United States and the United States magistrate judges may, within their respective jurisdictions, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue such warrants or other process, including warrants or other process issued in admiralty proceedings in United States district courts, as may be required for enforcement of this subchapter and any regulations issued thereunder.


(d) Execution of process; arrest; search; seizureAny person authorized by the Secretary to enforce this subchapter may execute any warrant or process issued by any officer or court of competent jurisdiction for the enforcement of this subchapter. Such a person so authorized may, in addition to any other authority conferred by law—(1) with or without warrant or other process, arrest any person committing in his presence or view a violation of this subchapter or the regulations issued thereunder;

(2) with a warrant or other process, or without a warrant if he has reasonable cause to believe that a vessel, other conveyance, or container subject to the jurisdiction of the United States or any person on board is </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1377_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Utilization of personnel Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Secretary shall enforce the provisions of this subchapter. The Secretary may utilize, by agreement, the personnel, services, and facilities of any other Federal agency for purposes of enforcing this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1377_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State officers and employees The Secretary may also designate officers and employees of any State or of any possession of the United States to enforce the provisions of this subchapter. When so designated, such officers and employees are authorized to function as Federal law enforcement agents for these purposes, but they shall not be held and considered as employees of the United States for the purposes of any laws administered by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1377_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warrants and other process for enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Warrants and other process for enforcement The judges of the district courts of the United States and the United States magistrate judges may, within their respective jurisdictions, upon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause, issue such warrants or other process, including warrants or other process issued in admiralty proceedings in United States district courts, as may be required for enforcement of this subchapter and any regulations issued thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1377_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Execution of process; arrest; search; seizure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Execution of process; arrest; search; seizure Any person authorized by the Secretary to enforce this subchapter may execute any warrant or process issued by any officer or court of competent jurisdiction for the enforcement of this subchapter. Such a person so authorized may, in addition to any other authority conferred by law—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1377_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of seized cargo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disposition of seized cargo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>