<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1387"><akn:num>1387</akn:num><akn:heading>Taking of marine mammals incidental to commercial fishing operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1387. Taking of marine mammals incidental to commercial fishing operations(a) In general(1) Effective on April 30, 1994, and except as provided in section 1383a of this title and in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, the provisions of this section shall govern the incidental taking of marine mammals in the course of commercial fishing operations by persons using vessels of the United States or vessels which have valid fishing permits issued by the Secretary in accordance with section 1824(b) of this title. In any event it shall be the immediate goal that the incidental mortality or serious injury of marine mammals occurring in the course of commercial fishing operations be reduced to insignificant levels approaching a zero mortality and serious injury rate within 7 years after April 30, 1994.

(2) In the case of the incidental taking of marine mammals from species or stocks designated under this chapter as depleted on the basis of their listing as threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.), both this section and section 1371(a)(5)(E) of this title shall apply.

(3) Sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “Section”. 1374(h) of this title and subchapter IV, and not this section, shall govern the taking of marine mammals in the course of commercial purse seine fishing for yellowfin tuna in the eastern tropical Pacific Ocean.

(4) This section shall not govern the incidental taking of California sea otters and shall not be deemed to amend or repeal the Act of November 7, 1986 (Public Law 99–625; 100 Stat. 3500).

(5) Except as provided in section 1371(c) of this title, the intentional lethal take of any marine mammal in the course of commercial fishing operations is prohibited.

(6) Sections 1373 and 1374 of this title shall not apply to the incidental taking of marine mammals under the authority of this section.


(b) Zero mortality rate goal(1) Commercial fisheries shall reduce inci</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Zero mortality rate goal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Zero mortality rate goal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration and authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of incidental takes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monitoring of incidental takes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting requirement The owner or operator of a commercial fishing vessel subject to this chapter shall report all incidental mortality and injury of marine mammals in the course of commercial fishing operations to the Secretary by mail or other means acceptable to the Secretary within 48 hours after the end of each fishing trip on a standard postage-paid form to be developed by the Secretary under this section. Such form shall be capable of being readily entered into and usable by an automated or computerized data processing system and shall require the vessel owner or operator to provide the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Take reduction plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Take reduction plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Emergency regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Penalties Except as provided in subsection (c), any person who violates this section shall be subject to the provisions of sections 1375 and 1377 of this title, and may be subject to section 1376 of this title as the Secretary shall establish by regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Assistance The Secretary shall provide assistance to Regional Fishery Management Councils, States, interstate fishery commissions, and Indian tribal organizations in meeting the goal of reducing incidental mortality and serious injury to insignificant levels approaching a zero mortality and serious injury rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1387_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contributions For purposes of carrying out this section, the Secretary may accept, solicit, receive, hold, administer, and use gifts, devises, and bequests.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>