<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1391"><akn:num>1391</akn:num><akn:heading>Near real-time monitoring and mitigation program for large cetaceans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1391. Near real-time monitoring and mitigation program for large cetaceans(a) EstablishmentThe Under Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall design and deploy a cost-effective, efficient, and results-oriented near real-time monitoring and mitigation program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) for threatened or endangered cetaceans.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the Program shall be to reduce the risk to large cetaceans posed by vessel collisions and to minimize other impacts on large cetaceans through the use of near real-time location monitoring and location information.


(c) RequirementsThe Program shall—(1) prioritize species of large cetaceans for which impacts from vessel collisions are of particular concern;

(2) prioritize areas where such impacts are of particular concern;

(3) be capable of detecting and alerting ocean users and enforcement agencies of the probable location of large cetaceans on an actionable real-time basis, including through real-time data whenever possible;

(4) inform sector-specific mitigation protocols to effectively reduce takes (as defined in section 216.3 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations) of large cetaceans;

(5) integrate technology improvements; and

(6) be informed by technologies, monitoring methods, and mitigation protocols developed under the pilot project required under subsection (d).


(d) Pilot project(1) EstablishmentIn carrying out the Program, the Under Secretary shall first establish a pilot monitoring and mitigation project (referred to in this section as the “pilot project”) for North Atlantic right whales for the purposes of informing the Program.


(2) RequirementsIn designing and deploying the pilot project, the Under Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall, using the best available scientific information, identify and ensure coverage of—(A) core foraging habitats; and

(B) importa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Under Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall design and deploy a cost-effective, efficient, and results-oriented near real-time monitoring and mitigation program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) for threatened or endangered cetaceans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the Program shall be to reduce the risk to large cetaceans posed by vessel collisions and to minimize other impacts on large cetaceans through the use of near real-time location monitoring and location information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The Program shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pilot project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mitigation protocols</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mitigation protocols The Under Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Secretary of the Interior, and with input from affected stakeholders, shall develop and deploy mitigation protocols that make use of any monitoring system designed and deployed under this section to direct sector-specific mitigation measures that avoid and significantly reduce risk of serious injury and mortality to North Atlantic right whales.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Access to data The Under Secretary shall provide access to data generated by any monitoring system designed and deployed under this section for purposes of scientific research and evaluation and public awareness and education, including through the Right Whale Sighting Advisory System of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and WhaleMap or other successor public website portals, subject to review for national security considerations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional authority The Under Secretary may enter into and perform such contracts, leases, grants, or cooperative agreements as may be necessary to carry out this section on such terms as the Under Secretary considers appropriate, consistent with the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Savings clause An activity may not be carried out under this section if the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Under Secretary, determines that the activity would negatively impact the defense readiness or the national security of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding From funds otherwise appropriated to the Under Secretary $5,000,000 is authorized to support development, deployment, application, and ongoing maintenance of the Program and to otherwise carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>