<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1421f"><akn:num>1421f</akn:num><akn:heading>National Marine Mammal Tissue Bank and tissue analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1421f. National Marine Mammal Tissue Bank and tissue analysis(a) Tissue Bank(1) In generalThe Secretary shall make provision for the storage, preparation, examination, and archiving of marine mammal tissues. Tissues archived pursuant to this subsection shall be known as the “National Marine Mammal Tissue Bank”.


(2) Guidance for marine mammal tissue collection, preparation, and archivingThe Secretary shall, in consultation with individuals with knowledge and expertise in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, issue guidance, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for marine mammal tissue collection, preparation, archiving, and quality control procedures, regarding—(A) appropriate and uniform methods and standards for those activities to provide confidence in marine mammal tissue samples used for research; and

(B) documentation of procedures used for collecting, preparing, and archiving those samples.


(3) Source of tissueIn addition to tissues taken during marine mammal unusual mortality events, the Tissue Bank shall incorporate tissue samples taken from other sources in the wild, including—(A) samples from marine mammals taken incidental to commercial fishing operations;

(B) samples from marine mammals taken for subsistence purposes;

(C) biopsy samples; and

(D) any other samples properly collected.



(b) Tissue analysisThe Secretary shall, in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission, the Secretary of the Interior, and individuals with knowledge and experience in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, issue guidance, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for analyzing tissue samples (by use of the most effective and advanced diagnostic technologies and tools practicable) as a means to monitor and measure overall health trends in representative species or populations of marine m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tissue Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tissue Bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tissue analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tissue analysis The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission, the Secretary of the Interior, and individuals with knowledge and experience in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, issue guidance, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for analyzing tissue samples (by use of the most effective and advanced diagnostic technologies and tools practicable) as a means to monitor and measure overall health trends in representative species or populations of marine mammals, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data base</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Data base</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, establish criteria, after an opportunity for public review and comment, for public access to— which provide for appropriate uses of the tissues, analyses, and data by qualified scientists, including stranding network participants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>