<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1421a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1421a"><akn:num>1421a</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination; data collection and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1421a. Determination; data collection and dissemination(a) Determination for releaseThe Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Marine Mammal Commission, and individuals with knowledge and experience in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, including stranding network participants, develop objective criteria, after an opportunity for public review and comment, to provide guidance for determining at what point a rehabilitated marine mammal is releasable to the wild.


(b) CollectionThe Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, collect and update, periodically, existing information on—(1) procedures and practices for—(A) rescuing and rehabilitating stranded or entangled marine mammals, including criteria used by stranding network participants, on a species-by-species basis, for determining at what point a marine mammal undergoing rescue and rehabilitation is returnable to the wild; and

(B) collecting, preserving, labeling, and transporting marine mammal tissues for physical, chemical, and biological analyses;


(2) appropriate scientific literature on marine mammal health, disease, and rehabilitation;

(3) strandings and entanglements, including unusual mortality events, which the Secretary shall compile and analyze, by stranding region, to monitor species, numbers, conditions, and causes of illnesses and deaths of stranded marine mammals and entangled marine mammals to allow comparison of the causes of illness and deaths in stranded marine mammals and entangled marine mammals with physical, chemical, and biological environmental parameters; and

(4) other life history and reference level data, including marine mammal tissue analyses.


(c) Information required to be submitted and collected(1) In generalAfter each response to a stranding or entanglement event, the Secretary shall collect (including from any staff of the National Oc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination for release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination for release The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Marine Mammal Commission, and individuals with knowledge and experience in marine science, marine mammal science, marine mammal veterinary and husbandry practices, and marine conservation, including stranding network participants, develop objective criteria, after an opportunity for public review and comment, to provide guidance for determining at what point a rehabilitated marine mammal is releasable to the wild.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collection The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, collect and update, periodically, existing information on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required to be submitted and collected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information required to be submitted and collected</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Standards The Secretary, in consultation with the marine mammal stranding community, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Management policy In collaboration with the regional stranding networks, the Secretary shall develop, and periodically update, a data management and public outreach collaboration policy for stranding or entanglement events.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorship agreements and acknowledgment policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorship agreements and acknowledgment policy The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, shall include authorship agreements or other acknowledgment considerations for use of data by the public, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Savings clause The Secretary shall not require submission of research data that are not described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>