<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1423d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1423d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1423d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1423d"><akn:num>1423d</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission appointments; compensation, travel expenses, and claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1423d. Commission appointments; compensation, travel expenses, and claims(a) Appointment of United States commissioners(1) AppointmentThe United States commissioners on the Commission shall be appointed by the President, in accordance with paragraph 2 of article 8 of the Agreement, after taking into consideration the recommendations of—(A) the Secretary;

(B) the Secretary of State; and

(C) the Alaska Nanuuq Commission.


(2) QualificationsWith respect to the United States commissioners appointed under this subsection, in accordance with paragraph 2 of article 8 of the Agreement—(A) 1 United States commissioner shall be an official of the Federal Government;

(B) 1 United States commissioner shall be a representative of the Native people of Alaska, and, in particular, the Native people for whom polar bears are an integral part of their culture; and

(C) both commissioners shall be knowledgeable of, or have expertise in, polar bears.


(3) Service and termEach United States commissioner shall serve—(A) at the pleasure of the President; and

(B) for an initial 4-year term and such additional terms as the President shall determine.


(4) Vacancies(A) In generalAny individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of any term of office of a United States commissioner shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.


(B) MannerAny vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.




(b) Alternate commissioners(1) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Alaska Nanuuq Commission, shall designate an alternate commissioner for each member of the United States section.


(2) DutiesIn the absence of a United States commissioner, an alternate commissioner may exercise all functions of the United States commissioner at any meetings of the Commission or of the United States section.


(3) ReappointmentAn alternate commissioner—(A) shall be eligible for reappointment by the Pre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of United States commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment of United States commissioners</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternate commissioners</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The members of the United States section may carry out the functions and responsibilities described in article 8 of the Agreement in accordance with this subchapter and the Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Agency designation The United States section shall, for the purpose of title 28 relating to claims against the United States and tort claims procedure, be considered to be a Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>