<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1442" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1442/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1442/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1442"><akn:num>1442</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements, donations, and acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1442. Cooperative agreements, donations, and acquisitions(a) Agreements and grantsThe Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with, or make grants to, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, or other persons to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.


(b) Authorization to solicit donationsThe Secretary may enter into such agreements with any nonprofit organization authorizing the organization to solicit private donations to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.


(c) DonationsThe Secretary may accept donations of funds, property, and services for use in designating and administering national marine sanctuaries under this chapter. Donations accepted under this section shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.


(d) AcquisitionsThe Secretary may acquire by purchase, lease, or exchange, any land, facilities, or other property necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.


(e) Use of resources of other government agenciesThe Secretary may, whenever appropriate, enter into an agreement with a State or other Federal agency to use the personnel, services, or facilities of such agency on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, to assist in carrying out the purposes and policies of this chapter.


(f) Authority to obtain grantsNotwithstanding any other provision of law that prohibits a Federal agency from receiving assistance, the Secretary may apply for, accept, and use grants from other Federal agencies, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, foundations, or other persons, to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 92–532, title III, § 311, as added Pub. L. 100–627, title II, § 203(3), Nov. 7, 1988, 102 Stat. 3215; amended Pub. L. 102–587, title II, § 2109, Nov. 4, 1992, 106 Stat. 5045; Pub. L. 104–283, § 9(d), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3367; Pub. L. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreements and grants The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with, or make grants to, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, or other persons to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to solicit donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization to solicit donations The Secretary may enter into such agreements with any nonprofit organization authorizing the organization to solicit private donations to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Donations The Secretary may accept donations of funds, property, and services for use in designating and administering national marine sanctuaries under this chapter. Donations accepted under this section shall be considered as a gift or bequest to or for the use of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acquisitions The Secretary may acquire by purchase, lease, or exchange, any land, facilities, or other property necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of resources of other government agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of resources of other government agencies The Secretary may, whenever appropriate, enter into an agreement with a State or other Federal agency to use the personnel, services, or facilities of such agency on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, to assist in carrying out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to obtain grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority to obtain grants Notwithstanding any other provision of law that prohibits a Federal agency from receiving assistance, the Secretary may apply for, accept, and use grants from other Federal agencies, States, local governments, regional agencies, interstate agencies, foundations, or other persons, to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>