<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1443" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1443/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1443/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1443"><akn:num>1443</akn:num><akn:heading>Destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1443. Destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources(a) Liability(1) Liability to United StatesAny person who destroys, causes the loss of, or injures any sanctuary resource is liable to the United States for an amount equal to the sum of—(A) the amount of response costs and damages resulting from the destruction, loss, or injury; and

(B) interest on that amount calculated in the manner described under section 2705 of title 33.


(2) Liability in remAny vessel used to destroy, cause the loss of, or injure any sanctuary resource shall be liable in rem to the United States for response costs and damages resulting from such destruction, loss, or injury. The amount of that liability shall constitute a maritime lien on the vessel and may be recovered in an action in rem in any district court of the United States that has jurisdiction over the vessel.


(3) DefensesA person is not liable under this subsection if that person establishes that—(A) the destruction or loss of, or injury to, the sanctuary resource was caused solely by an act of God, an act of war, or an act or omission of a third party, and the person acted with due care;

(B) the destruction, loss, or injury was caused by an activity authorized by Federal or State law; or

(C) the destruction, loss, or injury was negligible.


(4) Limits to liabilityNothing in sections 4281–4289 of the Revised Statutes of the United States or section 30706 of title 46 shall limit the liability of any person under this chapter.



(b) Response actions and damage assessment(1) Response actionsThe Secretary may undertake or authorize all necessary actions to prevent or minimize the destruction or loss of, or injury to, sanctuary resources, or to minimize the imminent risk of such destruction, loss, or injury.


(2) Damage assessmentThe Secretary shall assess damages to sanctuary resources in accordance with section 1432(6) of this title.



(c) Civil actions for response costs and damages(1) The Attorney General, up</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response actions and damage assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Response actions and damage assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions for response costs and damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil actions for response costs and damages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of recovered amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of recovered amounts Response costs and damages recovered by the Secretary under this section shall be retained by the Secretary in the manner provided for in section 9607(f)(1) of title 42, and used as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Statute of limitations An action for response costs or damages under subsection (c) shall be barred unless the complaint is filed within 3 years after the date on which the Secretary completes a damage assessment and restoration plan for the sanctuary resources to which the action relates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>