<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445b"><akn:num>1445b</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing support for national marine sanctuaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445b. Enhancing support for national marine sanctuaries(a) AuthorityThe Secretary may establish a program consisting of—(1) the creation, adoption, and publication in the Federal Register by the Secretary of a symbol for the national marine sanctuary program, or for individual national marine sanctuaries or the System;

(2) the solicitation of persons to be designated as official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries;

(3) the designation of persons by the Secretary as official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual sanctuaries;

(4) the authorization by the Secretary of the manufacture, reproduction, or other use of any symbol published under paragraph (1), including the sale of items bearing such a symbol, by official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries;

(5) the creation, marketing, and selling of products to promote the national marine sanctuary program, and entering into exclusive or nonexclusive agreements authorizing entities to create, market or sell on the Secretary’s behalf;

(6) the solicitation and collection by the Secretary of monetary or in-kind contributions from official sponsors for the manufacture, reproduction or use of the symbols published under paragraph (1);

(7) the retention of any monetary or in-kind contributions collected under paragraphs (5) and (6) by the Secretary; and

(8) the expenditure and use of any monetary and in-kind contributions, without appropriation, by the Secretary to designate and manage national marine sanctuaries.


Monetary and in-kind contributions raised through the sale, marketing, or use of symbols and products related to an individual national marine sanctuary shall be used to support that sanctuary.

(b) Contract authorityThe Secretary may contract with any person for the creation of symbols or the solicitation of official sponsors under subsection (a).


(c) Restric</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Secretary may establish a program consisting of— Monetary and in-kind contributions raised through the sale, marketing, or use of symbols and products related to an individual national marine sanctuary shall be used to support that sanctuary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract authority The Secretary may contract with any person for the creation of symbols or the solicitation of official sponsors under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restrictions The Secretary may restrict the use of the symbols published under subsection (a), and the designation of official sponsors of the national marine sanctuary program or of individual national marine sanctuaries to ensure compatibility with the goals of the national marine sanctuary program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Property of United States Any symbol which is adopted by the Secretary and published in the Federal Register under subsection (a) is deemed to be the property of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited activities It is unlawful for any person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Collaborations The Secretary may authorize the use of a symbol adopted by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1) of this section by any person engaged in a collaborative effort with the Secretary to carry out the purposes and policies of this chapter and to benefit a national marine sanctuary or the System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for non-profit partner organization to solicit sponsors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization for non-profit partner organization to solicit sponsors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>