<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1445a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445a"><akn:num>1445a</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Councils</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445a. Advisory Councils(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary may establish one or more advisory councils (in this section referred to as an “Advisory Council”) to advise and make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the designation and management of national marine sanctuaries. The Advisory Councils shall be exempt from chapter 10 of title 5.


(b) MembershipMembers of the Advisory Councils may be appointed from among—(1) persons employed by Federal or State agencies with expertise in management of natural resources;

(2) members of relevant Regional Fishery Management Councils established under section 1852 of this title; and

(3) representatives of local user groups, conservation and other public interest organizations, scientific organizations, educational organizations, or others interested in the protection and multiple use management of sanctuary resources.


(c) Limits on membershipFor sanctuaries designated after November 4, 1992, the membership of Advisory Councils shall be limited to no more than 15 members.


(d) Staffing and assistanceThe Secretary may make available to an Advisory Council any staff, information, administrative services, or assistance the Secretary determines are reasonably required to enable the Advisory Council to carry out its functions.


(e) Public participation and procedural mattersThe following guidelines apply with respect to the conduct of business meetings of an Advisory Council:(1) Each meeting shall be open to the public, and interested persons shall be permitted to present oral or written statements on items on the agenda.

(2) Emergency meetings may be held at the call of the chairman or presiding officer.

(3) Timely notice of each meeting, including the time, place, and agenda of the meeting, shall be published locally and in the Federal Register, except that in the case of a meeting of an Advisory Council established to provide assistance regarding any individual national marine sanctuary the notice is not required to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary may establish one or more advisory councils (in this section referred to as an “Advisory Council”) to advise and make recommendations to the Secretary regarding the designation and management of national marine sanctuaries. The Advisory Councils shall be exempt from chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership Members of the Advisory Councils may be appointed from among—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits on membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limits on membership For sanctuaries designated after November 4, 1992, the membership of Advisory Councils shall be limited to no more than 15 members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staffing and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Staffing and assistance The Secretary may make available to an Advisory Council any staff, information, administrative services, or assistance the Secretary determines are reasonably required to enable the Advisory Council to carry out its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation and procedural matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public participation and procedural matters The following guidelines apply with respect to the conduct of business meetings of an Advisory Council:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>