<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1451"><akn:num>1451</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1451. Congressional findings
The Congress finds that—(a) There is a national interest in the effective management, beneficial use, protection, and development of the coastal zone.

(b) The coastal zone is rich in a variety of natural, commercial, recreational, ecological, industrial, and esthetic resources of immediate and potential value to the present and future well-being of the Nation.

(c) The increasing and competing demands upon the lands and waters of our coastal zone occasioned by population growth and economic development, including requirements for industry, commerce, residential development, recreation, extraction of mineral resources and fossil fuels, transportation and navigation, waste disposal, and harvesting of fish, shellfish, and other living marine resources, have resulted in the loss of living marine resources, wildlife, nutrient-rich areas, permanent and adverse changes to ecological systems, decreasing open space for public use, and shoreline erosion.

(d) The habitat areas of the coastal zone, and the fish, shellfish, other living marine resources, and wildlife therein, are ecologically fragile and consequently extremely vulnerable to destruction by man’s alterations.

(e) Important ecological, cultural, historic, and esthetic values in the coastal zone which are essential to the well-being of all citizens are being irretrievably damaged or lost.

(f) New and expanding demands for food, energy, minerals, defense needs, recreation, waste disposal, transportation, and industrial activities in the Great Lakes, territorial sea, exclusive economic zone, and Outer Continental Shelf are placing stress on these areas and are creating the need for resolution of serious conflicts among important and competing uses and values in coastal and ocean waters; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.

(g) Special natural and scenic characteristics are being damaged by ill-planned development that threatens these values.

(h) In light of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is a national interest in the effective management, beneficial use, protection, and development of the coastal zone.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The coastal zone is rich in a variety of natural, commercial, recreational, ecological, industrial, and esthetic resources of immediate and potential value to the present and future well-being of the Nation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The increasing and competing demands upon the lands and waters of our coastal zone occasioned by population growth and economic development, including requirements for industry, commerce, residential development, recreation, extraction of mineral resources and fossil fuels, transportation and navigation, waste disposal, and harvesting of fish, shellfish, and other living marine resources, have resulted in the loss of living marine resources, wildlife, nutrient-rich areas, permanent and adverse changes to ecological systems, decreasing open space for public use, and shoreline erosion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The habitat areas of the coastal zone, and the fish, shellfish, other living marine resources, and wildlife therein, are ecologically fragile and consequently extremely vulnerable to destruction by man’s alterations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Important ecological, cultural, historic, and esthetic values in the coastal zone which are essential to the well-being of all citizens are being irretrievably damaged or lost.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) New and expanding demands for food, energy, minerals, defense needs, recreation, waste disposal, transportation, and industrial activities in the Great Lakes, territorial sea, exclusive economic zone, and Outer Continental Shelf are placing stress on these areas and are creating the need for resolution of serious conflicts among important and competing uses and values in coastal and ocean waters; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special natural and scenic characteristics are being damaged by ill-planned development that threatens these values.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In light of competing demands and the urgent need to protect and to give high priority to natural systems in the coastal zone, present state and local institutional arrangements for planning and regulating land and water uses in such areas are inadequate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The key to more effective protection and use of the land and water resources of the coastal zone is to encourage the states to exercise their full authority over the lands and waters in the coastal zone by assisting the states, in cooperation with Federal and local governments and other vitally affected interests, in developing land and water use programs for the coastal zone, including unified policies, criteria, standards, methods, and processes for dealing with land and water use decisions of more than local significance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The national objective of attaining a greater degree of energy self-sufficiency would be advanced by providing Federal financial assistance to meet state and local needs resulting from new or expanded energy activity in or affecting the coastal zone.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>