<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1456" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1456/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1456/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1456"><akn:num>1456</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1456. Coordination and cooperation(a) Federal agenciesIn carrying out his functions and responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary shall consult with, cooperate with, and, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate his activities with other interested Federal agencies.


(b) Adequate consideration of views of Federal agenciesThe Secretary shall not approve the management program submitted by a state pursuant to section 1455 of this title unless the views of Federal agencies principally affected by such program have been adequately considered.


(c) Consistency of Federal activities with State management programs; Presidential exemption; certification(1)(A) Each Federal agency activity within or outside the coastal zone that affects any land or water use or natural resource of the coastal zone shall be carried out in a manner which is consistent to the maximum extent practicable with the enforceable policies of approved State management programs. A Federal agency activity shall be subject to this paragraph unless it is subject to paragraph (2) or (3).

(B) After any final judgment, decree, or order of any Federal court that is appealable under section 1291 or 1292 of title 28, or under any other applicable provision of Federal law, that a specific Federal agency activity is not in compliance with subparagraph (A), and certification by the Secretary that mediation under subsection (h) is not likely to result in such compliance, the President may, upon written request from the Secretary, exempt from compliance those elements of the Federal agency activity that are found by the Federal court to be inconsistent with an approved State program, if the President determines that the activity is in the paramount interest of the United States. No such exemption shall be granted on the basis of a lack of appropriations unless the President has specifically requested such appropriations as part of the budgetary process, and the Congress has failed to make available </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal agencies In carrying out his functions and responsibilities under this chapter, the Secretary shall consult with, cooperate with, and, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate his activities with other interested Federal agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adequate consideration of views of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adequate consideration of views of Federal agencies The Secretary shall not approve the management program submitted by a state pursuant to section 1455 of this title unless the views of Federal agencies principally affected by such program have been adequately considered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency of Federal activities with State management programs; Presidential exemption; certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consistency of Federal activities with State management programs; Presidential exemption; certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of local governments for Federal assistance; relationship of activities with approved management programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application of local governments for Federal assistance; relationship of activities with approved management programs State and local governments submitting applications for Federal assistance under other Federal programs, in or outside of the coastal zone, affecting any land or water use of natural resource of the coastal zone shall indicate the views of the appropriate state or local agency as to the relationship of such activities to the approved management program for the coastal zone. Such applications shall be submitted and coordinated in accordance with the provisions of section 6506 of title 31. Federal agencies shall not approve proposed projects that are inconsistent with the enforceable policies of a coastal state’s management program, except upon a finding by the Secretary that such project is consistent with the purposes of this chapter or necessary in the interest of national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction with other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction with other laws Nothing in this chapter shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction with existing requirements of water and air pollution programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction with existing requirements of water and air pollution programs Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, nothing in this chapter shall in any way affect any requirement (1) established by the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.], or the Clean Air Act, as amended [42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.], or (2) established by the Federal Government or by any state or local government pursuant to such Acts. Such requirements shall be incorporated in any program developed pursuant to this chapter and shall be the water pollution control and air pollution control requirements applicable to such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrence with programs which affect inland areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Concurrence with programs which affect inland areas When any state’s coastal zone management program, submitted for approval or proposed for modification pursuant to section 1455 of this title, includes requirements as to shorelands which also would be subject to any Federally supported national land use program which may be hereafter enacted, the Secretary, prior to approving such program, shall obtain the concurrence of the Secretary of the Interior, or such other Federal official as may be designated to administer the national land use program, with respect to that portion of the coastal zone management program affecting such inland areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mediation of disagreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Mediation of disagreements In case of serious disagreement between any Federal agency and a coastal state— the Secretary, with the cooperation of the Executive Office of the President, shall seek to mediate the differences involved in such disagreement. The process of such mediation shall, with respect to any disagreement described in paragraph (2), include public hearings which shall be conducted in the local area concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application fee for appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application fee for appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>