<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1467" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1467/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1467/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1467"><akn:num>1467</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Digital Coast</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1467. Establishment of the Digital Coast(a) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program for the provision of an enabling platform that integrates geospatial data, decision-support tools, training, and best practices to address coastal management issues and needs. Under the program, the Secretary shall strive to enhance resilient communities, ecosystem values, and coastal economic growth and development by helping communities address their issues, needs, and challenges through cost-effective and participatory solutions.


(2) DesignationThe program established under paragraph (1) shall be known as the “Digital Coast” (in this section referred to as the “program”).



(b) Program requirementsIn carrying out the program, the Secretary shall ensure that the program provides data integration, tool development, training, documentation, dissemination, and archive by—(1) making data and resulting integrated products developed under this section readily accessible via the Digital Coast internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the GeoPlatform.gov and data.gov internet websites, and such other information distribution technologies as the Secretary considers appropriate;

(2) developing decision-support tools that use and display resulting integrated data and provide training on use of such tools;

(3) documenting such data to Federal Geographic Data Committee standards; and

(4) archiving all raw data acquired under this Act at the appropriate National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration data center or such other Federal data center as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(c) CoordinationThe Secretary shall coordinate the activities carried out under the program to optimize data collection, sharing, and integration, and to minimize duplication by—(1) consulting with coastal managers and decision makers concerning coastal issues, and sharing information and best practices, as the Secretary considers appropriate, with</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program requirements In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall ensure that the program provides data integration, tool development, training, documentation, dissemination, and archive by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination The Secretary shall coordinate the activities carried out under the program to optimize data collection, sharing, and integration, and to minimize duplication by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filling needs and gaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filling needs and gaps In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial agreements and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Financial agreements and contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ocean economy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Ocean economy The Secretary may establish publically available tools that track ocean and Great Lakes economy data for each coastal State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $4,000,000 for each fiscal year 2021 through 2025 to carry out the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>