<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1468" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1468/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1468/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1468"><akn:num>1468</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Ocean Partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1468. Regional Ocean Partnerships(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.


(2) Coastal StateThe term “coastal State” has the meaning given the term “Coastal state” 11 So in original. Probably should be “ ‘coastal state’ ” as it appears in section 1453 of this title. in section 1453 of this title.


(3) Indian TribeThe term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304 of title 25.


(4) Regional Ocean PartnershipThe term “Regional Ocean Partnership” means a Regional Ocean Partnership designated under subsection (b).



(b) Regional Ocean Partnerships(1) In generalA coastal State or Indian Tribe may form a partnership with—(A) a coastal State that shares a common ocean or coastal area with the coastal State, without regard to whether the coastal States are contiguous; and

(B) States—(i) that share a common ocean, coastal area, or watershed with the coastal State, without regard to whether the coastal States are contiguous; or

(ii) that would contribute to the priorities of the partnership; and


(C) Indian Tribes.


(2) RequirementsA partnership formed under paragraph (1) may apply for designation as a Regional Ocean Partnership in such time and manner as determined appropriate by the Secretary if the partnership—(A) is established to coordinate the management of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources among the members of the partnership;

(B) focuses on the environmental issues affecting the ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes areas of the members participating in the partnership;

(C) complements existing coastal and ocean management efforts of States and Indian Tribes on an interstate scale, focusing on shared regional priorities;

(D) does not have a regulatory function; and

(E) is not duplicative of an existing Regional Ocean Partnership designated under paragraph (3), as determined by the Secretary.


(3) Designation of certain e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Ocean Partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regional Ocean Partnerships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing bodies of Regional Ocean Partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Governing bodies of Regional Ocean Partnerships A Regional Ocean Partnership shall have a governing body that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions A Regional Ocean Partnership may perform the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination, consultation, and engagement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination, consultation, and engagement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grants and contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Availability of Federal funds In addition to amounts made available to the Regional Ocean Partnerships by the Administrator under this section, the head of any other Federal agency may provide grants to, enter into contracts with, or otherwise provide funding to such partnerships, subject to availability of appropriations for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorities Nothing in this section establishes any new legal or regulatory authority of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration or of the Regional Ocean Partnerships, other than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>