<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_152"><akn:num>152</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional land withdrawn; payment; management and control; regulations; sale of improvements; penal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 152. Additional land withdrawn; payment; management and control; regulations; sale of improvements; penalties; town lots
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to withhold from sale or other disposition the irregular tract of land containing seventy-eight and sixty-eight one-hundredths acres, more or less, lying in the northwest quarter of section 2 and the northeast quarter of section 3, township 1 south, range 3 east, and being within the exterior boundaries of the proposed town site of Sulphur, in the Chickasaw Nation, Indian Territory, and excluded from said town site by order of the Secretary of the Interior, of October 20, 1903, and also to withdraw and withhold from disposition the tract of land within the exterior boundaries of said proposed town site, lying south of and adjacent to the tract above mentioned, containing in the aggregate one hundred and thirty-eight acres, more or less, and mentioned in the report of Gerard H. Matthes, of December 27, 1903, to F. H. Newell, chief engineer United States Geological Survey, and shown upon the map accompanying said report by a yellow line.
The land reserved shall be paid for by the United States at the rate of $60 per acre and in the same manner as the land acquired in accordance with the provisions of section 151 of this title and shall be a part of the reservation established at the village of Sulphur, subject to all the provisions of said section 151, respecting the care, control, direction, use, and occupancy thereof as if they had been included in the original segregation. The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in the absence of other provisions for the care and management thereof, to designate an officer or employee of his department to take charge of the land, acquired under this section and section 151 of this title, and to enforce rules and regulations for the control and use thereof, and of the waters of the springs and creeks within the reservation. The Secretary of the Interi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>