<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1534"><akn:num>1534</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1534. Land acquisition(a) Implementation of conservation program; authorization of Secretary and Secretary of AgricultureThe Secretary, and the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to the National Forest System, shall establish and implement a program to conserve fish, wildlife, and plants, including those which are listed as endangered species or threatened species pursuant to section 1533 of this title. To carry out such a program, the appropriate Secretary—(1) shall utilize the land acquisition and other authority under the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956, as amended [16 U.S.C. 742a et seq.], the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act, as amended [16 U.S.C. 661 et seq.], and the Migratory Bird Conservation Act [16 U.S.C. 715 et seq.], as appropriate; and

(2) is authorized to acquire by purchase, donation, or otherwise, lands, waters, or interest therein, and such authority shall be in addition to any other land acquisition authority vested in him.


(b) Availability of funds for acquisition of lands, waters, etc.Funds made available pursuant to chapter 2003 of title 54 may be used for the purpose of acquiring lands, waters, or interests therein under subsection (a) of this section.


(Pub. L. 93–205, § 5, Dec. 28, 1973, 87 Stat. 889; Pub. L. 95–632, § 12, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3766; Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(32), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3267.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is act Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, 70 Stat. 119, which is classified generally to sections 742a to 742d and 742e to 742j–2 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 742a of this title and Tables.
The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is act Mar. 10, 1934, ch. 55, 48 Stat. 401, which is classified generally to sections 661 to 666c–1 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of conservation program; authorization of Secretary and Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation of conservation program; authorization of Secretary and Secretary of Agriculture The Secretary, and the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to the National Forest System, shall establish and implement a program to conserve fish, wildlife, and plants, including those which are listed as endangered species or threatened species pursuant to section 1533 of this title. To carry out such a program, the appropriate Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds for acquisition of lands, waters, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of funds for acquisition of lands, waters, etc. Funds made available pursuant to chapter 2003 of title 54 may be used for the purpose of acquiring lands, waters, or interests therein under subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>