<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1537a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1537a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1537a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1537a"><akn:num>1537a</akn:num><akn:heading>Convention implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1537a. Convention implementation(a) Management Authority and Scientific AuthorityThe Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) is designated as the Management Authority and the Scientific Authority for purposes of the Convention and the respective functions of each such Authority shall be carried out through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.


(b) Management Authority functionsThe Secretary shall do all things necessary and appropriate to carry out the functions of the Management Authority under the Convention.


(c) Scientific Authority functions; determinations(1) The Secretary shall do all things necessary and appropriate to carry out the functions of the Scientific Authority under the Convention.

(2) The Secretary shall base the determinations and advice given by him under Article IV of the Convention with respect to wildlife upon the best available biological information derived from professionally accepted wildlife management practices; but is not required to make, or require any State to make, estimates of population size in making such determinations or giving such advice.


(d) Reservations by the United States under ConventionIf the United States votes against including any species in Appendix I or II of the Convention and does not enter a reservation pursuant to paragraph (3) of Article XV of the Convention with respect to that species, the Secretary of State, before the 90th day after the last day on which such a reservation could be entered, shall submit to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate, a written report setting forth the reasons why such a reservation was not entered.


(e) Wildlife preservation in Western Hemisphere(1) The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “Secretary”), in cooperation with the Secretary of State, shall act on behalf</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management Authority and Scientific Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Management Authority and Scientific Authority The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) is designated as the Management Authority and the Scientific Authority for purposes of the Convention and the respective functions of each such Authority shall be carried out through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management Authority functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management Authority functions The Secretary shall do all things necessary and appropriate to carry out the functions of the Management Authority under the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific Authority functions; determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scientific Authority functions; determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservations by the United States under Convention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reservations by the United States under Convention If the United States votes against including any species in Appendix I or II of the Convention and does not enter a reservation pursuant to paragraph (3) of Article XV of the Convention with respect to that species, the Secretary of State, before the 90th day after the last day on which such a reservation could be entered, shall submit to the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate, a written report setting forth the reasons why such a reservation was not entered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wildlife preservation in Western Hemisphere</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Wildlife preservation in Western Hemisphere</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>