<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/157d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/157d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/157d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_157d"><akn:num>157d</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional boundary revision; acquisition of lands and interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 157d. Additional boundary revision; acquisition of lands and interests
The boundaries of Big Bend National Park, established by the Act of June 20, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 156), are hereby revised to include the lands and interests therein, together with all improvements thereon, within the area comprising approximately sixty-seven thousand one hundred and twenty-five acres as generally depicted on the map entitled “Harte Ranch Addition, Big Bend National Park”, numbered 155/80,044 and dated September 1987. Such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire lands and interests therein, together with all improvements thereon, within the addition described in such map by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.
(Pub. L. 100–201, Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1328.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAct of June 20, 1935, referred to in text, is act June 30, 1935, ch. 283, 49 Stat. 393, which is classified to sections 156, 157, and 158 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>