<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1674a"><akn:num>1674a</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1674a. Expanded programs(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the State cooperative extension services, and in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, school boards, and universities, shall expand forestry and natural resources education programs conducted under this subchapter for private forest owners and managers, public officials, youth, and the general public, and shall include guidelines for the transfer of technology.


(b) Activities(1) In generalIn expanding the programs conducted under this subchapter, the Secretary shall ensure that activities are undertaken to promote policies and practices that enhance the health, vitality, productivity, economic value, and environmental attributes of the forest lands of the United States.


(2) TypesThe activities referred to in paragraph (1) shall include—(A) demonstrating and teaching landowners and forest managers the concepts of multiple-use and sustainable natural resource management;

(B) conducting comprehensive environmental education programs that assist citizens to participate in environmentally positive activities such as tree planting, recycling, erosion prevention, and waste management; and

(C) educational programs and materials that will improve the capacity of schools, local governments and resource agencies to deliver forestry and natural resources information to young people, environmentally concerned citizens, and action groups.



(Pub. L. 95–306, § 5A, as added Pub. L. 101–624, title XII, § 1251(a), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3552; amended Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(34), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1270; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, § 7511(c)(34), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2032.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Amendments2008—Subsec. (a). P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the State cooperative extension services, and in consultation with State foresters or equivalent State officials, school boards, and universities, shall expand forestry and natural resources education programs conducted under this subchapter for private forest owners and managers, public officials, youth, and the general public, and shall include guidelines for the transfer of technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>