<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1674/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1674"><akn:num>1674</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable Resources Extension Program plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1674. Renewable Resources Extension Program plan(a) Preparation and submission to Congress; purposes; contentsThe Secretary shall prepare a five-year plan for implementing this subchapter, which is to be called the “Renewable Resources Extension Program” and shall submit such plan to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate no later than the last day of the first half of the fiscal year ending September 30, 1980, and the last day of the first half of each fifth fiscal year thereafter. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall provide national emphasis and direction as well as guidance to State directors and administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in the development of their respective State renewable resources extension programs, which are to be appropriate in terms of the conditions, needs, and opportunities in each State. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall contain, but not be limited to, brief outlines of general extension programs for fish and wildlife management (for both game and nongame species), range management, timber management (including brief outlines of general extension programs for timber utilization, timber harvesting, timber marketing, wood utilization, and wood products marketing), and watershed management (giving special attention to water quality protection), as well as brief outlines of general extension programs for recognition and enhancement of forest- and range-based outdoor recreation opportunities, for urban and community forestry activities, and for planting and management of trees and shrubs in shelterbelts, and give special attention to water quality protection and natural resource and environmental education for landowners and managers, public officials, and the public.


(b) Considerations governing preparationIn preparing the Renewable Resources Extension Program, the Secretary shall take i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and submission to Congress; purposes; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation and submission to Congress; purposes; contents The Secretary shall prepare a five-year plan for implementing this subchapter, which is to be called the “Renewable Resources Extension Program” and shall submit such plan to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate no later than the last day of the first half of the fiscal year ending September 30, 1980, and the last day of the first half of each fifth fiscal year thereafter. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall provide national emphasis and direction as well as guidance to State directors and administrative heads of extension for eligible colleges and universities in the development of their respective State renewable resources extension programs, which are to be appropriate in terms of the conditions, needs, and opportunities in each State. The Renewable Resources Extension Program shall contain, but not be limited to, </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations governing preparation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Considerations governing preparation In preparing the Renewable Resources Extension Program, the Secretary shall take into account the respective capabilities of private forests and rangelands for yielding renewable resources and the relative needs for such resources identified in the periodic Renewable Resource Assessment provided for in section 1601 of this title and the periodic appraisal of land and water resources provided for in section 2004 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1674_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of activities and evaluation of progress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of activities and evaluation of progress To assist Congress and the public in evaluating the Renewable Resources Extension Program, the program shall include a review of activities undertaken in response to the preceding five-year plan and an evaluation of the progress made toward accomplishing the goals and objectives set forth in such preceding plan. Such review and evaluation shall be displayed in the program, for the Nation as a whole, and for each State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>