<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1702"><akn:num>1702</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1702. Establishment(a) Age of participantsTo carry out the purposes of this subchapter, there is established in the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture a Youth Conservation Corps (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Corps”). The Corps shall consist of young men and women who are permanent residents of the United States, its territories, possessions, trust territories, or Commonwealth of Puerto Rico who have attained age fifteen but have not attained age nineteen, and whom the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture may employ without regard to the civil service or classification laws, rules, or regulations, for the purpose of developing, preserving, or maintaining the lands and waters of the United States.


(b) Equal employment opportunity and employment; termThe Corps shall be open to youth from all parts of the country of both sexes and youth of all social, economic, and racial classifications with all Corps members receiving compensation consistent with work accomplished, and with no person being employed as a member of the Corps for a term in excess of ninety days during any single year.


(Pub. L. 91–378, title I, § 102, formerly § 2, Aug. 13, 1970, 84 Stat. 795; Pub. L. 92–597, Oct. 27, 1972, 86 Stat. 1319; Pub. L. 93–408, Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1066; renumbered title I, § 102, and amended Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 105(1)–(4), Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 848.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1993—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–82, § 105(2), (4), substituted “subchapter” for “chapter” and inserted “in this subchapter” after “(hereinafter”.
1974—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 93–408 extended eligibility to permanent residents of Puerto Rico, removed the restriction that employment be in the summer months only, and substituted “waters of the United States” for “waters of the United States under his jurisdiction”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 93–408 substituted “from all parts of the country of both sexes and youth of all social, ec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Age of participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Age of participants To carry out the purposes of this subchapter, there is established in the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture a Youth Conservation Corps (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Corps”). The Corps shall consist of young men and women who are permanent residents of the United States, its territories, possessions, trust territories, or Commonwealth of Puerto Rico who have attained age fifteen but have not attained age nineteen, and whom the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture may employ without regard to the civil service or classification laws, rules, or regulations, for the purpose of developing, preserving, or maintaining the lands and waters of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal employment opportunity and employment; term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Equal employment opportunity and employment; term The Corps shall be open to youth from all parts of the country of both sexes and youth of all social, economic, and racial classifications with all Corps members receiving compensation consistent with work accomplished, and with no person being employed as a member of the Corps for a term in excess of ninety days during any single year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>