<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1703"><akn:num>1703</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions of Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1703. Duties and functions of Secretary of the Interior and Secretary of Agriculture(a) Programs and projects; conditions of employment; regulations; use of facilities by educational institutionsIn carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall—(1) determine the areas under their administrative jurisdictions which are appropriate for carrying out the programs using employees of the Corps;

(2) determine with other Federal agencies the areas under the administrative jurisdiction of these agencies which are appropriate for carrying out programs using members of the Corps, and determine and select appropriate work and education programs and projects for participation by members of the Corps;

(3) determine the rates of pay, hours, and other conditions of employment in the Corps, except that all members of the Corps shall not be deemed to be Federal employees other than for the purpose of chapter 171 of title 28, and chapter 81 of title 5.11 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.

(4) provide for such transportation, lodging, subsistence, and other services and equipment as they may deem necessary or appropriate for the needs of members of the Corps in their duties;

(5) promulgate regulation 22 So in original. Probably should be “regulations”. to insure the safety, health, and welfare of the Corps members; and

(6) provide to the extent possible, that permanent or semipermanent facilities used as Corps camps be made available to local schools, school districts, State junior colleges and universities, and other education institutions for use as environmental/ecological education camps during periods of nonuse by the Corps program.


Costs for operations maintenance, and staffing of Corps camp facilities during periods of use by non-Corps programs as well as any liability for personal injury or property damage stemming from such use shall be the responsibility of the entity or organization using th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs and projects; conditions of employment; regulations; use of facilities by educational institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Programs and projects; conditions of employment; regulations; use of facilities by educational institutions In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall— Costs for operations maintenance, and staffing of Corps camp facilities during periods of use by non-Corps programs as well as any liability for personal injury or property damage stemming from such use shall be the responsibility of the entity or organization using the facility and shall not be a responsibility of the Secretaries or the Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of unoccupied Federal facilities and equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of unoccupied Federal facilities and equipment Existing but unoccupied Federal facilities and surplus or unused equipment (or both), of all types including military facilities and equipment, shall be utilized for the purposes of the Corps, where appropriate and with the approval of the Federal agency involved. To minimize transportation costs, Corps members shall be employed on conservation projects as near to their places of residence as is feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for the operation of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracts for the operation of projects The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture may contract with any public agency or organization or any private nonprofit agency or organization which has been in existence for at least five years for the operation of any Youth Conservation Corps project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>