<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704"><akn:num>1704</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704. Grants to States(a) Projects for preservation of non-Federal public lands and waters; “States” definedThe Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly establish a program under which grants shall be made to States to assist them in meeting the cost of projects for the employment of young men and women to develop, preserve, and maintain non-Federal public lands and waters within the States. For purposes of this section, the term “States” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and American Samoa.


(b) Application requirements for grants; approval by Secretaries(1) No grant may be made under this section unless an application therefor has been submitted to, and approved by, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture. Such application shall be in such form, and submitted in such manner, as the Secretaries shall jointly by regulation prescribe, and shall contain—(A) assurances satisfactory to the Secretaries that individuals employed under the project for which the application is submitted shall (i) have attained the age of fifteen but not attained the age of nineteen, (ii) be permanent residents of the United States or its territories, possessions, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, (iii) be employed without regard to the personnel laws, rules, and regulations applicable to full-time employees of the applicant, (iv) be employed for a period of not more than ninety days in any calendar year, and (v) be employed without regard to their sex or social, economic, or racial classification; and

(B) such other information as the Secretaries may jointly by regulation prescribe.


(2) The Secretaries may approve applications which they determine (A) to meet the requirements of paragraph (1), and (B) are for projects which will further the development, preservation, or maintenance of non-Federal public lands or wat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects for preservation of non-Federal public lands and waters; “States” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Projects for preservation of non-Federal public lands and waters; “States” defined The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly establish a program under which grants shall be made to States to assist them in meeting the cost of projects for the employment of young men and women to develop, preserve, and maintain non-Federal public lands and waters within the States. For purposes of this section, the term “States” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and American Samoa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements for grants; approval by Secretaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application requirements for grants; approval by Secretaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on the amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on the amount of grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appropriation percentage Thirty per centum of the sums appropriated under section 1706 of this title for any fiscal year shall be made available for grants under this section for such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>