<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1723" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1723/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1723/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1723"><akn:num>1723</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Lands Corps program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1723. Public Lands Corps program(a) Establishment of Public Lands Corps(1) In generalThere is established in the Department of the Interior, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Commerce a corps, to be known as the “Public Lands Corps”.


(2) No effect on other agenciesNothing in this subsection precludes the establishment of a public lands corps by the head of a Federal department or agency other than a department described in paragraph (1), in accordance with this subchapter.



(b) ParticipantsThe Corps shall consist of individuals between the ages of 16 and 30, inclusive, and veterans age 35 or younger who are enrolled as participants in the Corps by the Secretary. To be eligible for enrollment in the Corps, an individual shall satisfy the criteria specified in paragraphs (1), (2), (4), and (5) of section 12591(a) of title 42. The Secretary may enroll such individuals in the Corps without regard to the civil service and classification laws, rules, or regulations of the United States. The Secretary may establish a preference for the enrollment in the Corps of individuals who are economically, physically, or educationally disadvantaged.


(c) Qualified youth or conservation corps(1) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with any qualified youth or conservation corps to perform appropriate conservation projects referred to in subsection (d).


(2) Preference(A) In generalFor purposes of entering into contracts and cooperative agreements under paragraph (1), the Secretary may give preference to qualified youth or conservation corps located in a specific area that have a substantial portion of members who are economically, physically, or educationally disadvantaged to carry out projects within the area.


(B) Priority projectsIn carrying out priority projects in a specific area, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, give preference to qualified youth or conservation corps located i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Public Lands Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Public Lands Corps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participants The Corps shall consist of individuals between the ages of 16 and 30, inclusive, and veterans age 35 or younger who are enrolled as participants in the Corps by the Secretary. To be eligible for enrollment in the Corps, an individual shall satisfy the criteria specified in paragraphs (1), (2), (4), and (5) of section 12591(a) of title 42. The Secretary may enroll such individuals in the Corps without regard to the civil service and classification laws, rules, or regulations of the United States. The Secretary may establish a preference for the enrollment in the Corps of individuals who are economically, physically, or educationally disadvantaged.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified youth or conservation corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified youth or conservation corps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects to be carried out</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects to be carried out</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for certain projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preference for certain projects In selecting appropriate conservation projects to be carried out under this subchapter, the Secretary shall give preference to those projects which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consistency Each appropriate conservation project carried out under this subchapter on eligible service lands shall be consistent with the provisions of law and policies relating to the management and administration of such lands, with all other applicable provisions of law, and with all management, operational, and other plans and documents which govern the administration of the area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect Nothing in this section authorizes the use of the Public Lands Corps for projects on or impacting real property owned by, operated by, or within the custody, control, or administrative jurisdiction of the Administrator of General Services without the express permission of the Administrator of General Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>