<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1821" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1821/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1821/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1821"><akn:num>1821</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1821. Foreign fishing(a) In generalAfter February 28, 1977, no foreign fishing is authorized within the exclusive economic zone, or for anadromous species or Continental Shelf fishery resources beyond the exclusive economic zone, unless such foreign fishing—(1) is authorized under subsections (b) or (c) or section 1824(e) of this title, or under a permit issued under section 1824(d) of this title;

(2) is not prohibited under subsection (f); and

(3) is conducted under, and in accordance with, a valid and applicable permit issued pursuant to section 1824 of this title.


(b) Existing international fishery agreementsForeign fishing described in subsection (a) may be conducted pursuant to an international fishery agreement (subject to the provisions of section 1822(b) or (c) of this title), if such agreement—(1) was in effect on April 13, 1976; and

(2) has not expired, been renegotiated, or otherwise ceased to be of force and effect with respect to the United States.


(c) Governing international fishery agreementsForeign fishing described in subsection (a) may be conducted pursuant to an international fishery agreement (other than a treaty) which meets the requirements of this subsection if such agreement becomes effective after application of section 1823 of this title. Any such international fishery agreement shall hereafter in this chapter be referred to as a “governing international fishery agreement”. Each governing international fishery agreement shall acknowledge the exclusive fishery management authority of the United States, as set forth in this chapter. It is the sense of the Congress that each such agreement shall include a binding commitment, on the part of such foreign nation and its fishing vessels, to comply with the following terms and conditions:(1) The foreign nation, and the owner or operator of any fishing vessel fishing pursuant to such agreement, will abide by all regulations promulgated by the Secretary pursuant to this chapter, including an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general After February 28, 1977, no foreign fishing is authorized within the exclusive economic zone, or for anadromous species or Continental Shelf fishery resources beyond the exclusive economic zone, unless such foreign fishing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing international fishery agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Existing international fishery agreements Foreign fishing described in subsection (a) may be conducted pursuant to an international fishery agreement (subject to the provisions of section 1822(b) or (c) of this title), if such agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing international fishery agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Governing international fishery agreements Foreign fishing described in subsection (a) may be conducted pursuant to an international fishery agreement (other than a treaty) which meets the requirements of this subsection if such agreement becomes effective after application of section 1823 of this title. Any such international fishery agreement shall hereafter in this chapter be referred to as a “governing international fishery agreement”. Each governing international fishery agreement shall acknowledge the exclusive fishery management authority of the United States, as set forth in this chapter. It is the sense of the Congress that each such agreement shall include a binding commitment, on the part of such foreign nation and its fishing vessels, to comply with the following terms and conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Total allowable level of foreign fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Total allowable level of foreign fishing The total allowable level of foreign fishing, if any, with respect to any fishery subject to the exclusive fishery management authority of the United States, is that portion of the optimum yield of such fishery which cannot, or will not, be harvested by vessels of the United States, as determined in accordance with this chapter. Allocations of the total allowable level of foreign fishing are discretionary, except that the total allowable level shall be zero for fisheries determined by the Secretary to have adequate or excess domestic harvest capacity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of allowable level</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocation of allowable level</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reciprocity Foreign fishing shall not be authorized for the fishing vessels of any foreign nation unless such nation satisfies the Secretary and the Secretary of State that such nation extends substantially the same fishing privileges to fishing vessels of the United States, if any, as the United States extends to foreign fishing vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary fishery management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preliminary fishery management plans The Secretary, when notified by the Secretary of State that any foreign nation has submitted an application under section 1824(b) of this title shall prepare a preliminary fishery management plan for any fishery covered by such application if the Secretary determines that no fishery management plan for that fishery will be prepared and implemented, pursuant to subchapter IV, before March 1, 1977. To the extent practicable, each such plan— Each preliminary fishery management plan shall be in effect with respect to foreign fishing for which permits have been issued until a fishery management plan is prepared and implemented, pursuant to subchapter IV, with respect to such fishery. The Secretary may, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, also prepare and promulgate interim regulations with respect to any such preliminary plan. Such regulations shall be in effect until regulations implementing the applicable fishery management plan are promulga</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full observer coverage program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Full observer coverage program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreational fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Recreational fishing Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, foreign fishing vessels which are not operated for profit may engage in recreational fishing within the exclusive economic zone and the waters within the boundaries of a State subject to obtaining such permits, paying such reasonable fees, and complying with such conditions and restrictions as the Secretary and the Governor of the State (or his designee) shall impose as being necessary or appropriate to insure that the fishing activity of such foreign vessels within such zone or waters, respectively, is consistent with all applicable Federal and State laws and any applicable fishery management plan implemented under section 1854 of this title. The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating in formulating the conditions and restrictions to be applied by the Secretary under the authority of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>