<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1824" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1824/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1824/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1824"><akn:num>1824</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits for foreign fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1824. Permits for foreign fishing(a) In generalAfter February 28, 1977, no foreign fishing vessel shall engage in fishing within the exclusive economic zone, or for anadromous species or Continental Shelf fishery resources beyond such zone, unless such vessel has on board a valid permit issued under this section for such vessel.


(b) Applications and permits under governing international fishery agreements(1) Eligibility; durationEach foreign nation with which the United States has entered into a governing international fishery agreement shall submit an application to the Secretary of State each year for a permit for each of its fishing vessels that wishes to engage in fishing described in subsection (a). No permit issued under this section may be valid for longer than a year; and section 558(c) of title 5 does not apply to the renewal of any such permit.


(2) FormsThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall prescribe the forms for permit applications submitted under this subsection and for permits issued pursuant to any such application.


(3) ContentsAny application made under this subsection shall specify—(A) the name and official number or other identification of each fishing vessel for which a permit is sought, together with the name and address of the owner thereof;

(B) the tonnage, hold capacity, speed, processing equipment, type and quantity of fishing gear, and such other pertinent information with respect to characteristics of each such vessel as the Secretary may require;

(C) each fishery in which each such vessel wishes to fish;

(D) the estimated amount of tonnage of fish which will be caught, taken, or harvested in each such fishery by each such vessel during the time the permit is in force;

(E) the amount or tonnage of United States harvested fish, if any, which each such vessel proposes to receive at sea from vessels of the United States;

(F) the o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1824_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general After February 28, 1977, no foreign fishing vessel shall engage in fishing within the exclusive economic zone, or for anadromous species or Continental Shelf fishery resources beyond such zone, unless such vessel has on board a valid permit issued under this section for such vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1824_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications and permits under governing international fishery agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications and permits under governing international fishery agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1824_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration permits The Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Secretary, shall issue annually a registration permit for each fishing vessel of a foreign nation which is a party to an international fishery agreement under which foreign fishing is authorized by section 1821(b) of this title and which wishes to engage in fishing described in subsection (a). Each such permit shall set forth the terms and conditions contained in the agreement that apply with respect to such fishing, and shall include the additional requirement that the owner or operator of the fishing vessel for which the permit is issued shall prominently display such permit in the wheelhouse of such vessel and show it, upon request, to any officer authorized to enforce the provisions of this chapter (as provided for in section 1861 of this title). The Secretary of State, after consultation with the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall prescribe the form and </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1824_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transshipment permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transshipment permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1824_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pacific Insular Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pacific Insular Areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>