<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1826" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1826/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1826/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1826"><akn:num>1826</akn:num><akn:heading>Large-scale driftnet fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1826. Large-scale driftnet fishing(a) Short titleThis section incorporates and expands upon provisions of the Driftnet Impact Monitoring, Assessment, and Control Act of 1987 and may be cited as the “Driftnet Act Amendments of 1990”.


(b) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) the continued widespread use of large-scale driftnets beyond the exclusive economic zone of any nation is a destructive fishing practice that poses a threat to living marine resources of the world’s oceans, including but not limited to the North and South Pacific Ocean and the Bering Sea;

(2) the use of large-scale driftnets is expanding into new regions of the world’s oceans, including the Atlantic Ocean and Caribbean Sea;

(3) there is a pressing need for detailed and reliable information on the number of seabirds, sea turtles, nontarget fish, and marine mammals that become entangled and die in actively fished large-scale driftnets and in large-scale driftnets that are lost, abandoned, or discarded;

(4) increased efforts, including reliable observer data and enforcement mechanisms, are needed to monitor, assess, control, and reduce the adverse impact of large-scale driftnet fishing on living marine resources;

(5) the nations of the world have agreed in the United Nations, through General Assembly Resolution Numbered 44–225, approved December 22, 1989, by the General Assembly, that a moratorium should be imposed by June 30, 1992, on the use of large-scale driftnets beyond the exclusive economic zone of any nation;

(6) the nations of the South Pacific have agreed to a moratorium on the use of large-scale driftnets in the South Pacific through the Convention for the Prohibition of Fishing with Long Driftnets in the South Pacific, which was agreed to in Wellington, New Zealand, on November 29, 1989;

(7) increasing population pressures and new knowledge of the importance of living marine resources to the health of the global ecosystem demand that greater responsibility be exercised by persons</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section incorporates and expands upon provisions of the Driftnet Impact Monitoring, Assessment, and Control Act of 1987 and may be cited as the “Driftnet Act Amendments of 1990”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Policy It is declared to be the policy of the Congress in this section that the United States should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>International agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) International agreements The Secretary, through the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall seek to secure international agreements to implement immediately the findings, policy, and provisions of this section, and in particular an international ban on large-scale driftnet fishing. The Secretary, through the Secretary of State, shall include, in any agreement which addresses the taking of living marine resources of the United States, provisions to ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on sovereign rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect on sovereign rights This section shall not serve or be construed to expand or diminish the sovereign rights of the United States, as stated by Presidential Proclamation Numbered 5030, dated March 10, 1983, and reflected in this chapter or other existing law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Living marine resources” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Living marine resources” defined As used in this section, the term “living marine resources” includes fish, marine mammals, sea turtles, and seabirds and other waterfowl.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1826_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. See Codification note below. Fishing gear transition program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>