<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1855" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1855/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1855/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1855"><akn:num>1855</akn:num><akn:heading>Other requirements and authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1855. Other requirements and authority(a) Gear evaluation and notification of entry(1) Not later than 18 months after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register, after notice and an opportunity for public comment, a list of all fisheries—(A) under the authority of each Council and all fishing gear used in such fisheries, based on information submitted by the Councils under section 1853(a) of this title; and

(B) to which section 1852(a)(3) of this title applies and all fishing gear used in such fisheries.


(2) The Secretary shall include with such list guidelines for determining when fishing gear or a fishery is sufficiently different from those listed as to require notification under paragraph (3).

(3) Effective 180 days after the publication of such list, no person or vessel may employ fishing gear or engage in a fishery not included on such list without giving 90 days advance written notice to the appropriate Council, or the Secretary with respect to a fishery to which section 1852(a)(3) of this title applies. A signed return receipt shall serve as adequate evidence of such notice and as the date upon which the 90-day period begins.

(4) A Council may submit to the Secretary any proposed changes to such list or such guidelines the Council deems appropriate. The Secretary shall publish a revised list, after notice and an opportunity for public comment, upon receiving any such proposed changes from a Council.

(5) A Council may request the Secretary to promulgate emergency regulations under subsection (c) to prohibit any persons or vessels from using an unlisted fishing gear or engaging in an unlisted fishery if the appropriate Council, or the Secretary for fisheries to which section 1852(a)(3) of this title applies, determines that such unlisted gear or unlisted fishery would compromise the effectiveness of conservation and management efforts under this chapter.

(6) Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to permit a person or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gear evaluation and notification of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Gear evaluation and notification of entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish habitat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fish habitat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency actions and interim measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emergency actions and interim measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Responsibility of Secretary The Secretary shall have general responsibility to carry out any fishery management plan or amendment approved or prepared by him, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The Secretary may promulgate such regulations, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, as may be necessary to discharge such responsibility or to carry out any other provision of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of certain laws on certain time requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of certain laws on certain time requirements The Paperwork Reduction Act of 1980 (44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), and Executive Order Numbered 12866, dated September 30, 1993, shall be complied with within the time limitations specified in subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 1854 of this title as they apply to the functions of the Secretary under such provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiated conservation and management measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Negotiated conservation and management measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Central registry system for limited access system permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Central registry system for limited access system permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska and western Pacific community development programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Alaska and western Pacific community development programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1855_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Western Pacific and Northern Pacific regional marine education and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Western Pacific and Northern Pacific regional marine education and training</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>