<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1861"><akn:num>1861</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1861. Enforcement(a) ResponsibilityThe provisions of this chapter shall be enforced by the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. Such Secretaries may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel, services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal agency, including all elements of the Department of Defense, and of any State agency, in the performance of such duties.


(b) Powers of authorized officers(1) Any officer who is authorized (by the Secretary, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or the head of any Federal or State agency which has entered into an agreement with such Secretaries under subsection (a)) to enforce the provisions of this chapter may—(A) with or without a warrant or other process—(i) arrest any person, if he has reasonable cause to believe that such person has committed an act prohibited by section 1857 of this title;

(ii) board, and search or inspect, any fishing vessel which is subject to the provisions of this chapter;

(iii) seize any fishing vessel (together with its fishing gear, furniture, appurtenances, stores, and cargo) used or employed in, or with respect to which it reasonably appears that such vessel was used or employed in, the violation of any provision of this chapter;

(iv) seize any fish (wherever found) taken or retained in violation of any provision of this chapter;

(v) seize any other evidence related to any violation of any provision of this chapter; and

(vi) access, directly or indirectly, for enforcement purposes any data or information required to be provided under this subchapter or regulations under this subchapter, including data from vessel monitoring systems, satellite-based maritime distress and safety systems, or any similar system, subject to the confidentiality provisions of section 1881a of this title;


(B) execute any warrant or other process issued by any c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Responsibility The provisions of this chapter shall be enforced by the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. Such Secretaries may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel, services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal agency, including all elements of the Department of Defense, and of any State agency, in the performance of such duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of authorized officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Powers of authorized officers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of citations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of citations If any officer authorized to enforce the provisions of this chapter (as provided for in this section) finds that a fishing vessel is operating or has been operated in violation of any provision of this chapter, such officer may, in accordance with regulations issued jointly by the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, issue a citation to the owner or operator of such vessel in lieu of proceeding under subsection (b). If a permit has been issued pursuant to this chapter for such vessel, such officer shall note the issuance of any citation under this subsection, including the date thereof and the reason therefor, on the permit. The Secretary shall maintain a record of all citations issued pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Jurisdiction of courts The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any case or controversy arising under the provisions of this chapter. In the case of Hawaii or any possession of the United States in the Pacific Ocean, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Hawaii, except that in the case of Guam and Wake Island, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of Guam, and in the case of the Northern Mariana Islands, the appropriate court is the United States District Court for the District of the Northern Mariana Islands. Any such court may, at any time—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of storage, care, and other costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment of storage, care, and other costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Northeast Multispecies Fishery Management Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enforcement of Northeast Multispecies Fishery Management Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement in Pacific Insular Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Enforcement in Pacific Insular Areas The Secretary, in consultation with the Governors of the Pacific Insular Areas and the Western Pacific Council, shall to the extent practicable support cooperative enforcement agreements between Federal and Pacific Insular Area authorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint enforcement agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Joint enforcement agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved data sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Improved data sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>