<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1861a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1861a"><akn:num>1861a</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition to sustainable fisheries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1861a. Transition to sustainable fisheries(a) Fishery resource disaster relief(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Allowable causeThe term “allowable cause” means a natural cause, discrete anthropogenic cause, or undetermined cause, including a cause that occurred not more than 5 years prior to the date of a request for a fishery resource disaster determination that affected such applicable fishery.


(B) Anthropogenic causeThe term “anthropogenic cause” means an anthropogenic event, such as an oil spill or spillway opening—(i) that could not have been addressed or prevented by fishery management measures; and

(ii) that is otherwise beyond the control of fishery managers to mitigate through conservation and management measures, including regulatory restrictions imposed as a result of judicial action or to protect human health or marine animals, plants, or habitats.


(C) Fishery resource disasterThe term “fishery resource disaster” means a disaster that is determined by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection and—(i) is an unexpected large decrease in fish stock biomass or other change that results in significant loss of access to the fishery resource, which may include loss of fishing vessels and gear for a substantial period of time and results in significant revenue loss or negative subsistence impact due to an allowable cause; and

(ii) does not include—(I) reasonably predictable, foreseeable, and recurrent fishery cyclical variations in species distribution or stock abundance; or

(II) reductions in fishing opportunities resulting from conservation and management measures taken pursuant to this chapter.



(D) Indian TribeThe term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 5130 of title 25, and the term “Tribal” means of or pertaining to such an Indian tribe.


(E) Natural causeThe term “natural cause”—(i) means a weather, climatic, hazard, or biology-related event, such as—(I) a hurricane;

(II) a flood;

(III) a harmful algal bloom</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishery resource disaster relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fishery resource disaster relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishing capacity reduction program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fishing capacity reduction program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry fee system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Industry fee system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1861a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>