<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862"><akn:num>1862</akn:num><akn:heading>North Pacific fisheries conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862. North Pacific fisheries conservation(a) In generalThe North Pacific Council may prepare, in consultation with the Secretary, a fisheries research plan for any fishery under the Council’s jurisdiction except a salmon fishery which—(1) requires that observers be stationed on fishing vessels engaged in the catching, taking, or harvesting of fish and on United States fish processors fishing for or processing species under the jurisdiction of the Council, including the Northern Pacific halibut fishery, for the purpose of collecting data necessary for the conservation, management, and scientific understanding of any fisheries under the Council’s jurisdiction; and

(2) establishes a system, or system,11 So in original. of fees, which may vary by fishery, management area, or observer coverage level, to pay for the cost of implementing the plan.


(b) Standards(1) Any plan or plan amendment prepared under this section shall be reasonably calculated to—(A) gather reliable data, by stationing observers on all or a statistically reliable sample of the fishing vessels and United States fish processors included in the plan, necessary for the conservation, management, and scientific understanding of the fisheries covered by the plan;

(B) be fair and equitable to all vessels and processors;

(C) be consistent with applicable provisions of law; and

(D) take into consideration the operating requirements of the fisheries and the safety of observers and fishermen.


(2) Any system of fees established under this section shall—(A) provide that the total amount of fees collected under this section not exceed the combined cost of (i) stationing observers, or electronic monitoring systems, on board fishing vessels and United States fish processors, (ii) the actual cost of inputting collected data, and (iii) assessments necessary for a risk-sharing pool implemented under subsection (e) of this section, less any amount received for such purpose from another source or from an existin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The North Pacific Council may prepare, in consultation with the Secretary, a fisheries research plan for any fishery under the Council’s jurisdiction except a salmon fishery which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishery Observer Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fishery Observer Fund There is established in the Treasury a North Pacific Fishery Observer Fund. The Fund shall be available, without appropriation or fiscal year limitation, only to the Secretary for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section, subject to the restrictions in subsection (b)(2) of this section. The Fund shall consist of all monies deposited into it in accordance with this section. Sums in the Fund that are not currently needed for the purposes of this section shall be kept on deposit or invested in obligations of, or guaranteed by, the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provisions regarding observers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special provisions regarding observers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bycatch reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Bycatch reduction In implementing section 1853(a)(11) of this title and this section, the North Pacific Council shall submit conservation and management measures to lower, on an annual basis for a period of not less than four years, the total amount of economic discards occurring in the fisheries under its jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bycatch reduction incentives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bycatch reduction incentives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Catch measurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Catch measurement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full retention and utilization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Full retention and utilization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands crab rationalization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Bering Sea and Aleutian Islands crab rationalization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>