<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881a"><akn:num>1881a</akn:num><akn:heading>Information collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881a. Information collection(a) Collection programs(1) Council requestsIf a Council determines that additional information would be beneficial for developing, implementing, or revising a fishery management plan or for determining whether a fishery is in need of management, the Council may request that the Secretary implement an information collection program for the fishery which would provide the types of information specified by the Council. The Secretary shall undertake such an information collection program if he determines that the need is justified, and shall promulgate regulations to implement the program within 60 days after such determination is made. If the Secretary determines that the need for an information collection program is not justified, the Secretary shall inform the Council of the reasons for such determination in writing. The determinations of the Secretary under this paragraph regarding a Council request shall be made within a reasonable period of time after receipt of that request.


(2) Secretarial initiationIf the Secretary determines that additional information is necessary for developing, implementing, revising, or monitoring a fishery management plan, or for determining whether a fishery is in need of management, the Secretary may, by regulation, implement an information collection or observer program requiring submission of such additional information for the fishery.



(b) Confidentiality of information(1) Any information submitted to the Secretary, a State fishery management agency, or a marine fisheries commission by any person in compliance with the requirements of this chapter shall be confidential and shall not be disclosed except—(A) to Federal employees and Council employees who are responsible for fishery management plan development, monitoring, or enforcement;

(B) to State or Marine Fisheries Commission employees as necessary to further the Department’s mission, subject to a confidentiality agreement that prohibits public</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Collection programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Confidentiality of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on use of certain information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contracting authority Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may provide a grant, contract, or other financial assistance on a sole-source basis to a State, Council, or Marine Fisheries Commission for the purpose of carrying out information collection or other programs if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Resource assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>