<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1881d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881d"><akn:num>1881d</akn:num><akn:heading>Incidental harvest research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881d. Incidental harvest research(a) Collection of informationWithin nine months after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Gulf Council and South Atlantic Council, conclude the collection of information in the program to assess the impact on fishery resources of incidental harvest by the shrimp trawl fishery within the authority of such Councils. Within the same time period, the Secretary shall make available to the public aggregated summaries of information collected prior to June 30, 1994 under such program.


(b) Identification of stockThe program concluded pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide for the identification of stocks of fish which are subject to significant incidental harvest in the course of normal shrimp trawl fishing activity.


(c) Collection and assessment of specific stock informationFor stocks of fish identified pursuant to subsection (b), with priority given to stocks which (based upon the best available scientific information) are considered to be overfished, the Secretary shall conduct—(1) a program to collect and evaluate information on the nature and extent (including the spatial and temporal distribution) of incidental mortality of such stocks as a direct result of shrimp trawl fishing activities;

(2) an assessment of the status and condition of such stocks, including collection of information which would allow the estimation of life history parameters with sufficient accuracy and precision to support sound scientific evaluation of the effects of various management alternatives on the status of such stocks; and

(3) a program of information collection and evaluation for such stocks on the magnitude and distribution of fishing mortality and fishing effort by sources of fishing mortality other than shrimp trawl fishing activity.


(d) Bycatch reduction programNot later than 12 months after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall, in cooperation with affected interests, and based upon the best scientific inf</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Collection of information Within nine months after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall, after consultation with the Gulf Council and South Atlantic Council, conclude the collection of information in the program to assess the impact on fishery resources of incidental harvest by the shrimp trawl fishery within the authority of such Councils. Within the same time period, the Secretary shall make available to the public aggregated summaries of information collected prior to June 30, 1994 under such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of stock The program concluded pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide for the identification of stocks of fish which are subject to significant incidental harvest in the course of normal shrimp trawl fishing activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and assessment of specific stock information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Collection and assessment of specific stock information For stocks of fish identified pursuant to subsection (b), with priority given to stocks which (based upon the best available scientific information) are considered to be overfished, the Secretary shall conduct—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bycatch reduction program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Bycatch reduction program Not later than 12 months after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall, in cooperation with affected interests, and based upon the best scientific information available, complete a program to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report to Congress The Secretary shall, within one year of completing the programs required by this section, submit a detailed report on the results of such programs to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation criteria To the extent practicable, any conservation and management measure implemented under this chapter to reduce the incidental mortality of bycatch in the course of shrimp trawl fishing shall be consistent with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>