<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1882" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1882/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/1882/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1882"><akn:num>1882</akn:num><akn:heading>Fisheries systems research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1882. Fisheries systems research(a) Establishment of panelNot later than 180 days after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall establish an advisory panel under this chapter to develop recommendations to expand the application of ecosystem principles in fishery conservation and management activities.


(b) Panel membershipThe advisory panel shall consist of not more than 20 individuals and include—(1) individuals with expertise in the structures, functions, and physical and biological characteristics of ecosystems; and

(2) representatives from the Councils, States, fishing industry, conservation organizations, or others with expertise in the management of marine resources.


(c) RecommendationsPrior to selecting advisory panel members, the Secretary shall, with respect to panel members described in subsection (b)(1), solicit recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences.


(d) ReportWithin 2 years after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a completed report of the panel established under this section, which shall include—(1) an analysis of the extent to which ecosystem principles are being applied in fishery conservation and management activities, including research activities;

(2) proposed actions by the Secretary and by the Congress that should be undertaken to expand the application of ecosystem principles in fishery conservation and management; and

(3) such other information as may be appropriate.


(e) Procedural matterThe advisory panel established under this section shall be deemed an advisory panel under section 1852(g) of this title.


(f) Regional ecosystem research(1) StudyWithin 180 days after January 12, 2007, the Secretary, in consultation with the Councils, shall undertake and complete a study on the state of the science for advancing the concepts and integration of ecosystem considerations in regional fishery management. The study should build upon the recommendations of the advisory panel and include—(A) recommen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of panel Not later than 180 days after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall establish an advisory panel under this chapter to develop recommendations to expand the application of ecosystem principles in fishery conservation and management activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Panel membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Panel membership The advisory panel shall consist of not more than 20 individuals and include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendations Prior to selecting advisory panel members, the Secretary shall, with respect to panel members described in subsection (b)(1), solicit recommendations from the National Academy of Sciences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Within 2 years after October 11, 1996, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a completed report of the panel established under this section, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural matter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procedural matter The advisory panel established under this section shall be deemed an advisory panel under section 1852(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1882_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional ecosystem research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regional ecosystem research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>