<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2101a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2101a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2101a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2101a"><akn:num>2101a</akn:num><akn:heading>State-wide assessment and strategies for forest resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2101a. State-wide assessment and strategies for forest resources(a) Assessment and strategies for forest resourcesFor a State to be eligible to receive funds under the authorities of this chapter, the State forester of that State or equivalent State official shall develop and submit to the Secretary, not later than two years after the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, the following:(1) A State-wide assessment of forest resource conditions, including—(A) the conditions and trends of forest resources in that State;

(B) the threats to forest lands and resources in that State consistent with the national priorities specified in section 2101(c) of this title;

(C) any areas or regions of that State that are a priority; and

(D) any multi-State areas that are a regional priority.


(2) A long-term State-wide forest resource strategy, including—(A) strategies for addressing threats to forest resources in the State outlined in the assessment required by paragraph (1); and

(B) a description of the resources necessary for the State forester or equivalent State official from all sources to address the State-wide strategy.



(b) UpdatingAt such times as the Secretary determines to be necessary, the State forester or equivalent State official shall update and resubmit to the Secretary the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a).


(c) CoordinationIn developing or updating the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a), the State Forester or equivalent State official shall coordinate with—(1) the State Forest Stewardship Coordinating Committee established for the State under section 2113(b) of this title;

(2) the State wildlife agency, with respect to strategies contained in the State wildlife action plans;

(3) the State Technical Committee;

(4) applicable Federal land management agencies;

(5) as feasible, appropriate military installations where the voluntary participation </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment and strategies for forest resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment and strategies for forest resources For a State to be eligible to receive funds under the authorities of this chapter, the State forester of that State or equivalent State official shall develop and submit to the Secretary, not later than two years after the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Updating At such times as the Secretary determines to be necessary, the State forester or equivalent State official shall update and resubmit to the Secretary the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination In developing or updating the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a), the State Forester or equivalent State official shall coordinate with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation of other plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Incorporation of other plans In developing or updating the State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy required by subsection (a), the State forester or equivalent State official shall incorporate any forest management plan of the State, including community wildfire protection plans and State wildlife action plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sufficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sufficiency Once approved by the Secretary, a State-wide assessment and State-wide strategy developed under subsection (a) shall be deemed to be sufficient to satisfy all relevant State planning and assessment requirements under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual report on use of funds The State forester or equivalent State official shall submit to the Secretary an annual report detailing how funds made available to the State under this chapter are being used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>