<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2103c"><akn:num>2103c</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest Legacy Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2103c. Forest Legacy Program(a) Establishment and purposeThe Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the Forest Legacy Program, in cooperation with appropriate State, regional, and other units of government for the purposes of ascertaining and protecting environmentally important forest areas that are threatened by conversion to nonforest uses and, through the use of conservation easements and other mechanisms, for promoting forest land protection and other conservation opportunities. Such purposes shall also include the protection of important scenic, cultural, fish, wildlife, and recreational resources, riparian areas, and other ecological values.


(b) State and regional forest legacy programsThe Secretary shall exercise the authority under subsection (a) in conjunction with State or regional programs that the Secretary deems consistent with this section.


(c) Interests in landIn addition to the authorities granted under section 515 of this title and section 2268a(a) of title 7, the Secretary may acquire from willing landowners lands and interests therein, including conservation easements and rights of public access, for Forest Legacy Program purposes. The Secretary shall not acquire conservation easements with title held in common ownership with any other entity.


(d) Implementation(1) In generalLands and interests therein acquired under subsection (c) may be held in perpetuity for program and easement administration purposes as the Secretary may provide. In administering lands and interests therein under the program, the Secretary shall identify the environmental values to be protected by entry of the lands into the program, management activities which are planned and the manner in which they may affect the values identified, and obtain from the landowner other information determined appropriate for administration and management purposes.


(2) Initial programsNot later than November 28, 1991, the Secretary shall establish a regional program in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and purpose The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the Forest Legacy Program, in cooperation with appropriate State, regional, and other units of government for the purposes of ascertaining and protecting environmentally important forest areas that are threatened by conversion to nonforest uses and, through the use of conservation easements and other mechanisms, for promoting forest land protection and other conservation opportunities. Such purposes shall also include the protection of important scenic, cultural, fish, wildlife, and recreational resources, riparian areas, and other ecological values.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and regional forest legacy programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State and regional forest legacy programs The Secretary shall exercise the authority under subsection (a) in conjunction with State or regional programs that the Secretary deems consistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interests in land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interests in land In addition to the authorities granted under section 515 of this title and section 2268a(a) of title 7, the Secretary may acquire from willing landowners lands and interests therein, including conservation easements and rights of public access, for Forest Legacy Program purposes. The Secretary shall not acquire conservation easements with title held in common ownership with any other entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility Not later than November 28, 1991, and in consultation with State Forest Stewardship Coordinating Committees established under section 2113(b) of this title and similar regional organizations, the Secretary shall establish eligibility criteria for the designation of forest areas from which lands may be entered into the Forest Legacy Program and subsequently select such appropriate areas. To be eligible, such areas shall have significant environmental values or shall be threatened by present or future conversion to nonforest uses. Of land proposed to be included in the Forest Legacy Program, the Secretary shall give priority to lands which can be effectively protected and managed, and which have important scenic or recreational values; riparian areas; fish and wildlife values, including threatened and endangered species; or other ecological values.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application For areas included in the Forest Legacy Program, an owner of lands or interests in lands who wishes to participate may prepare and submit an application at such time in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may prescribe. The Secretary shall give reasonable advance notice for the submission of all applications to the State forester, equivalent State official, or other appropriate State or regional natural resource management agency. If applications exceed the ability of the Secretary to fund them, priority shall be given to those forest areas having the greatest need for protection pursuant to the criteria described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State consent Where a State has not approved the acquisition of land under section 515 of this title, the Secretary shall not acquire lands or interests therein under authority granted by this section outside an area of that State designated as a part of a program established under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest management activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Forest management activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Duties of owners Under the terms of a conservation easement or other property interest acquired under subsection (b),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (c),”. the landowner shall be required to manage property in a manner that is consistent with the purposes for which the land was entered in the Forest Legacy Program and shall not convert such property to other uses. Hunting, fishing, hiking, and similar recreational uses shall not be considered inconsistent with the purposes of this program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Compensation and cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>