<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2103d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2103d"><akn:num>2103d</akn:num><akn:heading>Community forest and open space conservation program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2103d. Community forest and open space conservation program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a local governmental entity, Indian tribe, or nonprofit organization that owns or acquires a parcel under the program.


(2) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.


(3) Local governmental entityThe term “local governmental entity” includes any municipal government, county government, or other local government body with jurisdiction over local land use decisions.


(4) Nonprofit organizationThe term “nonprofit organization” means any organization that—(A) is described in section 170(h)(3) of title 26; and

(B) operates in accordance with 1 or more of the purposes specified in section 170(h)(4)(A) of title 26.


(5) ProgramThe term “Program” means the community forest and open space conservation program established under subsection (b).


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.



(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the “community forest and open space conservation program”.


(c) Grant program(1) In generalThe Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to acquire private forest land,11 So in original. Probably should be “lands,”. to be owned in fee simple, that—(A) are threatened by conversion to nonforest uses; and

(B) provide public benefits to communities, including—(i) economic benefits through sustainable forest management;

(ii) environmental benefits, including clean water and wildlife habitat;

(iii) benefits from forest-based educational programs, including vocational education programs in forestry;

(iv) benefits from serving as models of effective forest stewardship for private landowners; and

(v) recreational benefits, including hunting and fishing.



(2) Federal cost shareAn eligible entity may receive a grant under the Program in an a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the “community forest and open space conservation program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties of eligible entity An eligible entity shall provide public access to, and manage, forest land acquired with a grant under this section in a manner that is consistent with the purposes for which the land was acquired under the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State administration and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State administration and technical assistance The Secretary may allocate not more than 10 percent of all funds made available to carry out the Program for each fiscal year to State foresters or equivalent officials (including equivalent officials of Indian tribes) for Program administration and technical assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2103d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>