<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2106c"><akn:num>2106c</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced community fire protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2106c. Enhanced community fire protection(a) Cooperative management related to wildfire threatsThe Secretary may cooperate with State foresters and equivalent State officials in the management of lands in the United States for the following purposes:(1) Aid in wildfire prevention and control.

(2) Protect communities from wildfire threats.

(3) Enhance the growth and maintenance of trees and forests that promote overall forest health.

(4) Ensure the continued production of all forest resources, including timber, outdoor recreation opportunities, wildlife habitat, and clean water, through conservation of forest cover on watersheds, shelterbelts, and windbreaks.


(b) Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program(1) Establishment; purposeThe Secretary shall establish a Community and Private Land Fire Assistance program (in this subsection referred to as the “Program”)—(A) to focus the Federal role in promoting optimal firefighting efficiency at the Federal, State, and local levels;

(B) to augment Federal projects that establish landscape level protection from wildfires;

(C) to expand outreach and education programs to homeowners and communities about fire prevention; and

(D) to establish space around homes and property of private landowners that is defensible against wildfires.


(2) Administration and implementationThe Program shall be administered by the Forest Service and implemented through State foresters or equivalent State officials.


(3) ComponentsIn coordination with existing authorities under this chapter, the Secretary, in consultation with the State forester or equivalent State official, may undertake on non-Federal lands—(A) fuel hazard mitigation and prevention;

(B) invasive species management;

(C) multiresource wildfire planning;

(D) community protection planning;

(E) community and landowner education enterprises, including the program known as FIREWISE;

(F) market development and expansion;

(G) improved wood utilization; and

(H) spec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative management related to wildfire threats</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperative management related to wildfire threats The Secretary may cooperate with State foresters and equivalent State officials in the management of lands in the United States for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>