<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2106"><akn:num>2106</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural fire prevention and control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2106. Rural fire prevention and control(a) Congressional findingsCongress finds that—(1) significant accomplishments have been made by the Secretary and cooperating States in the prevention and control of fires on forest lands and on nonforested watersheds for more than fifty years;

(2) progress is being made by the Secretary and cooperating States and rural communities in the protection of human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources from fires in rural areas;

(3) notwithstanding the accomplishments and progress that have been made, fire prevention and control on rural lands and in rural communities are of continuing high priority to protect human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources;

(4) the effective cooperative relationships between the Secretary and the States regarding fire prevention and control on rural lands and in rural communities should be retained and improved;

(5) efforts in fire prevention and control in rural areas should be coordinated among Federal, State, and local agencies; and

(6) in addition to providing assistance to State and local rural fire prevention and control programs, the Secretary should provide prompt and adequate assistance whenever a rural fire emergency overwhelms, or threatens to overwhelm, the firefighting capability of the affected State or rural area.


(b) Implementation of provisionsNotwithstanding the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 [15 U.S.C. 2201 et seq.] the Secretary is authorized, under whatever conditions the Secretary may prescribe, to—(1) cooperate with State foresters or equivalent State officials in developing systems and methods for the prevention, control, suppression, and prescribed use of fires on rural lands and in rural communities that will protect human lives, agricultural crops and livestock, property and other improvements, and natural resources;

(2) provide financia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementation of provisions Notwithstanding the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 [15 U.S.C. 2201 et seq.] the Secretary is authorized, under whatever conditions the Secretary may prescribe, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement of use of excess personal property by State and local fire forces receiving assistance; cooperation and assistance of Administrator of General Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Encouragement of use of excess personal property by State and local fire forces receiving assistance; cooperation and assistance of Administrator of General Services The Secretary, with the cooperation and assistance of the Administrator of General Services, shall encourage the use of excess personal property (within the meaning of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41) by State and local fire forces receiving assistance under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of assistance with assistance of Secretary of Commerce under Federal fire prevention and control provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination of assistance with assistance of Secretary of Commerce under Federal fire prevention and control provisions To promote maximum effectiveness and economy, the Secretary shall seek to coordinate the assistance the Secretary provides under this section with the assistance provided by the Secretary of Commerce under the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 [15 U.S.C. 2201 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for implementation of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations for implementation of provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rural fire disaster fund; establishment, appropriations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rural fire disaster fund; establishment, appropriations, etc. There shall be established in the Treasury a special rural fire disaster fund that shall be immediately available to and used by the Secretary to supplement any other money available to carry out this section with respect to rural fire emergencies, as determined by the Secretary. The Secretary shall determine that State and local resources are fully used or will be fully used before expending money in the disaster fund to assist a State in which one or more rural fire emergencies exist. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be needed to establish and replenish the disaster fund established by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>