<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2109a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2109a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2109a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2109a"><akn:num>2109a</akn:num><akn:heading>State and private forest landscape-scale restoration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2109a. State and private forest landscape-scale restoration program(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.


(2) Nonindustrial private forest landThe term “nonindustrial private forest land” means land that—(A) is rural, as determined by the Secretary;

(B) has existing tree cover or is suitable for growing trees; and

(C) is owned by any private individual, group, association, corporation, Indian tribe, or other private legal entity.


(3) State forest landThe term “State forest land” means land that—(A) is rural, as determined by the Secretary; and

(B) is under State or local governmental ownership and considered to be non-Federal forest land.



(c) EstablishmentThe Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or appropriate State agencies, shall establish a competitive grant program to provide financial and technical assistance to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.


(d) EligibilityTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an applicant shall submit to the Secretary, through the State forester or appropriate State agency, a State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal based on a restoration strategy that—(1) is complete or substantially complete;

(2) is for a multiyear period;

(3) covers nonindustrial private forest land or State forest land;

(4) is accessible by wood-processing infrastructure; and

(5) is based on the best available science.


(e) Plan criteriaA State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal submitted under this section shall include plans—(1) to reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfires;

(2) to improve fish and wildlife habitats, including the habitats of threatened and endangered species;

(3) to maintain or improve water qu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment The Secretary, in consultation with State foresters or appropriate State agencies, shall establish a competitive grant program to provide financial and technical assistance to encourage collaborative, science-based restoration of priority forest landscapes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an applicant shall submit to the Secretary, through the State forester or appropriate State agency, a State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal based on a restoration strategy that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan criteria A State and private forest landscape-scale restoration proposal submitted under this section shall include plans—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Priorities In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to plans that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration and consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Collaboration and consultation The Chief of the Forest Service, the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, and relevant stakeholders shall collaborate and consult on an ongoing basis regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Matching funds required As a condition of receiving a grant under this section, the Secretary shall require the recipient of the grant to provide funds or in-kind support from non-Federal sources in an amount that is at least equal to the amount of Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and proximity encouraged</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Coordination and proximity encouraged In making grants under this section, the Secretary may consider coordination with and proximity to other landscape-scale projects on other land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, the Secretary of the Interior, or a Governor of a State, including under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate such regulations as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>