<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2113"><akn:num>2113</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal, State, and local coordination and cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2113. Federal, State, and local coordination and cooperation(a) Forest Resource Coordinating Committee(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Forest Resource Coordinating Committee” (in this section referred to as the “Coordinating Committee”), to coordinate nonindustrial private forestry activities within the Department of Agriculture and with the private sector.


(2) CompositionThe Coordinating Committee shall be composed of the following:(A) The Chief of the Forest Service.

(B) The Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service.

(C) The Director of the Farm Service Agency.

(D) The Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture.

(E) Non-Federal representatives appointed by the Secretary to 3 year terms, although initial appointees shall have staggered terms, including the following persons:(i) At least three State foresters or equivalent State officials from geographically diverse regions of the United States.

(ii) A representative of a State fish and wildlife agency.

(iii) An owner of nonindustrial private forest land.

(iv) A forest industry representative.

(v) A conservation organization representative.

(vi) A land-grant university or college representative.

(vii) A private forestry consultant.

(viii) A representative from a State Technical Committee established under section 3861 of this title.


(F) Such other persons as determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.


(3) ChairpersonThe Chief of the Forest Service shall serve as chairperson of the Coordinating Committee.


(4) DutiesThe Coordinating Committee shall—(A) provide direction and coordination of actions within the Department of Agriculture, and coordination with State agencies and the private sector, to effectively address the national priorities specified in section 2101(c) of this title, with specific focus 11 So in original. The word “on” probably should appear after “focus”. owners of nonindustrial private forest land;

(B) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest Resource Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Forest Resource Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Coordinating Committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State Coordinating Committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>