<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/215" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/215/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/215/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_215"><akn:num>215</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvements and preservation of lands and buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 215. Improvements and preservation of lands and buildings
For the purpose of protecting from disintegration and of improving, beautifying, and preserving the Abraham Lincoln Birthplace National Historical Park or Reservation established under sections 211 to 214 of this title, the National Park Service is authorized and directed to provide for (1) the improvement of such existing roadways, walks, and buildings in such park or reservation; and (2) the planting of such trees, plants, and shrubbery; the construction of such additional roadways, walks, and buildings, and of such fences, parking spaces, drainage structures, culverts, and bridges; and the making of such other improvements, as in its judgment may be necessary for the preservation, beautification, and protection from disintegration of such park or reservation, including the log cabin in which Abraham Lincoln was born and the memorial hall inclosing the same, and which may serve to render such park or reservation convenient for the appropriate use and enjoyment by the public.
(Feb. 11, 1929, ch. 176, § 1, 45 Stat. 1162; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 2, June 10, 1933; Ex. Ord. No. 6228, § 1, July 28, 1933; Mar. 2, 1934, ch. 38, § 1, 48 Stat. 389; Aug. 11, 1939, ch. 686, 53 Stat. 1405; Pub. L. 86–231, Sept. 8, 1959, 73 Stat. 466; Pub. L. 111–11, title VII, § 7114(b), Mar. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 1202.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Abraham Lincoln Birthplace National Historical Park” substituted for “Abraham Lincoln Birthplace National Historic Site” pursuant to Pub. L. 111–11.
“Abraham Lincoln Birthplace National Historic Site” substituted for “Abraham Lincoln National Historical Park” pursuant to Pub. L. 86–231.
“Abraham Lincoln National Historical Park” substituted for “Abraham Lincoln National Park” pursuant to act Aug. 11, 1939.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
All national parks, national monuments, and national cemeteries consolidated in an office of National Parks, Building</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>