<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/21b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/21b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/21b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21b"><akn:num>21b</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of certain laws to park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21b. Extension of certain laws to park
The provisions of the Act of March 1, 1872,11 See References in Text note below. reserving lands for park purposes, the Act of July 10, 1890,1 admitting the State of Wyoming into the Union, the Act of May 7, 1894, entitled “An Act to protect the birds and animals in the Yellowstone National Park and to punish crimes in said park, and for other purposes,” 1 the Act of August 25, 1916, entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,” 1 and all Acts supplementary to and amendatory of said Acts are made applicable to and extended over the lands added to the park: Provided, That the provisions of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.] shall not apply to or extend over such lands.
(Mar. 1, 1929, ch. 437, § 2, 45 Stat. 1436.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act of March 1, 1872, referred to in text, is act Mar. 1, 1872, ch. 24, 17 Stat. 32. That Act was incorporated into the Revised Statutes as R.S. §§ 2474 and 2475 which are classified to sections 21 and 22, respectively, of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The Act of July 10, 1890, referred to in text, is act July 10, 1890, ch. 664, 26 Stat. 222. The Act was classified to sections 481 and 490 of former Title 28, Judicial Code and Judiciary, which were repealed and reenacted in sections 501 and 541 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, by act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, §§ 1, 39, 62 Stat. 869, 992. See section 541 of Title 28.
The Act of May 7, 1894, entitled “An Act to protect the birds and animals in the Yellowstone National Park and to punish crimes in said park, and for other purposes,”, referred to in text, is act May 7, 1894, ch. 72, 28 Stat. 73, which is classified to sections 24 to 30a of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The Act of August 25, 1916, entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes,”, referred</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>