<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/230" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/230/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/230/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_230"><akn:num>230</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; description of area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 230. Establishment; description of area
In order to preserve for the education, inspiration, and benefit of present and future generations significant examples of natural and historical resources of the Mississippi Delta region and to provide for their interpretation in such manner as to portray the development of cultural diversity in the region, there is authorized to be established in the State of Louisiana the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve (hereinafter referred to as the “park”). The park shall consist of (1) the area generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Barataria Preserve Unit, Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve”, numbered 467/80100A, and dated December 2007, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior; (2) the area known as Big Oak Island; (3) an area or areas within the French Quarter section of the city of New Orleans as may be designated by the Secretary of the Interior for an interpretive and administrative facility; (4) folk life centers to be established in the Acadian region; (5) the Chalmette Unit of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve; and (6) such additional natural, cultural, and historical resources in the French Quarter and Garden District of New Orleans, forts in the delta region, plantations, and Acadian towns and villages in the Saint Martinville area and such other areas and sites as are subject to cooperative agreements in accordance with the provisions of this part.
(Pub. L. 95–625, title IX, §§ 901, 909, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3534, 3538; Pub. L. 100–250, § 1(a), Feb. 16, 1988, 102 Stat. 16; Pub. L. 111–11, title VII, § 7105(a), (f)(1)(B), (2)(B), Mar. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 1191, 1193.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2009—Pub. L. 111–11, § 7105(f)(2)(B), which directed amendment of title IX of Pub. L. 95–625 by substituting “Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve” for “Jean L</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>