<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2403a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2403a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2403a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2403a"><akn:num>2403a</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2403a. Environmental impact assessment(a) Federal activities(1)(A) The obligations of the United States under Article 8 of and Annex I to the Protocol shall be implemented by applying the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) to proposals for Federal agency activities in Antarctica, as specified in this section.

(B) The obligations contained in section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)) shall apply to all proposals for Federal agency activities occurring in Antarctica and affecting the quality of the human environment in Antarctica or dependent or associated ecosystems, only as specified in this section. For purposes of the application of such section 102(2)(C) under this subsection, the term “significantly affecting the quality of the human environment” shall have the same meaning as the term “more than a minor or transitory impact”.


(2)(A) Unless an agency which proposes to conduct a Federal activity in Antarctica determines that the activity will have less than a minor or transitory impact, or unless a comprehensive environmental evaluation is being prepared in accordance with subparagraph (C), the agency shall prepare an initial environmental evaluation in accordance with Article 2 of Annex I to the Protocol.

(B) If the agency determines, through the preparation of the initial environmental evaluation, that the proposed Federal activity is likely to have no more than a minor or transitory impact, the activity may proceed if appropriate procedures are put in place to assess and verify the impact of the activity.

(C) If the agency determines, through the preparation of the initial environmental evaluation or otherwise, that a proposed Federal activity is likely to have more than a minor or transitory impact, the agency shall prepare and circulate a comprehensive environmental evaluation in accordance with Article 3 of Annex I to the Protocol, and shall make such comprehensive enviro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal activities carried out jointly with foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal activities carried out jointly with foreign governments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nongovernmental activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nongovernmental activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision to proceed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Decision to proceed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cases of emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cases of emergency The requirements of this section, and of regulations promulgated under this section, shall not apply in cases of emergency relating to the safety of human life or of ships, aircraft, or equipment and facilities of high value, or the protection of the environment, which require an activity to be undertaken without fulfilling those requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive mechanism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusive mechanism Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the requirements of this section shall constitute the sole and exclusive statutory obligations of the Federal agencies with regard to assessing the environmental impacts of proposed Federal activities occurring in Antarctica.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions on permit applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Decisions on permit applications The provisions of this section requiring environmental impact assessments (including initial environmental evaluations and comprehensive environmental evaluations) shall not apply to Federal actions with respect to issuing permits under section 2404 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2403a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of notices Whenever the Secretary of State makes a determination under paragraph (2) of subsection (b) of this section, or receives a draft comprehensive environmental evaluation in accordance with Annex I, Article 3(3) to the Protocol, the Secretary of State shall cause timely notice thereof to be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>