<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2405" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2405/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2405/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2405"><akn:num>2405</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2405. Regulations(a) Regulations to be issued by Director(1) The Director shall issue such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement Annex II and Annex V to the Protocol and the provisions of this chapter which implement those annexes, including section 2403(b)(2), (3), (4), and (5) of this title. The Director shall designate as native species—(A) each species of the class Aves;

(B) each species of the class Mammalia; and

(C) each species of plant,


which is indigenous to Antarctica or which occurs there seasonally through natural migrations.

(2) The Director, with the concurrence of the Administrator, shall issue such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement Annex III to the Protocol and the provisions of this chapter which implement that Annex, including section 2403(a)(1), (2), (3), and (4) of this title, and section 2403(b)(1) of this title.

(3) The Director shall issue such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement Article 15 of the Protocol with respect to land areas and ice shelves in Antarctica.

(4) The Director shall issue such additional regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement the Protocol and this chapter, except as provided in subsection (b).


(b) Regulations to be issued by Secretary of Department in which Coast Guard is operatingThe Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall issue such regulations as are necessary and appropriate, in addition to regulations issued under the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (33 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.), to implement Annex IV to the Protocol and the provisions of this chapter which implement that Annex, and, with the concurrence of the Director, such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement Article 15 of the Protocol with respect to vessels.


(c) Time period for regulationsThe regulations to be issued under subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section shall be issued within 2 years after October 2, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2405_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to be issued by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations to be issued by Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2405_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to be issued by Secretary of Department in which Coast Guard is operating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations to be issued by Secretary of Department in which Coast Guard is operating The Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall issue such regulations as are necessary and appropriate, in addition to regulations issued under the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (33 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.), to implement Annex IV to the Protocol and the provisions of this chapter which implement that Annex, and, with the concurrence of the Director, such regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement Article 15 of the Protocol with respect to vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2405_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time period for regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time period for regulations The regulations to be issued under subsection (a)(1) and (2) of this section shall be issued within 2 years after October 2, 1996. The regulations to be issued under subsection (a)(3) of this section shall be issued within 3 years after October 2, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>