<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2432" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2432/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2432/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2432"><akn:num>2432</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2432. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter—(1) Antarctic ConvergenceThe term “Antarctic Convergence” means a line joining the following points along the parallels of latitude and meridians of longitude: 50 degrees south, 0 degrees; 50 degrees south, 30 degrees east; 45 degrees south, 30 degrees east; 45 degrees south, 80 degrees east; 55 degrees south, 80 degrees east; 55 degrees south, 150 degrees east; 60 degrees south, 150 degrees east; 60 degrees south; 11 So in original. Probably should be a comma. 50 degrees west; 50 degrees south, 50 degrees west; and 50 degrees south, 0 degrees.


(2) Antarctic marine living resourcesThe term “Antarctic marine living resources” means the population of finfish, molluscs, crustaceans and all other species of living organisms, including birds, found south of the Antarctic Convergence.


(3) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Commission for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources established pursuant to article VII of the Convention.


(4) ConventionThe term “Convention” means the Convention on the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources, done at Canberra, Australia, May 7, 1980, and entered into force with respect to the United States on April 7, 1982.


(5) Harvesting or other associated activitiesThe terms “harvesting” and “harvesting or other associated activities” mean—(A) the harassing, molesting, harming, pursuing, hunting, shooting, wounding, killing, trapping, or capturing of Antarctic marine living resources;

(B) attempting to engage in any activity set forth in subparagraph (A);

(C) any other activity which can reasonably be expected to result in any activity described in subparagraph (A); and

(D) any operations at sea in support of, or in preparation for, any activity described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).


(6) HarvestThe term “harvest” means to engage in harvesting or other associated activities.


(7) ImportThe term “import” means to land on, bring into, or introduce in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antarctic Convergence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Antarctic Convergence The term “Antarctic Convergence” means a line joining the following points along the parallels of latitude and meridians of longitude: 50 degrees south, 0 degrees; 50 degrees south, 30 degrees east; 45 degrees south, 30 degrees east; 45 degrees south, 80 degrees east; 55 degrees south, 80 degrees east; 55 degrees south, 150 degrees east; 60 degrees south, 150 degrees east; 60 degrees south; 11 So in original. Probably should be a comma. 50 degrees west; 50 degrees south, 50 degrees west; and 50 degrees south, 0 degrees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antarctic marine living resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Antarctic marine living resources The term “Antarctic marine living resources” means the population of finfish, molluscs, crustaceans and all other species of living organisms, including birds, found south of the Antarctic Convergence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Commission The term “Commission” means the Commission for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources established pursuant to article VII of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Convention The term “Convention” means the Convention on the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources, done at Canberra, Australia, May 7, 1980, and entered into force with respect to the United States on April 7, 1982.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harvesting or other associated activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Harvesting or other associated activities The terms “harvesting” and “harvesting or other associated activities” mean—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harvest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Harvest The term “harvest” means to engage in harvesting or other associated activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Import</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Import The term “import” means to land on, bring into, or introduce into, or attempt to land on, bring into, or introduce into, any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, whether or not such landing constitutes an importation within the meaning of the customs laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Person The term “person” means an individual, partnership, corporation, trust, association, and any other entity subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Scientific Committee The term “Scientific Committee” means the Scientific Committee for the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources established pursuant to article XIV of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2432_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Vessel of the United States The term “vessel of the United States” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>