<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2433"><akn:num>2433</akn:num><akn:heading>Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2433. Representatives(a) Representative to the CommissionThe Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation, shall appoint an officer or employee of the United States as the United States representative to the Commission.


(b) Representative to the Scientific CommitteeThe Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall designate the United States representative to the Scientific Committee.


(c) CompensationThe United States representatives to the Commission and the Scientific Committee shall receive no additional compensation by reason of their services as such representatives.


(Pub. L. 98–623, title III, § 304, Nov. 8, 1984, 98 Stat. 3400.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representative to the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Representative to the Commission The Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation, shall appoint an officer or employee of the United States as the United States representative to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representative to the Scientific Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Representative to the Scientific Committee The Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall designate the United States representative to the Scientific Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation The United States representatives to the Commission and the Scientific Committee shall receive no additional compensation by reason of their services as such representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>