<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2441"><akn:num>2441</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2441. Federal agency cooperation(a) Responsibilities(1) For the purpose of carrying out the policies and objectives of the Convention or to implement any decision of the Commission—(A) the Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the heads of other appropriate departments and agencies of the United States, shall continue to support basic research investigations of the Antarctic marine ecosystem as a part of the United States Antarctic Program;

(B) the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Secretary of State and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall design and conduct the program of directed scientific research as set forth in paragraph 2 supplemental to and coordinated with the United States Antarctic Program; and

(C) the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may furnish facilities and personnel to the Commission in order to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions.


(2)(A) The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Director of the National Science Foundation, and other appropriate Federal officials, shall prepare a plan, which shall be updated annually, for conducting the directed research program required under paragraph (1)(B) for each period of three consecutive fiscal years occurring during the period beginning on October 1, 1985, and ending on September 30, 1991. The plan shall—(i) describe priority directed research needs for the implementation of the Convention;

(ii) identify which of those needs are to be fulfilled by the United States; and

(iii) specify the design of the research referred to in paragraph (1)(B) and the funds, personnel, and facilities required for the research, including, in particular, the need for the cost of enhanced ship capacity.


(B) In preparing the plan referred to in subpar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation with other agencies In carrying out their functions under this section, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Director of the National Science Foundation shall consult, as appropriate, with the Marine Mammal Commission and with other departments and agencies of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Icebreaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Icebreaking The Department of Homeland Security shall facilitate planning for the design, procurement, maintenance, deployment, and operation of icebreakers needed to provide a platform for Antarctic research. All funds necessary to support icebreaking operations, except for recurring incremental costs associated with specific projects, shall be allocated to the United States Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>