<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_251g"><akn:num>251g</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition; study and investigation of use of private lands; transmittal to President and Cong</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 251g. Land acquisition; study and investigation of use of private lands; transmittal to President and Congress; transfer of lands to Secretary of Agriculture; excluded property within Indian reservation; continuation of concession contracts; termination of concession contracts and purchase of possessory interest; Indian hunting and fishing rights
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, within the boundaries of the park as revised by and pursuant to sections 251e to 251m of this title, the Secretary is authorized to acquire lands, privately owned aquatic lands, and interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, exchange, or transfer from any Federal agency. Property so acquired shall become part of Olympic National Park and shall be administered by the Secretary subject to the laws and regulations applicable to such park. The Secretary is authorized and directed to exclude from the boundaries of the park such private lands and publicly owned and maintained roads within Grays Harbor County which are near and adjacent to Lake Quinault, and which do not exceed two thousand, one hundred and sixty-eight acres in total. Prior to excluding such lands from the park, the Secretary shall study and investigate current and prospective uses of the private lands, as well as the implications of their exclusion both for the lands involved and for Olympic National Park. The results of such study shall be transmitted to the President and to the Congress within two years of October 21, 1976, and shall take effect unless disapproved by simple majority vote of the House of Representatives or the Senate of the United States of America within ninety legislative days of their submission to the Congress. Property excluded from the boundaries of the park by sections 251e to 251m of this title may be exchanged for non-Federal property within the boundaries; or it may be transferred to the jurisdiction of any Federal agency or to the State of Washington or a p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>