<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/251k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_251k"><akn:num>251k</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic dislocation in land acquisition; exchange of lands; transfers of land within a national for</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 251k. Economic dislocation in land acquisition; exchange of lands; transfers of land within a national forest; concurrence of Secretary of Agriculture
In order to minimize economic dislocation in acquiring property within the park, the Secretary may acquire with the consent of the owner, lands and interests in lands outside the boundaries of the park, but within the State of Washington, and with the concurrence of the Secretary of Agriculture, he may utilize lands and interests therein within a national forest in the State of Washington hereby authorized to be transferred to the Secretary, for the purpose of exchanging lands and interests so acquired or transferred for property within the park.
(Pub. L. 94–578, title III, § 320(h), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2741.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Land ExchangesPub. L. 100–71, title I, July 11, 1987, 101 Stat. 415, provided in part: “That pursuant to 16 U.S.C. 251k, the Secretary may acquire the 270-acre parcel known as Keystone Spit on Whidbey Island, Washington, and convey such parcel to the State of Washington in exchange for the approximately 1,000 acres of tidelands owned by such State within the boundary of Olympic National Park: Provided further, That if recreational uses of these tidelands must be regulated, the National Park Service shall consult with the State of Washington prior to the implementation of any such regulations: Provided further, That the exchange must include the mineral rights of the tidelands.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>