<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2626"><akn:num>2626</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports respecting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2626. Reports respecting standards(a) State authorities and nonregulated utilitiesNot later than one year after November 9, 1978, and annually thereafter for ten years, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each State regulated electric utility for which it has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated electric utility, shall report to the Secretary, in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe, respecting its consideration of the standards established by sections 2621(d) and 2623(b) of this title. Such report shall include a summary of the determinations made and actions taken with respect to each such standard on a utility-by-utility basis.


(b) SecretaryNot later than eighteen months after November 9, 1978, and annually thereafter for ten years, the Secretary shall submit a report to the President and the Congress containing—(1) a summary of the reports submitted under subsection (a),

(2) his analysis of such reports, and

(3) his actions under this chapter, and his recommendations for such further Federal actions, including any legislation, regarding retail electric utility rates (and other practices) as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 95–617, title I, § 116, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3128.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was in the original “this title”, meaning title I (§ 101 et seq.) of Pub. L. 95–617, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3120, which enacted subchapters I to IV of this chapter and section 6808 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and amended sections 6802 to 6807 of Title 42. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2626_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State authorities and nonregulated utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State authorities and nonregulated utilities Not later than one year after November 9, 1978, and annually thereafter for ten years, each State regulatory authority (with respect to each State regulated electric utility for which it has ratemaking authority), and each nonregulated electric utility, shall report to the Secretary, in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe, respecting its consideration of the standards established by sections 2621(d) and 2623(b) of this title. Such report shall include a summary of the determinations made and actions taken with respect to each such standard on a utility-by-utility basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2626_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretary Not later than eighteen months after November 9, 1978, and annually thereafter for ten years, the Secretary shall submit a report to the President and the Congress containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>