<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/268a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/268a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/268a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_268a"><akn:num>268a</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of Fern Lake watershed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 268a. Acquisition of Fern Lake watershed(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Fern Lake Conservation and Recreation Act”.


(b) Findings and purposes(1) FindingsThe Congress finds the following:(A) Fern Lake and its surrounding watershed in Bell County, Kentucky, and Claiborne County, Tennessee, is 11 So in original. Probably should be “are”. within the potential boundaries of Cumberland Gap National Historical Park as originally authorized by the Act of June 11, 1940 (54 Stat. 262; 16 U.S.C. 261 et seq.).

(B) The acquisition of Fern Lake and its surrounding watershed and its inclusion in Cumberland Gap National Historical Park would protect the vista from Pinnacle Overlook, which is one of the park’s most valuable scenic resources and most popular attractions, and enhance recreational opportunities at the park.

(C) Fern Lake is the water supply source for the city of Middlesboro, Kentucky, and environs.

(D) The 4,500-acre Fern Lake watershed is privately owned, and the 150-acre lake and part of the watershed are currently for sale, but the Secretary of the Interior is precluded by the first section of the Act of June 11, 1940 (16 U.S.C. 261), from using appropriated funds to acquire the lands.


(2) PurposesThe purposes of the section are—(A) to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to use appropriated funds if necessary, in addition to other acquisition methods, to acquire from willing sellers Fern Lake and its surrounding watershed, in order to protect scenic and natural resources and enhance recreational opportunities at Cumberland Gap National Historical Park; and

(B) to allow the continued supply of water from Fern Lake to the city of Middlesboro, Kentucky, and environs.



(c) Land acquisition and conveyance authority, Fern Lake, Cumberland Gap National Historical Park(1) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) Fern LakeThe term “Fern Lake” means Fern Lake located in Bell County, Kentucky, and Claiborne County, Tennessee.


(B) LandThe term “land” m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_268a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Fern Lake Conservation and Recreation Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_268a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings and purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_268a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition and conveyance authority, Fern Lake, Cumberland Gap National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Land acquisition and conveyance authority, Fern Lake, Cumberland Gap National Historical Park</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>