<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/272g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/272g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/272g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_272g"><akn:num>272g</akn:num><akn:heading>Land exchange involving school trust land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 272g. Land exchange involving school trust land(a) Exchange requirement(1) In generalIf, not later than 1 year after October 30, 1998, and in accordance with this section, the State of Utah offers to transfer all right, title, and interest of the State in and to the school trust land described in subsection (b)(1) to the United States, the Secretary—(A) shall accept the offer on behalf of the United States; and

(B) not later than 180 days after the date of acceptance, shall convey to the State of Utah all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the land described in subsection (b)(2).


(2) Simultaneous conveyancesTitle to the school trust land shall be conveyed at the same time as conveyance of title to the Federal lands by the Secretary.


(3) Valid existing rightsThe land exchange under this section shall be subject to valid existing rights, and each party shall succeed to the rights and obligations of the other party with respect to any lease, right-of-way, or permit encumbering the exchanged land.



(b) Description of parcels(1) State conveyanceThe school trust land to be conveyed by the State of Utah under subsection (a) is section 16, Township 23 South, Range 22 East of the Salt Lake base and meridian.


(2) Federal conveyanceThe Federal land to be conveyed by the Secretary consists of approximately 639 acres located in section 1, Township 25 South, Range 18 East, Salt Lake base and meridian, and more fully described as follows:(A) Lots 1 through 12.

(B) The S½N½ of such section.

(C) The N½N½N½S½ of such section.


(3) Equivalent valueThe Federal land described in paragraph (2) shall be considered to be of equivalent value to that of the school trust land described in paragraph (1).



(c) Management by State(1) In generalAt least 60 days before undertaking or permitting any surface disturbing activities to occur on land acquired by the State of Utah under this section, the State shall consult with the Utah State Office of the Bureau o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_272g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exchange requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_272g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of parcels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Description of parcels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_272g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management by State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management by State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>