<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2803"><akn:num>2803</akn:num><akn:heading>National Aquaculture Development Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2803. National Aquaculture Development Plan(a) In general(1) Within eighteen months after September 26, 1980, the Secretaries shall establish the National Aquaculture Development Plan.

(2) In developing the Plan, and revisions thereto under subsection (d), beginning not later than six months after September 26, 1980, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, other appropriate Federal officers, States, regional fishery management councils established under section 1852 of this title, and representatives of the aquaculture industry. In addition, the Secretary shall give interested persons and organizations an opportunity to comment during the development of the Plan.


(b) Contents of PlanThe Plan shall—(1) identify aquatic species that the Secretaries determine to have significant potential for culturing on a commercial or other basis;

(2) recommend actions to be taken by the public and private sectors (which may include, but are not limited to, research and development, technical assistance, demonstration, extension education, and training activities) that are necessary to achieve such potential;

(3) address, after taking into account the status of aquaculture regarding the aquatic species concerned—(A) aquaculture facility design and operation,

(B) water quality management,

(C) use of waste products (including thermal effluents),

(D) nutrition and the development of economical feeds, including natural food sources,

(E) life history, genetics, physiology, pathology, and disease control (including research regarding organisms that may not be harmful to fish and shellfish, but are injurious to humans),

(F) processing and market development,

(G) production management and quality control, and

(H) the development of adequate supplies of seed stock;


(4) include, where appropriate, research programs on the effect of aquaculture on estuarine and other water areas and on the management of such areas for aquacu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of Plan The Plan shall— In formulating the Plan, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, take into account any significant action that (i) has been, or is proposed to be, undertaken by any other Federal department or agency, any State agency, or any person, and (ii) may affect the implementation of the Plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions and implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Actions and implementation The Plan shall specify— The specifications of Secretarial responsibilities under paragraph (2) for implementing actions shall be determined on the basis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Revision of Plan The Secretaries shall undertake periodic reviews of the operation and effectiveness of the Plan. If as a result of any such review, or the aquaculture assessment required under subsection (e), the Secretaries determine that— the Secretaries shall appropriately amend the Plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing aquaculture assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Continuing aquaculture assessment The Secretaries, through the coordinating group, shall undertake a continuing assessment of aquaculture in the United States for the purpose of maintaining, on a continuing basis—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>