<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/281e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/281e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/281e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_281e"><akn:num>281e</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and cooperative agreements with State of Idaho, and others</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 281e. Contracts and cooperative agreements with State of Idaho, and others(a) Protection, preservation, maintenance, and operation; obligation of general fund of TreasuryIn order to carry out the purpose of this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior may contract and make cooperative agreements with the States of Idaho, Oregon, Washington, Montana, Wyoming, their political subdivisions or agencies, corporations, associations, the Nez Perce Tribe, or individuals, to protect, preserve, maintain, or operate any site, object, or property included within the Nez Perce National Historical Park, regardless of whether title thereto is in the United States: Provided, That no contract or cooperative agreement shall be made or entered into which will obligate the general fund of the Treasury unless or until Congress has appropriated money for such purpose.


(b) Erection and maintenance of tablets and markersTo facilitate the interpretation of the Nez Perce country the Secretary is authorized to erect and maintain tablets or markers in accordance with the provisions contained in the Act approved August 21, 1935, entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes” (49 Stat. 666).11 See References in Text note below.


(c) Consultation with Nez Perce Tribe officialsThe Secretary shall consult with officials of the Nez Perce Tribe on the interpretation of the park and its history.


(Pub. L. 89–19, § 6, May 15, 1965, 79 Stat. 111; Pub. L. 102–576, § 2(5), (6), Oct. 30, 1992, 106 Stat. 4771.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act approved August 21, 1935, entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes” (49 Stat. 666), referred to in subsec. (b), is act Aug. 21, 1935, ch. 593, 49 Stat. 666, known as the Historic Sites Act of 1935 and also as the His</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection, preservation, maintenance, and operation; obligation of general fund of Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Protection, preservation, maintenance, and operation; obligation of general fund of Treasury In order to carry out the purpose of this subchapter, the Secretary of the Interior may contract and make cooperative agreements with the States of Idaho, Oregon, Washington, Montana, Wyoming, their political subdivisions or agencies, corporations, associations, the Nez Perce Tribe, or individuals, to protect, preserve, maintain, or operate any site, object, or property included within the Nez Perce National Historical Park, regardless of whether title thereto is in the United States: Provided, That no contract or cooperative agreement shall be made or entered into which will obligate the general fund of the Treasury unless or until Congress has appropriated money for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Erection and maintenance of tablets and markers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Erection and maintenance of tablets and markers To facilitate the interpretation of the Nez Perce country the Secretary is authorized to erect and maintain tablets or markers in accordance with the provisions contained in the Act approved August 21, 1935, entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes” (49 Stat. 666).11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with Nez Perce Tribe officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation with Nez Perce Tribe officials The Secretary shall consult with officials of the Nez Perce Tribe on the interpretation of the park and its history.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>