<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/2905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2905"><akn:num>2905</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of State costs for developing, revising, and implementing conservation plans and imple</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2905. Reimbursement of State costs for developing, revising, and implementing conservation plans and implementing certain nongame fish and wildlife conservation actions(a) In generalAny State may apply to the Secretary for reimbursement under this section for costs incurred by the State for the following:(1) The development of a conservation plan.

(2) The revision of an approved conservation plan.

(3) The implementation of nongame fish and wildlife conservation actions approved under section 2904(c) and (d) of this title.

(4) The implementation of conservation actions specified in an approved conservation plan.

(5) The coordination, consolidation, or implementation of the conservation plan or conservation actions approved under this chapter with other related plans or actions developed pursuant to the Act of September 2, 1937 (16 U.S.C. 669e(a)(1)), commonly referred to as the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act [16 U.S.C. 669 et seq.] and the Act of August 9, 1950 (16 U.S.C. 777c(a)(1)), commonly referred to as the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act [16 U.S.C. 777 et seq.].


(b) ApplicationsApplication for reimbursement under this section shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall contain such information as is necessary to enable the Secretary to determine whether the State meets the eligibility requirements set forth in subsection (c).


(c) EligibilityNo State is eligible for reimbursement under this section unless the Secretary finds that the costs, for which reimbursement is sought, have been incurred by the State as follows:(1) If reimbursement is sought under subsection (a)(1), such costs have been incurred in developing a conservation plan that meets the requirements set forth in section 2903 of this title.

(2) If reimbursement is sought under subsection (a)(2), such costs have been incurred in revising the plan in a manner consistent with such requirements.

(3) If reimbursement is sought un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any State may apply to the Secretary for reimbursement under this section for costs incurred by the State for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications Application for reimbursement under this section shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall contain such information as is necessary to enable the Secretary to determine whether the State meets the eligibility requirements set forth in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility No State is eligible for reimbursement under this section unless the Secretary finds that the costs, for which reimbursement is sought, have been incurred by the State as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement Subject to the limitations in subsection (c) and the terms and conditions imposed under section 2906 of this title, and to the availability of funds appropriated under section 2910 of this title, the Secretary shall reimburse each State which the Secretary finds to be eligible therefor under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>