<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3142"><akn:num>3142</akn:num><akn:heading>Arctic National Wildlife Refuge coastal plain resource assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3142. Arctic National Wildlife Refuge coastal plain resource assessment(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide for a comprehensive and continuing inventory and assessment of the fish and wildlife resources of the coastal plain of the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge; an analysis of the impacts of oil and gas exploration, development, and production, and to authorize exploratory activity within the coastal plain in a manner that avoids significant adverse effects on the fish and wildlife and other resources.


(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) The term “coastal plain” means that area identified as such in the map entitled “Arctic National Wildlife Refuge”, dated August 1980.

(2) The term “exploratory activity” means surface geological exploration or seismic exploration, or both, for oil and gas within the coastal plain.


(c) Baseline studyThe Secretary, in consultation with the Governor of the State, Native Village and Regional Corporations, and the North Slope Borough within the study area and interested persons, shall conduct a continuing study of the fish and wildlife (with special emphasis on caribou, wolves, wolverines, grizzly bears, migratory waterfowl, musk oxen, and polar bears) of the coastal plain and their habitat. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall—(A) assess the size, range, and distribution of the populations of the fish and wildlife;

(B) determine the extent, location and carrying capacity of the habitats of the fish and wildlife;

(C) assess the impacts of human activities and natural processes on the fish and wildlife and their habitats;

(D) analyze the potential impacts of oil and gas exploration, development, and production on such wildlife and habitats; and

(E) analyze the potential effects of such activities on the culture and lifestyle (including subsistence) of affected Native and other people.


Within eighteen months after December 2, 1980, the Secretary shall publish the results of the study as of that </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide for a comprehensive and continuing inventory and assessment of the fish and wildlife resources of the coastal plain of the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge; an analysis of the impacts of oil and gas exploration, development, and production, and to authorize exploratory activity within the coastal plain in a manner that avoids significant adverse effects on the fish and wildlife and other resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Baseline study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Baseline study The Secretary, in consultation with the Governor of the State, Native Village and Regional Corporations, and the North Slope Borough within the study area and interested persons, shall conduct a continuing study of the fish and wildlife (with special emphasis on caribou, wolves, wolverines, grizzly bears, migratory waterfowl, musk oxen, and polar bears) of the coastal plain and their habitat. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall— Within eighteen months after December 2, 1980, the Secretary shall publish the results of the study as of that date and shall thereafter publish such revisions thereto as are appropriate as new information is obtained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exploration plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exploration plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification to exploration plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Modification to exploration plans If at any time while exploratory activity is being carried out under an exploration plan approved under subsection (e), the Secretary, on the basis of information available to him, determines that continuation of further activities under the plan or permit will significantly adversely affect fish or wildlife, their habitat, or the environment, the Secretary may suspend the carrying out of activities under the plan or permit for such time, make such modifications to the plan or to the terms and conditions of the permit (or both suspend and so modify) as he determines necessary and appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not earlier than five years after December 2, 1980, and not later than five years and nine months after such date, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect of other laws Until otherwise provided for in law enacted after December 2, 1980, all public lands within the coastal plain are withdrawn from all forms of entry or appropriation under the mining laws, and from operation of the mineral leasing laws, of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>