<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3149" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3149/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3149/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3149"><akn:num>3149</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil and gas lease applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3149. Oil and gas lease applications(a) Lands within National Wildlife Refuge System but not part of National Wilderness Preservation SystemNotwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, whenever the Secretary receives an application for an oil and gas lease pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 [30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.] for lands in Alaska within a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System which are not also part of the national Wilderness Preservation System he shall, in addition to any other requirements of applicable law, follow the procedures set forth in this section.


(b) Statement of reasons for decision to issue or not to issue leaseAny decision to issue or not to issue a lease shall be accompanied by a statement setting forth the reasons for the decision, including the reasons why oil and gas leasing would be compatible or incompatible with the purposes of the refuge.


(c) Environmental impact statementIf the Secretary determines that the requirements of section 4332(2)(C) of title 42 do not apply to his decision, the Secretary shall render his decision within six months after receipt of a lease application. If such requirements are applicable to the Secretary’s decision, he shall render his decision within three months after publication of the final environmental impact statement.


(Pub. L. 96–487, title X, § 1009, Dec. 2, 1980, 94 Stat. 2456.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Mineral Leasing Act of 1920, referred to in subsec. (a), is act Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85, 41 Stat. 437, known as the Mineral Leasing Act, which is classified generally to chapter 3A (§ 181 et seq.) of Title 30, Mineral Lands and Mining. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 181 of Title 30 and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3149_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands within National Wildlife Refuge System but not part of National Wilderness Preservation System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lands within National Wildlife Refuge System but not part of National Wilderness Preservation System Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, whenever the Secretary receives an application for an oil and gas lease pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 [30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.] for lands in Alaska within a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System which are not also part of the national Wilderness Preservation System he shall, in addition to any other requirements of applicable law, follow the procedures set forth in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3149_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of reasons for decision to issue or not to issue lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statement of reasons for decision to issue or not to issue lease Any decision to issue or not to issue a lease shall be accompanied by a statement setting forth the reasons for the decision, including the reasons why oil and gas leasing would be compatible or incompatible with the purposes of the refuge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3149_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental impact statement If the Secretary determines that the requirements of section 4332(2)(C) of title 42 do not apply to his decision, the Secretary shall render his decision within six months after receipt of a lease application. If such requirements are applicable to the Secretary’s decision, he shall render his decision within three months after publication of the final environmental impact statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>