<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3164"><akn:num>3164</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3164. Procedural requirements(a) In generalNotwithstanding any provision of applicable law, no action by any Federal agency under applicable law with respect to the approval or disapproval of the authorization, in whole or in part, of any transportation or utility system shall have any force or effect unless the provisions of this section are complied with.


(b) Consolidated applications(1) Within one hundred and eighty days after December 2, 1980, the Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall jointly prescribe and publish a consolidated application form to be used for applying for the approval of each type of transportation or utility system. Each such application form shall be designed to elicit such information as may be necessary to meet the requirements of this subchapter and the applicable law with respect to the type of system concerned.

(2) For purposes of this section, the heads of all appropriate Federal agencies, including the Secretary of Transportation, shall share decisionmaking responsibility in the case of any transportation or utility system described in section 3162(4)(B)(ii), (iii), or (vii) of this title; but with respect to any such system for which he does not have programmatic responsibility, the Secretary of Transportation shall provide to the other Federal agencies concerned such planning and other assistance as may be appropriate.


(c) FilingEach applicant for the approval of any transportation or utility system shall file on the same day an application with each appropriate Federal agency. The applicant shall utilize the consolidated form prescribed under subsection (b) for the type of transportation or utility system concerned.


(d) Agency notice(1) Within sixty days after the receipt of an application filed pursuant to subsection (c), the head of each Federal agency with whom the application was filed shall inform the app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any provision of applicable law, no action by any Federal agency under applicable law with respect to the approval or disapproval of the authorization, in whole or in part, of any transportation or utility system shall have any force or effect unless the provisions of this section are complied with.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consolidated applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Filing Each applicant for the approval of any transportation or utility system shall file on the same day an application with each appropriate Federal agency. The applicant shall utilize the consolidated form prescribed under subsection (b) for the type of transportation or utility system concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agency notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental impact statement The draft of any environmental impact statement required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] in connection with any application filed under this section shall be completed, within nine months from the date of filing, by the head of the Federal agency assigned lead responsibility for the statement. Any such statement shall be jointly prepared by all Federal agencies with which the application was filed under subsection (c). The final environmental impact statement shall be completed within one year from the date of such filing. Such nine-month and one-year periods may be extended for good cause by the Federal agency head assigned lead responsibility for the preparation of such statement if he determines that additional time is necessary for such preparation, notifies the applicant in writing of such determination, and publishes notice of such determination, together with the reasons therefor, in the Federal Regi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other views</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other views During both the nine-month period, and the succeeding three-month period plus any extension thereof provided for in subsection (e), the heads of the Federal agencies concerned shall solicit and consider the views of other Federal departments and agencies, the Alaska Land Use Council, the State, affected units of local government in the State, and affected corporations formed pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.], and, after public notice, shall receive and consider statements and recommendations regarding the application submitted by interested individuals and organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3164_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Agency decision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>