<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3181" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3181/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3181/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3181"><akn:num>3181</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska Land Use Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3181. Alaska Land Use Council(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established the Alaska Land Use Council (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Council”).


(b) CochairmenThe Council shall have Cochairmen. The Federal Cochairman shall be appointed by the President of the United States with the advice and consent of the Senate. The State Cochairman shall be the Governor of Alaska.


(c) MembersIn addition to the Cochairmen, the Council shall consist of the following members:(1) the head of the Alaska offices of each of the following Federal agencies: National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, United States Forest Service, Bureau of Land Management, Heritage Conservation and Recreation Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and Department of Transportation;

(2) the Commissioners of the Alaska Departments of Natural Resources, Fish and Game, Environmental Conservation, and Transportation; and

(3) two representatives selected by the Alaska Native Regional Corporations (in consultation with their respective Village Corporations) which represent the twelve geographic regions described in section 1606(a) of title 43.


Any vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.

(d) State decision not to participateIf the State elects not to participate on the Council or elects to end its participation prior to termination of the Council, the Council shall be composed of the Federal Cochairman, the agencies referred to in subsection (c)(1) and the representatives of the Alaska Native Regional Corporations referred to in subsection (c)(3). The Council, so composed, shall carry out the administrative functions required by this subchapter and shall make recommendations to Federal officials with respect to the matters referred to in subsections (i) and (j). In addition, the Council may make recommendations from time to time to State officials and private landowners concerning su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established the Alaska Land Use Council (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cochairmen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cochairmen The Council shall have Cochairmen. The Federal Cochairman shall be appointed by the President of the United States with the advice and consent of the Senate. The State Cochairman shall be the Governor of Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Members In addition to the Cochairmen, the Council shall consist of the following members: Any vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State decision not to participate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State decision not to participate If the State elects not to participate on the Council or elects to end its participation prior to termination of the Council, the Council shall be composed of the Federal Cochairman, the agencies referred to in subsection (c)(1) and the representatives of the Alaska Native Regional Corporations referred to in subsection (c)(3). The Council, so composed, shall carry out the administrative functions required by this subchapter and shall make recommendations to Federal officials with respect to the matters referred to in subsections (i) and (j). In addition, the Council may make recommendations from time to time to State officials and private landowners concerning such matters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation and expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings; authorities; reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings; authorities; reports The Council shall meet at the call of the Cochairmen, but not less than four times each year. In addition, the Council may, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section, hold such hearings, take such testimony, receive such evidence and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute reports concerning so much of its proceedings as the Council deems advisable. No later than February 1 of each calendar year following the calendar year in which the Council is established, the Cochairmen shall submit to the President, the Congress, the Governor of Alaska, and the Alaska Legislature, in writing, a report on the activities of the Council during the previous year, together with their recommendations, if any, for legislative or other action in furtherance of the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules The Council shall adopt such internal rules of procedure as it deems necessary. All Council meetings shall be open to the public, and at least fifteen days prior to the date when any meeting of the Council is to take place the Cochairman shall publish public notice of such meeting in the Federal Register and in newspapers of general circulation in various areas throughout Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of the Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Functions of the Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3181_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative planning</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>