<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3192" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3192/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3192/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3192"><akn:num>3192</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3192. Land acquisition authority(a) General authorityExcept as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary is authorized, consistent with other applicable law in order to carry out the purposes of this Act, to acquire by purchase, donation, exchange, or otherwise any lands within the boundaries of any conservation system unit other than National Forest Wilderness.


(b) RestrictionsLands located within the boundaries of a conservation system unit which are owned by—(A) the State or a political subdivision of the State;

(B) a Native Corporation or Native Group which has Natives as a majority of its stockholders;

(C) the actual occupant of a tract, title to the surface estate of which was on, before, or after December 2, 1980, conveyed to such occupant pursuant to section 1613(c)(1) and (h)(5) of title 43, unless the Secretary determines that the tract is no longer occupied for the purpose described in section 1613(c)(1) or (h)(5) of title 43 for which the tract was conveyed and that activities on the tract are or will be detrimental to the purposes of the unit in which the tract is located; or

(D) a spouse or lineal descendant of the actual occupant of a tract described in subparagraph (C), unless the Secretary determines that activities on the tract are or will be detrimental to the purposes of the unit in which the tract is located—


may not be acquired by the Secretary without the consent of the owner.

(c) ExchangesLands located within the boundaries of a conservation system unit (other than National Forest Wilderness) which are owned by persons or entities other than those described in subsection (b) of this section shall not be acquired by the Secretary without the consent of the owner unless prior to final judgment on the value of the acquired land, the owner, after being offered appropriate land of similar characteristics and like value (if such land is available from public lands located outside the boundaries of any conservation</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, the Secretary is authorized, consistent with other applicable law in order to carry out the purposes of this Act, to acquire by purchase, donation, exchange, or otherwise any lands within the boundaries of any conservation system unit other than National Forest Wilderness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions Lands located within the boundaries of a conservation system unit which are owned by— may not be acquired by the Secretary without the consent of the owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exchanges Lands located within the boundaries of a conservation system unit (other than National Forest Wilderness) which are owned by persons or entities other than those described in subsection (b) of this section shall not be acquired by the Secretary without the consent of the owner unless prior to final judgment on the value of the acquired land, the owner, after being offered appropriate land of similar characteristics and like value (if such land is available from public lands located outside the boundaries of any conservation system unit), chooses not to accept the exchange. In identifying public lands for exchange pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the Alaska Land Use Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Improved property No improved property shall be acquired under subsection (a) without the consent of the owner unless the Secretary first determines that such acquisition is necessary to the fulfillment of the purposes of this Act or to the fulfillment of the purposes for which the concerned conservation system unit was established or expanded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retained rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Retained rights The owner of an improved property on the date of its acquisition, as a condition of such acquisition, may retain for himself, his heirs and assigns, a right of use and occupancy of the improved property for noncommercial residential or recreational purposes, as the case may be, for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the death of his spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the owner’s interest in the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value on that date of the right retained by the owner. A right retained by the owner pursuant to this section shall be subject to termination by the Secretary upon his determination that such right is being exercised in a manner inconsistent with the purposes of this Act, and it sh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Improved property” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Improved property” defined For the purposes of this section, the term “improved property” means— In determining when and to what extent a property is to be considered an “improved property”, the Secretary shall take into consideration the manner of use of such buildings and lands prior to January 1, 1980, and shall designate such lands as are reasonably necessary for the continued enjoyment of the property in the same manner and to the same extent as existed before such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of hardship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Consideration of hardship The Secretary shall give prompt and careful consideration to any offer made by the owner of any property within a conservation system unit to sell such property, if such owner notifies the Secretary that the continued ownership is causing, or would result in, undue hardship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exchange authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3192_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donation or exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Donation or exchange</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>