<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3195" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3195/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3195/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3195"><akn:num>3195</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative information and education centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3195. Cooperative information and education centers
The Secretary is authorized in consultation with other Federal agencies, to investigate and plan for an information and education center for visitors to Alaska on not to exceed one thousand acres of Federal land at a site adjacent to the Alaska Highway, and to investigate and plan for similar centers in Anchorage and Fairbanks, Alaska. For the purposes of this investigation, the Secretary shall seek participation in the program planning and/or operation of such centers from appropriate agencies of the State of Alaska, and he is authorized to accept contributions of funds, personnel, and planning and program assistance from such State agencies, other Federal agencies, and Native representatives. The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to investigate and plan for, in a similar manner, an information and education center for visitors to Alaska in either Juneau, Ketchikan, or Sitka, Alaska. No information center shall be developed pursuant to investigations and plans conducted under authority of this section unless and until such development is specifically authorized by Congress.
(Pub. L. 96–487, title XIII, § 1305, Dec. 2, 1980, 94 Stat. 2478.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Authorization of Appropriations; Purposes of Center; Operation of Center; Development PlansPub. L. 99–664, § 11, Nov. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 4308, provided that:
“(a) Authorization.—There is hereby authorized to be appropriated $250,000 to be used by the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct surveys, develop designs, and carry out other preliminary work related to the establishment of an Information and Education Center provided for in section 1305 of Public Law 96–487 [16 U.S.C. 3195].

“(b) Purposes.—The purposes of the Center authorized by subsection (a) shall be—“(1) to collect and disseminate to visitors to and residents of Alaska information about the natural, recreational, cultural, historical, archeological, multiple use, and o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>