<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3198" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3198/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3198/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3198"><akn:num>3198</akn:num><akn:heading>Local hire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3198. Local hire(a) ProgramAfter consultation with the Office of Personnel Management, the Secretary shall establish an excepted service appointment authority, under which any individual who, by reason of having lived or worked in or near public lands, has special knowledge or expertise concerning the natural or cultural resources of public lands and the management thereof (as determined by the Secretary) shall be considered for selection for any position within public lands without regard to—(1) any provision of the civil service laws or regulations thereunder which require minimum periods of formal training or experience,

(2) any such provision which provides an employment preference to any other class of applicant is such selection, and

(3) any numerical limitation on personnel otherwise applicable.


Individuals appointed under this subsection shall not be taken into account in applying any personnel limitation described in paragraph (3).

(b) Preference eligibles within local hireNotwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a), any individual who is eligible to be selected for a position under the provisions of subsection (a) and is a preference eligible as defined in section 2108(3) of title 5 shall be given an employment preference, consistent with the preference in the excepted service as defined in section 2103 of such title.


(c) Payment of expenses after death of an employee(1) Definition of immediate family memberIn this subsection, the term “immediate family member” means a person related to a deceased employee that was a member of the household of the deceased employee at the time of death.


(2) PaymentsIf an employee appointed under the program established by subsection (a) dies in the performance of any assigned duties on or after October 1, 2002, the Secretary may—(A) pay or reimburse reasonable expenses, regardless of when those expenses are incurred, for the preparation and transportation of the remains of the deceased employee to a locatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program After consultation with the Office of Personnel Management, the Secretary shall establish an excepted service appointment authority, under which any individual who, by reason of having lived or worked in or near public lands, has special knowledge or expertise concerning the natural or cultural resources of public lands and the management thereof (as determined by the Secretary) shall be considered for selection for any position within public lands without regard to— Individuals appointed under this subsection shall not be taken into account in applying any personnel limitation described in paragraph (3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference eligibles within local hire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preference eligibles within local hire Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a), any individual who is eligible to be selected for a position under the provisions of subsection (a) and is a preference eligible as defined in section 2108(3) of title 5 shall be given an employment preference, consistent with the preference in the excepted service as defined in section 2103 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of expenses after death of an employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of expenses after death of an employee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports The Secretary shall from time to time prepare and submit to the Congress reports indicating the actions taken in carrying out the provisions of subsection (a) of this section together with any recommendations for legislation in furtherance of the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Competitive status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>