<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3233" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3233/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3233/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3233"><akn:num>3233</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Congressional review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3233. Expedited Congressional review(a) RulemakingThis subsection is enacted by Congress—(1) as an exercise of the rulemaking power of each House of Congress, respectively, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in the House in the case of resolutions described by subsection (b) of this section and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent therewith; and

(2) with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as those relate to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of such House.


(b) ResolutionFor purposes of this section, the term “resolution” means a joint resolution, the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the House of Representatives and Senate approve the recommendation of the President for              in              submitted to the Congress on              19    .”, the first blank space therein to be filled in with appropriate activity, the second blank space therein to be filled in with the name or description of the area of land affected by the activity, and the third blank space therein to be filled with the date on which the President submits his recommendation to the House of Representatives and the Senate. Such resolution may also include material relating to the application and effect of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] to the recommendation.


(c) ReferralA resolution once introduced with respect to such Presidential recommendation shall be referred to one or more committees (and all resolutions with respect to the same Presidential recommendation shall be referred to the same committee or committees) by the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Representatives, as the case may be.


(d) Other proceduresExcept as otherwise provided in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3233_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rulemaking This subsection is enacted by Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3233_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Resolution For purposes of this section, the term “resolution” means a joint resolution, the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the House of Representatives and Senate approve the recommendation of the President for              in              submitted to the Congress on              19    .”, the first blank space therein to be filled in with appropriate activity, the second blank space therein to be filled in with the name or description of the area of land affected by the activity, and the third blank space therein to be filled with the date on which the President submits his recommendation to the House of Representatives and the Senate. Such resolution may also include material relating to the application and effect of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] to the recommendation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3233_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Referral A resolution once introduced with respect to such Presidential recommendation shall be referred to one or more committees (and all resolutions with respect to the same Presidential recommendation shall be referred to the same committee or committees) by the President of the Senate or the Speaker of the House of Representatives, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3233_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other procedures Except as otherwise provided in this section the provisions of section 719f(d) of title 15 shall apply to the consideration of the resolution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>