<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3333" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3333/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3333/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3333"><akn:num>3333</akn:num><akn:heading>Program approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3333. Program approval(a) Submission for approvalThe State shall submit its program and submit revisions, modifications, or amendments to the Secretary in accordance with standards established pursuant to section 3332 of this title and in such manner and form as the Secretary shall prescribe.


(b) Requirements for approvalPrior to approving such program or any revision, modification, or amendment, and authorizing Federal funds to be distributed in accordance with this subchapter, the Secretary must find that—(1) the State, acting through its chosen agency or agencies, has authority to carry out a commercial and charter vessel fleet reduction program in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter;

(2) the State program provides that a fishing or charter vessel may not be purchased by the State from other than the person who owned the vessel on December 22, 1980;

(3) the State program prevents the expenditure of a disproportionate amount of funds available for vessel acquisition on vessels owned by any one person;

(4) the State program prohibits the purchase of any fishing or charter vessel unless all State commercial and charter salmon fishing licenses attached to the vessel are also sold to the State;

(5) the State program provides that no person may purchase from the State any vessel which that person or a member of that person’s immediate family had previously sold to the State;

(6) the State program provides that no person may purchase any vessel sold to the State pursuant to the program and use such vessel for commercial or charter salmon fishing in the Washington conservation area, unless State law provides that the use of such vessel could not result in any additional fishing effort in the non-Indian fishing fleet;

(7) the State program provides for purchase of vessels at their fair market value;

(8) the State program provides for the reduction of salmon fishing licenses, through purchase of such licenses at their fair market value, and the use</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3333_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission for approval The State shall submit its program and submit revisions, modifications, or amendments to the Secretary in accordance with standards established pursuant to section 3332 of this title and in such manner and form as the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3333_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for approval Prior to approving such program or any revision, modification, or amendment, and authorizing Federal funds to be distributed in accordance with this subchapter, the Secretary must find that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3333_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretarial action The Secretary shall approve such program within ninety days of the date of receipt of the program if found to be consistent with this chapter and other applicable law. If the Secretary finds that such program is not in conformity with the provisions of this chapter or other applicable law, he shall return such program to the State with recommendations. Any revision, modification, or amendment to the program shall be approved within thirty days of receipt unless found to be inconsistent with this chapter or other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>