<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3377" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3377/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3377/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3377"><akn:num>3377</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3377. Exceptions(a) Activities regulated by plan under Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management ActThe provisions of paragraph (1) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to any activity regulated by a fishery management plan in effect under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.).


(b) Activities regulated by Tuna Convention Acts; harvesting of highly migratory species taken on high seasThe provisions of paragraphs (1), (2)(A), and (3)(A) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to—(1) any activity regulated by the Tuna Conventions Act of 1950 (16 U.S.C. 951–961) or the Atlantic Tunas Convention Act of 1975 (16 U.S.C. 971–971(h) 11 So in original. Probably was meant to be “971–971h”.); or

(2) any activity involving the harvesting of highly migratory species (as defined in paragraph (14) of section 3 22 See References in Text note below. of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [16 U.S.C. 1802(14)]) taken on the high seas (as defined in paragraph (13) of such section 3) if such species are taken in violation of the laws of a foreign nation and the United States does not recognize the jurisdiction of the foreign nation over such species.


(c) Interstate shipment or transshipment through Indian country of fish, wildlife, or plants for legal purposesThe provisions of paragraph (2) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to the interstate shipment or transshipment through Indian country as defined in section 1151 of title 18 or a State of any fish or wildlife or plant legally taken if the shipment is en route to a State in which the fish or wildlife or plant may be legally possessed.


(Pub. L. 97–79, § 8, Nov. 16, 1981, 95 Stat. 1078.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 94–265, Apr. 13, 1976, 90 Stat. 331, which is classified principally to chapter 38 (§ 1801</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3377_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities regulated by plan under Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Activities regulated by plan under Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act The provisions of paragraph (1) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to any activity regulated by a fishery management plan in effect under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3377_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities regulated by Tuna Convention Acts; harvesting of highly migratory species taken on high seas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities regulated by Tuna Convention Acts; harvesting of highly migratory species taken on high seas The provisions of paragraphs (1), (2)(A), and (3)(A) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3377_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate shipment or transshipment through Indian country of fish, wildlife, or plants for legal purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interstate shipment or transshipment through Indian country of fish, wildlife, or plants for legal purposes The provisions of paragraph (2) of section 3372(a) of this title shall not apply to the interstate shipment or transshipment through Indian country as defined in section 1151 of title 18 or a State of any fish or wildlife or plant legally taken if the shipment is en route to a State in which the fish or wildlife or plant may be legally possessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>