<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/342b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/342b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/342b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_342b"><akn:num>342b</akn:num><akn:heading>Lafayette National Park name changed to Acadia National Park; land unaffected by Federal Power Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 342b. Lafayette National Park name changed to Acadia National Park; land unaffected by Federal Power Act
The area now within the Lafayette National Park, together with such additions as may hereafter be made thereto, shall be known as the Acadia National Park, under which name the aforesaid national park shall be entitled to receive and to use all moneys heretofore or hereafter appropriated for the Lafayette National Park: Provided, That the provisions of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.] shall not apply to or extend to any lands now or hereafter included in said park.
(Jan. 19, 1929, ch. 77, § 2, 45 Stat. 1083.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Power Act, referred to in text, was in the original the “Act of June 10, 1920, entitled ‘An Act to create a Federal Power Commission, to provide for the improvement of navigation, the development of water power, the use of the public lands in relation thereto, and to repeal section 18 of the River and Harbor Appropriation Act, approved August 8, 1917, and for other purposes’ ”, was redesignated the Federal Power Act by section 791a of this title. The Federal Power Act is act June 10, 1920, ch. 285, 41 Stat. 1063, and is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 791a of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>