<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3451"><akn:num>3451</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3451. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Area planThe term “area plan” means a resource conservation and use plan developed through a locally led planning process by a council for a designated area of 1 or more States, or of land under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe, that includes 1 or more of the following elements:(A) A land conservation element, the purpose of which is to control erosion and sedimentation.

(B) A water management element that provides 1 or more clear environmental or conservation benefits, the purpose of which is to provide for—(i) the conservation, use, and quality of water, including irrigation and rural water supplies;

(ii) the mitigation of floods and high water tables;

(iii) the repair and improvement of reservoirs;

(iv) the improvement of agricultural water management; and

(v) the improvement of water quality.


(C) A community development element, the purpose of which is to improve—(i) the development of resources-based industries;

(ii) the protection of rural industries from natural resource hazards;

(iii) the development of adequate rural water and waste disposal systems;

(iv) the improvement of recreation facilities;

(v) the improvement in the quality of rural housing;

(vi) the provision of adequate health and education facilities;

(vii) the satisfaction of essential transportation and communication needs; and

(viii) the promotion of food security, economic development, and education.


(D) A land management element, the purpose of which is—(i) energy conservation, including the production of energy crops;

(ii) the protection of agricultural land, as appropriate, from conversion to other uses;

(iii) farmland protection; and

(iv) the protection of fish and wildlife habitats.



(2) BoardThe term “Board” means the Resource Conservation and Development Policy Advisory Board established under section 3456(a) of this title.


(3) CouncilThe term “council” means a nonprofit entity (including an affiliate of the entity) op</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Area plan The term “area plan” means a resource conservation and use plan developed through a locally led planning process by a council for a designated area of 1 or more States, or of land under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe, that includes 1 or more of the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Board The term “Board” means the Resource Conservation and Development Policy Advisory Board established under section 3456(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Council The term “council” means a nonprofit entity (including an affiliate of the entity) operating in a State that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Designated area The term “designated area” means a geographic area designated by the Secretary to receive technical assistance and financial assistance under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Financial assistance The term “financial assistance” means a grant or loan provided by the Secretary (or the Secretary and other Federal agencies) to, or a cooperative agreement entered into by the Secretary (or the Secretary and other Federal agencies) with, a council, or association of councils, to carry out an area plan in a designated area, including assistance provided for planning, analysis, feasibility studies, training, education, and other activities necessary to carry out the area plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local unit of government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Local unit of government The term “local unit of government” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Locally led planning process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Locally led planning process The term “planning process” means actions taken by a locally led council to develop and carry out an effective area plan in a designated area, including development of the area plan, goals, purposes, policies, implementation activities, evaluations and reviews, and the opportunity for public participation in the actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Nonprofit organization The term “nonprofit organization” means any organization that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3451_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Project The term “project” means a project that is carried out by a council to achieve any of the elements of an area plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>