<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/346a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/346a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/346a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_346a_1"><akn:num>346a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Addition of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 346a–1. Addition of lands
The boundaries of the Zion National Park are revised to include the following described lands:
Salt Lake Meridian
Township 39 south, range 10 west: Section 30, those portions of lots 1 to 7, inclusive, lying south of Kolob Creek and lots 8 to 32, inclusive; section 31, lots 1, 2, 3, 15, 16, 17, 18, 31 and 32.
Township 41 south, range 10 west: Section 28, northeast quarter, that portion of the northwest quarter lying east of the North Fork of the Virgin River and lot 9 of the O. D. Gifford survey, the ownership of which is recorded on page 247 of deed book U12 in Washington County, Utah; section 29, west half; section 31; section 32 (partly surveyed), northeast quarter northwest quarter and west half northwest quarter.
Township 39 south, range 11 west: Section 13, southeast quarter southeast quarter; section 32, north half and southeast quarter.
Township 40 south, range 11 west: Section 5, lots 1 and 2 and south half northeast quarter.
Township 38 south, range 12 west: Section 29, those portions of lot 2 and of the southwest quarter lying east of the easterly right-of-way line of United States Highway 91, identified as project numbered I–01–1(1), Washington County, Utah, said line being 150 feet from and parallel the centerline of such highway, as constructed.
(Pub. L. 86–387, § 1, Feb. 20, 1960, 74 Stat. 4.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>