<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3502"><akn:num>3502</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3502. Definitions(a) In generalFor purposes of this chapter:(1) Coastal barrierThe term “coastal barrier” means—(A) a depositional geologic feature (such as a bay barrier, tombolo, barrier spit, bluff, or barrier island) that—(i) is subject to wave, tidal, and wind energies; and

(ii) protects landward aquatic habitats from direct wave attack; and


(B) all associated aquatic habitats including the adjacent wetlands, marshes, estuaries, inlets, and nearshore waters.


(2) CommitteesThe term “Committees” means the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.


(3) Financial assistance(A) In generalThe term “financial assistance” means any form of loan, grant, guaranty, insurance, payment, rebate, subsidy, or any other form of direct or indirect Federal assistance other than—(i) deposit or account insurance for customers of banks, savings and loan associations, credit unions, or similar institutions;

(ii) the purchase of mortgages or loans by the Government National Mortgage Association, the Federal National Mortgage Association, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;

(iii) assistance for environmental studies, planning, and assessments that are required incident to the issuance of permits or other authorizations under Federal law; and

(iv) assistance pursuant to programs entirely unrelated to development, such as any Federal or federally assisted public assistance program or any Federal old-age survivors or disability insurance program.


(B) Flood insuranceThe term “financial assistance” includes flood insurance described in section 4028 of title 42.



(4) Great LakesThe term “Great Lakes” means Lake Ontario, Lake Erie, Lake Huron, Lake St. Clair, Lake Michigan, and Lake Superior, to the extent that those lakes are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.


(5) Otherwise Protected Area(A) In generalThe term “Otherwise Protected Area” means any unit of the System</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Savings clause Nothing in this section supersedes the official maps described in section 3503(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>