<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3505"><akn:num>3505</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions to limitations on expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3505. Exceptions to limitations on expenditures(a) In generalNotwithstanding section 3504 of this title, the appropriate Federal officer, after consultation with the Secretary, may make Federal expenditures and may make financial assistance available within the System for the following:(1) Any use or facility necessary for the exploration, extraction, or transportation of energy resources which can be carried out only on, in, or adjacent to a coastal water area because the use or facility requires access to the coastal water body.

(2) The maintenance or construction of improvements of existing Federal navigation channels (including the Intracoastal Waterway) and related structures (such as jetties), including the disposal of dredge materials related to such maintenance or construction.

(3) The maintenance, replacement, reconstruction, or repair, but not the expansion, of publicly owned or publicly operated roads, structures, or facilities that are essential links in a larger network or system.

(4) Military activities essential to national security.

(5) The construction, operation, maintenance, and rehabilitation of Coast Guard facilities and access thereto.

(6) Any of the following actions or projects, if a particular expenditure or the making available of particular assistance for the action or project is consistent with the purposes of this chapter:(A) Projects for the study, management, protection, and enhancement of fish and wildlife resources and habitats, including acquisition of fish and wildlife habitats and related lands, stabilization projects for fish and wildlife habitats, and recreational projects.

(B) Establishment, operation, and maintenance of air and water navigation aids and devices, and for access thereto.

(C) Projects under chapter 2003 of title 54 and the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.).

(D) Scientific research, including aeronautical, atmospheric, space, geologic, marine, fish and wildlife, and other resea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding section 3504 of this title, the appropriate Federal officer, after consultation with the Secretary, may make Federal expenditures and may make financial assistance available within the System for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Federal navigation channels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Existing Federal navigation channels For purposes of subsection (a)(2), a Federal navigation channel or a related structure is an existing channel or structure, respectively, if it was authorized before the date on which the relevant System unit or portion of the System unit was included within the System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of highways in Michigan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expansion of highways in Michigan The limitations on the use of Federal expenditures or financial assistance within the System under subsection (a)(3) shall not apply to a highway—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services and facilities outside System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services and facilities outside System</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Otherwise Protected Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability to Otherwise Protected Areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3505_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to additions and insurable structures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability to additions and insurable structures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>