<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3602"><akn:num>3602</akn:num><akn:heading>United States representation on Council and Commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3602. United States representation on Council and Commissions(a) Appointment and qualifications of CommissionersThe United States shall be represented on the Council and Commissions by three United States Commissioners to be appointed by the President to serve at his pleasure. Of such Commissioners, one shall be an official of the United States Government, and two shall be individuals (not officials of the United States Government) who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning the conservation and management of salmon of United States origin.


(b) Alternate CommissionersThe Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, may designate alternate United States Commissioners. In the absence of a Commissioner appointed under subsection (a) of this section, an alternate Commissioner may exercise at any meeting of the Organization, the Council, or any Commission all functions of such Commissioner.


(c) Limited Federal employee statusIndividuals who serve as Commissioners and alternate Commissioners shall not receive any compensation for such service. Such individuals shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.


(d) Consultation with other partiesIn carrying out their functions under the Convention, the Commissioners may consult with the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Councils established by section 302 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1852), and may consult with such other interested parties as they consider appropriate. Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to consultations described in this subsection.


(Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 303, Dec. 29, 1982, 96 Stat. 1952; Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 102(1), July 12, 1983, 97 Stat. 216; Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(117), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4318.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsec. (d). Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and qualifications of Commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment and qualifications of Commissioners The United States shall be represented on the Council and Commissions by three United States Commissioners to be appointed by the President to serve at his pleasure. Of such Commissioners, one shall be an official of the United States Government, and two shall be individuals (not officials of the United States Government) who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning the conservation and management of salmon of United States origin.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate Commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternate Commissioners The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior, may designate alternate United States Commissioners. In the absence of a Commissioner appointed under subsection (a) of this section, an alternate Commissioner may exercise at any meeting of the Organization, the Council, or any Commission all functions of such Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited Federal employee status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limited Federal employee status Individuals who serve as Commissioners and alternate Commissioners shall not receive any compensation for such service. Such individuals shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with other parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation with other parties In carrying out their functions under the Convention, the Commissioners may consult with the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Councils established by section 302 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1852), and may consult with such other interested parties as they consider appropriate. Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to consultations described in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>