<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3606"><akn:num>3606</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3606. Violations and penalties(a) Directed fishing for salmon; Convention, rules and regulationsIt is unlawful for any person, or any vessel, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—(1) to conduct directed fishing for salmon in waters seaward of twelve miles from the baselines from which the breadths of territorial seas are measured, in waters of the Atlantic Ocean north of 36 degrees north latitude; or

(2) to violate any provision of the Convention or this chapter, or of any regulation promulgated under this chapter.


(b) Civil and criminal penaltiesAny person who commits any act that is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall—(1) be liable to the United States for a civil penalty under section 308 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1858) to the same extent as if such act were an act prohibited under section 307 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1857); and

(2) be guilty of an offense under section 309 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1859) to the same extent as if such act were an act prohibited by section 307(1)(D), (E), (F), or (H) of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1857(1)(D), (E), (F), or (H)).


(c) Civil forfeiture of vesselAny vessel used, and any fish (or the fair market value thereof) taken or retained in any manner, in connection with or as the result of the commission of an act which is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to civil forfeiture under section 310 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1860) to the same extent as if such vessel was used in, or such fish was taken or retained in connection with or as the result of, the commission of an act prohibited by section 307 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1857).


(Pub. L. 97–389, title III, § 307, Dec. 29, 1982, 96 Stat. 1953; Pub. L. 98–44, title I, § 102(2), July 12, 1983, 97 Stat. 216.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1983—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 98–44 inserted provision that any fish, or the fair market value thereof, taken or retained in connection with or as the result of the co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directed fishing for salmon; Convention, rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Directed fishing for salmon; Convention, rules and regulations It is unlawful for any person, or any vessel, subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil and criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil and criminal penalties Any person who commits any act that is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3606_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil forfeiture of vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil forfeiture of vessel Any vessel used, and any fish (or the fair market value thereof) taken or retained in any manner, in connection with or as the result of the commission of an act which is unlawful under subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to civil forfeiture under section 310 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1860) to the same extent as if such vessel was used in, or such fish was taken or retained in connection with or as the result of, the commission of an act prohibited by section 307 of the Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1857).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>