<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3632"><akn:num>3632</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3632. United States Section(a) CommissionersThe United States shall be represented on the Commission by four United States Commissioners who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning Pacific salmon, to be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President. Of these, one shall be an official of the United States Government who shall be a nonvoting member of the United States Section; one shall be a resident of the State of Alaska and shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the Governor of that State; one shall be a resident of the States 11 So in original. Probably should be “State”. of Oregon,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. or Washington and shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the Governors of those States; and one shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the treaty Indian tribes of the States of Idaho, Oregon or Washington. Two of the initial appointments shall be for two-year terms; all other appointments shall be for four-year terms. Each Commissioner is eligible for reappointment. Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of any term of office shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. Unless otherwise agreed, the chairmanship of the United States Section shall rotate annually among all four members with the order of rotation determined by lot at the first meeting.


(b) Alternate CommissionersThe Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior, shall designate an Alternate Commissioner for each Commissioner from the respective lists referred to in subsection (a), and may designate an Alternate Commissioner for the Federal Commissioner. In the absence of a Commissioner, the Alternate Commissioner may exercise all functions of such Commissioner at any meeting of the Commission or of the United States Section. Alternate C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commissioners The United States shall be represented on the Commission by four United States Commissioners who are knowledgeable or experienced concerning Pacific salmon, to be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President. Of these, one shall be an official of the United States Government who shall be a nonvoting member of the United States Section; one shall be a resident of the State of Alaska and shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the Governor of that State; one shall be a resident of the States 11 So in original. Probably should be “State”. of Oregon,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. or Washington and shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the Governors of those States; and one shall be appointed from a list of at least six qualified individuals nominated by the treaty Indian tribes of the States of Idaho, Oregon or Washington. Two of the initial appointme</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate Commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternate Commissioners The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior, shall designate an Alternate Commissioner for each Commissioner from the respective lists referred to in subsection (a), and may designate an Alternate Commissioner for the Federal Commissioner. In the absence of a Commissioner, the Alternate Commissioner may exercise all functions of such Commissioner at any meeting of the Commission or of the United States Section. Alternate Commissioners are eligible for reappointment and may attend all meetings of the United States Section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Southern Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Southern Panel The United States shall be represented on the southern Panel by six Panel members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Northern Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Northern Panel The United States shall be represented on the northern Panel by six Panel members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraser River Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fraser River Panel The United States shall be represented on the Fraser River Panel by four Panel members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transboundary Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transboundary Panel The United States shall be represented on the Transboundary Panel by seven panel members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Panel appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Panel appointments Panel members described in subsections (c)(2), (c)(3), (d)(2), and (e)(2) shall be appointed by the Governor of the applicable State. Panel members described in subsections (c)(4) and (e)(3) shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior from lists of nominations provided by the appropriate treaty Indian tribes. All other Panel members shall be appointed by the Secretary: Provided, That at least one member of the northern Panel shall be a voting member of the North Pacific Fishery Management Council, at least one member of the southern Panel shall be a voting member of the Pacific Fishery Management Council; and the Panel members described in subsections (c)(5), (d)(3), and (e)(4) shall be appointed from lists of nominations provided by the Governors of the applicable States. For the northern, southern, and Fraser River panels, the appointing authorities listed above may also designate an alternate Panel member, meeting the same qualifications and having the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Voting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3632_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Consultation In carrying out their functions under the Treaty, the Commissioners and Panel members may consult with such other interested parties as they consider appropriate. Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>