<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3634" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3634/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3634/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3634"><akn:num>3634</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3634. Interagency cooperation(a) States, United States agencies, treaty Indian tribes, private institutions and organizationsIn carrying out the provisions of the Treaty and this chapter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, may arrange for cooperation with agencies of the United States, the States, treaty Indian tribes, private institutions and organizations, and may execute such memoranda as may be necessary to reflect such agreements.


(b) United States agencies; facilities and personnelAgencies of the United States may cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs, and may furnish facilities and personnel, for the purposes of assisting the Commission and Panels in carrying out their responsibilities under the Treaty. Such agencies may accept reimbursement from the Commission for providing such services, facilities, and personnel.


(Pub. L. 99–5, § 5, Mar. 15, 1985, 99 Stat. 11.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3634_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>States, United States agencies, treaty Indian tribes, private institutions and organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) States, United States agencies, treaty Indian tribes, private institutions and organizations In carrying out the provisions of the Treaty and this chapter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, may arrange for cooperation with agencies of the United States, the States, treaty Indian tribes, private institutions and organizations, and may execute such memoranda as may be necessary to reflect such agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3634_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States agencies; facilities and personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States agencies; facilities and personnel Agencies of the United States may cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs, and may furnish facilities and personnel, for the purposes of assisting the Commission and Panels in carrying out their responsibilities under the Treaty. Such agencies may accept reimbursement from the Commission for providing such services, facilities, and personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>