<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3637" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3637/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3637/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3637"><akn:num>3637</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3637. Prohibited acts and penalties(a) Unlawful actsIt is unlawful for any person or vessel subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—(1) to violate any provision of this chapter, or of any regulation adopted hereunder, or of any Fraser River Panel regulation approved by the United States under the Treaty;

(2) to refuse to permit any officer authorized to enforce the provisions of this chapter to board a fishing vessel subject to such person’s control for purposes of conducting any search, investigation, or inspection in connection with the enforcement of this chapter;

(3) to forcibly assault, resist, oppose, impede, intimidate, or interfere with any such authorized officer in the conduct of any search, investigation, or inspection described in paragraph (2);

(4) to resist a lawful arrest for any act prohibited by this section;

(5) to ship, transport, offer for sale, sell, purchase, import, export, or have custody, control, or possession of, any fish taken or retained in violation of this chapter;

(6) to interfere with, delay, or prevent, by any means, the apprehension or arrest of another person, knowing that such other person has committed any act prohibited by this section.


(b) Additional prohibitions and enforcementFor additional prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see section 1826g of this title.


(Pub. L. 99–5, § 8, Mar. 15, 1985, 99 Stat. 12; Pub. L. 114–81, title I, § 104, Nov. 5, 2015, 129 Stat. 657.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 114–81, § 104(1)(B), made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to “this chapter”.
Pub. L. 114–81, § 104(1)(A), inserted “, investigation,” after “search”.
Subsec. (a)(3). Pub. L. 114–81, § 104(2), inserted “, investigation,” after “search” and substituted “paragraph (2);” for “subparagraph (2);”.
Subsec. (a)(5). Pub. L. 114–81, § 104(3), made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3637_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unlawful acts It is unlawful for any person or vessel subject to the jurisdiction of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3637_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional prohibitions and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional prohibitions and enforcement For additional prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see section 1826g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>