<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3772" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3772/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3772/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3772"><akn:num>3772</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3772. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Federal trust speciesThe term “Federal trust species” means migratory birds, threatened species, endangered species, interjurisdictional fish, marine mammals, and other species of concern.


(2) Habitat enhancement(A) In generalThe term “habitat enhancement” means the manipulation of the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a habitat to change a specific function or seral stage of the habitat.


(B) InclusionsThe term “habitat enhancement” includes—(i) an activity conducted to increase or decrease a specific function for the purpose of benefitting species, including—(I) increasing the hydroperiod and water depth of a stream or wetland beyond what would naturally occur;

(II) improving waterfowl habitat conditions;

(III) establishing water level management capabilities for native plant communities;

(IV) creating mud flat conditions important for shorebirds; and

(V) cross fencing or establishing a rotational grazing system on native range to improve grassland nesting bird habitat conditions; and


(ii) an activity conducted to shift a native plant community successional stage, including—(I) burning an established native grass community to reduce or eliminate invading brush or exotic species;

(II) brush shearing to set back early successional plant communities; and

(III) forest management that promotes a particular seral stage.



(C) ExclusionsThe term “habitat enhancement” does not include regularly scheduled and routine maintenance and management activities, such as annual mowing or spraying of unwanted vegetation.



(3) Habitat establishmentThe term “habitat establishment” means the manipulation of physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a project site to create and maintain habitat that did not previously exist on the project site, including construction of—(A) shallow water impoundments on non-hydric soils; and

(B) side channel spawning and rearing habitat.


(4) Habitat improvementThe te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal trust species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Federal trust species The term “Federal trust species” means migratory birds, threatened species, endangered species, interjurisdictional fish, marine mammals, and other species of concern.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Habitat enhancement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Habitat enhancement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Habitat establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Habitat establishment The term “habitat establishment” means the manipulation of physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a project site to create and maintain habitat that did not previously exist on the project site, including construction of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Habitat improvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Habitat improvement The term “habitat improvement” means restoring, enhancing, or establishing physiographic, hydrological, or disturbance conditions necessary to establish or maintain native plant and animal communities, including periodic manipulations to maintain intended habitat conditions on completed project sites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Habitat restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Habitat restoration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Private land</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Project The term “project” means a project carried out under the Partners for Fish and Wildlife Program established by section 3773 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3772_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>