<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3821" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3821/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3821/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3821"><akn:num>3821</akn:num><akn:heading>Program ineligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3821. Program ineligibility(a) Production on converted wetlandExcept as provided in this subchapter and notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person who in any crop year produces an agricultural commodity on converted wetland, as determined by the Secretary, shall be—(1) in violation of this section; and

(2) ineligible for loans or payments in an amount determined by the Secretary to be proportionate to the severity of the violation.


(b) Ineligibility for certain loans and paymentsIf a person is determined to have committed a violation under subsection (a) during a crop year, the Secretary shall determine which of, and the amount of, the following loans and payments for which the person shall be ineligible:(1) Contract payments under a production flexibility contract, marketing assistance loans, and any type of price support or payment made available under the Agricultural Market Transition Act [7 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.], the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (15 U.S.C. 714 et seq.), or any other Act.

(2) A loan made or guaranteed under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1921 et seq.) or any other provision of law administered by the Consolidated Farm Service Agency,11 See Change of Name note below. if the Secretary determines that the proceeds of the loan will be used for a purpose that will contribute to conversion of a wetland (other than as provided in this subchapter) to produce an agricultural commodity.

(3) During the crop year:(A) A payment made pursuant to a contract entered into under the environmental quality incentives program under subpart A of part IV of subchapter IV.

(B) A payment under any other provision of subchapter IV.

(C) A payment under section 2201 or 2202 of this title.

(D) A payment, loan, or other assistance under section 1003 or 1006a of this title.



(c) Ineligibility for crop insurance premium assistance(1) Requirements(A) In generalIf a person is determined to have committed a violation u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production on converted wetland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Production on converted wetland Except as provided in this subchapter and notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person who in any crop year produces an agricultural commodity on converted wetland, as determined by the Secretary, shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility for certain loans and payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ineligibility for certain loans and payments If a person is determined to have committed a violation under subsection (a) during a crop year, the Secretary shall determine which of, and the amount of, the following loans and payments for which the person shall be ineligible:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility for crop insurance premium assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ineligibility for crop insurance premium assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetland conversion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Wetland conversion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prior loans This section shall not apply to a loan described in subsection (b) made before December 23, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3821_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wetland The Secretary shall have, and shall not delegate to any private person or entity, authority to determine whether a person has complied with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>