<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3831b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3831b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3831b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3831b"><akn:num>3831b</akn:num><akn:heading>Farmable wetland program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3831b. Farmable wetland program(a) Program required(1) In generalDuring the 2008 through 2023 fiscal years, the Secretary shall carry out a farmable wetland program in each State under which the Secretary shall enroll eligible acreage described in subsection (b).


(2) Participation among StatesThe Secretary shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that owners and operators in each State have an equitable opportunity to participate in the program established under this section.



(b) Eligible acreage(1) Wetland and related landSubject to subsections (c) and (d), an owner or operator may enroll in the conservation reserve, pursuant to the program established under this section, land—(A) that is wetland (including a converted wetland described in section 3822(b)(1)(A) of this title) that had a cropping history during at least 3 of the immediately preceding 10 crop years;

(B) on which a constructed wetland is to be developed that will receive surface and subsurface flow from row crop agricultural production and is designed to provide nitrogen removal in addition to other wetland functions;

(C) that was devoted to commercial pond-raised aquaculture in any year during the period of calendar years 2002 through 2007; or

(D) that, after January 1, 1990, and before December 31, 2002, was—(i) cropped during at least 3 of 10 crop years; and

(ii) subject to the natural overflow of a prairie wetland.



(2) Buffer acreageSubject to subsections (c) and (d), an owner or operator may enroll in the conservation reserve, pursuant to the program established under this section, buffer acreage that—(A) with respect to land described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1)—(i) is contiguous to such land;

(ii) is used to protect such land; and

(iii) is of such width as the Secretary determines is necessary to protect such land, taking into consideration and accommodating the farming practices (including the straightening of boundaries to accommodate machinery) u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible acreage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner or operator enrollment limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Owner or operator enrollment limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of owners and operators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties of owners and operators During the term of a contract entered into under the program established under this section, an owner or operator shall agree—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3831b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duties of the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>