<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3839aa–25" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3839aa–25/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3839aa–25/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3839aa_25"><akn:num>3839aa–25</akn:num><akn:heading>Grassland conservation initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3839aa–25. Grassland conservation initiative(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible landNotwithstanding sections 3839aa–21(4) and 3839aa–22(b)(2) of this title, the term “eligible land” means cropland on a farm for which base acres have been maintained by the Secretary under section 9012(d)(3) of title 7.


(2) InitiativeThe term “initiative” means the grassland conservation initiative established under subsection (b).



(b) Establishment and purposeThe Secretary shall establish within the program a grassland conservation initiative for the purpose of assisting producers in protecting grazing uses, conserving and improving soil, water, and wildlife resources, and achieving related conservation values by conserving eligible land through grassland conservation contracts under subsection (e).


(c) ElectionBeginning in fiscal year 2019, the Secretary shall provide a 1-time election to enroll eligible land in the initiative under a contract described in subsection (e).


(d) Method of enrollmentThe Secretary shall—(1) notwithstanding subsection (b) of section 3839aa–23 of this title, determine under subsection (c) of that section that eligible land ranks sufficiently high under the evaluation criteria described in subsection (b) of that section; and

(2) enroll the eligible land in the initiative under a contract described in subsection (e).


(e) Grassland conservation contract(1) In generalNotwithstanding section 3839aa–23(a)(1) of this title, to enroll eligible land in the initiative under a grassland conservation contract, a producer shall agree—(A) to meet or exceed the stewardship threshold for not less than 1 priority resource concern by the date on which the contract expires; and

(B) to comply with the terms and conditions of the contract.


(2) TermsA grassland conservation contract entered into under this section shall—(A)(i) be for a single 5-year term; and

(ii) not be subject to renewal or reenrollment under section 3839aa–23(e) of this title; and

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and purpose The Secretary shall establish within the program a grassland conservation initiative for the purpose of assisting producers in protecting grazing uses, conserving and improving soil, water, and wildlife resources, and achieving related conservation values by conserving eligible land through grassland conservation contracts under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election Beginning in fiscal year 2019, the Secretary shall provide a 1-time election to enroll eligible land in the initiative under a contract described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Method of enrollment The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grassland conservation contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grassland conservation contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grassland conservation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grassland conservation plan The grassland conservation plan developed for eligible land shall be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considered planted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Considered planted The Secretary shall consider land enrolled under a grassland conservation contract under this section during a crop year to be planted or considered planted to a covered commodity (as defined in section 9011 of title 7) during that crop year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3839aa_25_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Other contracts A producer with an agricultural operation that contains land eligible under this section and land eligible under section 3839aa–23 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>