<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3842" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3842/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3842/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3842"><akn:num>3842</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3842. Delivery of technical assistance(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible participantThe term “eligible participant” means a producer, landowner, or entity that is participating in, or seeking to participate in, programs in which the producer, landowner, or entity is otherwise eligible to participate under this chapter or the agricultural management assistance program under section 1524(b) of title 7.


(2) Third-party providerThe term “third-party provider” means a commercial entity (including a farmer cooperative, agriculture retailer, or other commercial entity (as defined by the Secretary)), a nonprofit entity, a State or local government (including a conservation district), or a Federal agency, that has expertise in the technical aspect of conservation planning, including nutrient management planning, watershed planning, or environmental engineering.



(b) Purpose of technical assistanceThe purpose of technical assistance authorized by this section is to provide eligible participants with consistent, science-based, site-specific practices designed to achieve conservation objectives on land active in agricultural, forestry, or related uses.


(c) Provision of technical assistanceThe Secretary shall provide technical assistance under this chapter to an eligible participant—(1) directly;

(2) through an agreement with a third-party provider; or

(3) at the option of the eligible participant, through a payment, as determined by the Secretary, to the eligible participant for an approved third-party provider, if available.


(d) Non-Federal assistanceThe Secretary may request the services of, and enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with, other agencies within the Department or non-Federal entities to assist the Secretary in providing technical assistance necessary to assist in implementing conservation programs under this chapter.


(e) Certification of third-party providers(1) PurposeThe purpose of the third-party provider program is to increas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of technical assistance The purpose of technical assistance authorized by this section is to provide eligible participants with consistent, science-based, site-specific practices designed to achieve conservation objectives on land active in agricultural, forestry, or related uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance under this chapter to an eligible participant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Non-Federal assistance The Secretary may request the services of, and enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with, other agencies within the Department or non-Federal entities to assist the Secretary in providing technical assistance necessary to assist in implementing conservation programs under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of third-party providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification of third-party providers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of technical services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability of technical services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of conservation practice standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Review of conservation practice standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3842_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Addressing concerns of specialty crop, organic, and precision agriculture producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Addressing concerns of specialty crop, organic, and precision agriculture producers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>