<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3865c"><akn:num>3865c</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetland reserve easements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3865c. Wetland reserve easements(a) Availability of assistanceThe Secretary shall provide assistance to owners of eligible land to restore, protect, and enhance wetlands through—(1) wetland reserve easements and related wetland reserve easement plans; and

(2) technical assistance.


(b) Easements(1) Method of enrollmentThe Secretary shall enroll eligible land under this section through the use of—(A) 30-year easements;

(B) permanent easements;

(C) easements for the maximum duration allowed under applicable State laws; or

(D) as an option for Indian tribes only, 30-year contracts.


(2) Limitations(A) Ineligible landThe Secretary may not acquire easements on—(i) land established to trees under the conservation reserve program, except in cases where the Secretary determines it would further the purposes of this section; and

(ii) farmed wetlands or converted wetlands where the conversion was not commenced prior to December 23, 1985.


(B) Changes in ownershipNo wetland reserve easement shall be created on land that has changed ownership during the preceding 24-month period unless—(i) the new ownership was acquired by will or succession as a result of the death of the previous owner;

(ii)(I) the ownership change occurred because of foreclosure on the land; and

(II) immediately before the foreclosure, the owner of the land exercises a right of redemption from the mortgage holder in accordance with State law; or


(iii) the Secretary determines that the land was acquired under circumstances that give adequate assurances that such land was not acquired for the purposes of placing it in the program.



(3) Evaluation and ranking of offers(A) CriteriaThe Secretary shall establish evaluation and ranking criteria for offers from landowners under this section to maximize the benefit of Federal investment under the program.


(B) ConsiderationsWhen evaluating offers from landowners, the Secretary may consider—(i) the conservation benefits of obtaining a wetland reserve </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability of assistance The Secretary shall provide assistance to owners of eligible land to restore, protect, and enhance wetlands through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Easements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Easement restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Easement restoration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetland reserve enhancement option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Wetland reserve enhancement option The Secretary may enter into 1 or more agreements with a State (including a political subdivision or agency of a State), nongovernmental organization, or Indian tribe to carry out a special wetland reserve enhancement option that the Secretary determines would advance the purposes of program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application The relevant provisions of this section shall also apply to a 30-year contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>