<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3865a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3865a"><akn:num>3865a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3865a. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Agricultural land easementThe term “agricultural land easement” means an easement or other interest in eligible land that—(A) is conveyed for the purpose of protecting natural resources and the agricultural nature of the land; and

(B) permits the landowner the right to continue agricultural production and related uses.


(2) Buy-protect-sell transaction(A) In generalThe term “buy-protect-sell transaction” means a legal arrangement—(i) between an eligible entity and the Secretary relating to land that an eligible entity owns or is going to purchase prior to acquisition of an agricultural land easement;

(ii) under which the eligible entity certifies to the Secretary that the eligible entity shall—(I)(aa) hold an agricultural land easement on that land, but transfer ownership of the land to a farmer or rancher that is not an eligible entity prior to or on acquisition of the agricultural land easement; or

(bb) hold an agricultural land easement on that land, but transfer ownership of the land to a farmer or rancher that is not an eligible entity in a timely manner and, subject to subparagraph (B), not later than 3 years after the date of acquisition of the agricultural land easement; and


(II) make an initial sale of the land subject to the agricultural land easement to a farmer or rancher at not more than agricultural value, plus any reasonable holding and transaction costs incurred by the eligible entity, as determined by the Secretary; and


(iii) under which the Secretary shall be reimbursed for the entirety of the Federal share of the cost of the agricultural land easement by the eligible entity if the eligible entity fails to transfer ownership under item (aa) or (bb), as applicable, of clause (ii)(I).


(B) Time extensionUnder subparagraph (A)(ii)(I)(bb), an eligible entity may transfer land later than 3 years after the date of acquisition of the agricultural land easement if the Secretary determines an extension of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural land easement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural land easement The term “agricultural land easement” means an easement or other interest in eligible land that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buy-protect-sell transaction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Buy-protect-sell transaction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Eligible entity The term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Eligible land The term “eligible land” means private or tribal land that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Monitoring report The term “monitoring report” means a report, the contents of which are formulated and prepared by the holder of an agricultural land easement, that accurately documents whether the land subject to the agricultural land easement is in compliance with the terms and conditions of the agricultural land easement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Program The term “program” means the agricultural conservation easement program established by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3865a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetland reserve easement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Wetland reserve easement The term “wetland reserve easement” means a reserved interest in eligible land that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>