<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3871c"><akn:num>3871c</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3871c. Assistance to producers(a) In generalA producer may receive financial or technical assistance to conduct eligible activities on eligible land through a program contract entered into with the Secretary.


(b) Program contracts(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program contract to be entered into with a producer to conduct eligible activities on eligible land, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may establish.


(2) Application bundles(A) In generalAn eligible partner may submit to the Secretary, on behalf of producers, a bundle of applications for assistance under the program through program contracts to address a substantial portion of the conservation benefits to be achieved by the project, as defined in the partnership agreement.


(B) PriorityThe Secretary may give priority to applications described in subparagraph (A).




(c) Payments(1) In generalSubject to section 3871d of this title, the Secretary may make payments to a producer in an amount determined by the Secretary to be necessary to achieve the purposes of the program.


(2) Payments to certain producersThe Secretary may provide payments for a period of 5 years—(A) to producers participating in a project that addresses water quantity concerns and in an amount sufficient to encourage conversion from irrigated to dryland farming; and

(B) to producers participating in a project that addresses water quality concerns and in an amount sufficient to encourage adoption of conservation practices and systems that improve nutrient management.


(3) Waiver authorityTo assist in the implementation of the program, the Secretary may waive the applicability of the limitation in section 1308–3a(b)(2) of title 7 for producers if the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary to fulfill the objectives of the program.



(d) Funding through alternative funding arrangements or grant agreements(1) In generalA partnership agreement entered into with an eligible partner may be fund</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A producer may receive financial or technical assistance to conduct eligible activities on eligible land through a program contract entered into with the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding through alternative funding arrangements or grant agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding through alternative funding arrangements or grant agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>