<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3871f"><akn:num>3871f</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical conservation areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3871f. Critical conservation areas(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Critical conservation areaThe term “critical conservation area” means a geographical area that contains a critical conservation condition that can be addressed through the program.


(2) Priority resource concernThe term “priority resource concern” means a natural resource concern located in a critical conservation area that can be addressed through—(A) water quality improvement, including through reducing erosion, promoting sediment control, and addressing nutrient management activities affecting large bodies of water of regional, national, or international significance;

(B) water quantity improvement, including improvement relating to—(i) drought;

(ii) groundwater, surface water, aquifer, or other water sources; or

(iii) water retention and flood prevention;


(C) wildlife habitat restoration to address species of concern at a Federal, State, or local level; and

(D) other natural resource improvements, as determined by the Secretary, within the critical conservation area.



(b) ApplicationsIn administering funds under section 3871d(d)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall select applications for partnership agreements and program contracts within critical conservation areas designated under this section that address 1 or more priority resource concerns for which the critical conservation area is designated.


(c) Critical conservation area designations(1) In generalThe Secretary shall identify 1 or more priority resource concerns that apply to each critical conservation area designated under this section after February 7, 2014, including the conservation goals and outcomes sufficient to demonstrate that progress is being made to address the priority resource concern.


(2) PriorityIn designating critical conservation areas under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to geographical areas based on the degree to which the geographical area—(A) includes multiple States with signific</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications In administering funds under section 3871d(d)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall select applications for partnership agreements and program contracts within critical conservation areas designated under this section that address 1 or more priority resource concerns for which the critical conservation area is designated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical conservation area designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Critical conservation area designations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach to eligible partners and producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Outreach to eligible partners and producers The Secretary shall provide outreach and education to eligible partners and producers in critical conservation areas designated under this section to encourage the development of projects to address each priority resource concern identified by the Secretary for that critical conservation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>