<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3871a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3871a"><akn:num>3871a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3871a. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Covered programThe term “covered program” means the following:(A) The agricultural conservation easement program.

(B) The environmental quality incentives program.

(C) The conservation stewardship program, not including the grassland conservation initiative under section 3839aa–25 of this title.

(D) The healthy forests reserve program established under section 6571 of this title.

(E) The conservation reserve program established under subpart B of part I of subchapter IV.

(F) The programs established by the Secretary to carry out the Watershed Protection and Flood Prevention Act (16 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.), except for any program established by the Secretary to carry out section 14 (16 U.S.C. 1012) of that Act.


(2) Eligible activityThe term “eligible activity” means a practice, activity, agreement, easement, or related conservation measure that is available under the statutory authority for a covered program.


(3) Eligible landThe term “eligible land” means any agricultural or nonindustrial private forest land or associated land on which the Secretary determines an eligible activity would help achieve conservation benefits.


(4) Eligible partnerThe term “eligible partner” means any of the following:(A) An agricultural or silvicultural producer association or other group of producers.

(B) A State or unit of local government.

(C) An Indian tribe.

(D) A farmer cooperative.

(E) A water district, irrigation district, acequia, rural water district or association, or other organization with specific water delivery authority to producers on agricultural land.

(F) A municipal water or wastewater treatment entity.

(G) An institution of higher education.

(H) An organization or entity with an established history of working cooperatively with producers on agricultural land, as determined by the Secretary, to address—(i) local conservation priorities related to agricultural production, wildlife habitat development, or nonind</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Covered program The term “covered program” means the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible activity The term “eligible activity” means a practice, activity, agreement, easement, or related conservation measure that is available under the statutory authority for a covered program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Eligible land The term “eligible land” means any agricultural or nonindustrial private forest land or associated land on which the Secretary determines an eligible activity would help achieve conservation benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible partner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Eligible partner The term “eligible partner” means any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnership agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Partnership agreement The term “partnership agreement” means the programmatic agreement entered into between the Secretary and an eligible partner, subject to the terms and conditions under section 3871b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Program The term “program” means the regional conservation partnership program established by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3871a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Program contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>