<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/391c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/391c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/391c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_391c"><akn:num>391c</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of lands for use as bombing target range</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 391c. Withdrawal of lands for use as bombing target range
Within a tract of land containing six thousand four hundred fifty acres, more or less, on the island of Hawaii in the Territory of Hawaii, located in the Hawaii National Park, created by sections 391, 393 and 394 of this title, and described as follows, to wit:
Beginning at a place called Na Puu O na Elemakule located at the southeastern corner of the Hawaii National Park, said point being marked by a triangle on a large flat stone, thence by azimuth (measured clockwise from true south) and distances as follows: Eighty-nine degrees twenty-seven minutes thirty seconds, three thousand three hundred feet along the southern boundary of Hawaii National Park; one hundred and seventy-nine degrees twenty-seven minutes thirty seconds, fourteen thousand five hundred and fifty feet over and across Pali to a point on Kau Desert Plateau; two hundred and forty-three degrees fifty-seven minutes no seconds, eighteen thousand four hundred and fifty feet to a point located above Hilima Pali; three hundred and fifty-nine degrees twenty-seven minutes thirty seconds, twelve thousand nine-hundred and ninety feet more or less to high-water line; thence in southwesterly direction along the high-water line to the point of beginning; containing an area of six thousand four hundred and fifty acres, more or less; there shall be withdrawn from the control and jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior and transferred to the jurisdiction and control of the Secretary of the Air Force so much thereof as may be agreed upon between the Secretaries of the Air Force and Interior for use as an Air Force bombing target range, and for such other military purposes and uses as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force.
(July 16, 1940, ch. 630, 54 Stat. 761; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 207(a), (f), 61 Stat. 502, 503.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
“Air Force” substituted in text for “War” on authority of section 207(a), (f) of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>