<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3954" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3954/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3954/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3954"><akn:num>3954</akn:num><akn:heading>National coastal wetlands conservation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3954. National coastal wetlands conservation grants(a) Matching grantsThe Director shall, with the funds made available in accordance with section 3955 of this title, make matching grants to any coastal State to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects from funds made available for that purpose.


(b) PrioritySubject to the cost-sharing requirements of this section, the Director may grant or otherwise provide any matching moneys to any coastal State which submits a proposal substantial in character and design to carry out a coastal wetlands conservation project. In awarding such matching grants, the Director shall give priority to coastal wetlands conservation projects that are—(1) consistent with the National Wetlands Priority Conservation Plan developed under section 3921 of this title; and

(2) in coastal States that have established dedicated funding for programs to acquire coastal wetlands, natural areas and open spaces. In addition, priority consideration shall be given to coastal wetlands conservation projects in maritime forests on coastal barrier islands.


(c) ConditionsThe Director may only grant or otherwise provide matching moneys to a coastal State for purposes of carrying out a coastal wetlands conservation project if the grant or provision is subject to terms and conditions that will ensure that any real property interest acquired in whole or in part, or enhanced, managed, or restored with such moneys will be administered for the long-term conservation of such lands and waters and the fish and wildlife dependent thereon.


(d) Cost-sharing(1) Federal shareGrants to coastal States of matching moneys by the Director for any fiscal year to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects shall be used for the payment of not to exceed 50 percent of the total costs of such projects: except that such matching moneys may be used for payment of not to exceed 75 percent of the costs of such projects if a coastal State has established and is using on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Matching grants The Director shall, with the funds made available in accordance with section 3955 of this title, make matching grants to any coastal State to carry out coastal wetlands conservation projects from funds made available for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority Subject to the cost-sharing requirements of this section, the Director may grant or otherwise provide any matching moneys to any coastal State which submits a proposal substantial in character and design to carry out a coastal wetlands conservation project. In awarding such matching grants, the Director shall give priority to coastal wetlands conservation projects that are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions The Director may only grant or otherwise provide matching moneys to a coastal State for purposes of carrying out a coastal wetlands conservation project if the grant or provision is subject to terms and conditions that will ensure that any real property interest acquired in whole or in part, or enhanced, managed, or restored with such moneys will be administered for the long-term conservation of such lands and waters and the fish and wildlife dependent thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cost-sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Partial payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3954_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetlands assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wetlands assessment The Director shall, with the funds made available in accordance with section 3955 of this title, direct the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service’s National Wetland Inventory to update and digitize wetlands maps in the State of Texas and to conduct an assessment of the status, condition, and trends of wetlands in that State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>