<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3957" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3957/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/3957/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3957"><akn:num>3957</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3957. Environmental banks(a) GuidelinesNot later than 1 year after December 16, 2016, the Task Force shall, after public notice and opportunity for comment, issue guidelines for the use, maintenance, and oversight of environmental banks in Louisiana.


(b) RequirementsThe guidelines issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall—(1) set forth procedures for establishment and approval of environmental banks subject to the approval of the heads of the appropriate Federal agencies responsible for implementation of Federal environmental laws for which mitigation credits may be used;

(2) establish criteria for siting of environmental banks that enhance the resilience of coastal resources to inundation and coastal erosion in high priority areas, as identified within Federal or State restoration plans, including the restoration of resources within the scope of a project authorized for construction;

(3) establish criteria that ensure environmental banks secure adequate financial assurances and legally enforceable protection for the land or resources that generate the credits from environmental banks;

(4) stipulate that credits from environmental banks may not be used for mitigation of impacts required under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1342) 11 See References in Text note below. or the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.) in an area where an existing mitigation bank approved pursuant to such laws within 5 years of enactment of the Water Resources Development Act of 2016 has credits available;

(5) establish performance criteria for environmental banks; and

(6) establish criteria and financial assurance for the operation and monitoring of environmental banks.


(c) Environmental bank(1) Definition of environmental bankIn this section, the term “environmental bank” means a project, project increment, or projects for purposes of restoring, creating, or enhancing natural resources at a designated site to establish mitigation credit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3957_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Guidelines Not later than 1 year after December 16, 2016, the Task Force shall, after public notice and opportunity for comment, issue guidelines for the use, maintenance, and oversight of environmental banks in Louisiana.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3957_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements The guidelines issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3957_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3957_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Savings clause</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3957_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sunset No new environmental bank may be created or approved pursuant to this section after the date that is 14 years after December 16, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>