<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/396d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/396d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/396d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_396d"><akn:num>396d</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 396d. Establishment(a) In general(1) In order to provide a center for the preservation, interpretation, and perpetuation of traditional native Hawaiian activities and culture, and to demonstrate historic land use patterns as well as to provide a needed resource for the education, enjoyment, and appreciation of such traditional native Hawaiian activities and culture by local residents and visitors, there is established the Kaloko-Honoko̅hau National Historical Park (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “park”) in Hawaii comprising approximately one thousand three hundred acres as generally depicted on the map entitled “Kaloko-Honoko̅hau National Historical Park,” numbered KHN–80,000, and dated May 1978.

(2) The boundaries of the park are modified to include lands and interests therein comprised of Parcels 1 and 2 totaling 2.14 acres, identified as “Tract A” on the map entitled “Kaloko-Honoko̅hau National Historical Park Proposed Boundary Adjustment”, numbered PWR (PISO) 466/82,043 and dated April 2002.

(3) The maps referred to in this subsection shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(b) Land acquisition; mannerExcept for any lands owned by the State of Hawaii or its subdivisions, which may be acquired only by donation, the Secretary is authorized to acquire the lands described above by donation, exchange, or purchase through the use of donated or appropriated funds, notwithstanding any prior restriction of law.


(c) Administration; applicable provisionsThe Secretary shall administer the park in accordance with this section and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Acts approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 461–467),11 See References in Text note below. and August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.),1 and generally in accordance with the guidelines provided in the study report entitled “Kaloko-Honoko̅h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition; manner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land acquisition; manner Except for any lands owned by the State of Hawaii or its subdivisions, which may be acquired only by donation, the Secretary is authorized to acquire the lands described above by donation, exchange, or purchase through the use of donated or appropriated funds, notwithstanding any prior restriction of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration; applicable provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration; applicable provisions The Secretary shall administer the park in accordance with this section and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Acts approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 461–467),11 See References in Text note below. and August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.),1 and generally in accordance with the guidelines provided in the study report entitled “Kaloko-Honoko̅hau” prepared by the Honokohau Study Advisory Commission and the National Park Service, May 1974, GPO 690–514.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities and agreements; native accommodations; cooperative marine management agreement; fishing, shoreline food gathering and small boat harbor activities: regulation; land and water management agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities and agreements; native accommodations; cooperative marine management agreement; fishing, shoreline food gathering and small boat harbor activities: regulation; land and water management agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of native Hawaiians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employment of native Hawaiians In carrying out the purposes of this section the Secretary is authorized and directed as appropriate to employ native Hawaiians. For the purposes of this section, native Hawaiians are defined as any lineal descendants of the race inhabiting the Hawaiian Islands prior to the year 1778.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Commission; establishment; membership; qualifications; term; Chairman; vacancies; compensation and expenses; ex officio members; duties; meetings; termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Advisory Commission; establishment; membership; qualifications; term; Chairman; vacancies; compensation and expenses; ex officio members; duties; meetings; termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are hereby authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $25,000,000 for acquisition and $1,000,000 for development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>