<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/397" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/397/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/397/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_397"><akn:num>397</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 397. Establishment; boundaries(a) EstablishmentWhen title to such lands located on the island of Hawaii, within the following-described area, as shall be designated by the Secretary of the Interior, in the exercise of his judgment and discretion as necessary and suitable for the purpose, shall have been vested in the United States, said lands shall be set apart as the Puʻuhonua o Ho̅naunau National Historical Park, in the Territory of Hawaii, for the benefit and inspiration of the people:



parcel 1

Being all of R. P. 3306, L. C. Aw. 7219, Apana 2 to Kaliae, all of L. C. Aw. 9470 to Muki, and portions of R. P. 7874, L. C. Aw. 11216 Apana 34 to M. Kekauonohi (Ahupuaa of Honaunau), and R. P. 6852, L. C. Aw. 7712 Apana 1 to M. Kekuanaoa (Ahupuaa of Keokea).

Beginning at a one and one-half-inch pipe in concrete monument called “Kalani”, at the southeast corner of this parcel, the northeast corner of parcel 3, and on the common boundary of the lands of Keokea and Kiilae, the coordinates of said point of beginning referred to Government Survey Triangulation Station “Lae-O-Kanoni” being seven thousand four hundred forty-four and eight-tenths feet south and five thousand three and two-tenths feet east, and running by azimuths measured clockwise from true south:

1. Seventy-nine degrees thirty-three minutes fifteen seconds six hundred and eighty feet along the land of Kiilae, L. C. Aw. 8521–B to G. D. Hueu and passing over a rock called “Kuwaia”, marked K+K at six hundred seventy-three and two-tenths feet to high-water mark; thence along high-water mark, along seacoast for the next three courses, the direct azimuths and distances between points at seacoast being:

2. One hundred and thirty-five degrees fifty-one minutes three thousand nine hundred seventy-six and one-tenth feet;

3. One hundred and fifty-two degrees twenty-five minutes one thousand and seventy-eight feet;

4. Two hundred and forty degrees fifty-five minutes one thousand two hundred four and four-tenths </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment When title to such lands located on the island of Hawaii, within the following-described area, as shall be designated by the Secretary of the Interior, in the exercise of his judgment and discretion as necessary and suitable for the purpose, shall have been vested in the United States, said lands shall be set apart as the Puʻuhonua o Ho̅naunau National Historical Park, in the Territory of Hawaii, for the benefit and inspiration of the people:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boundary modification The boundaries of Puʻuhonua o Ho̅naunau National Historical Park are hereby modified to include approximately 238 acres of lands and interests therein within the area identified as “Parcel A” on the map entitled “Puʻuhonua o Ho̅naunau National Historical Park Proposed Boundary Additions, Kiʻilae Village”, numbered PUHO–P 415/82,013 and dated May, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire approximately 159 acres of lands and interests therein within the area identified as “Parcel B” on the map referenced in subsection (b). Upon the acquisition of such lands or interests therein, the Secretary shall modify the boundaries of Puʻuhonua o Ho̅naunau National Historical Park to include such lands or interests therein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>