<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/398d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/398d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/398d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_398d"><akn:num>398d</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of lands, waters, and interests therein</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 398d. Acquisition of lands, waters, and interests therein(a) Authorization; payment requirements; interest rateWithin the boundaries of Virgin Islands National Park as established and adjusted pursuant to sections 398 and 398a of this title, and as revised by sections 398c to 398f of this title, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire lands, waters, and interests therein by purchase, exchange or donation or with donated funds. In acquiring such lands, up to 6.6 acres, the Secretary may, when agreed upon by the landowner involved, defer payment or schedule payments over a period of ten years and pay interest on the unpaid balance at a rate not exceeding the current prevailing commercial rate.


(b) Employment and training of residents to develop, etc., areaThe Secretary is authorized and directed to the maximum extent feasible to employ and train residents of the Virgin Islands to develop, maintain, and administer the Virgin Islands National Park.


(c) Payment requirements for acquisition of Hassel Island from United StatesSubject to continued protection and use of Hassel Island for park and recreation purposes, and such other conditions as the Secretary may deem appropriate, the Territory of the Virgin Islands may, within, but not after, five years after August 18, 1978, by duly enacted legislation acquire all interests of the United States in Hassel Island by reimbursing the United States in an amount equal to the amount actually expended by the United States for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands and for the costs of construction of permanent improvements, if any.


(d) Rights of owners of improved property on Hassel Island to use and occupancy of property for noncommercial residential purposes; term; payment requirements; suspension of authority to condemn Royal Mail property; “improved property” defined; termination of rights of owners to use and occupancy(1) Except for property deemed necessary by the Secretary of the Interior for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_398d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; payment requirements; interest rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; payment requirements; interest rate Within the boundaries of Virgin Islands National Park as established and adjusted pursuant to sections 398 and 398a of this title, and as revised by sections 398c to 398f of this title, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire lands, waters, and interests therein by purchase, exchange or donation or with donated funds. In acquiring such lands, up to 6.6 acres, the Secretary may, when agreed upon by the landowner involved, defer payment or schedule payments over a period of ten years and pay interest on the unpaid balance at a rate not exceeding the current prevailing commercial rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_398d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment and training of residents to develop, etc., area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment and training of residents to develop, etc., area The Secretary is authorized and directed to the maximum extent feasible to employ and train residents of the Virgin Islands to develop, maintain, and administer the Virgin Islands National Park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_398d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment requirements for acquisition of Hassel Island from United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment requirements for acquisition of Hassel Island from United States Subject to continued protection and use of Hassel Island for park and recreation purposes, and such other conditions as the Secretary may deem appropriate, the Territory of the Virgin Islands may, within, but not after, five years after August 18, 1978, by duly enacted legislation acquire all interests of the United States in Hassel Island by reimbursing the United States in an amount equal to the amount actually expended by the United States for the acquisition of lands and interests in lands and for the costs of construction of permanent improvements, if any.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_398d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of owners of improved property on Hassel Island to use and occupancy of property for noncommercial residential purposes; term; payment requirements; suspension of authority to condemn Royal Mail property; “improved property” defined; termination of rights of owners to use and occupancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rights of owners of improved property on Hassel Island to use and occupancy of property for noncommercial residential purposes; term; payment requirements; suspension of authority to condemn Royal Mail property; “improved property” defined; termination of rights of owners to use and occupancy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>