<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4009" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4009/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4009/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4009"><akn:num>4009</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of seafood marketing councils</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4009. Establishment of seafood marketing councils(a) ApplicationAn application for a charter for a seafood marketing council for one or more species of fish and fish products of that species may be filed by persons who meet the requirements specified in accordance with subsection (b)(6) of this section.


(b) Form of applicationAn application for a charter for a council shall be made by filing with the Secretary the text of a proposed charter in such form as shall be prescribed by regulation by the Secretary. The text of a proposed charter must contain such information as the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate for carrying out the provisions of this chapter, including—(1) the name of the council and a provision proclaiming its establishment;

(2) a declaration of the purposes and objectives of the council;

(3) a description of the species of fish and fish products for which the council will implement marketing and promotion plans under section 4010 of this title;

(4) the identification of each sector and the number and terms of representatives of each sector that will be represented as voting members of the council;

(5) the identification of those sectors (including the sector consisting of harvesters, the sector consisting of receivers, and, if subject to assessment, the sector consisting of importers) subject to a referendum to establish a council under subsection (e) of this section;

(6) a specification for each sector described under paragraph (5) of this subsection of the minimum requirements, as measured by income, volume, or other relevant factors, that a person engaging in business in the sector must meet in order to participate in a referendum;

(7)(A) a description of the procedures for determining assessment rates under section 4012 of this title;

(B) the proposed rate or rates that will be imposed by the council on receivers and, if subject to assessment, importers during its first year of operation;

(C) the maximum amount an assessment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application An application for a charter for a seafood marketing council for one or more species of fish and fish products of that species may be filed by persons who meet the requirements specified in accordance with subsection (b)(6) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form of application An application for a charter for a council shall be made by filing with the Secretary the text of a proposed charter in such form as shall be prescribed by regulation by the Secretary. The text of a proposed charter must contain such information as the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate for carrying out the provisions of this chapter, including— The text of a proposed charter shall be accompanied by a document identifying, to the extent practicable by address of place of business, the persons (hereinafter referred to as “sector participants”) that are considered by the applicants to meet the requirements specified in paragraph (6) of this subsection. The text of a proposed charter shall include provisions setting forth procedures for providing refunds to those sector participants subject to assessment under section 4012 of this title, and may also include provisions which establish a maximum limit on the amount that any one sector participant may be re</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of charter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of charter The Secretary may not approve a proposed charter filed under subsection (a) of this section unless such charter provides that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of charter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of charter</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of referendum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conduct of referendum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nominations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nature of a council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nature of a council A council is not an instrumentality of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>