<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/403f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/403f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/403f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_403f"><akn:num>403f</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Smoky Mountains National Park; extension of boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 403f. Great Smoky Mountains National Park; extension of boundaries
The boundary limits of the tract of land in the Great Smoky Mountains in the States of North Carolina and Tennessee, recommended by the Secretary of the Interior in his report of April 14, 1926, for the establishment of the Great Smoky Mountains National Park, are extended to include lands adjacent to the east boundary as defined in said report to a line approximately as follows:
From a point on top of the Balsam Mountains at the boundary of Swain and Hayward Counties just north of Black Camp Gap; thence following east the top of the mountain range to Jonathan Knob and Hemphill Bald; thence along top of ridge through Camp Gap to Bent Knee Knob; thence following the main ridge to Cataloochee Creek to a point on the boundary of the area described in report of the Secretary of the Interior of April 14, 1926; and the lands within said boundary extension, or any part thereof, may be accepted on behalf of the United States in accordance with the provisions of sections 403 and 403a to 403c of this title for inclusion in the area to be known as the Great Smoky Mountains National Park.
(Apr. 19, 1930, ch. 197, 46 Stat. 225.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>