<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/406d–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/406d–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/406d–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_406d_1"><akn:num>406d–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; boundaries; administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 406d–1. Establishment; boundaries; administration
For the purpose of including in one national park, for public benefit and enjoyment, the lands within the present Grand Teton National Park and a portion of the lands within the Jackson Hole National Monument, there is established a new “Grand Teton National Park”. The park shall comprise, subject to valid existing rights, all of the present Grand Teton National Park and all lands of the Jackson Hole National Monument that are not otherwise expressly provided for in this Act, and an order setting forth the boundaries of the park shall be prepared by the Secretary of the Interior and published in the Federal Register. The national park so established shall, so far as consistent with the provisions of this Act, be administered in accordance with the general statutes governing national parks, and shall supersede the present Grand Teton National Park and the Jackson Hole National Monument.
(Sept. 14, 1950, ch. 950, § 1, 64 Stat. 849.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is act Sept. 14, 1950, ch. 950, 64 Stat. 849, which enacted this section, sections 406d–2 to 406d–5, 431a, 451a, 482m, 673b, and 673c of this title, and provisions set out as notes below. Section 1 of the Act was partially repealed and restated as sections 104907 and 320301(d) of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, by Pub. L. 113–287, §§ 3, 7, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3094, 3272. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The Jackson Hole National Monument, referred to in text, was created in Wyoming by Presidential Proc. No. 2578, Mar. 15, 1943, 57 Stat. 731. For provisions transferring other lands of such former national monument, see sections 482m and 673b of this title.
Provisions relating to the “present Grand Teton National Park”, referred to in text, were contained in former sections 406 to 406d of this title, which sections were repealed by another provision of section 1 of a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>