<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/407p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/407p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/407p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_407p"><akn:num>407p</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of advisory commission; composition, appointment, and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 407p. Establishment of advisory commission; composition, appointment, and duties
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion, to establish a suitable advisory commission of not to exceed eleven members. The members of the advisory commission shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Interior, with three members to be recommended by the Governor of Pennsylvania, three by the mayor of Philadelphia, and one each by the Carpenters’ Company of Philadelphia and the Independence Hall Association.
The functions of the advisory commission shall be to render advice to the Secretary of the Interior, from time to time, upon matters which the Secretary of the Interior may refer to them for consideration.
(June 28, 1948, ch. 687, § 4, 62 Stat. 1062.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Advisory CommissionsAdvisory commissions in existence on Jan. 5, 1973, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period following Jan. 5, 1973, unless, in the case of a commission established by the President or an officer of the Federal Government, such commission is renewed by appropriate action prior to the expiration of such 2-year period, or in the case of a commission established by the Congress, its duration is otherwise provided for by law. See sections 1001(2) and 1013 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>