<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aa" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aa/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aa/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410aa"><akn:num>410aa</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410aa. Establishment
In order to preserve and commemorate for the people of the United States the area associated with the heroic suffering, hardship, and determination and resolve of General George Washington’s Continental Army during the winter of 1777–1778 at Valley Forge, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to establish the Valley Forge National Historical Park (hereinafter referred to as the “park”), in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.
(Pub. L. 94–337, § 1, July 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 796.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 1999 AmendmentPub. L. 106–86, § 1, Oct. 31, 1999, 113 Stat. 1298, provided that: “This Act [enacting provisions set out as a note under this section] may be cited as the ‘Pennsylvania Battlefields Protection Act of 1999’.”


Valley Forge National Historical ParkPub. L. 106–86, title II, Oct. 31, 1999, 113 Stat. 1299, provided that:
“SEC. 201. PURPOSE.“The purpose of this title is to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the Valley Forge Historical Society (hereinafter referred to as the ‘Society’), to construct and operate a museum within the boundary of Valley Forge National Historical Park in cooperation with the Secretary.


“SEC. 202. VALLEY FORGE MUSEUM OF THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION AUTHORIZATION.“(a) Agreement Authorized.—The Secretary of the Interior, in administering the Valley Forge National Historical Park, is authorized to enter into an agreement under appropriate terms and conditions with the Society to facilitate the planning, construction, and operation of the Valley Forge Museum of the American Revolution on Federal land within the boundary of Valley Forge National Historical Park.

“(b) Contents and Implementation of Agreement.—An agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall—“(1) authorize the Society to develop and operate the museum pursuant to plans developed by the Secretary and to provide at the museum appropriat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>