<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–82" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–82/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–82/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410aaa_82"><akn:num>410aaa–82</akn:num><akn:heading>Military overflights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410aaa–82. Military overflights(a) OverflightsNothing in this Act, the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.], or other land management laws generally applicable to the new units of the National Park or Wilderness Preservation Systems (or any additions to existing units), scenic areas, off-highway vehicle recreation areas, or special management areas designated by this Act, shall restrict or preclude low-level overflights of military aircraft over such units, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within such units.


(b) Special airspaceNothing in this Act, the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.], or other land management laws generally applicable to the new units of the National Park or Wilderness Preservation Systems (or any additions to existing units), scenic areas, off-highway vehicle recreation areas, or special management areas designated by this Act, shall restrict or preclude the designation of new units of special airspace or the use or establishment of military flight training routes over such new park system or wilderness units.


(c) No effect on other lawsNothing in this section shall be construed to modify, expand, or diminish any authority under other Federal law.


(d) Department of Defense facilitiesNothing in this Act alters any authority of the Secretary of Defense to conduct military operations at installations and ranges within the California Desert Conservation Area that are authorized under any other provision of law.


(Pub. L. 103–433, title VIII, § 802, Oct. 31, 1994, 108 Stat. 4501; Pub. L. 116–9, title I, § 1460(b), Mar. 12, 2019, 133 Stat. 719.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsecs. (a), (b), and (d), is defined in section 3 of Pub. L. 103–433, which is set out as a Definitions note under section 410aaa of this title.
The Wilderness Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is Pub. L. 88–577, Sept. 3, 1964, 78 Stat. 890, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_82_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overflights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Overflights Nothing in this Act, the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.], or other land management laws generally applicable to the new units of the National Park or Wilderness Preservation Systems (or any additions to existing units), scenic areas, off-highway vehicle recreation areas, or special management areas designated by this Act, shall restrict or preclude low-level overflights of military aircraft over such units, including military overflights that can be seen or heard within such units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_82_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special airspace</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special airspace Nothing in this Act, the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.], or other land management laws generally applicable to the new units of the National Park or Wilderness Preservation Systems (or any additions to existing units), scenic areas, off-highway vehicle recreation areas, or special management areas designated by this Act, shall restrict or preclude the designation of new units of special airspace or the use or establishment of military flight training routes over such new park system or wilderness units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_82_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No effect on other laws Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify, expand, or diminish any authority under other Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_82_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Department of Defense facilities Nothing in this Act alters any authority of the Secretary of Defense to conduct military operations at installations and ranges within the California Desert Conservation Area that are authorized under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>