<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–91" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–91/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–91/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410aaa_91"><akn:num>410aaa–91</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410aaa–91. Designation of Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Areas(a) In general(1) DesignationIn accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) and resource management plans developed under this part and subject to valid rights, the following land within the Conservation Area in San Bernardino County, California, is designated as Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Areas:(A) Dumont Dunes Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation AreaCertain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 7,620 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Dumont Dunes OHV Recreation Area” and dated November 7, 2018, which shall be known as the “Dumont Dunes Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area”.


(B) El Mirage Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation AreaCertain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 16,370 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed El Mirage OHV Recreation Area” and dated December 10, 2018, which shall be known as the “El Mirage Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area”.


(C) Rasor Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation AreaCertain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 23,900 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Rasor OHV Recreation Area” and dated November 7, 2018, which shall be known as the “Rasor Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area”.


(D) Spangler Hills Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation AreaCertain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 92,340 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Spangler Hills OHV Recreation Area” and dated December 10, 2018, which shall be known as the “Spangler Hills Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area”.


(E) Stoddard Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation AreaCertain Bureau of Land Management land in the Conservation Area, comprising approximately 40,110 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated or expanded under subsection (a) is to preserve and enhance the recreational opportunities within the Conservation Area (including opportunities for off-highway vehicle recreation), while conserving the wildlife and other natural resource values of the Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps and descriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maps and descriptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of the land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of the land</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the off-highway vehicle recreation areas designated or expanded by subsection (a) is withdrawn from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Southern California Edison Company utility facilities and rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Southern California Edison Company utility facilities and rights-of-way</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410aaa_91_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pacific Gas and Electric Company utility facilities and rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Pacific Gas and Electric Company utility facilities and rights-of-way</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>