<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410aaa–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410aaa_7"><akn:num>410aaa–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410aaa–7. Boundary adjustment
In preparing the maps and legal descriptions required by section 410aaa–3 of this title and section 602 of this Act, the Secretary shall adjust the boundaries of the Death Valley National Park and Death Valley National Park Wilderness so as to exclude from such National Park and Wilderness the lands generally depicted on the map entitled “Porter Mine (Panamint Range) Exclusion Area” dated June 1994.
(Pub. L. 103–433, title III, § 308, Oct. 31, 1994, 108 Stat. 4487.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 602 of this Act, referred to in text, is section 602 of Pub. L. 103–433, title VI, Oct. 31, 1994, 108 Stat. 4496, which is not classified to the Code.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Death Valley National Park Boundary RevisionPub. L. 116–9, title I, § 1431(a)–(c), Mar. 12, 2019, 133 Stat. 699, provided that:
“(a) In General.—The boundary of Death Valley National Park is adjusted to include—“(1) the approximately 28,923 acres of Bureau of Land Management land in San Bernardino County, California, abutting the southern end of the Death Valley National Park that lies between Death Valley National Park to the north and Ft. Irwin Military Reservation to the south and which runs approximately 34 miles from west to east, as depicted on the map entitled ‘Death Valley National Park Proposed Boundary Addition-Bowling Alley’, numbered 143/128,605A, and dated November 1, 2018; and

“(2) the approximately 6,369 acres of Bureau of Land Management land in Inyo County, California, located in the northeast area of Death Valley National Park that is within, and surrounded by, land under the jurisdiction of the Director of the National Park Service, as depicted on the map entitled ‘Death Valley National Park Proposed Boundary Addition-Crater’, numbered 143/100,079D, and dated November 1, 2018.


“(b) Availability of Map.—The maps described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>