<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410bbb–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410bbb–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410bbb–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410bbb_2"><akn:num>410bbb–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410bbb–2. Administration(a) In general(1) The Secretary shall administer the historical park in accordance with this subchapter and with provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4); 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461–467).1 The Secretary shall manage the historical park in such a manner as will preserve and perpetuate knowledge and understanding of the history of jazz and its continued evolution as a true American art form.

(2) To minimize operational costs associated with the management and administration of the historical park and to avoid duplication of effort, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, utilize the facilities, administrative staff and other services of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve.


(b) DonationsThe Secretary may accept and retain donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, corporations, or other public entities for the purposes of providing services, programs, and facilities that further the purposes of this subchapter.


(c) Interpretive centerThe Secretary is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain an interpretive center in the historical park on lands identified by the Secretary pursuant to section 410bbb–1(b)(1) of this title. Programs at the center shall include, but need not be limited to, live jazz interpretive and educational programs, and shall provide visitors with information about jazz-related programs, performances, and opportunities.


(d) Jazz heritage districtsThe Secretary may provide technical assistance to the city of New Orleans and other appropriate entities for the designation of certain areas in and around New Orleans as jazz heritage districts. Such districts shall include those areas with an exce</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Donations The Secretary may accept and retain donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, corporations, or other public entities for the purposes of providing services, programs, and facilities that further the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpretive center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interpretive center The Secretary is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain an interpretive center in the historical park on lands identified by the Secretary pursuant to section 410bbb–1(b)(1) of this title. Programs at the center shall include, but need not be limited to, live jazz interpretive and educational programs, and shall provide visitors with information about jazz-related programs, performances, and opportunities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jazz heritage districts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Jazz heritage districts The Secretary may provide technical assistance to the city of New Orleans and other appropriate entities for the designation of certain areas in and around New Orleans as jazz heritage districts. Such districts shall include those areas with an exceptional concentration of jazz historical sites and established community traditions of jazz street parades.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements, grants and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cooperative agreements, grants and technical assistance In furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410bbb_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jazz educational programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Jazz educational programs The Secretary shall, in the administration of the historical park, promote a broad range of educational activities relating to jazz and its history. The Secretary shall cooperate with schools, universities, and organizations supporting jazz education to develop educational programs that provide expanded public understanding of jazz and enhanced opportunities for public appreciation. The Secretary may assist appropriate entities in the development of an information base including archival material, audiovisual records, and objects that relate to the history of jazz.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>