<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ccc_21"><akn:num>410ccc–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ccc–21. Establishment(a) In generalThere is hereby established the Cane River National Heritage Area (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “heritage area”).


(b) PurposeIn furtherance of the need to recognize the value and importance of the Cane River region and in recognition of the findings of section 410ccc(a) of this title, it is the purpose of this part to establish a heritage area to complement the historical park and to provide for a culturally sensitive approach to the preservation of the heritage of the Cane River region, and for other needs including—(1) recognizing areas important to the Nation’s heritage and identity;

(2) assisting in the preservation and enhancement of the cultural landscape and traditions of the Cane River region;

(3) providing a framework for those who live within this important dynamic cultural landscape to assist in preservation and educational actions; and

(4) minimizing the need for Federal land acquisition and management.


(c) Area includedThe heritage area shall include—(1) an area approximately 1 mile on both sides of the Cane River as depicted on map CARI, 80,000A, dated May 1994;

(2) those properties within the Natchitoches National Historic Landmark District which are the subject of cooperative agreements pursuant to section 410ccc–2(d) of this title;

(3) the Los Adaes State Commemorative Area;

(4) the Fort Jesup State Commemorative Area;

(5) the Fort St. Jean Baptiste State Commemorative Area; and

(6) the Kate Chopin House.


A final identification of all areas and sites to be included in the heritage area shall be included in the heritage area management plan as required in section 410ccc–23 of this title.

(Pub. L. 103–449, title IV, § 401, Nov. 2, 1994, 108 Stat. 4760.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is hereby established the Cane River National Heritage Area (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “heritage area”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose In furtherance of the need to recognize the value and importance of the Cane River region and in recognition of the findings of section 410ccc(a) of this title, it is the purpose of this part to establish a heritage area to complement the historical park and to provide for a culturally sensitive approach to the preservation of the heritage of the Cane River region, and for other needs including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Area included The heritage area shall include— A final identification of all areas and sites to be included in the heritage area shall be included in the heritage area management plan as required in section 410ccc–23 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>