<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410cc_13"><akn:num>410cc–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410cc–13. Authorization of appropriations(a) General authority; maximum amountsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter, except that—(1) 11 So in original. There is no par. (2). the total of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out section 410cc–32(b)(2) of this title, for the payment of grants and loans under section 410cc–33 of this title, for the acquisition of property under section 410cc–34 of this title, and for carrying out any transportation program and any educational and cultural program described in section 410cc–32(c) of this title shall not exceed $33,600,000.


(b) Commencement dateNo funds shall be authorized pursuant to this section prior to October 1, 1978.


(c) Availability of appropriationsFunds appropriated under subsection (a) of this section shall remain available until expended.


(d) Aggregate amount of money expended; certifying statement to Congress as limiting availability of appropriated amounts(1) Within 60 days after June 5, 1978, and on each subsequent October 1 and March 1, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a statement certifying the aggregate amount of money expended by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, the city of Lowell, and by any nonprofit entity for activities in the city of Lowell consistent with the purpose of this subchapter during the period beginning on January 1, 1974, and ending on the date such statement is submitted.

(2) The aggregate amount of funds made available by the Secretary to the Commission from funds appropriated under subsection (a)(2) of this section may not exceed the amount certified by the Secretary in the most recent statement submitted to the Congress under paragraph (1) of this subsection.


(Pub. L. 95–290, title I, § 103, June 5, 1978, 92 Stat. 292; Pub. L. 100–134, § 1(1), Oct. 16, 1987, 101 Stat. 810; Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title I, § 122, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 4789.)

Editorial Notes
Amend</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority; maximum amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority; maximum amounts There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commencement date No funds shall be authorized pursuant to this section prior to October 1, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of appropriations Funds appropriated under subsection (a) of this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregate amount of money expended; certifying statement to Congress as limiting availability of appropriated amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Aggregate amount of money expended; certifying statement to Congress as limiting availability of appropriated amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>