<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ccc–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ccc_22"><akn:num>410ccc–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Cane River National Heritage Area Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ccc–22. Cane River National Heritage Area Commission(a) EstablishmentTo assist in implementing the purposes of this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. and to provide guidance for the management of the heritage area, there is established the Cane River National Heritage Area Commission (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “Commission”).


(b) MembershipThe Commission shall consist of 19 members to be appointed no later than 6 months after November 2, 1994. The Commission shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows—(1) one member from recommendations submitted by the Mayor of Natchitoches;

(2) one member from recommendations submitted by the Association for the Preservation of Historic Natchitoches;

(3) one member from recommendations submitted by the Natchitoches Historic Foundation, Inc.;

(4) two members with experience in and knowledge of tourism in the heritage area from recommendations submitted by local business and tourism organizations;

(5) one member from recommendations submitted by the Governor of the State of Louisiana;

(6) one member from recommendations submitted by the Police Jury of Natchitoches Parish;

(7) one member from recommendations submitted by the Concern 22 So in original. Citizens of Cloutierville;

(8) one member from recommendations submitted by the St. Augustine Historical Society;

(9) one member from recommendations submitted by the Black Heritage Committee;

(10) one member from recommendations submitted by the Los Adaes/Robeline Community;

(11) one member from recommendations submitted by the Natchitoches Historic District Commission;

(12) one member from recommendations submitted by the Cane River Waterway Commission;

(13) two members who are landowners in and residents of the heritage area;

(14) one member with experience and knowledge of historic preservation from recommendations submitted by the Museum Contents, Inc.;

(15) one member with experience and knowledge of historic preservation fro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment To assist in implementing the purposes of this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. and to provide guidance for the management of the heritage area, there is established the Cane River National Heritage Area Commission (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Commission shall consist of 19 members to be appointed no later than 6 months after November 2, 1994. The Commission shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of Commission The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Powers of Commission In furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, the Commission is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation Members of the Commission shall receive no compensation for their service on the Commission. While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chairman The Commission shall elect a chairman from among its members. The term of the chairman shall be for 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Terms The terms of Commission members shall be for 3 years. Any member of the Commission appointed by the Secretary for a 3-year term may serve after expiration of his or her term until a successor is appointed. Any vacancy shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor was appointed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ccc_22_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual reports The Commission shall submit an annual report to the Secretary identifying its expenses and any income, the entities to which any grants or technical assistance were made during the year for which the report is made, and actions that are planned for the following year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>