<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–33" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–33/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–33/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410cc_33"><akn:num>410cc–33</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410cc–33. Financial and technical assistance(a) Loans to Lowell Development and Financial Corporation for loans for preservation, etc., of property; terms of loan agreement with corporation; determination of compliance by corporation with requirements for loans; repayment by corporationThe Commission may make loans to the Lowell Development and Financial Corporation (established under chapter 844 of the Massachusetts General Laws and hereinafter referred to as the “corporation”) to enable the corporation to provide low interest loans for the preservation, restoration, or development of any property described in section 410cc–32(d)(1) of this title. The Commission may make any such loan to the corporation only after entering into a loan agreement with the corporation which includes the following terms:(1) The loan to the corporation shall have a maturity of thirty-five years. At the end of such period, the corporation shall repay to the Secretary of the Treasury (in a lump sum) for deposit in the general fund of the Treasury the full amount of the loan and any additional amounts accruing to the corporation pursuant to this subsection excepting those amounts expended by the corporation for reasonable administrative expenses.

(2) The money received from the Commission, and any interest earned on such money, may be obligated by the corporation only for low interest loans made under paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection, except that the corporation may use such money to the extent the Commission considers reasonable to satisfy the costs of the corporation in administering the loan or procuring loan guarantees or insurance.

(3) Within five years after receiving the loan from the Commission, the corporation shall make loans under paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection which, in the aggregate, obligate the full amount of money received from the Commission (minus any amount required to satisfy the costs described in paragraph (2) of this subsection).

(4) As loans</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_33_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to Lowell Development and Financial Corporation for loans for preservation, etc., of property; terms of loan agreement with corporation; determination of compliance by corporation with requirements for loans; repayment by corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Loans to Lowell Development and Financial Corporation for loans for preservation, etc., of property; terms of loan agreement with corporation; determination of compliance by corporation with requirements for loans; repayment by corporation The Commission may make loans to the Lowell Development and Financial Corporation (established under chapter 844 of the Massachusetts General Laws and hereinafter referred to as the “corporation”) to enable the corporation to provide low interest loans for the preservation, restoration, or development of any property described in section 410cc–32(d)(1) of this title. The Commission may make any such loan to the corporation only after entering into a loan agreement with the corporation which includes the following terms: In order to determine whether the corporation has complied with this subsection, the Commission, or such other appropriate person or entity as the Commission may designate, shall conduct an audit at least once every two years of a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_33_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to property owners for preservation, etc., of property; grants to persons or public or private entities for educational and cultural programs or for necessary services; terms of grant agreements; recovery of amounts for inconsistent uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants to property owners for preservation, etc., of property; grants to persons or public or private entities for educational and cultural programs or for necessary services; terms of grant agreements; recovery of amounts for inconsistent uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_33_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to property owners, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance to property owners, etc. The Commission with the advice of the Secretary may provide technical assistance to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_33_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability to Secretary of all accounts, financial records, and other information relating to loans and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability to Secretary of all accounts, financial records, and other information relating to loans and grants The Commission shall make available to the Secretary, upon request, all accounts, financial records, and other information of the Commission relating to grants and loans made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>