<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–32" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–32/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410cc–32/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410cc_32"><akn:num>410cc–32</akn:num><akn:heading>Park preservation plan and index</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410cc–32. Park preservation plan and index(a) Submission by Commission and approval or disapproval by Secretary of draft and final plans; procedures applicable; revisions in approved plan(1) Within one year after the date on which the Commission conducts its first meeting, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary a draft park preservation plan meeting the requirements of subsection (c) of this section. The Secretary shall review the draft park preservation plan and, within ninety days after the date on which such plan is submitted to the Secretary, suggest appropriate changes in such plan to the Commission.

(2) Within eighteen months after the date on which the Commission conducts its first meeting, the Commission shall submit to the Secretary a park preservation plan which meets the requirements of subsection (c) of this section. The Secretary shall, within ninety days after the date on which such plan is submitted to the Secretary, approve or disapprove such plan. The Secretary may not approve such plan unless the Secretary determines that such plan would adequately carry out the purpose of this subchapter.

(3) If the Secretary disapproves a park preservation plan, the Secretary shall advise the Commission of the reasons for such disapproval together with the recommendations of the Secretary for revision of such plan. Within such period as the Secretary may designate, the Commission shall submit a revised park preservation plan to the Secretary. The Secretary shall approve or disapprove any revised park preservation plan in the same manner as required in paragraph (2) of this subsection for the approval or disapproval of the original park preservation plan.

(4) If the Secretary approves a park preservation plan, the Secretary shall publish notice of such approval in the Federal Register and shall forward copies of the approved plan to the Congress.

(5) Any park preservation plan or draft plan submitted to the Secretary under this subsection shall, upon r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_32_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission by Commission and approval or disapproval by Secretary of draft and final plans; procedures applicable; revisions in approved plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission by Commission and approval or disapproval by Secretary of draft and final plans; procedures applicable; revisions in approved plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_32_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding availability and requirements for plan implementation, activities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding availability and requirements for plan implementation, activities, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_32_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for plan Any plan submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_32_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and contents of index; modification of index</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishment and contents of index; modification of index The Commission shall establish, within one year after the date on which the Commission conducts its first meeting, an index which includes— The index may be modified only by a majority vote of the members of the Commission, taken when a quorum is present.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410cc_32_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and criteria for construction, preservation, etc., of properties within preservation district and park; authorization; establishment; revisions; publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Standards and criteria for construction, preservation, etc., of properties within preservation district and park; authorization; establishment; revisions; publication in Federal Register</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>