<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410dddd" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410dddd/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410dddd/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410dddd"><akn:num>410dddd</akn:num><akn:heading>White Sands National Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410dddd. White Sands National Park(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) MapThe term “Map” means the map entitled “White Sands National Park Proposed Boundary Revision &amp; Transfer of Lands Between National Park Service &amp; Department of the Army”, numbered 142/136,271, and dated February 14, 2017.


(2) Military munitionsThe term “military munitions” has the meaning given the term in section 101(e) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 10.


(3) Missile rangeThe term “missile range” means the White Sands Missile Range, New Mexico, administered by the Secretary of the Army.


(4) MonumentThe term “Monument” means the White Sands National Monument, New Mexico, established by Presidential Proclamation No. 2025 (54 U.S.C. 320301 note), dated January 18, 1933, and administered by the Secretary of the Interior.


(5) Munitions debrisThe term “munitions debris” has the meaning given the term in volume 8 of the Department of Defense Manual Number 6055.09-M entitled “DoD Ammunitions and Explosives Safety Standards” and dated February 29, 2008 (as in effect on December 20, 2019).


(6) ParkThe term “Park” means the White Sands National Park established by subsection (b)(1).


(7) Public land orderThe term “Public Land Order” means Public Land Order 833, dated May 21, 1952 (17 Fed. Reg. 4822).


(8) StateThe term “State” means the State of New Mexico.



(b) White Sands National Park(1) EstablishmentTo protect, preserve, and restore its scenic, scientific, educational, natural, geological, historical, cultural, archaeological, paleontological, hydrological, fish, wildlife, and recreational values and to enhance visitor experiences, there is established in the State the White Sands National Park as a unit of the National Park System.


(2) Abolishment of White Sands National Monument(A) AbolishmentDue to the establishment of the Park, the Monument is abolished.


(B) IncorporationThe land and interests in land that comprise the Monument are incorporated in, and shall be con</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410dddd_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410dddd_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>White Sands National Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) White Sands National Park</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410dddd_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of Boundaries of White Sands National Park and White Sands Missile Range</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Modification of Boundaries of White Sands National Park and White Sands Missile Range</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>