<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ee"><akn:num>410ee</akn:num><akn:heading>San Antonio Missions National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ee. San Antonio Missions National Historical Park(a) Establishment(1) In generalIn order to provide for the preservation, restoration, and interpretation of the Spanish Missions of San Antonio, Texas, for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations of Americans, there is hereby established the San Antonio Missions National Historical Park (hereafter in this section referred to as the “park”) consisting of Concepcion, San Jose, San Juan, and Espada Missions, together with areas and features historically associated therewith, as generally depicted on the drawing entitled “Boundary Map, San Antonio Missions National Historical Park”, numbered 930–80,022–C and dated May 1978, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and in the offices of the Superintendent of the park.


(2) Additional landThe park shall also consist of the lands and interests therein within the area bounded by the line depicted as “Proposed Boundary Extension” on the maps entitled “San Antonio Missions National Historical Park”, numbered 472–80,075, 472–80,076, 472–80,077, 472–80,078, 472–80,079, 472–80,080, and 472–80,081 and dated June 7, 1990, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the same manner as is such drawing.


(3) Boundary modification(A) In generalThe boundary of the park is modified to include approximately 137 acres, as depicted on the map entitled “San Antonio Missions National Historical Park Proposed Boundary Addition”, numbered 472/113,006A, and dated June 2012.


(B) Availability of mapThe map described in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(C) Acquisition of landThe Secretary of the Interior may acquire the land or any interest in the land described in subparagraph (A) only by donation or exchange.



(4) RevisionsAfter advising the Committee on Energy and Natural</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of lands and interests; cooperative agreements; submittal to Department of Justice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of lands and interests; cooperative agreements; submittal to Department of Justice For the purposes of this section, the Secretary is authorized— Each agreement under paragraph (2) shall provide among other things that the owner will hold and preserve the historic property in perpetuity and will not undertake or permit the alteration or removal of historic features or the erection of markers, structures, or buildings without the prior concurrence of the Secretary, and that the public shall have reasonable access to those portions of the property to which access is necessary in the judgment of the Secretary for the proper appreciation and interpretation of its historical and architectural value. Pursuant to such cooperative agreements and notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary the Secretary may, directly or by contract, construct, reconstruct, rehabilitate, or develop such buildings, structures, and related facilities including roads, trails, and othe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of rights by owners; compensation for property; termination of rights; “improved property” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Retention of rights by owners; compensation for property; termination of rights; “improved property” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection and preservation of historical and architectural values; administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Protection and preservation of historical and architectural values; administration The Secretary is authorized and directed to take prompt and appropriate action in accordance with the provisions of this section and any cooperative agreement hereunder to assure the protection and preservation of the historical and architectural values of the missions and the areas and features historically associated therewith within the boundaries of the park. The park shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this section and provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.) 22 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461–467).2</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>San Antonio Missions Advisory Commission; membership; Chairman; vacancies; compensation and expenses; meeting and consultation between Secretary and Advisory Commission; termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) San Antonio Missions Advisory Commission; membership; Chairman; vacancies; compensation and expenses; meeting and consultation between Secretary and Advisory Commission; termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ee_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>