<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410eeee_2"><akn:num>410eeee–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410eeee–2. Acquisition of property(a) Authority of Secretary; manner; donation of State lands; improved and unimproved propertiesWithin the boundaries of the New River Gorge National River,11 See Change of Name note below. the Secretary may acquire lands and waters or interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer, or exchange. Lands owned by the State of West Virginia or a political subdivision thereof may be acquired by donation only. In addition, the Secretary may acquire by any of the foregoing methods not to exceed ten acres outside the boundaries of the national river for an administrative headquarters site, and funds appropriated for land acquisition shall be available for the acquisition of the administrative headquarters site. The authority of the Secretary to condemn in fee, improved properties as defined in subsection (c) of this section shall not be invoked as long as the owner of such improved property holds and uses it in a manner compatible with the purposes of this subchapter. The Secretary may acquire any such improved property without the consent of the owner whenever he finds that such property has undergone, since January 1, 1978, or is imminently about to undergo, changes in land use which are incompatible with the purposes of the national river. The Secretary may acquire less than fee interest in any improved or unimproved property within the boundaries of the national river.


(b) Non-federally owned lands; cooperative agreements affecting properties of historical significanceOn non-federally owned lands within the national river boundaries, the Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with organizations or individuals to mark or interpret properties of significance to the history of the Gorge area.


(c) “Improved property” definedFor the purposes of this Act, the term “improved property” means (i) a detached single family dwelling, the construction of which was begun before January </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; manner; donation of State lands; improved and unimproved properties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; manner; donation of State lands; improved and unimproved properties Within the boundaries of the New River Gorge National River,11 See Change of Name note below. the Secretary may acquire lands and waters or interests therein by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer, or exchange. Lands owned by the State of West Virginia or a political subdivision thereof may be acquired by donation only. In addition, the Secretary may acquire by any of the foregoing methods not to exceed ten acres outside the boundaries of the national river for an administrative headquarters site, and funds appropriated for land acquisition shall be available for the acquisition of the administrative headquarters site. The authority of the Secretary to condemn in fee, improved properties as defined in subsection (c) of this section shall not be invoked as long as the owner of such improved property holds and uses it in a manner compatible with the purposes of this</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-federally owned lands; cooperative agreements affecting properties of historical significance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non-federally owned lands; cooperative agreements affecting properties of historical significance On non-federally owned lands within the national river boundaries, the Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with organizations or individuals to mark or interpret properties of significance to the history of the Gorge area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Improved property” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Improved property” defined For the purposes of this Act, the term “improved property” means (i) a detached single family dwelling, the construction of which was begun before January 1, 1977 (hereafter referred to as “dwelling”), together with so much of the land on which the dwelling is situated, the said land being in the same ownership as the dwelling, as the Secretary shall designate to be reasonably necessary for the enjoyment of the dwelling for the sole purpose of noncommercial residential use, together with any structures necessary to the dwelling which are situated on the land so designated, or (ii) property developed for agricultural uses, together with any structures accessory thereto which were so used on or before January 1, 1977, or (iii) commercial and small business properties which were so used on or before January 1, 1977, the purpose of which is determined by the Secretary to contribute to visitor use and enjoyment of the national river. In determining when and t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for fixed term of years or for life; election by owner; fair market value; termination; notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for fixed term of years or for life; election by owner; fair market value; termination; notification The owner of an improved property, as defined in this subchapter, on the date of its acquisition, as a condition of such acquisition, may retain for himself, his heirs and assigns, a right of use and occupancy of the improved property for noncommercial residential, or agricultural purposes, or the continuation of existing commercial operations, as the case may be, for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or, in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the death of his spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value of the property on that date of the right retained by the owner. A right ret</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>