<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410eeee_13"><akn:num>410eeee–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of access at Cunard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410eeee–13. Improvement of access at Cunard(a) Development and improvementThe Secretary shall expeditiously acquire such lands, and undertake such developments and improvements, as may be necessary to provide for commercial and noncommercial access to the river near Cunard. No restriction shall be imposed on such access based on the time of day, except to the extent required to protect public health and safety.


(b) Interim measuresPending completion of the developments and improvements referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary shall permit the motorized towing of whitewater rafts in the section of the national river between Thurmond and Cunard when the volume of flow in the river is less than three thousand cubic feet per second.


(Pub. L. 95–625, title XI, § 1114, as added Pub. L. 100–534, title I, § 103, Oct. 26, 1988, 102 Stat. 2700.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 460m–27 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and improvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development and improvement The Secretary shall expeditiously acquire such lands, and undertake such developments and improvements, as may be necessary to provide for commercial and noncommercial access to the river near Cunard. No restriction shall be imposed on such access based on the time of day, except to the extent required to protect public health and safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410eeee_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interim measures Pending completion of the developments and improvements referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary shall permit the motorized towing of whitewater rafts in the section of the national river between Thurmond and Cunard when the volume of flow in the river is less than three thousand cubic feet per second.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>