<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410eeee–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410eeee_1"><akn:num>410eeee–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; administration, protection, and development; utilization of other authorities; bounda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410eeee–1. Establishment; administration, protection, and development; utilization of other authorities; boundary description, availability for public inspection
For the purpose of conserving and interpreting outstanding natural, scenic, and historic values and objects in and around the New River Gorge and preserving as a free-flowing stream an important segment of the New River in West Virginia for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish and administer the New River Gorge National River.11 See Change of Name note below. The Secretary shall administer, protect, and develop the national river in accordance with the provisions of the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.),22 See References in Text note below. as amended and supplemented; except that any other statutory authority available to the Secretary for the preservation and management of natural resources may be utilized to the extent he finds such authority will further the purposes of this subchapter. The boundaries of the national river shall be as generally depicted on the drawing entitled “Proposed New River Gorge National River” numbered NERI 80,034, dated May 2001, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.
(Pub. L. 95–625, title XI, § 1101, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3544; Pub. L. 100–534, title I, § 101, Oct. 26, 1988, 102 Stat. 2700; Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title IV, § 406(a)(1), Nov. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 4149; Pub. L. 107–356, § 2(a), Dec. 17, 2002, 116 Stat. 3013.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.), referred to in text, is act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, 39 Stat. 535, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under section 100101 of Ti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>