<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ff–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ff–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ff–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ff_1"><akn:num>410ff–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ff–1. Acquisition of property(a) Authority of Secretary of the Interior; fair market value; State-owned land; Federal property located within parkWithin the boundaries of the park as established in section 410ff of this title, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to acquire lands, waters, or interests therein (including but not limited to scenic easements) by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer from any Federal agency, exchange, or otherwise. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value on that date of any right retained by the owner. Any lands, waters, or interests therein owned by the State of California or any political subdivision thereof shall not be acquired. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Federal property located within the boundaries of the park shall with the concurrence of the head of the agency having custody thereof, be transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purposes of the park: Provided, That the Secretary shall permit the use of federally owned park lands and waters which (i) have been transferred from another Federal agency pursuant to this section or which (ii) were the subject of a lease or permit issued by a Federal agency as of March 5, 1980, for essential national security missions and for navigational aids, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to protect park resources.


(b) Lands owned, or under option to, National Park Foundation, The Nature Conservancy, or similar organizationsNotwithstanding the acquisition authority contained in subsection (a), any lands, waters, or interests therein, which are owned wholly or in part, by or which hereafter may be owned by, or under option to, the National Park Foundation, The Nature Conservancy (including</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ff_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary of the Interior; fair market value; State-owned land; Federal property located within park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary of the Interior; fair market value; State-owned land; Federal property located within park Within the boundaries of the park as established in section 410ff of this title, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to acquire lands, waters, or interests therein (including but not limited to scenic easements) by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer from any Federal agency, exchange, or otherwise. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value on that date of any right retained by the owner. Any lands, waters, or interests therein owned by the State of California or any political subdivision thereof shall not be acquired. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Federal property located within the boundaries of the park shall with the concurrence of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ff_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands owned, or under option to, National Park Foundation, The Nature Conservancy, or similar organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Lands owned, or under option to, National Park Foundation, The Nature Conservancy, or similar organizations Notwithstanding the acquisition authority contained in subsection (a), any lands, waters, or interests therein, which are owned wholly or in part, by or which hereafter may be owned by, or under option to, the National Park Foundation, The Nature Conservancy (including any lands, waters, or interests therein which are designated as “Nature Conservancy Lands” on the map referred to in section 410ff of this title) or any similar national, nonprofit conservation organization, or an affiliate or subsidiary thereof shall be acquired only with the consent of the owner thereof: Provided, That the Secretary may acquire such property in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter if he determines that the property is undergoing or is about to undergo a change in use which is inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ff_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privately owned lands on Santa Rosa Island</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Privately owned lands on Santa Rosa Island With respect to the privately owned lands on Santa Rosa Island, the Secretary shall acquire such lands as expeditiously as possible after March 5, 1980. The acquisition of these lands shall take priority over the acquisition of other privately owned lands within the park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ff_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of rights by owners; compatible use under lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retention of rights by owners; compatible use under lease</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ff_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of certain property on Santa Cruz Island</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acquisition of certain property on Santa Cruz Island</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>