<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ffff–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ffff–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ffff–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ffff_2"><akn:num>410ffff–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Weir Farm National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ffff–2. Establishment of Weir Farm National Historical Park(a) In generalThere is established, as a unit of the National Park System, the Weir Farm National Historical Park in the State of Connecticut.


(b) DescriptionThe historical park shall consist of—(1) the approximately 2-acre core parcel containing the Weir house, studio, and barn;

(2) the approximately 60 acres and improvements thereon owned by the State of Connecticut;

(3) the approximately 2-acre parcel of land situated in the town of Wilton, Connecticut, designated as lot 18 on a map entitled “Revised Map of Section I, Thunder Lake at Wilton, Connecticut, Scale l’=100’, October 27, 1978, Ryan and Faulds Land Surveyors, Wilton, Connecticut”, that is on file in the office of the town clerk of the town of Wilton, and therein numbered 3673; and

(4) the approximately 0.9-acre western portion of a parcel of land situated in the town of Wilton, Connecticut, designated as Tall Oaks Road on the map referred to in paragraph (3).


(c) General depictionThe parcels referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b) are all as generally depicted on a map entitled “Boundary Map, Weir Farm National Historic Site, Fairfield County Connecticut”, dated June 1994. Such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(d) Acquisition of land for visitor and administrative facilities; limitations(1) Acquisition(A) In generalTo preserve and maintain the historic setting and character of the historical park, the Secretary may acquire not more than 15 additional acres for the development of visitor and administrative facilities for the historical park.


(B) ProximityThe property acquired under this subsection shall be within Fairfield County.


(C) ManagementThe acquired property shall be included within the boundary of the historical park and shall be managed and maintained as part of the historical park.



(2) Development(A) Maintaining natu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ffff_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established, as a unit of the National Park System, the Weir Farm National Historical Park in the State of Connecticut.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ffff_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Description The historical park shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ffff_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General depiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General depiction The parcels referred to in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b) are all as generally depicted on a map entitled “Boundary Map, Weir Farm National Historic Site, Fairfield County Connecticut”, dated June 1994. Such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ffff_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of land for visitor and administrative facilities; limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acquisition of land for visitor and administrative facilities; limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>