<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ggg–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ggg–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ggg–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ggg_1"><akn:num>410ggg–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of the National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ggg–1. Administration of the National Historical Park(a) In general(1) General administrationThe Secretary of the Interior (in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer the park in accordance with this subchapter and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 through 4),11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461–467).1


(2) Specific authoritiesThe Secretary may interpret the story of Rosie the Riveter and the World War II home front, conduct and maintain oral histories that relate to the World War II home front theme, and provide technical assistance in the preservation of historic properties that support this story.


(3) Nystrom Elementary SchoolNothing in this subchapter affects the authority of the West Contra Costa Unified School District to administer Nystrom Elementary School.



(b) Cooperative agreements(1) General agreementsThe Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the owners of the Child Development Field Centers (Ruth C. Powers) (Maritime), Atchison Housing, the Kaiser-Permanente Field Hospital, and Richmond Fire Station 67A, pursuant to which the Secretary may mark, interpret, improve, restore, and provide technical assistance with respect to the preservation and interpretation of such properties. Such agreements shall contain, but need not be limited to, provisions under which the Secretary shall have the right of access at reasonable times to public portions of the property for interpretive and other purposes, and that no changes or alterations shall be made in the property except by mutual agreement.


(2) Limited agreementsThe Secretary may consult and enter into cooperative agreements with interested persons for interpretation and technical assistance with the preser</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Education center The Secretary may establish a World War II Home Front Education Center in the Ford Assembly Building. Such center shall include a program that allows for distance learning and linkages to other representative sites across the country, for the purpose of educating the public as to the significance of the site and the World War II Home Front.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of Federal funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acquisition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Donations The Secretary may accept and use donations of funds, property, and services to carry out this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ggg_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>General management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) General management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>