<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410gggg" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410gggg/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410gggg/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410gggg"><akn:num>410gggg</akn:num><akn:heading>Homestead National Historical Park; establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410gggg. Homestead National Historical Park; establishment
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized and directed to acquire, on behalf of the United States, by gift, purchase, or condemnation, the south half of the northwest quarter, the northeast quarter of the northwest quarter, and the southwest quarter of the northeast quarter section 26, township 4 north, range 5 east, of the sixth principal meridian, Gage County, Nebraska, the same being the first homestead entered upon under the General Homestead Act of May 20, 1862, by Daniel Freeman, and that when so acquired, the said area be designated the “Homestead National Historical Park”.
(Mar. 19, 1936, ch. 157, § 1, 49 Stat. 1184; Pub. L. 116–328, § 1(a), Jan. 13, 2021, 134 Stat. 5099.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe General Homestead Act, referred to in text, is act May 20, 1862, ch. 75, 12 Stat. 392. See chapter 7 (§ 161 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 450u of this title.

Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–328 substituted “designated the ‘Homestead National Historical Park’.” for “designated ‘The Homestead National Monument of America.’ ”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Pub. L. 116–328, § 1(b), Jan. 13, 2021, 134 Stat. 5099, provided that: “Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the unit of the National Park System known as ‘The Homestead National Monument of America’ shall be considered to be a reference to the ‘Homestead National Historical Park’.”


Homestead National Monument of America AdditionsPub. L. 107–332, Dec. 16, 2002, 116 Stat. 2871, known as the Homestead National Monument of America Additions Act, provided for addition of certain parcels of private and State-owned land to the Homestead National Monument of America and authorized appropriations and cooperative agreements with the appropriate State and local governments.
Pub. L. 91–411, Sept. 25, 197</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>