<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410hhh_8"><akn:num>410hhh–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410hhh–8. Advisory Council(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the “Great Sand Dunes National Park Advisory Council”.


(b) DutiesThe Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of a management plan for the national park and the preserve.


(c) MembersThe Advisory Council shall consist of 10 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, as follows:(1) One member of, or nominated by, the Alamosa County Commission.

(2) One member of, or nominated by, the Saguache County Commission.

(3) One member of, or nominated by, the Friends of the Dunes Organization.

(4) Four members residing in, or within reasonable proximity to, the San Luis Valley and 3 of the general public, all of whom have recognized backgrounds reflecting—(A) the purposes for which the national park and the preserve are established; and

(B) the interests of persons that will be affected by the planning and management of the national park and the preserve.



(d) Applicable lawThe Advisory Council shall function in accordance with chapter 10 of title 5 and other applicable laws.


(e) VacancyA vacancy on the Advisory Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.


(f) ChairpersonThe Advisory Council shall elect a chairperson and shall establish such rules and procedures as it deems necessary or desirable.


(g) No compensationMembers of the Advisory Council shall serve without compensation.


(h) TerminationThe Advisory Council shall terminate upon the completion of the management plan for the national park and preserve.


(Pub. L. 106–530, § 10, Nov. 22, 2000, 114 Stat. 2535; Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(87), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4315.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 117–286 substituted “chapter 10 of title 5” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.)”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the “Great Sand Dunes National Park Advisory Council”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of a management plan for the national park and the preserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Members The Advisory Council shall consist of 10 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicable law The Advisory Council shall function in accordance with chapter 10 of title 5 and other applicable laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Vacancy A vacancy on the Advisory Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chairperson The Advisory Council shall elect a chairperson and shall establish such rules and procedures as it deems necessary or desirable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No compensation Members of the Advisory Council shall serve without compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination The Advisory Council shall terminate upon the completion of the management plan for the national park and preserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>