<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhh–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410hhh_5"><akn:num>410hhh–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of national park and preserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410hhh–5. Administration of national park and preserve(a) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the national park and the preserve in accordance with—(1) this subchapter; and

(2) all laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—(A) the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4); 11 See References in Text note below. and

(B) the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes”, approved August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1



(b) Grazing(1) Acquired State or private landWith respect to former State or private land on which grazing is authorized to occur on November 22, 2000, and which is acquired for the national monument, or the national park and preserve, or the wildlife refuge, the Secretary, in consultation with the lessee, may permit the continuation of grazing on the land by the lessee at the time of acquisition, subject to applicable law (including regulations).


(2) Federal landWhere grazing is permitted on land that is Federal land as of November 22, 2000, and that is located within the boundaries of the national monument or the national park and preserve, the Secretary is authorized to permit the continuation of such grazing activities unless the Secretary determines that grazing would harm the resources or values of the national park or the preserve.


(3) Termination of leasesNothing in this subsection shall prohibit the Secretary from accepting the voluntary termination of leases or permits for grazing within the national monument or the national park or the preserve.



(c) Hunting, fishing, and trapping(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on land and water within the preserve in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws.


(2) Admini</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall administer the national park and the preserve in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closed Basin Division, San Luis Valley Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Closed Basin Division, San Luis Valley Project Any feature of the Closed Basin Division, San Luis Valley Project, located within the boundaries of the national monument, national park or the national wildlife refuge, including any well, pump, road, easement, pipeline, canal, ditch, power line, power supply facility, or any other project facility, and the operation, maintenance, repair, and replacement of such a feature—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhh_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wilderness protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>