<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhhh–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhhh–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hhhh–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410hhhh_2"><akn:num>410hhhh–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of historic site 11 So in original. Probably should be “historical park”. See Codific</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410hhhh–2. Administration of historic site 11 So in original. Probably should be “historical park”. See Codification note set out under section 410hhhh of this title. and preservation district(a) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the historical park and the preservation district in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4),22 See References in Text note below. and the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes”, approved August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).2


(b) Cooperation with State of GeorgiaThe Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the State of Georgia pursuant to which the Secretary may cooperate in the operation and use of the State of Georgia Visitor Center in Sumter County.


(c) HistoryThe Secretary shall gather oral history on the historical park, its occupants, and environs. The Secretary may also preserve personal property that has been acquired by the Secretary for purposes of the historical park.


(d) Report25 years after December 23, 1987, the Secretary shall convene a distinguished group of nationally recognized historians, scholars, and other experts to examine the life of President Carter in greater historical perspective. The group shall examine the research then available on President Carter, his life and Presidency, and make recommendations on interpretation, preservation, and other issues (as appropriate) at the Jimmy Carter National Historical Park and the Jimmy Carter National Preservation District.


(Pub. L. 100–206, § 3, Dec. 23, 1987, 101 Stat. 1435; Pub. L. 116–341, § 2(b)(2), (4), (5), Jan. 13, 2021, 134 Stat. 5132.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextT</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhhh_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall administer the historical park and the preservation district in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4),22 See References in Text note below. and the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes”, approved August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).2</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhhh_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with State of Georgia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperation with State of Georgia The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the State of Georgia pursuant to which the Secretary may cooperate in the operation and use of the State of Georgia Visitor Center in Sumter County.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhhh_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>History</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) History The Secretary shall gather oral history on the historical park, its occupants, and environs. The Secretary may also preserve personal property that has been acquired by the Secretary for purposes of the historical park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410hhhh_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report 25 years after December 23, 1987, the Secretary shall convene a distinguished group of nationally recognized historians, scholars, and other experts to examine the life of President Carter in greater historical perspective. The group shall examine the research then available on President Carter, his life and Presidency, and make recommendations on interpretation, preservation, and other issues (as appropriate) at the Jimmy Carter National Historical Park and the Jimmy Carter National Preservation District.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>