<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hh–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hh–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410hh–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410hh_2"><akn:num>410hh–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration; hunting and subsistence uses; admission fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410hh–2. Administration; hunting and subsistence uses; admission fees
Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall administer the lands, waters, and interests therein added to existing areas or established by the foregoing sections of this subchapter as new areas of the National Park System, pursuant to the provisions of the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535), as amended and supplemented (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. and, as appropriate, under section 3201 of this title and the other applicable provisions of this Act: Provided, however, That hunting shall be permitted in areas designated as national preserves under the provisions of this Act. Subsistence uses by local residents shall be allowed in national preserves and, where specifically permitted by this Act, in national monuments and parks. Lands, waters, and interests therein withdrawn or reserved for the former Katmai and Glacier Bay National Monuments are hereby incorporated within and made a part of Katmai National Park or Glacier Bay National Park, as appropriate. Any funds available for the purposes of such monuments are hereby made available for the purposes of Katmai National Park and Preserve or Glacier Bay National Park and Preserve, as appropriate. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no fees shall be charged for entrance or admission to any unit of the National Park System located in Alaska.
(Pub. L. 96–487, title II, § 203, Dec. 2, 1980, 94 Stat. 2383.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535), as amended and supplemented (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.), referred to in text, is act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, 39 Stat. 535, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under section 100101 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs. Sections 1 to 4 of the Act were repealed and restated as section 1865(a) of Title 18, Crimes and C</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>