<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410iiii_5"><akn:num>410iiii–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Brown v. Board of Education affiliated areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410iiii–5. Establishment of the Brown v. Board of Education affiliated areas(a) In generalOn the date on which the Secretary determines that an appropriate management entity has been identified for the applicable affiliated area, as generally depicted on the map described in section 410iiii–2(c)(1) of this title, the following shall be established as affiliated areas of the National Park System:(1) The Robert Russa Moton Museum in Farmville, Virginia.

(2) The Delaware Brown v. Board of Education Civil Rights Sites, to include—(A) the former Howard High School in Wilmington, Delaware;

(B) Claymont High School in Claymont, Delaware; and

(C) Hockessin Colored School #107 in Hockessin, Delaware.


(3) The John Philip Sousa Middle School in the District of Columbia.


(b) AdministrationEach affiliated area shall be managed in a manner consistent with—(1) this subchapter; and

(2) the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.


(c) Management plans(1) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the management entity for the applicable affiliated area, shall develop a management plan for each affiliated area.


(2) RequirementsA management plan under paragraph (1) shall—(A) be prepared in consultation and coordination with interested State, county, and local governments, management entities, organizations, and interested members of the public associated with the affiliated area;

(B) identify, as appropriate, the roles and responsibilities of the National Park Service and the management entity in administering and interpreting the affiliated area in a manner that does not interfere with existing operations and continued use of existing facilities; and

(C) require the Secretary to coordinate the preparation and implementation of the management plan and interpretation of the affiliated area with the historical park.


(3) Public commentThe Secretary shall—(A) hold not less than 1 public meeting in the general proximity of each affiliated area on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general On the date on which the Secretary determines that an appropriate management entity has been identified for the applicable affiliated area, as generally depicted on the map described in section 410iiii–2(c)(1) of this title, the following shall be established as affiliated areas of the National Park System:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration Each affiliated area shall be managed in a manner consistent with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative agreements The Secretary may provide technical and financial assistance to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the management entity for each affiliated area to provide financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the applicable affiliated area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Land use Nothing in this section affects—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited role of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limited role of the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>