<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410iiii–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410iiii_2"><akn:num>410iiii–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Civil Rights in Education: Brown v. Board of Education National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410iiii–2. Establishment of the Civil Rights in Education: Brown v. Board of Education National Historical Park(a) In generalThere is hereby established as a unit of the National Park System the Brown v. Board of Education National Historical Park in the State of Kansas.


(b) DescriptionThe historical park shall consist of the Monroe Elementary School site in the city of Topeka, Shawnee County, Kansas, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Brown v. Board of Education National Historic Site,” numbered Appendix A and dated June 1992. Such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(c) Boundary adjustment(1) AdditionsIn addition to the land described in subsection (b), the historical park shall include the land and interests in land, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Brown v. Board of Education National Historical Park Boundary Additions and Affiliated Areas”, numbered 462/178,449, and dated February 2022, and more particularly described as—(A) the Summerton High School site in Summerton, Clarendon County, South Carolina;

(B) the former Scott’s Branch High School site in Summerton, Clarendon County, South Carolina; and

(C) approximately 1 acre of land adjacent to Monroe Elementary School in Topeka, Shawnee County, Kansas.


(2) MapThe map described in paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.



(Pub. L. 102–525, title I, § 103, Oct. 26, 1992, 106 Stat. 3439; Pub. L. 117–123, §§ 2(c)(2)–(4), 3(e), May 12, 2022, 136 Stat. 1196, 1198.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Pub. L. 117–123, § 2(c)(3), substituted “Historical Park” for “Historic Site” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 117–123, § 2(c)(2), substituted “National Historical Park” for “National Historic Site”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 117–123, § 2(c)(4), substituted “historical park” for “historic site”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 117–123, § 3(e), a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is hereby established as a unit of the National Park System the Brown v. Board of Education National Historical Park in the State of Kansas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Description The historical park shall consist of the Monroe Elementary School site in the city of Topeka, Shawnee County, Kansas, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Brown v. Board of Education National Historic Site,” numbered Appendix A and dated June 1992. Such map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410iiii_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Boundary adjustment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>