<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ll–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ll–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ll–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ll_1"><akn:num>410ll–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Votes for Women Trail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ll–1. Votes for Women Trail(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ParkThe term “Park” means the Women’s Rights National Historical Park established by section 410ll of this title.


(2) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.


(3) StateThe term “State” means the State of New York.


(4) TrailThe term “Trail” means the Votes for Women History Trail Route designated under subsection (b).



(b) Establishment of Trail RouteThe Secretary, with concurrence of the agency having jurisdiction over the relevant roads, may designate a vehicular tour route, to be known as the “Votes for Women History Trail Route”, to link properties in the State that are historically and thematically associated with the struggle for women’s suffrage in the United States.


(c) AdministrationThe Trail shall be administered by the National Park Service through the Park.


(d) ActivitiesTo facilitate the establishment of the Trail and the dissemination of information regarding the Trail, the Secretary shall—(1) produce and disseminate appropriate educational materials regarding the Trail, such as handbooks, maps, exhibits, signs, interpretive guides, and electronic information;

(2) coordinate the management, planning, and standards of the Trail in partnership with participating properties, other Federal agencies, and State and local governments;

(3) create and adopt an official, uniform symbol or device to mark the Trail; and

(4) issue guidelines for the use of the symbol or device adopted under paragraph (3).


(e) Elements of Trail RouteSubject to the consent of the owner of the property, the Secretary may designate as an official stop on the Trail—(1) all units and programs of the Park relating to the struggle for women’s suffrage;

(2) other Federal, State, local, and privately owned properties that the Secretary determines have a verifiable connection to the struggle for women’s suffrage; and

(3) other</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Trail Route</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Trail Route The Secretary, with concurrence of the agency having jurisdiction over the relevant roads, may designate a vehicular tour route, to be known as the “Votes for Women History Trail Route”, to link properties in the State that are historically and thematically associated with the struggle for women’s suffrage in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration The Trail shall be administered by the National Park Service through the Park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities To facilitate the establishment of the Trail and the dissemination of information regarding the Trail, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of Trail Route</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Elements of Trail Route Subject to the consent of the owner of the property, the Secretary may designate as an official stop on the Trail—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ll_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>