<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410r_8"><akn:num>410r–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of certain water projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410r–8. Modification of certain water projects(a) Improved water deliveries(1) Upon completion of a final report by the Chief of the Army Corps of Engineers, the Secretary of the Army, in consultation with the Secretary, is authorized and directed to construct modifications to the Central and Southern Florida Project to improve water deliveries into the park and shall, to the extent practicable, take steps to restore the natural hydrological conditions within the park.

(2) Such modifications shall be based upon the findings of the Secretary’s experimental program authorized in section 1302 of the 1984 Supplemental Appropriations Act (97 Stat. 1292) and generally as set forth in a General Design Memorandum to be prepared by the Jacksonville District entitled “Modified Water Deliveries to Everglades National Park”. The Draft of such Memorandum and the Final Memorandum, as prepared by the Jacksonville District, shall be submitted as promptly as practicable to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the United States House of Representatives.

(3) Construction of project modifications authorized in this subsection and flood protection systems authorized in subsections (c) and (d) are justified by the environmental benefits to be derived by the Everglades ecosystem in general and by the park in particular and shall not require further economic justification.

(4) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the operation of project facilities to achieve their design objectives, as set forth in the Congressional authorization and any modifications thereof.


(b) Determination of adverse effect(1) Upon completion of the Final Memorandum referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Army, in consultation with the South Florida Water Management District, shall make a determination as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved water deliveries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Improved water deliveries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of adverse effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of adverse effect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flood protection; Eight and One-Half Square Mile Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Flood protection; Eight and One-Half Square Mile Area If the Secretary of the Army makes a determination pursuant to subsection (b) that the “Eight and One-Half Square Mile Area” will be adversely affected, the Secretary of the Army is authorized and directed to construct a flood protection system for that portion of presently developed land within such area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flood protection; adjacent agricultural area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Flood protection; adjacent agricultural area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Periodic review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current canal operating levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Current canal operating levels Nothing in this section shall be construed to require or prohibit the Secretary of the Army or the South Florida Water Management District from maintaining the water level within any project canal below the maximum authorized operating level as of December 13, 1989.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No limitation on other claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No limitation on other claims If the Secretary of the Army makes a determination of no adverse effect pursuant to subsection (b), such determination shall not be considered as a limitation or prohibition against any available legal remedy which may otherwise be available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination The Secretary and the Secretary of the Army shall coordinate the construction program authorized under this section and the land acquisition program authorized in section 410r–6 of this title in such a manner as will permit both to proceed concurrently and as will avoid unreasonable interference with property interests prior to the acquisition of such interests by the Secretary under section 410r–6 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>West Dade Wellfield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) West Dade Wellfield No Federal license, permit, approval, right-of-way or assistance shall be granted or issued with respect to the West Dade Wellfield (to be located in the Bird Drive Drainage Basin, as identified in the Comprehensive Development Master Plan for Dade County, Florida) until the Secretary, the Governor of the State of Florida, the South Florida Water Management District and Dade County, Florida enter into an agreement providing that the South Florida Water Management District’s water use permit for the wellfield, if granted, must include the following limiting conditions: (1) the wellfield’s peak pumpage rate shall not exceed 140,000,000 gallons per day; (2) the permit shall include reasonable, enforceable measures to limit demand on the wellfield in times of water shortage; and (3) if, during times of water shortage, the District fails to limit demand on the wellfield pursuant to (2), or if the District limits demand on the wellfield pursuant to (2), but the Secret</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_8_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of natural values</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Protection of natural values The Secretary of the Army is directed in analysis, design and engineering associated with the development of a general design memorandum for works and operations in the “C–111 basin” area of the East Everglades, to take all measures which are feasible and consistent with the purposes of the project to protect natural values associated with Everglades National Park. Upon completion of a general design memorandum for the area, the Secretary shall prepare and transmit a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the United States House of Representatives on the status of the natural resources of the C–111 basin and functionally related lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>