<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410r–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410r_6"><akn:num>410r–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410r–6. Boundary modification(a) Area included(1) In generalThe park boundary is hereby modified to include approximately 107,600 acres as generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Everglades National Park Addition, Dade County, Florida”, numbered 160–20,013B and dated September 1989.


(2) Availability of mapThe map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.


(3) Acquisition of additional land(A) In generalThe Secretary may acquire from 1 or more willing sellers not more than 10 acres of land located outside the boundary of the park and adjacent to or near the East Everglades area of the park for the development of administrative, housing, maintenance, or other park purposes.


(B) Administration; applicable lawOn acquisition of the land under subparagraph (A), the land shall be administered as part of the park in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the park.




(b) Boundary adjustmentThe Secretary may from time to time make minor revisions in the boundaries of the park in accordance with section 100506(c) of title 54. In exercising the boundary adjustment authority the Secretary shall ensure all actions will enhance resource preservation and shall not result in a net loss of acreage from the park.


(c) Acquisition(1) Within the boundaries of the addition described in subsection (a), the Secretary may acquire lands and interests in land by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange. For purposes of acquiring property by exchange, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, exchange the approximately one acre of Federal land known as “Gilberts’ Marina” for non-Federal land of equal value located within the boundaries of the addition. Any lands or interests in land which are owned by the State of Florida or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation.

(2) It is the express in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Area included</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boundary adjustment The Secretary may from time to time make minor revisions in the boundaries of the park in accordance with section 100506(c) of title 54. In exercising the boundary adjustment authority the Secretary shall ensure all actions will enhance resource preservation and shall not result in a net loss of acreage from the park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of tracts partially outside boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acquisition of tracts partially outside boundaries When any tract of land is only partly within boundaries referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary may acquire all or any portion of the land outside of such boundaries in order to minimize the payment of severance costs. Land so acquired outside of the boundaries may be exchanged by the Secretary for non-Federal lands within the boundaries, and any land so acquired and not utilized for exchange shall be reported to the General Services Administration for disposal under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offers to sell</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Offers to sell In exercising the authority to acquire property under sections 410r–5 to 410r–8 of this title, the Secretary shall give prompt and careful consideration to any offer made by any person owning property within the boundaries of the addition to sell such property, if such owner notifies the Secretary that the continued ownership of such property is causing, or would result in undue hardship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance Upon the request of the Governor of the State of Florida, the Secretary is authorized to provide technical assistance and personnel to assist in the acquisition of lands and waters within the Kissimmee River/Lake Okeechobee/Everglades Hydrologic Basin, including the Big Cypress Swamp, through the provision of Federal land acquisition personnel, practices, and procedures. The State of Florida shall reimburse the Secretary for such assistance in such amounts and at such time as agreed upon by the Secretary and the State. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, reimbursement received by the Secretary for such assistance shall be retained by the Secretary and shall be available without further appropriation for purposes of carrying out any authorized activity of the Secretary within the boundaries of the park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410r_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Land exchanges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>