<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410s"><akn:num>410s</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410s. Establishment(a) In generalIn order to preserve for the benefit of the American people certain historic structures and properties of outstanding national significance associated with the opening of the War of the American Revolution, Minute Man National Historical Park is authorized to be established in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts. The purposes of the park shall include the preservation and interpretation of (1) the historic landscape along the road between Lexington and Concord, (2) sites associated with the causes and consequences of the American Revolution, and (3) the Wayside on Lexington Road in Concord, the home of Nathaniel Hawthorne, Bronson Alcott, Louisa May Alcott, and Margaret Sidney, whose works illustrate the nineteenth century American literary renaissance.


(b) BoundariesThe park shall be comprised of the lands depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map NARO–406–20015C”, dated June 1991.


(Pub. L. 86–321, § 1, Sept. 21, 1959, 73 Stat. 591; Pub. L. 91–548, § 1, Dec. 14, 1970, 84 Stat. 1436; Pub. L. 102–488, § 2[(1)], Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3135.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–488 substituted “The purposes of the park shall include the preservation and interpretation of (1) the historic landscape along the road between Lexington and Concord, (2) sites associated with the causes and consequences of the American Revolution, and (3) the Wayside on Lexington Road in Concord, the home of Nathaniel Hawthorne, Bronson Alcott, Louisa May Alcott, and Margaret Sidney, whose works illustrate the nineteenth century American literary renaissance.” for “The park shall comprise not more than seven hundred and fifty acres as may be designated by the Secretary of the Interior from within the area beginning at Fiske Hill and thence lying along Massachusetts Avenue, Marrett Road and Marrett Street in the town of Lexington, along Nelson Road, Virginia Road, Old Bedford Road, and North Great Road or State Route 2–A in the town o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to preserve for the benefit of the American people certain historic structures and properties of outstanding national significance associated with the opening of the War of the American Revolution, Minute Man National Historical Park is authorized to be established in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts. The purposes of the park shall include the preservation and interpretation of (1) the historic landscape along the road between Lexington and Concord, (2) sites associated with the causes and consequences of the American Revolution, and (3) the Wayside on Lexington Road in Concord, the home of Nathaniel Hawthorne, Bronson Alcott, Louisa May Alcott, and Margaret Sidney, whose works illustrate the nineteenth century American literary renaissance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boundaries The park shall be comprised of the lands depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map NARO–406–20015C”, dated June 1991.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>