<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ss–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ss–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ss–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ss_1"><akn:num>410ss–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ss–1. Administration(a) In generalThe Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer the park in accordance with this subchapter and with the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1–4) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461–467).1 The Secretary may acquire lands or interests in land within the boundaries of the park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.


(b) DonationsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may accept and retain donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, corporations, or public entities for the purpose of providing services and facilities which he deems consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.


(c) Separate unitsThe Secretary shall provide for the identification of the Guevavi, Calabazas, and Tumacacori sites as 3 separate units of the park.


(d) Recognition of Father Eusebio Francisco Kino’s roleIn administering the park, the Secretary shall utilize such interpretative materials and other devices as may be necessary to give appropriate recognition to the role of the Jesuit Missionary Priest, Father Eusebio Francisco Kino, in the development of the mission sites and the settlement of the region.


(Pub. L. 101–344, § 2, Aug. 6, 1990, 104 Stat. 393.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1–4), referred to in subsec. (a), is act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, 39 Stat. 535, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this title and provisions set out as a note under section 100101 of Title 54, National Par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ss_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer the park in accordance with this subchapter and with the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the national park system, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1–4) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461–467).1 The Secretary may acquire lands or interests in land within the boundaries of the park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ss_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Donations Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may accept and retain donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, corporations, or public entities for the purpose of providing services and facilities which he deems consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ss_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Separate units The Secretary shall provide for the identification of the Guevavi, Calabazas, and Tumacacori sites as 3 separate units of the park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ss_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of Father Eusebio Francisco Kino’s role</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recognition of Father Eusebio Francisco Kino’s role In administering the park, the Secretary shall utilize such interpretative materials and other devices as may be necessary to give appropriate recognition to the role of the Jesuit Missionary Priest, Father Eusebio Francisco Kino, in the development of the mission sites and the settlement of the region.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>