<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410sss" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410sss/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410sss/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410sss"><akn:num>410sss</akn:num><akn:heading>Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park, Maryland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410sss. Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park, Maryland(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Historical parkThe term “historical park” means the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park established by subsection (b)(1)(A).


(2) MapThe term “map” means the map entitled “Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park, Proposed Boundary and Authorized Acquisition Areas”, numbered T20/80,001A, and dated March 2014.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(4) StateThe term “State” means the State of Maryland.



(b) Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park(1) Establishment(A) In generalThere is established as a unit of the National Park System the Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park in the State, consisting of the area depicted on the map as “Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park Boundary”.


(B) BoundaryThe boundary of the historical park shall consist of—(i) the land described in subparagraph (A); and

(ii) any land and interests in land acquired under paragraph (3).


(C) Availability of mapThe map shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the National Park Service.



(2) PurposeThe purpose of the historical park is to preserve and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the historical, cultural, and natural resources associated with the life of Harriet Tubman and the Underground Railroad.


(3) Land acquisition(A) In generalThe Secretary may acquire land and interests in land within the areas depicted on the map as “Authorized Acquisition Areas for the National Historical Park” only by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange.


(B) LimitationThe Secretary may not acquire land or an interest in land for purposes of this section by condemnation.


(C) Boundary adjustmentOn acquisition of land or an interest in land under subparagraph (A), the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410sss_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410sss_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Harriet Tubman Underground Railroad National Historical Park</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410sss_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410sss_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>