<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ttt" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ttt/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ttt/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ttt"><akn:num>410ttt</akn:num><akn:heading>Harriet Tubman National Historical Park, Auburn, New York</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ttt. Harriet Tubman National Historical Park, Auburn, New York(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Historical parkThe term “historical park” means the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park established by subsection (b)(1)(A).


(2) HomeThe term “Home” means The Harriet Tubman Home, Inc., located in Auburn, New York.


(3) MapThe term “map” means the map entitled “Harriet Tubman National Historical Park”, numbered T18/80,000, and dated March 2009.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(5) StateThe term “State” means the State of New York.



(b) Harriet Tubman National Historical Park(1) Establishment(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), there is established the Harriet Tubman National Historical Park in Auburn, New York, as a unit of the National Park System.


(B) Determination by SecretaryThe historical park shall not be established until the date on which the Secretary determines that a sufficient quantity of land, or interests in land, has been acquired to constitute a manageable park unit.


(C) NoticeNot later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes a determination under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the establishment of the historical park.


(D) MapThe map shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the National Park Service.



(2) BoundaryThe historical park shall include the Harriet Tubman Home, the Tubman Home for the Aged, the Thompson Memorial AME Zion Church and Rectory, and associated land, as identified in the area entitled “National Historical Park Proposed Boundary” on the map.


(3) PurposeThe purpose of the historical park is to preserve and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the historical, cultural, and natural resources associated with the life of Harriet Tubman.


(4) Land acquisition(A) In generalThe Secretary may acquire land and interests in land within the areas depi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ttt_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ttt_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harriet Tubman National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Harriet Tubman National Historical Park</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ttt_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ttt_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>