<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410tt_1"><akn:num>410tt–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve at St. Croix, Virgin Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410tt–1. Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve at St. Croix, Virgin Islands(a) EstablishmentIn order to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations certain nationally significant historical, cultural, and natural sites and resources in the Virgin Islands, there is established the Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve at St. Croix, Virgin Islands (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “park”).


(b) Area includedThe park shall consist of approximately 1015 acres of lands, waters, and interests in lands as generally depicted on the map entitled “Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve, St. Croix, U.S.V.I.”, numbered 141/80002, and dated May 2, 2002. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and the Offices of the Lieutenant Governor of St. Thomas and St. Croix, Virgin Islands.


(Pub. L. 102–247, title I, § 103, Feb. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 34; Pub. L. 107–329, title III, § 301, Dec. 6, 2002, 116 Stat. 2819.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title I of Pub. L. 102–247, known as the Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve at St. Croix, Virgin Islands, Act of 1992, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments2002—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 107–329 amended first sentence generally. Prior to amendment, first sentence read as follows: “The park shall consist of approximately 912 acres of land, waters, submerged lands, and interests therein within the area generally depicted on the map entitled ‘Salt River Study Area—Alternative “C” ’ in the ‘Alternatives Study and Environmental Assessment for the Columbus Landing Site, St. Croix, U.S. Virgin Islands’, prepared by the National Park Service and dated June 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410tt_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations certain nationally significant historical, cultural, and natural sites and resources in the Virgin Islands, there is established the Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve at St. Croix, Virgin Islands (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “park”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410tt_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Area included The park shall consist of approximately 1015 acres of lands, waters, and interests in lands as generally depicted on the map entitled “Salt River Bay National Historical Park and Ecological Preserve, St. Croix, U.S.V.I.”, numbered 141/80002, and dated May 2, 2002. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and the Offices of the Lieutenant Governor of St. Thomas and St. Croix, Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>