<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410tt–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410tt_2"><akn:num>410tt–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410tt–2. Acquisition of land(a) General authorityThe Secretary of the Interior (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) may acquire land and interests in land within the boundaries of the park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Government of the United States Virgin Islands from acquiring land or interest in land within the boundaries of the park.


(b) Limitations on authorityLands, and interests in lands, within the boundaries of the park which are owned by the United States Virgin Islands, or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation or exchange. No lands, or interests therein, containing dwellings lying within the park boundary as of July 1, 1991, may be acquired without the consent of the owner, unless the Secretary determines, after consultation with the Government of the United States Virgin Islands, that the land is being developed or proposed to be developed in a manner which is detrimental to the natural, scenic, historic, and other values for which the park was established.


(Pub. L. 102–247, title I, § 104, Feb. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 34.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410tt_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority The Secretary of the Interior (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) may acquire land and interests in land within the boundaries of the park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Government of the United States Virgin Islands from acquiring land or interest in land within the boundaries of the park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410tt_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on authority Lands, and interests in lands, within the boundaries of the park which are owned by the United States Virgin Islands, or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation or exchange. No lands, or interests therein, containing dwellings lying within the park boundary as of July 1, 1991, may be acquired without the consent of the owner, unless the Secretary determines, after consultation with the Government of the United States Virgin Islands, that the land is being developed or proposed to be developed in a manner which is detrimental to the natural, scenic, historic, and other values for which the park was established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>