<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ww–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ww–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410ww–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410ww_21"><akn:num>410ww–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Dayton Aviation Heritage Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410ww–21. Dayton Aviation Heritage Commission(a) EstablishmentThere is established the Dayton Aviation Heritage Commission to assist Federal, State, and local authorities and the private sector in preserving and managing the historic resources in the Miami Valley, Ohio, associated with the Wright brothers, aviation, or Paul Laurence Dunbar.


(b) MembershipThe Commission shall consist of 13 members as follows:(1) 3 members appointed by the Secretary, who shall have demonstrated expertise in aviation history, black history and literature, aviation technology, or historic preservation, at least one of whom shall represent the National Park Service.

(2) 3 members appointed by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations submitted by the Governor of the State of Ohio, who shall have demonstrated expertise in aviation history, black history and literature, aviation technology, or historic preservation, at least one of whom shall represent the Ohio Historical Society.

(3) 1 member appointed by the Secretary of Defense, who shall represent Wright-Patterson Air Force Base.

(4) 3 members appointed by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations submitted by the City Commission of Dayton, Ohio, at least one of whom shall reside near the core parcel of the park (as described in section 410ww(b)(1) of this title).

(5) 1 member appointed by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations submitted by the Board of Commissioners of Montgomery County, Ohio.

(6) 1 member appointed by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations submitted by the Board of Commissioners of Greene County, Ohio.

(7) 1 member appointed by the Secretary after consideration of recommendations submitted by the City Council of Fairborn, Ohio.


(c) Terms(1) Members shall be appointed for terms of 3 years. A member may be reappointed only 3 times unless such member was originally appointed to fill a vacancy pursuant to subsection (e)(1), in which case such member may be rea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the Dayton Aviation Heritage Commission to assist Federal, State, and local authorities and the private sector in preserving and managing the historic resources in the Miami Valley, Ohio, associated with the Wright brothers, aviation, or Paul Laurence Dunbar.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Commission shall consist of 13 members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair and vice chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chair and vice chair The chair and vice chair of the Commission shall be elected by the members of the Commission. The terms of the chair and vice chair shall be 2 years. The vice chair shall serve as chair in the absence of the chair.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Vacancy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quorum A majority of the members of the Commission then serving shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings The Commission shall meet not less than 3 times a year at the call of the chair or a majority of its members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Pay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Chapter 10 of title 5 Section 1013(b) of title 5 shall not apply to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410ww_21_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination The Commission shall cease to exist on January 1, 2004.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>