<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xxx" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xxx/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xxx/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410xxx"><akn:num>410xxx</akn:num><akn:heading>Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410xxx. Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Historic DistrictThe term “Historic District” means the Ste. Genevieve Historic District National Historic Landmark, as generally depicted on the Map.


(2) Historical ParkThe term “Historical Park” means the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park established by subsection (b).


(3) MapThe term “Map” means the map entitled “Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Proposed Boundary Addition”, numbered 571/177,464, and dated September 2021.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(5) Special resource studyThe term “special resource study” means the study entitled “Ste. Genevieve Final Special Resources Study and Environmental Assessment, Missouri” and dated May 2016.


(6) StateThe term “State” means the State of Missouri.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), there is established the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park in the State as a unit of the National Park System to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the themes of French settlement, vernacular architecture, and community form and farming on the frontier associated with Ste. Genevieve.


(2) Conditions for establishmentThe Historical Park shall not be established until the date on which the Secretary determines that—(A) sufficient land has been acquired for the Historical Park to constitute a manageable unit; and

(B) the Secretary has entered into a written agreement providing that land owned by the State, the City of Ste. Genevieve, or other entity within the Historic District shall be managed consistent with the purposes of this section.



(c) BoundariesThe boundaries of the Historical Park shall be the boundaries generally depicted on the Map.


(d) Availability of Map(1) In generalThe Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(2) Authority to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Boundaries The boundaries of the Historical Park shall be the boundaries generally depicted on the Map.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of Map</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acquisition authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xxx_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited role of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limited role of the Secretary Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the Historic District.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>