<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410xx_2"><akn:num>410xx–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition and transfer of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410xx–2. Land acquisition and transfer of property(a) In generalWithin the boundaries of the park the Secretary may acquire lands and interests in land by donation or exchange. For the purposes of acquiring property by exchange with the State of Florida, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, exchange those Federal lands which were deleted from the park by the boundary modifications enacted by section 201 of the Act of June 28, 1980 (Public Law 96–287), and which are directly adjacent to lands owned by the State of Florida outside of the park, for lands owned by the State of Florida within the park boundary.


(b) United States Coast Guard landsWhen all or any substantial portion of lands under the administration of the United States Coast Guard located within the park boundaries, including Loggerhead Key, have been determined by the United States Coast Guard to be excess to its needs, such lands shall be transferred directly to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purposes of this subchapter. The United States Coast Guard may reserve the right in such transfer to maintain and utilize the existing lighthouse on Loggerhead Key in a manner consistent with the purposes of the United States Coast Guard and the purposes of this subchapter.


(c) Administrative siteThe Secretary is authorized to lease or to acquire, by purchase, donation, or exchange, and to operate incidental administrative and support facilities in Key West, Florida, for park administration and to further the purposes of this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 102–525, title II, § 203, Oct. 26, 1992, 106 Stat. 3440.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 201 of the Act of June 28, 1980 (Public Law 96–287), referred to in subsec. (a), appears in a table under the heading “National Monuments Established Under Presidential Proclamation”, set out as a note under section 320301 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Within the boundaries of the park the Secretary may acquire lands and interests in land by donation or exchange. For the purposes of acquiring property by exchange with the State of Florida, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, exchange those Federal lands which were deleted from the park by the boundary modifications enacted by section 201 of the Act of June 28, 1980 (Public Law 96–287), and which are directly adjacent to lands owned by the State of Florida outside of the park, for lands owned by the State of Florida within the park boundary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Coast Guard lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States Coast Guard lands When all or any substantial portion of lands under the administration of the United States Coast Guard located within the park boundaries, including Loggerhead Key, have been determined by the United States Coast Guard to be excess to its needs, such lands shall be transferred directly to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purposes of this subchapter. The United States Coast Guard may reserve the right in such transfer to maintain and utilize the existing lighthouse on Loggerhead Key in a manner consistent with the purposes of the United States Coast Guard and the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative site The Secretary is authorized to lease or to acquire, by purchase, donation, or exchange, and to operate incidental administrative and support facilities in Key West, Florida, for park administration and to further the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>