<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410xx/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410xx"><akn:num>410xx</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410xx. Establishment(a) In generalIn order to preserve and protect for the education, inspiration, and enjoyment of present and future generations nationally significant natural, historic, scenic, marine, and scientific values in South Florida, there is hereby established the Dry Tortugas National Park (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “park”).


(b) Area includedThe park shall consist of the lands, waters, and interests therein generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Fort Jefferson National Monument”, numbered 364–90,001, and dated April 1980 (which is the map referenced by section 201 of Public Law 96–287). The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.


(c) Abolition of monumentThe Fort Jefferson National Monument is hereby abolished.


(Pub. L. 102–525, title II, § 201, Oct. 26, 1992, 106 Stat. 3439.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 102–525, Oct. 26, 1992, 106 Stat. 3439, which enacted this subchapter and amended provisions listed in a National Monuments Established Under Presidential Proclamation table set out under section 320301 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Tables.
Section 201 of Public Law 96–287, referred to in subsec. (b), appears in a table under the heading “National Monuments Established Under Presidential Proclamation”, set out as a note under section 320301 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to preserve and protect for the education, inspiration, and enjoyment of present and future generations nationally significant natural, historic, scenic, marine, and scientific values in South Florida, there is hereby established the Dry Tortugas National Park (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “park”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Area included The park shall consist of the lands, waters, and interests therein generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Fort Jefferson National Monument”, numbered 364–90,001, and dated April 1980 (which is the map referenced by section 201 of Public Law 96–287). The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410xx_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abolition of monument</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Abolition of monument The Fort Jefferson National Monument is hereby abolished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>