<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410yy–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410yy–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/410yy–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410yy_8"><akn:num>410yy–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Keweenaw National Historical Park Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410yy–8. Keweenaw National Historical Park Advisory Commission(a) Establishment and dutiesThere is established the Keweenaw National Historical Park Advisory Commission. The Commission shall—(1) advise the Secretary in the preparation and implementation of a general management plan described in section 410yy–5 of this title;

(2) advise the Secretary on the development of and priorities for implementing standards and criteria by which the Secretary, pursuant to agreements referred to in sections 410yy–6 and 410yy–7 of this title, will provide financial as well as technical assistance to owners of non-Federal properties within the park;

(3) advise the Secretary on the development of rules governing the disbursal of funds for the development of non-Federal properties;

(4) advise the Secretary with respect to the selection of sites for interpretation and preservation by means of cooperative agreements pursuant to section 410yy–6 of this title;

(5) assist the Secretary in developing policies and programs for the conservation and protection of the scenic, historical, cultural, natural and technological values of the park which would complement the purposes of this subchapter;

(6) assist the Secretary in coordinating with local governments and the State of Michigan the implementation of the general management plan, and furthering the purposes of this subchapter;

(7) be authorized to carry out historical, educational, or cultural programs which encourage or enhance appreciation of the historic resources in the park, surrounding areas, and on the Keweenaw Peninsula; and

(8) be authorized to seek, accept, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or donations of money, personal property, or services, received from any source, consistent with the purposes of this subchapter and the park management.


(b) Acquisition of property(1) The Commission may acquire real property, or interests in real property, to further the purposes of the subchapter by gift or devise; or, by purchase</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and duties There is established the Keweenaw National Historical Park Advisory Commission. The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation Members shall serve without pay. Members who are full-time officers or employees of the United States, the State of Michigan, or any political subdivision thereof shall receive no additional pay on account of their service on the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Travel expenses While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mails The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Staff The Commission may appoint and fix the pay of such personnel as the Commission deems desirable. The Secretary may provide the Commission with such staff and technical assistance as the Secretary, after consultation with the Commission, considers appropriate to enable the Commission to carry out its duties, on a cost reimbursable basis. Upon request of the Secretary, any Federal agency may provide information, personnel, property, and services on a reimbursable basis, to the Commission to assist in carrying out its duties under this section. The Secretary may accept the services of personnel detailed from the State of Michigan or any political subdivision of the State and reimburse the State or such political subdivision for such services. The Commission may procure additional temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, with funds obtained under subsection (a)(6), or as provided by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410yy_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Hearings The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this subchapter, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Commission considers appropriate. The Commission may not issue subpoenas or exercise any subpoena authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>