<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4221"><akn:num>4221</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of African elephant conservation programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4221. Review of African elephant conservation programs(a) In generalWithin one month after October 7, 1988, the Secretary shall issue a call for information on the African elephant conservation program of each ivory producing country by—(1) publishing a notice in the Federal Register requesting submission of such information to the Secretary by all interested parties; and

(2) submitting a written request for such information through the Secretary of State to each ivory producing country.


(b) Review and determination(1) In generalThe Secretary shall review the African elephant conservation program of each ivory producing country and, not later than one year after October 7, 1988, shall issue and publish in the Federal Register a determination of whether or not the country meets the following criteria:(A) The country is a party to CITES and adheres to the CITES Ivory Control System.

(B) The country’s elephant conservation program is based on the best available information, and the country is making expeditious progress in compiling information on the elephant habitat condition and carrying capacity, total population and population trends, and the annual reproduction and mortality of the elephant populations within the country.

(C) The taking of elephants in the country is effectively controlled and monitored.

(D) The country’s ivory quota is determined on the basis of information referred to in subparagraph (B) and reflects the amount of ivory which is confiscated or consumed domestically by the country.

(E) The country has not authorized or allowed the export of amounts of raw ivory which exceed its ivory quota under the CITES Ivory Control System.


(2) Delay in issuing determinationIf the Secretary finds within one year after October 7, 1988, that there is insufficient information upon which to make the determination under paragraph (1), the Secretary may delay issuing the determination until no later than December 31, 1989. The Secretary shall issue and p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Within one month after October 7, 1988, the Secretary shall issue a call for information on the African elephant conservation program of each ivory producing country by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review and determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>