<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_423l_2"><akn:num>423l–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 423l–2. Findings and purpose(a) FindingsThe Congress finds the following:(1) In the Act of March 2, 1936 (Chapter 113; 49 Stat. 1155; 16 U.S.C. 423j), Congress authorized the establishment of the Richmond National Battlefield Park, and the boundaries of the battlefield park were established to permit the inclusion of all military battlefield areas related to the battles fought during the Civil War in the vicinity of the City of Richmond, Virginia. The battlefield park originally included the area then known as the Richmond Battlefield State Park.

(2) The total acreage identified in 1936 for consideration for inclusion in the battlefield park consisted of approximately 225,000 acres in and around the City of Richmond. A study undertaken by the congressionally authorized Civil War Sites Advisory Committee determined that of these 225,000 acres, the historically significant areas relating to the campaigns against and in defense of Richmond encompass approximately 38,000 acres.

(3) In a 1996 general management plan, the National Park Service identified approximately 7,121 acres in and around the City of Richmond that satisfy the National Park Service criteria of significance, integrity, feasibility, and suitability for inclusion in the battlefield park. The National Park Service later identified an additional 186 acres for inclusion in the battlefield park.

(4) There is a national interest in protecting and preserving sites of historical significance associated with the Civil War and the City of Richmond.

(5) The Commonwealth of Virginia and its local units of government have authority to prevent or minimize adverse uses of these historic resources and can play a significant role in the protection of the historic resources related to the campaigns against and in defense of Richmond.

(6) The preservation of the New Market Heights Battlefield in the vicinity of the City of Richmond is an important aspect of American history that can be interpreted to the public. Th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose It is the purpose of sections 423l–1 to 423l–6 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>