<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/423l–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_423l_5"><akn:num>423l–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Park administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 423l–5. Park administration(a) Applicable lawsThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, shall administer the battlefield park in accordance with sections 423l–1 to 423l–6 of this title and laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act of August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1


(b) New Market Heights BattlefieldThe Secretary shall provide for the establishment of a monument or memorial suitable to honor the 14 Medal of Honor recipients from the United States Colored Troops who fought in the Battle of New Market Heights. The Secretary shall include the Battle of New Market Heights and the role of black Union soldiers in the battle in historical interpretations provided to the public at the battlefield park.


(c) Cooperative agreementsThe Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the Commonwealth of Virginia, its political subdivisions (including the City of Richmond), private property owners, and other members of the private sector to develop mechanisms to protect and interpret the historical resources within the battlefield park in a manner that would allow for continued private ownership and use where compatible with the purposes for which the battlefield is established.


(d) Technical assistanceThe Secretary may provide technical assistance to the Commonwealth of Virginia, its political subdivisions, nonprofit entities, and private property owners for the development of comprehensive plans, land use guidelines, special studies, and other activities that are consistent with the identification, protection, interpretation, and commemoration of historically significant Civil War resources located inside and outside of the boundaries of the battlefield park. The technical assistance does not authorize the Secretary to own or manage any of the resources outside the battlefield park boundaries.


(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicable laws The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, shall administer the battlefield park in accordance with sections 423l–1 to 423l–6 of this title and laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act of August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New Market Heights Battlefield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New Market Heights Battlefield The Secretary shall provide for the establishment of a monument or memorial suitable to honor the 14 Medal of Honor recipients from the United States Colored Troops who fought in the Battle of New Market Heights. The Secretary shall include the Battle of New Market Heights and the role of black Union soldiers in the battle in historical interpretations provided to the public at the battlefield park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperative agreements The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the Commonwealth of Virginia, its political subdivisions (including the City of Richmond), private property owners, and other members of the private sector to develop mechanisms to protect and interpret the historical resources within the battlefield park in a manner that would allow for continued private ownership and use where compatible with the purposes for which the battlefield is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423l_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance The Secretary may provide technical assistance to the Commonwealth of Virginia, its political subdivisions, nonprofit entities, and private property owners for the development of comprehensive plans, land use guidelines, special studies, and other activities that are consistent with the identification, protection, interpretation, and commemoration of historically significant Civil War resources located inside and outside of the boundaries of the battlefield park. The technical assistance does not authorize the Secretary to own or manage any of the resources outside the battlefield park boundaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>