<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/425m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/425m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/425m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_425m"><akn:num>425m</akn:num><akn:heading>Retained rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 425m. Retained rights(a) Retention of use and occupancyWith the exception of property which the Secretary determines is necessary for development or public use, the owner or owners of improved property acquired pursuant to sections 425k to 425o of this title may retain a right of use and occupancy of such improved property for noncommercial residential purposes for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or for a term ending at the death of the owner or the owner’s spouse. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved, except that if the owner is a corporation, trust, partnership, or any entity other than an individual, the term shall not exceed twenty-five years. Ownership shall be determined as of June 1, 1989. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the fair market value of the right retained by the owner.


(b) Terms and conditionsAny rights retained pursuant to this section shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe and may be terminated by the Secretary upon his determination and after reasonable notice to the owner thereof that such property is being used for any purpose which is incompatible with the administration, protection, or public use of the park. Such right shall terminate by operation of law upon notification of the owner by the Secretary and tendering to the owner an amount equal to the fair market value of that portion of the right which remains unexpired.


(c) “Improved property” definedAs used in this section, the term “improved property” means a year-round noncommercial single-family dwelling together with such land, in the same ownership as the dwelling, as the Secretary determines is reasonably necessary for the enjoyment of the dwelling for single-family residential use.


(Pub. L. 101–214, § 4, Dec. 11, 1989, 103 Stat. 1850.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_425m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of use and occupancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Retention of use and occupancy With the exception of property which the Secretary determines is necessary for development or public use, the owner or owners of improved property acquired pursuant to sections 425k to 425o of this title may retain a right of use and occupancy of such improved property for noncommercial residential purposes for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or for a term ending at the death of the owner or the owner’s spouse. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved, except that if the owner is a corporation, trust, partnership, or any entity other than an individual, the term shall not exceed twenty-five years. Ownership shall be determined as of June 1, 1989. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the fair market value of the right retained by the owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_425m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions Any rights retained pursuant to this section shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe and may be terminated by the Secretary upon his determination and after reasonable notice to the owner thereof that such property is being used for any purpose which is incompatible with the administration, protection, or public use of the park. Such right shall terminate by operation of law upon notification of the owner by the Secretary and tendering to the owner an amount equal to the fair market value of that portion of the right which remains unexpired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_425m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Improved property” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Improved property” defined As used in this section, the term “improved property” means a year-round noncommercial single-family dwelling together with such land, in the same ownership as the dwelling, as the Secretary determines is reasonably necessary for the enjoyment of the dwelling for single-family residential use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>