<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/426o–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/426o–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/426o–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_426o_1"><akn:num>426o–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 426o–1. Planning(a) Preparation of plan for Redoubt BrannanThe Secretary shall, on or before February 1, 1992, prepare a plan for the preservation and interpretation of Redoubt Brannan.


(b) Update of General Management PlanThe Secretary shall, on or before March 31, 1993, update the General Management Plan for the Stones River National Battlefield.


(c) Technical assistanceThe Secretary is authorized to provide technical assistance to the city and to Rutherford County in the development of zoning ordinances and other land use controls that would help preserve historically significant areas adjacent to the battlefield.


(d) Minor boundary revisionsIf the planning activities conducted under subsections (a) and (b) of this section show a need for minor revisions of the boundaries indicated on the map referred to in section 426n of this title, the Secretary may, following timely notice in writing to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate of his intention to do so and providing an opportunity for public comment, make such minor revisions by publication of a revised boundary map or other description in the Federal Register.


(Pub. L. 100–205, § 3, as added Pub. L. 102–225, § 1(4), Dec. 11, 1991, 105 Stat. 1683; amended Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(15), Nov. 2, 1994, 108 Stat. 4584.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 3 of Pub. L. 100–205 was renumbered section 4 and is classified to section 426p of this title.

Amendments1994—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 103–437 substituted “Natural Resources” for “Interior and Insular Affairs” after “Committee on”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of plan for Redoubt Brannan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation of plan for Redoubt Brannan The Secretary shall, on or before February 1, 1992, prepare a plan for the preservation and interpretation of Redoubt Brannan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Update of General Management Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Update of General Management Plan The Secretary shall, on or before March 31, 1993, update the General Management Plan for the Stones River National Battlefield.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance The Secretary is authorized to provide technical assistance to the city and to Rutherford County in the development of zoning ordinances and other land use controls that would help preserve historically significant areas adjacent to the battlefield.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minor boundary revisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Minor boundary revisions If the planning activities conducted under subsections (a) and (b) of this section show a need for minor revisions of the boundaries indicated on the map referred to in section 426n of this title, the Secretary may, following timely notice in writing to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate of his intention to do so and providing an opportunity for public comment, make such minor revisions by publication of a revised boundary map or other description in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>