<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/428p–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/428p–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/428p–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_428p_1"><akn:num>428p–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition related to Fort Donelson National Battlefield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 428p–1. Land acquisition related to Fort Donelson National Battlefield(a) Acquisition authoritySubject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary of the Interior may acquire land, interests in land, and improvements thereon for inclusion in the Fort Donelson National Battlefield. Such land, interests in land, and improvements may be acquired by the Secretary only by purchase from willing sellers with appropriated or donated funds, by donation, or by exchange with willing owners.


(b) Land eligible for acquisitionThe Secretary of the Interior may acquire land, interests in land, and improvements thereon under subsection (a)—(1) within the boundaries of the Fort Donelson National Battlefield described in section 428p(b) of this title; and

(2) outside such boundaries if the land has been identified by the American Battlefield Protection Program as part of the battlefield associated with Fort Donelson or if the Secretary otherwise determines that acquisition under subsection (a) will protect critical resources associated with the Battle of Fort Donelson in 1862 and the Union campaign that resulted in the capture of Fort Donelson.


(c) Boundary revisionUpon acquisition of land or interests in land described in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of the Interior shall revise the boundaries of the Fort Donelson National Battlefield to include the acquired property.


(d) Limitation on total acreage of parkThe total area encompassed by the Fort Donelson National Battlefield may not exceed 2,000 acres.


(Pub. L. 108–367, § 3, Oct. 25, 2004, 118 Stat. 1743.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_428p_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acquisition authority Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary of the Interior may acquire land, interests in land, and improvements thereon for inclusion in the Fort Donelson National Battlefield. Such land, interests in land, and improvements may be acquired by the Secretary only by purchase from willing sellers with appropriated or donated funds, by donation, or by exchange with willing owners.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_428p_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land eligible for acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land eligible for acquisition The Secretary of the Interior may acquire land, interests in land, and improvements thereon under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_428p_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Boundary revision Upon acquisition of land or interests in land described in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of the Interior shall revise the boundaries of the Fort Donelson National Battlefield to include the acquired property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_428p_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on total acreage of park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on total acreage of park The total area encompassed by the Fort Donelson National Battlefield may not exceed 2,000 acres.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>