<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/430kk" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/430kk/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/430kk/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_430kk"><akn:num>430kk</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield: establishment and acquisition of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 430kk. Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield: establishment and acquisition of lands(a) Establishment, initial boundariesThe Secretary of the Interior shall acquire, by gift, purchase, condemnation, or otherwise, the lands (together with any improvements thereon) comprising the Wilson’s Creek Battlefield site near Springfield, Missouri, and any other lands adjacent to such site which in his opinion are necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes of sections 430kk to 430mm of this title.


(b) Expansion of boundaries(1) Additional land(A) In generalThe boundaries of the Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield are revised to include lands and interests therein consisting of six parcels totaling 615 acres and identified as parcels “1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6” on the map entitled “Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield Proposed Boundary”, numbered 410/80,037 and dated January 27, 2004.


(B) Newtonia Battlefield additionThe boundary of the Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield is revised to include the approximately 25 acres of land identified as “Proposed Addition” on the map entitled “Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield Proposed Boundary Modification”, numbered 410/177,379, and dated July 2022.


(C) Availability of mapsThe maps described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(D) ErrorsThe Secretary of the Interior may correct any clerical or typographical error in a map described in subparagraph (A) or (B).



(2) Method of acquisitionThe Secretary of the Interior may acquire the land described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) by donation, by purchase from willing sellers with donated or appropriated funds, or by exchange. The Secretary may acquire by the same methods personal property associated with, and appropriate for, interpretation of Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield.



(c) Access to private propertyNothing in sections 430kk to 430mm of this title shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment, initial boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment, initial boundaries The Secretary of the Interior shall acquire, by gift, purchase, condemnation, or otherwise, the lands (together with any improvements thereon) comprising the Wilson’s Creek Battlefield site near Springfield, Missouri, and any other lands adjacent to such site which in his opinion are necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes of sections 430kk to 430mm of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expansion of boundaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to private property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Access to private property Nothing in sections 430kk to 430mm of this title shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability The revision of the boundaries of the Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield by subsection (b) shall not be considered to create any liability for, or to have any effect on any liability under any other law of, any owner of private property with respect to any person injured on that private property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of authority to control land use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recognition of authority to control land use Nothing in sections 430kk to 430mm of this title shall be construed to modify the authority of Federal, State, or local governments to regulate land use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of private property owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Participation of private property owners Nothing in sections 430kk to 430mm of this title shall be construed to require the owner of any private property located within the boundaries of the Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield to participate in, or be associated with, the National Battlefield.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430kk_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect of expansion The boundaries of the Wilson’s Creek National Battlefield, as revised by subsection (b), represent the area within which Federal funds appropriated for the purpose of sections 430kk to 430mm of this title may be expended. The boundary revision shall not be construed to provide any nonexisting regulatory authority on land use within the National Battlefield or its viewshed by the Secretary or the National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>