<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4310"><akn:num>4310</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Cave Research Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4310. Establishment of Cave Research Program(a) EstablishmentIn order to provide for needed research relating to cave resources on certain lands in the United States, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service shall establish and administer a Cave Research Program (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Program”). The Program shall include the orderly and scholarly collection, analysis, and dissemination of research material related to caves in lands managed by the National Park Service including, but not limited to, Carlsbad Caverns National Park and the Capitan Reef area.


(b) FunctionsThe Program shall produce educational and interpretive information and materials vital to public understanding of cave geology, assist students and researchers, and provide for a comprehensive evaluation of cave resources and measures needed for their protection.


(c) EmphasisThe program 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. shall be directed primarily toward lands managed by the National Park Service, but the Secretary of the Interior may enter into cooperative agreements with other agencies or entities as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.


(Pub. L. 101–578, title II, § 202, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2859.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis section, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), was in the original “this title” meaning title II of Pub. L. 101–578, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2859, which enacted this section and provisions set out as notes below. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Federal Cave Resources Protection Act of 1988 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
National Cave and Karst Research InstitutePub. L. 105–325, Oct. 30, 1998, 112 Stat. 3038, as amended by Pub. L. 111–11, title VII, § 7305, Mar. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 1219, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHO</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to provide for needed research relating to cave resources on certain lands in the United States, the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service shall establish and administer a Cave Research Program (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Program”). The Program shall include the orderly and scholarly collection, analysis, and dissemination of research material related to caves in lands managed by the National Park Service including, but not limited to, Carlsbad Caverns National Park and the Capitan Reef area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Program shall produce educational and interpretive information and materials vital to public understanding of cave geology, assist students and researchers, and provide for a comprehensive evaluation of cave resources and measures needed for their protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emphasis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emphasis The program 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. shall be directed primarily toward lands managed by the National Park Service, but the Secretary of the Interior may enter into cooperative agreements with other agencies or entities as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>