<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4407"><akn:num>4407</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of amounts available to carry out this chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4407. Allocation of amounts available to carry out this chapter(a) AllocationsOf the sums available to the Secretary for any fiscal year under this chapter and section 669b(b) of this title—(1) such percentage of that sum (but at least 30 percent and not more than 60 percent) as is considered appropriate by the Secretary, which can be matched with non-Federal moneys in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, less such amount (but not more than 4 percent of such percentage) considered necessary by the Secretary to defray the costs of administering this chapter during such fiscal year, shall be allocated by the Secretary to carry out approved wetlands conservation projects in Canada and Mexico in accordance with section 4405(b) of this title; and

(2) the remainder of such sum after paragraph (1) is applied (but at least 40 percent and not more than 70 percent), which can be matched with non-Federal moneys in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b) of this section, shall be allocated by the Secretary to carry out approved wetlands conservation projects in the United States in accordance with section 4405(a) of this title.


(b) Cost sharing(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), as a condition of providing assistance under this chapter for any approved wetlands conservation project, the Secretary shall require that the portion of the costs of the project paid with amounts provided by non-Federal United States sources is equal to at least the amount allocated under subsection (a) that is used for the project.

(2) Federal moneys allocated under subsection (a) may be used to pay 100 percent of the costs of such projects located on Federal lands and waters, including the acquisition of inholdings within such lands and waters.

(3) The non-Federal share of the United States contribution to the costs of such projects may not be derived from Federal grant programs. In the case of a project carried out in Canada or Mexico, the non-Fe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocations Of the sums available to the Secretary for any fiscal year under this chapter and section 669b(b) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Partial payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>