<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_441g"><akn:num>441g</akn:num><akn:heading>Orders to effectuate revision of boundaries; publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 441g. Orders to effectuate revision of boundaries; publication
The revision of boundaries of the national park, as authorized in section 441f of this title, shall be accomplished by the issuance, by the Secretary of the Interior, of an appropriate order, or orders, such order or orders to be effective upon publication in the Federal Register: Provided, That federally owned land under the administrative jurisdiction of any other department or agency of the Federal Government shall be included within the park only with the approval of the head of such department or agency.
(May 7, 1952, ch. 244, § 2, 66 Stat. 65; Pub. L. 95–625, title VI, § 611, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3521.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 441f of this title, referred to in text, was in the original “sections 1 and 5 of this Act”. Section 1 of the Act is classified to section 441f of this title. Section 5 is probably a reference to section 5 of the original bill, which would have authorized the inclusion of up to 4,000 acres of the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation within the Badlands National Monument. Such section 5 was stricken from the bill by Senate amendment, and as enacted the Act contained only four sections.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Word “park” substituted in text for “monument” pursuant to Pub. L. 95–625, § 611, which is classified to section 441e–1 of this title and which redesignated Badlands National Monument as Badlands National Park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>