<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/441i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_441i"><akn:num>441i</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 441i. Exchanges of land
In order that exchanges of land may be effectuated for the purposes of sections 441f to 441i of this title, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion and in accordance with the provisions of sections 3111 and 3112 of title 40, to accept, on behalf of the United States, title to any land or interests in land within the exterior boundaries of the Badlands National Park as revised pursuant to sections 441f to 441i of this title, and, in exchange therefor, with the approval and concurrence of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior may patent lands of approximately equal value which were formerly set apart and reserved from the public domain within the Badlands Fall River soil conservation project, SD–LU–1. In effectuating such exchanges, in lieu of conveyances by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture may convey lands of approximately equal value within said project which have been acquired heretofore by the United States. All such exchanges shall, in all other respects, be considered as exchanges under the provisions of section 32c,11  So in original. Probably should be “32(c),”. title III, of the Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act [7 U.S.C. 1011(c)] and shall otherwise be in accordance with provisions of said Act [7 U.S.C. 1000 et seq.]; except that, upon acceptance of title to any lands so acquired by the United States under this section, such lands and any other lands acquired otherwise by the United States within the park boundaries shall be a part of that area. In consummating land exchanges hereunder upon an equitable basis, patents and instruments of conveyance may be issued, and property may be accepted, by the United States, subject to such reservations as may be necessary or in the public interest.
(May 7, 1952, ch. 244, § 4, 66 Stat. 66; Pub. L. 95–625, title VI, § 611, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3521.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Bankhead-Jones Farm Tenant Act, ref</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>