<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4503b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4503b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4503b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4503b"><akn:num>4503b</akn:num><akn:heading>Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4503b. Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) ForestThe term “Forest” means the Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest.


(2) GovernorThe term “Governor” means the Governor of Hawaii.


(3) LandsThe term “lands” means lands, waters, and interests in lands and waters.


(4) StateThe term “State” means the State of Hawaii.



(b) Establishment and managementAt the request of the Governor, the Secretary shall establish and administer within the State a Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest. The Forest shall be managed as—(1) a model of quality tropical forest management where harvesting on a sustainable yield basis can be demonstrated in balance with natural resource conservation;

(2) a site for research on tropical forestry, conservation biology, and natural resource management; and

(3) a center for demonstration, education, training, and outreach on tropical forestry, conservation biology, and natural resources research and management.


(c) Delineation of location of Forest(1) Identification of landsThe Governor and the Secretary shall identify one or more suitable sites for the Forest in lands within the State. The identification of each site shall be based on scientific, ecological, administrative, and such other factors as the Governor and Secretary consider to be necessary or desirable to achieve the purposes of this section. Each site identified pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be of sufficient size and located so that the site can be effectively managed for Forest purposes.


(2) Exterior boundariesThe exterior boundaries of the Forest, including the boundaries of all sites identified for Forest purposes, shall be delineated on an official map. The map shall be available for public inspection in the office of the Administrator of the Division of Forestry and Wildlife of the Department of Land and Natural Resources of the State. The Governor and the Secretary may from time to time, by mutual agreement, amend the off</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and management At the request of the Governor, the Secretary shall establish and administer within the State a Hawaii Experimental Tropical Forest. The Forest shall be managed as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delineation of location of Forest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Delineation of location of Forest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorities of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>