<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450bb"><akn:num>450bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Harpers Ferry National Historical Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450bb. Harpers Ferry National Historical Park(a) In generalTo carry out the purposes of sections 450bb to 450bb–2 of this title, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in sections 450bb to 450bb–2 of this title as the “Secretary”) is authorized to acquire, by purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, by donation, or by exchange, land or an interest in land within the boundaries as generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Harpers Ferry National Historical Park”, numbered 385–80,021A, and dated April 1979.


(b) Bradley and Ruth Nash AdditionThe Secretary is authorized to acquire, by donation only, approximately 27 acres of land or interests in land that are outside the boundary of the Harpers Ferry National Historical Park and generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Bradley and Ruth Nash Addition—Harpers Ferry National Historical Park”, numbered 385–80056, and dated April 1, 1989.


(c) Boundary expansion(1) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to acquire, by purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, by donation, or by exchange, land or an interest in land within the area depicted as “Private Lands” on the map entitled “Harpers Ferry National Historical Park Proposed Boundary Expansion”, numbered 385/80,126, and dated July 14, 2003.


(2) AdministrationThe Secretary shall—(A) transfer to the National Park Service for inclusion in the Harpers Ferry National Historical Park (referred to in sections 450bb to 450bb–2 of this title as the “Park”) the land depicted on the map referred to in paragraph (1) as “U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service Lands” and revise the boundary of the Park accordingly; and

(B) revise the boundary of the Park to include the land depicted on the map referred to in paragraph (1) as “Appalachian NST” and exclude that land from the boundary of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail.



(d) Maximum number of acresThe number of acres of the Park shall not exceed 3,745.


(e) Ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To carry out the purposes of sections 450bb to 450bb–2 of this title, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in sections 450bb to 450bb–2 of this title as the “Secretary”) is authorized to acquire, by purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, by donation, or by exchange, land or an interest in land within the boundaries as generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Harpers Ferry National Historical Park”, numbered 385–80,021A, and dated April 1979.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bradley and Ruth Nash Addition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Bradley and Ruth Nash Addition The Secretary is authorized to acquire, by donation only, approximately 27 acres of land or interests in land that are outside the boundary of the Harpers Ferry National Historical Park and generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Bradley and Ruth Nash Addition—Harpers Ferry National Historical Park”, numbered 385–80056, and dated April 1, 1989.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Boundary expansion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum number of acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maximum number of acres The number of acres of the Park shall not exceed 3,745.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maps The maps referred to in this section shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquired land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Acquired land Land or an interest in land acquired under this section shall become a part of the Park, subject to the laws (including regulations) applicable to the Park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450bb_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>