<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450hh" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450hh/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450hh/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450hh"><akn:num>450hh</akn:num><akn:heading>Saint Croix Island International Historic Site; establishment; acceptance of land; size</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450hh. Saint Croix Island International Historic Site; establishment; acceptance of land; size
For the purpose of establishing a Federal area of national historical importance for the benefit of the people of the United States, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to accept, for national monument purposes, on behalf of the United States, the donation of all non-Federal lands and interests in land situated on Saint Croix (Dochet) Island, located in the Saint Croix River, in the State of Maine. The Secretary is authorized to acquire, in such manner as he may consider to be in the public interest, not to exceed fifty acres of land or interests therein situated on the mainland, such property to be used for general administrative purposes and for a landing dock in order to provide a suitable approach and ready access to the island.
(June 8, 1949, ch. 180, § 1, 63 Stat. 158.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Authorization of AppropriationsAct June 8, 1949, ch. 180, § 4, 63 Stat. 158, provided that: “There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act [sections 450hh to 450hh–2 of this title].”


Saint Croix Island Heritage CenterPub. L. 106–529, Nov. 22, 2000, 114 Stat. 2524, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.“This Act may be cited as the ‘Saint Croix Island Heritage Act’.


“SEC. 2. FINDINGS AND PURPOSES.“(a) Findings.—Congress finds that—“(1) Saint Croix Island is located in the Saint Croix River, a river that is the boundary between the State of Maine and Canada;

“(2) the Island is the only international historic site in the National Park System;

“(3) in 1604, French nobleman Pierre Dugua Sieur de Mons, accompanied by a courageous group of adventurers that included Samuel Champlain, landed on the Island and began the construction of a settlement;

“(4) the French settlement on the Island in 1604 and 1605 was the initial site of the first permanent settlement in the New World, pred</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>