<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450jj–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450jj–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450jj–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450jj_4"><akn:num>450jj–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450jj–4. Transfer of land
Where appropriate in the discretion of the Secretary of the Interior, he may transfer by lease or otherwise, to any appropriate person or governmental entity, land owned by the United States (or any interest therein) which has been acquired by the Secretary under section 450jj–3 of this title. Any such transfer shall be consistent with the management plan for the area and with the requirements of sections 100903 and 102901 of title 54 and shall be subject to such conditions and restrictions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of sections 450jj to 450jj–9 of this title, including terms and conditions which provide for—(1) the continuation of existing uses of the land which are compatible with the Memorial,

(2) the protection of the important historical resources of the leased area, and

(3) the retention by the Secretary of such access and development rights as the Secretary deems necessary to provide for appropriate visitor use and resource management.


In transferring any lands or interest in lands under this section, the Secretary shall take into account the views of the Commission established under section 450jj–6 of this title.
(May 17, 1954, ch. 204, § 5, as added Pub. L. 98–398, title II, § 201(a), Aug. 24, 1984, 98 Stat. 1468.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 450jj–6 of this title, referred to in text, was in the original “section 8”, meaning section 8 of act May 17, 1954, ch. 204, and was translated as reading “section 7” of such act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, because section 7 related to the establishment of the Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Commission.

Codification
In introductory provisions, “sections 100903 and 102901 of title 54” substituted for “section 5 of the Act of July 15, 1968 (82 Stat. 356; 16 U.S.C. 460l–22)” on authority of Pub. L. 113–287, § 6(e), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3272, which Act enacted Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs.

Pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450jj_4_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the continuation of existing uses of the land which are compatible with the Memorial,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450jj_4_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the protection of the important historical resources of the leased area, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450jj_4_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) the retention by the Secretary of such access and development rights as the Secretary deems necessary to provide for appropriate visitor use and resource management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>