<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450pp–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450pp–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450pp–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450pp_2"><akn:num>450pp–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with city of Providence and local historical and preservation societies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450pp–2. Cooperation with city of Providence and local historical and preservation societies(a) Maintenance, operation, and developmentThe Secretary is authorized to cooperate with the city of Providence, local historical and preservation societies, and interested persons in the maintenance and operation of the Roger Williams National Memorial, and he may seek the assistance of and consult with such city, societies, and persons from time to time with respect to matters concerning the development and operation of the memorial.


(b) Acceptance of giftsThe Secretary may accept on behalf of the people of the United States gifts of historic objects and records pertaining to Roger Williams for appropriate display or other use in keeping with the commemoration of the founding of the principles of freedom in the United States and of the historical events that took place in the city of Providence in connection therewith.


(Pub. L. 89–293, § 3, Oct. 22, 1965, 79 Stat. 1070.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450pp_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance, operation, and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maintenance, operation, and development The Secretary is authorized to cooperate with the city of Providence, local historical and preservation societies, and interested persons in the maintenance and operation of the Roger Williams National Memorial, and he may seek the assistance of and consult with such city, societies, and persons from time to time with respect to matters concerning the development and operation of the memorial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_450pp_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acceptance of gifts The Secretary may accept on behalf of the people of the United States gifts of historic objects and records pertaining to Roger Williams for appropriate display or other use in keeping with the commemoration of the founding of the principles of freedom in the United States and of the historical events that took place in the city of Providence in connection therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>