<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450p"><akn:num>450p</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property; donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450p. Acquisition of property; donations
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire on behalf of the United States out of any funds allotted and made available for this project by proper authority or out of any donated funds, by purchase at prices deemed by him reasonable, or by condemnation under the provisions of section 3113 of title 40, or to accept by donation, such land, interest in land, and/or buildings, structures, and other property within the boundaries of said national historic site as determined and fixed hereunder, and he is further authorized to accept donations of funds for the purchase and/or maintenance thereof.
(Aug. 29, 1935, ch. 801, § 2, 49 Stat. 958; Pub. L. 88–197, § 1, Dec. 11, 1963, 77 Stat. 349.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextHereunder, referred to in text, means act Aug. 29, 1935, which is classified to sections 450o to 450q of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
“Section 3113 of title 40” substituted in text for “the Act of August 1, 1888 (25 Stat. 357)” on authority of Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c), Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1303, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Historic site” substituted in text for “monument” on authority of Pub. L. 88–197, which redesignated Andrew Johnson National Monument as Andrew Johnson National Historic Site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>