<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/450y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_450y"><akn:num>450y</akn:num><akn:heading>Coronado National Memorial; establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 450y. Coronado National Memorial; establishment
For the purpose of permanently commemorating the explorations of Francisco Vásquez de Coronado, the President of the United States is authorized to declare, by proclamation, any lands within the following-described area, subject to all valid existing rights, to be established as the “Coronado National Memorial”:
Gila and Salt River meridian: Township 24 south, range 20 east, section 10, south half southwest quarter, south half southeast quarter; section 11, south half southwest quarter; section 13, southwest quarter northwest quarter, south half; section 14, northwest quarter, south half, northwest quarter northeast quarter, south half northeast quarter; section 15, all; section 22, all; section 23, all; section 24, all; township 24 south, range 21 east, section 17, south half southwest quarter; section 18, southwest quarter, south half southeast quarter; section 19, all; section 20, lots 3 and 4; aggregating approximately two thousand eight hundred and eighty acres.
(Aug. 18, 1941, ch. 365, § 1, 55 Stat. 630; July 9, 1952, ch. 610, §§ 1, 2, 66 Stat. 510.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1952—Act July 9, 1952, changed “Coronado International Memorial” to “Coronado National Memorial”, and struck out proviso which required action of Mexican Government prior to establishment of the Memorial.

Executive Documents
Establishment of Memorial; BoundariesMonument and boundaries established by Presidential Proc. No. 2995, Nov. 5, 1952, 17 F.R. 10157, 67 Stat. c18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>