<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459a–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459a–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459a–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_459a_9"><akn:num>459a–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of land for improvement with public health facility; reversion; consideration; status of </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 459a–9. Conveyance of land for improvement with public health facility; reversion; consideration; status of property upon transfer of title
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to convey the tract of land and improvements thereon situate in the village of Hatteras, Dare County, North Carolina, and administered as part of the Cape Hatteras National Seashore, formerly bearing General Services Administration excess property control number C–NC–444, comprising one and five-tenths acres, the exact description for which shall be determined by the Secretary, to the Board of Commissioners of Dare County, for purposes of providing thereon a public health facility: Provided, That title to the land and any improvements shall revert to the United States upon a finding and notification to the grantee by the Secretary that the property is used for purposes other than a public health facility. The conveyance herein authorized shall be without monetary consideration.
Upon the transfer of title to the grantee, the property herein conveyed shall cease to be a part of the Cape Hatteras National Seashore.
(Pub. L. 89–146, Aug. 28, 1965, 79 Stat. 583.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>