<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459b–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459b–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459b–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_459b_7"><akn:num>459b–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Cape Cod National Seashore Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 459b–7. Cape Cod National Seashore Advisory Commission(a) Establishment; terminationThere is established a Cape Cod National Seashore Advisory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”). The Commission shall terminate September 26, 2029.


(b) Membership; termThe Commission shall be composed of ten members each appointed for a term of two years by the Secretary as follows:(1) Six members to be appointed from recommendations made by each of the boards of selectmen of the towns referred to in section 459b of this title, one member from the recommendations made by each such board;

(2) One member to be appointed from recommendations of the county commissioners of Barnstable County, Commonwealth of Massachusetts;

(3) Two members to be appointed from recommendations of the Governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts; and

(4) One member to be designated by the Secretary.


(c) Chairman; vacanciesThe Secretary shall designate one member to be Chairman. Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.


(d) Compensation and expensesA member of the Commission shall serve without compensation as such. The Secretary is authorized to pay the expenses reasonably incurred by the Commission in carrying out its responsibilities under sections 459b to 459b–8 of this title upon vouchers signed by the Chairman.


(e) Majority voteThe Commission established by this section shall act and advise by affirmative vote of a majority of the members thereof.


(f) Consultation of Secretary with CommissionThe Secretary or his designee shall, from time to time, consult with the members of the Commission with respect to matters relating to the development of Cape Cod National Seashore and shall consult with the members with respect to carrying out the provisions of sections 459b–3 and 459b–4 of this title.


(g) Exemption from other provisions of law(1) Any member of the Advisory Commission appointed under sections 45</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; termination There is established a Cape Cod National Seashore Advisory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”). The Commission shall terminate September 26, 2029.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; term The Commission shall be composed of ten members each appointed for a term of two years by the Secretary as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairman; vacancies The Secretary shall designate one member to be Chairman. Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses A member of the Commission shall serve without compensation as such. The Secretary is authorized to pay the expenses reasonably incurred by the Commission in carrying out its responsibilities under sections 459b to 459b–8 of this title upon vouchers signed by the Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Majority vote</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Majority vote The Commission established by this section shall act and advise by affirmative vote of a majority of the members thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation of Secretary with Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consultation of Secretary with Commission The Secretary or his designee shall, from time to time, consult with the members of the Commission with respect to matters relating to the development of Cape Cod National Seashore and shall consult with the members with respect to carrying out the provisions of sections 459b–3 and 459b–4 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_459b_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from other provisions of law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exemption from other provisions of law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>