<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_459g"><akn:num>459g</akn:num><akn:heading>Cape Lookout National Seashore; purposes; authorization for establishment; description of area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 459g. Cape Lookout National Seashore; purposes; authorization for establishment; description of area
In order to preserve for public use and enjoyment an area in the State of North Carolina possessing outstanding natural and recreational values, there is hereby authorized to be established the Cape Lookout National Seashore (hereinafter referred to as “seashore”), which shall comprise the lands and adjoining marshlands and waters on the outer banks of Carteret County, North Carolina, between Ocracoke Inlet and Beaufort Inlet, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Boundary Map, Cape Lookout National Seashore”, dated March 1974, and numbered 623–20,009, which is on file in the Office of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior.
(Pub. L. 89–366, § 1, Mar. 10, 1966, 80 Stat. 33; Pub. L. 93–477, title IV, § 406(1), Oct. 26, 1974, 88 Stat. 1448.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1974—Pub. L. 93–477 substituted “ ‘Boundary Map, Cape Lookout National Seashore’, dated March 1974, and numbered 623–20,009” for “ ‘Proposed Boundaries—Proposed Cape Lookout National Seashore’, dated April 1964, and numbered NS–CL–7101–B”, and struck out proviso relating to certain property not to be included in seashore.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>