<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/459s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_459s"><akn:num>459s</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands for certain projects added to certain projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 459s. Lands for certain projects added to certain projects
After June 6, 1942, the lands acquired for the Acadia, French Creek, Shenandoah, and White Sands recreational demonstration projects shall be added to and become a part of Acadia National Park, Hopewell Village National Historic Site, Shenandoah National Park, and White Sands National Monument,11 See Change of Name note below. in the order named above, subject to all laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the respective areas to which such recreational demonstration projects are added.
(June 6, 1942, ch. 380, § 2, 56 Stat. 327.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Proviso directing the Secretary of the Interior to file with the National Archives within six months after June 6, 1942, a map of each recreational demonstration project enumerated in the section has been omitted as executed.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
White Sands National Monument abolished, and White Sands National Park established, by Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2851, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1895, which is classified to section 410dddd of this title and which provides that any reference to the White Sands National Monument shall be considered to be a reference to the White Sands National Park.

Hopewell Village Boundary RevisionAct July 24, 1946, ch. 604, 60 Stat. 655, provided: “That the Secretary of the Interior is hereby authorized to withdraw from the Hopewell Village National Historic Site, Pennsylvania, all or any part of the lands added to the Hopewell Village National Historic Site by the act approved June 6, 1942, entitled ‘An Act to authorize the disposition of recreational demonstration projects, and for other purposes [sections 459r to 459t of this title]’, which in his opinion are not required for historic-site purposes. Any lands so withdrawn shall revert to the status of a recreational demonstration area.”


Silver Creek Recreational Demonstration ProjectAct June 9, 1947, ch. 100, 61 Sta</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>