<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/45a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/45a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/45a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45a_1"><akn:num>45a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Addition of lands authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45a–1. Addition of lands authorized
The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, in his discretion, to accept title to lands and interests in lands near the entrance to the Sequoia National Park, subject to existing easements for public highways and public utilities, within the following described tracts:
Tract A. A portion of tract 37, township 17 south, range 29 east, Mount Diablo meridian, Tulare County, California, comprising approximately two acres.
Tract B. A portion of the east half of the northeast quarter of section 4, township 17 south, range 29 east, Mount Diablo meridian, Tulare County, California, comprising approximately thirty-eight acres.
Tract C. A portion of the south half of tract 37, township 17 south, range 29 east, Mount Diablo meridian, Tulare County, California, comprising approximately sixty one-hundredths acre.
The owners of the lands to be conveyed to the United States, before any exchange is effective, shall furnish to the Secretary of the Interior evidence satisfactory to him of title to such lands. Such property shall become a part of the Sequoia National Park upon the acceptance of title thereto by the Secretary, and shall thereafter be subject to all laws and regulations applicable to the park.
(Dec. 21, 1943, ch. 372, § 1, 57 Stat. 606.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Electric Power Development PermitsPub. L. 99–338, June 19, 1986, 100 Stat. 641, as amended by Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(4), Nov. 2, 1994, 108 Stat. 4583; Pub. L. 108–447, div. E, title I, § 139(c), Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 3069, provided: 
“That the Secretary of the Interior is hereby authorized to issue a permit for ten years, and may issue not more than 3 renewals of equivalent duration, for portions of an existing hydroelectric project, known as the Kaweah Project of Southern California Edison Company, to continue to occupy and use lands of the United States within Sequoia National Park as necessary for continued operation and maintenance.
“Sec. 2. The Secr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>