<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460aaa–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460aaa–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460aaa–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460aaa_2"><akn:num>460aaa–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460aaa–2. Administration(a) AdministrationSubject to valid existing rights, the Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer the national recreation area in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the National Forest System in furtherance of the purposes for which the national recreation area was established.


(b) Special management requirementsThe national recreation area also shall be administered according to the following special management requirements:(1) Subject to such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary, including the protection of threatened and endangered species and the protection of other natural, cultural, and scenic values, owners of privately owned land and homes within the national recreation area shall be afforded access across National Forest System lands.

(2) Consistent with section 460aaa–6 of this title, and the purposes of this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide for and maintain traditional public access, including vehicular roads for general recreational activities such as camping, hiking, hunting, fishing, and trapping.

(3) The Secretary shall permit the use of snowmobiles on Federal lands in the national recreation area in accordance with the rules and regulations of the National Forest System and consistent with the management plan developed pursuant to section 460aaa–6 of this title. Such use shall be regulated to protect the resources of the national recreation area in a way that minimizes the degradation of these resources.

(4) Timber management shall be utilized only as a tool to enhance public recreation, scenic quality, game and nongame wildlife species, and the protection and enhancement of threatened, endangered, or sensitive species. Trees damaged or downed due to fire, insects, disease, or blowdown may be utilized, salvaged, or removed from the recreation area as authorized by the Secretary to further the purposes o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460aaa_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer the national recreation area in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the National Forest System in furtherance of the purposes for which the national recreation area was established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460aaa_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special management requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special management requirements The national recreation area also shall be administered according to the following special management requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>