<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460a–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460a–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460a–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460a_7"><akn:num>460a–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of recreational development on parkway and national forest lands; administration of for</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460a–7. Coordination of recreational development on parkway and national forest lands; administration of forest land recreational facilities and access road development by Secretary of Agriculture; forest road and Appalachian Trail relocation and reconstruction and alternative forest road provision by Secretary of the Interior
To effectuate the recommendations in the report to the Congress on the North Carolina-Georgia extension of the Blue Ridge Parkway, made pursuant to the Act of August 10, 1961 (75 Stat. 337)—(1) The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, insofar as practicable, coordinate and correlate recreational development on lands within the parkway and adjacent or related national forests land: Provided, That within national forest boundaries recreational developments and facilities on Federal lands other than those actually within the national parkway shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture;

(2) Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior shall relocate and reconstruct any national forest roads that may be disturbed by the parkway extension, or provide alternative roads that are necessary to the protection, administration, or utilization of the national forests, and shall allow access to areas to be developed by the Secretary of Agriculture on adjacent national forest lands unless to do so will materially impair the primary purposes of the parkway;

(3) The Secretary of the Interior may relocate and reconstruct portions of the Appalachian Trail, including trail shelters, that may be disturbed by the parkway extension and such relocation and reconstruction may be performed (A) on non-Federal lands when the Appalachian Trail Conference obtains the consent of the owner to the use of the lands for the purpose and agrees to assume maintenance thereof, and (B) upon national forest lands with the approval of the Secretary of Agriculture.

(Pub. L. 90–555, § 2, Oct. 9, 1968, 82 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460a_7_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, insofar as practicable, coordinate and correlate recreational development on lands within the parkway and adjacent or related national forests land: Provided, That within national forest boundaries recreational developments and facilities on Federal lands other than those actually within the national parkway shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460a_7_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Upon the request of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior shall relocate and reconstruct any national forest roads that may be disturbed by the parkway extension, or provide alternative roads that are necessary to the protection, administration, or utilization of the national forests, and shall allow access to areas to be developed by the Secretary of Agriculture on adjacent national forest lands unless to do so will materially impair the primary purposes of the parkway;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460a_7_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The Secretary of the Interior may relocate and reconstruct portions of the Appalachian Trail, including trail shelters, that may be disturbed by the parkway extension and such relocation and reconstruction may be performed (A) on non-Federal lands when the Appalachian Trail Conference obtains the consent of the owner to the use of the lands for the purpose and agrees to assume maintenance thereof, and (B) upon national forest lands with the approval of the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>