<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bbb_6"><akn:num>460bbb–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Minerals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bbb–6. Minerals(a) WithdrawalSubject to valid existing rights, Federal lands within the exterior boundary of the recreation area are hereby withdrawn from all forms of location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws and from disposition under the mineral leasing laws, including all laws pertaining to geothermal leasing.


(b) PatentsPatents may not be issued under the mining laws of the United States after November 16, 1990, for locations and claims made before November 16, 1990, on Federal lands located within the exterior boundaries of the recreation area.


(c) AdministrationSubject to valid existing rights except for extraction of common variety minerals such as stone, sand, and gravel for use in construction and maintenance of roads and other facilities within the recreation area and the excluded areas, all other mineral development on federally owned lands within the recreation area is prohibited.


(d) RegulationsThe Secretary is authorized and directed to issue supplementary regulations to promote and protect the purposes for which the recreation area is designated.


(Pub. L. 101–612, § 8, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 3214.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, Federal lands within the exterior boundary of the recreation area are hereby withdrawn from all forms of location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws and from disposition under the mineral leasing laws, including all laws pertaining to geothermal leasing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Patents Patents may not be issued under the mining laws of the United States after November 16, 1990, for locations and claims made before November 16, 1990, on Federal lands located within the exterior boundaries of the recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration Subject to valid existing rights except for extraction of common variety minerals such as stone, sand, and gravel for use in construction and maintenance of roads and other facilities within the recreation area and the excluded areas, all other mineral development on federally owned lands within the recreation area is prohibited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Secretary is authorized and directed to issue supplementary regulations to promote and protect the purposes for which the recreation area is designated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>