<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbb–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bbb_8"><akn:num>460bbb–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Streamside protection zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bbb–8. Streamside protection zones(a) Three hundred foot zonesFor each of the rivers and river segments specified in this subsection, there is hereby established a streamside protection zone in which timber harvesting shall be prohibited except as permitted by section 460bbb–3(a)(7) of this title. Such zone shall extend 300 feet from each bank of the rivers and river segments, or 100 feet from the inner gorge of said rivers and river segments, or within the limit of high and extreme landslide hazards on said rivers and river segments, whichever is greater. The provisions of this subsection shall apply to the following rivers and river segments:(1) Rowdy Creek (from California-Oregon border to NRA boundary).

(2) Shelly Creek (from its headwaters to Patrick Creek).

(3) East Fork Patrick Creek (from its headwaters to Patrick Creek).

(4) West Fork Patrick Creek (from its headwaters to Patrick Creek).

(5) Little Jones Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(6) Patrick Creek (from the confluence of the East and West forks of Patrick Creek to the Middle Fork of the Smith River).

(7) Monkey Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the Middle Fork of the Smith River).

(8) Hardscrabble Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the Middle Fork of the Smith River).

(9) Quartz Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(10) Jones Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(11) Upper Hurdygurdy Creek (from its headwaters to Dry Lake).

(12) Gordon Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(13) Coon Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(14) Craigs Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River).

(15) Goose Creek (from its headwaters to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Three hundred foot zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Three hundred foot zones For each of the rivers and river segments specified in this subsection, there is hereby established a streamside protection zone in which timber harvesting shall be prohibited except as permitted by section 460bbb–3(a)(7) of this title. Such zone shall extend 300 feet from each bank of the rivers and river segments, or 100 feet from the inner gorge of said rivers and river segments, or within the limit of high and extreme landslide hazards on said rivers and river segments, whichever is greater. The provisions of this subsection shall apply to the following rivers and river segments:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>One-quarter mile zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) One-quarter mile zones For each of the rivers and river segments specified in this subsection there is established a streamside protection zone in which timber harvesting shall be prohibited except as permitted in section 460bbb–3(a)(7) of this title. Such zone shall extend on the average of one-quarter mile on either side of said rivers and river segments, or 100 feet from the inner gorge of said rivers and river segments, or within the limit of high and extreme landslide hazards on said rivers and river segments, whichever is greater. The provisions of this subsection shall apply to the following rivers and river segments:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lower Hurdygurdy Creek</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lower Hurdygurdy Creek For the Lower Hurdygurdy Creek (from Dry Lake to its confluence with the South Fork of the Smith River) there is established a streamside protection zone in which timber harvesting shall be prohibited except as permitted by section 460bbb–3(a)(7) of this title. Such zone shall extend one-eighth mile on either side of said Lower Hurdygurdy Creek.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbb_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other restrictions on timber harvesting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other restrictions on timber harvesting The provisions of this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any restrictions on timber harvesting or other activities applicable to the streamside protection zones established by this section under any other applicable provision of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>