<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbbb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbbb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bbbb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bbbb"><akn:num>460bbbb</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashley Karst National Recreation and Geologic Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bbbb. Ashley Karst National Recreation and Geologic Area(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Management PlanThe term “Management Plan” means the management plan for the Recreation Area prepared under subsection (e)(2)(A).


(2) MapThe term “Map” means the map entitled “Northern Utah Lands Management Act-Overview” and dated February 4, 2019.


(3) Recreation AreaThe term “Recreation Area” means the Ashley Karst National Recreation and Geologic Area established by subsection (b)(1).


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(5) StateThe term “State” means the State of Utah.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalSubject to valid existing rights, there is established the Ashley Karst National Recreation and Geologic Area in the State.


(2) Area includedThe Recreation Area shall consist of approximately 173,475 acres of land in the Ashley National Forest, as generally depicted on the Map.



(c) PurposesThe purposes of the Recreation Area are to conserve and protect the watershed, geological, recreational, wildlife, scenic, natural, cultural, and historic resources of the Recreation Area.


(d) Map and legal description(1) In generalAs soon as practicable after March 12, 2019, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and legal description of the Recreation Area.


(2) EffectThe map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this section, except that the Secretary may correct minor errors in the map or legal description.


(3) AvailabilityA copy of the map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.



(e) Administration(1) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Recreation Area in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purposes The purposes of the Recreation Area are to conserve and protect the watershed, geological, recreational, wildlife, scenic, natural, cultural, and historic resources of the Recreation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Map and legal description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Map and legal description</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Uses The Secretary shall only allow such uses of the Recreation Area that would—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motorized vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Motorized vehicles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Water infrastructure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Grazing The grazing of livestock in the Recreation Area, where established before March 12, 2019, shall be allowed to continue, subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary considers to be necessary in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bbbb_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fish and wildlife Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction of the State with respect to the management of fish and wildlife on Federal land in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>