<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bb_2"><akn:num>460bb–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bb–2. Acquisition policy(a) Authority of Secretary; exchange of property; disposal of certain lands; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; facilities and improvements under permit from Secretary of the ArmyWithin the boundaries of the recreation area, the Secretary may acquire lands, improvements, waters, or interests therein, by donation, purchase, exchange or transfer. Any lands, or interests therein, owned by the State of California or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation. When any tract of land is only partly within such boundaries, the Secretary may acquire all or any portion of the land outside of such boundaries in order to minimize the payment of severance costs. Land so acquired outside of the boundaries may be exchanged by the Secretary for non-Federal lands within the boundaries. Any portion of land acquired outside the boundaries and not utilized for exchange shall be reported to the General Services Administration for disposal under chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41: Provided, That no disposal shall be for less than fair market value. Except as hereinafter provided, Federal property within the boundaries of the recreation area is hereby transferred without consideration to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for the purposes of this subchapter, subject to the continuation of such existing uses as may be agreed upon between the Secretary and the head of the agency formerly having jurisdiction over the property. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may develop and administer for the purposes of this subchapter structures or other improvements and facilities on lands for which he receives a permit of use and occupancy from the Secretary of the Army.


(b) Transfer of certain properties to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; military properties</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; exchange of property; disposal of certain lands; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; facilities and improvements under permit from Secretary of the Army</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; exchange of property; disposal of certain lands; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; facilities and improvements under permit from Secretary of the Army Within the boundaries of the recreation area, the Secretary may acquire lands, improvements, waters, or interests therein, by donation, purchase, exchange or transfer. Any lands, or interests therein, owned by the State of California or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation. When any tract of land is only partly within such boundaries, the Secretary may acquire all or any portion of the land outside of such boundaries in order to minimize the payment of severance costs. Land so acquired outside of the boundaries may be exchanged by the Secretary for non-Federal lands within the boundaries. Any portion of land acquired outside the boundaries and not utilized for exchange shall be reported to the General Services Administration for disposal un</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain properties to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; military properties, reservation of use and occupancy by Secretary of the Army; radio receiver station, retention of jurisdiction when not superfluous</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of certain properties to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; military properties, reservation of use and occupancy by Secretary of the Army; radio receiver station, retention of jurisdiction when not superfluous Fort Cronkhite, Fort Barry, and the westerly one-half of Fort Baker, in Marin County, California, as depicted on the map entitled “Golden Gate Military Properties” numbered NRAGG–20,002 and dated January 1972, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, are hereby transferred to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for purposes of this subchapter, subject to continued use and occupancy by the Secretary of the Army of those lands needed for existing air defense missions, reserve activities and family housing, until he determines that such requirements no longer exist. The Coast Guard Radio Receiver Station, shall remain under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military property; public service facilities: construction, maintenance, and determinations of identity and location by Secretary of the Army</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Military property; public service facilities: construction, maintenance, and determinations of identity and location by Secretary of the Army The easterly one-half of Fort Baker in Marin County, California, shall remain under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Army. When this property is determined by the Department of Defense to be excess to its needs, it shall be transferred to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for purposes of this subchapter. The Secretary of the Army shall grant to the Secretary reasonable public access through such property to Horseshoe Bay, together with the right to construct and maintain such public service facilities as are necessary for the purposes of this subchapter. The precise facilities and location thereof shall be determined between the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidio of San Francisco; use and occupation of certain acreage by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Presidio of San Francisco; use and occupation of certain acreage by Secretary Upon enactment, the Secretary of the Army shall grant to the Secretary the irrevocable use and occupancy of one hundred acres of the Baker Beach area of the Presidio of San Francisco, as depicted on the map referred to in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use and occupancy of airfield acreage by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use and occupancy of airfield acreage by Secretary The Secretary of the Army shall grant to the Secretary within a reasonable time, the irrevocable use and occupancy of forty-five acres of the Crissy Army Airfield of the Presidio, as depicted on the map referred to in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of remainder to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; use and occupancy by Coast Guard under permit from Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of remainder to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; use and occupancy by Coast Guard under permit from Secretary When all or any substantial portion of the remainder of the Presidio is determined by the Department of Defense to be excess to its needs, such lands shall be transferred to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for purposes of this subchapter. The Secretary shall grant a permit for continued use and occupancy for that portion of said Fort Point Coast Guard Station necessary for activities of the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain Coast Guard properties to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; navigational aids: maintenance and operation by Coast Guard and plans for access to new installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer of certain Coast Guard properties to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; navigational aids: maintenance and operation by Coast Guard and plans for access to new installations Point Bonita, Point Diablo, Point Montara, and Lime Point shall remain under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating. When this property is determined to be excess to the needs of the Coast Guard, it shall be transferred to the jurisdiction of the Secretary for purposes of this subchapter. The Coast Guard may continue to maintain and operate existing navigational aids: Provided, That access to such navigational aids and the installation of necessary new navigational aids within the recreation area shall be undertaken in accordance with plans which are mutually acceptable to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating and which are consistent with both the purposes of this subchapter and the purpose of e</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain property of Navy Department to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transfer of certain property of Navy Department to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary That portion of Fort Miley comprising approximately one and seven-tenths acres of land presently used and required by the Secretary of the Navy for its inshore, underseas warfare installations shall remain under the administrative jurisdiction of the Department of the Navy until such time as all or any portion thereof is determined by the Department of Defense to be excess to its needs, at which time such excess portion shall be transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary for purposes of this subchapter. That property known as the Pillar Point Military Reservation, under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense shall be transferred to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary at such time as the property, or any portion thereof, becomes excess to the needs of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>New construction; limitation; notice and public hearing; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) New construction; limitation; notice and public hearing; exceptions New construction and development within the boundaries described in section 460bb–1(a) of this title on lands under the administrative jurisdiction of a department other than that of the Secretary is prohibited, except that improvements on lands which have not been transferred to his administrative jurisdiction may be reconstructed or demolished. Any such structure which is demolished may be replaced with an improvement of similar size, following consultation with the Secretary or his designated representative, who shall conduct a public hearing at a location in the general vicinity of the area, notice of which shall be given at least one week prior to the date thereof. The foregoing limitation on construction and development shall not apply to expansion of those facilities known as Letterman General Hospital or the Western Medical Institute of Research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for residential purposes for fixed term of years or for life; election by owner; adjustment of compensation; termination of use and occupancy inconsistent with statutory purposes and upon tender of sum for unexpired right; lease of Federal lands: restrictive covenants, offer to prior owner or leaseholder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for residential purposes for fixed term of years or for life; election by owner; adjustment of compensation; termination of use and occupancy inconsistent with statutory purposes and upon tender of sum for unexpired right; lease of Federal lands: restrictive covenants, offer to prior owner or leaseholder The owner of improved residential property or of agricultural property on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary under this subchapter may, as a condition of such acquisition, retain for himself and his or her heirs and assigns a right of use and occupancy for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or, in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the death of his or her spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. Unless the property is wholly or partly donated to the United States, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the da</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>