<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bb_4"><akn:num>460bb–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bb–4. Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established the Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”).


(b) Membership; appointment; term of officeThe Commission shall be composed of eighteen members appointed by the Secretary for terms of five years each.11 So in original. The period probably should be a colon. Provided, That the terms of those members who have been either appointed or reappointed subsequent to January 1, 1979, shall be extended so as to expire not before June 1, 1985.


(c) VacanciesAny vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.


(d) Compensation and expenses; vouchersMembers of the Commission shall serve without compensation, as such, but the Secretary may pay, upon vouchers signed by the Chairman, the expenses reasonably incurred by the Commission and its members in carrying out their responsibilities under this subchapter.


(e) Consultations of Secretary with membersThe Secretary, or his designee, shall from time to time, but at least annually, meet and consult with the Commission on general policies and specific matters related to planning, administration and development affecting the recreation area and other units of the national park system in Marin, San Mateo, and San Francisco Counties.


(f) VotingThe Commission shall act and advise by affirmative vote of a majority of the members thereof.


(g) Termination dateThe Commission shall cease to exist thirty years after October 27, 1972.


(Pub. L. 92–589, § 5, Oct. 27, 1972, 86 Stat. 1302; Pub. L. 95–625, title III, § 317(g), Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3486; Pub. L. 96–344, § 4(2), (3), Sept. 8, 1980, 94 Stat. 1134; Pub. L. 96–607, title X, § 1001(6), (7), Dec. 28, 1980, 94 Stat. 3545; Pub. L. 102–525, title III, § 303, Oct. 26, 1992, 106 Stat. 3441.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (g). Pub. L. 102–525 subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established the Golden Gate National Recreation Area Advisory Commission (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; appointment; term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; appointment; term of office The Commission shall be composed of eighteen members appointed by the Secretary for terms of five years each.11 So in original. The period probably should be a colon. Provided, That the terms of those members who have been either appointed or reappointed subsequent to January 1, 1979, shall be extended so as to expire not before June 1, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Vacancies Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses; vouchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses; vouchers Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation, as such, but the Secretary may pay, upon vouchers signed by the Chairman, the expenses reasonably incurred by the Commission and its members in carrying out their responsibilities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations of Secretary with members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultations of Secretary with members The Secretary, or his designee, shall from time to time, but at least annually, meet and consult with the Commission on general policies and specific matters related to planning, administration and development affecting the recreation area and other units of the national park system in Marin, San Mateo, and San Francisco Counties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Voting The Commission shall act and advise by affirmative vote of a majority of the members thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460bb_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination date The Commission shall cease to exist thirty years after October 27, 1972.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>