<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460bb"><akn:num>460bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460bb. Establishment
In order to preserve for public use and enjoyment certain areas of Marin and San Francisco Counties, California, possessing outstanding natural, historic, scenic, and recreational values, and in order to provide for the maintenance of needed recreational open space necessary to urban environment and planning, the Golden Gate National Recreation Area (hereinafter referred to as the “recreation area”) is hereby established. In the management of the recreation area, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall utilize the resources in a manner which will provide for recreation and educational opportunities consistent with sound principles of land use planning and management. In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary shall preserve the recreation area, as far as possible, in its natural setting, and protect it from development and uses which would destroy the scenic beauty and natural character of the area.
(Pub. L. 92–589, § 1, Oct. 27, 1972, 86 Stat. 1299.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2005 AmendmentPub. L. 109–131, title II, § 201, Dec. 20, 2005, 119 Stat. 2568, provided that: “This title [amending section 460bb–1 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Rancho Corral de Tierra Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act’.”


Short Title of 2000 AmendmentPub. L. 106–350, § 1, Oct. 24, 2000, 114 Stat. 1361, provided that: “This Act [amending section 460bb–1 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Golden Gate National Recreation Area Boundary Adjustment Act of 2000’.”


Short Title of 1992 AmendmentPub. L. 102–299, § 1, June 9, 1992, 106 Stat. 236, provided that: “This Act [amending section 460bb–1 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under section 460bb–1 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Golden Gate National Recreation Area Addition Act of 1992’.”


Visitor Services in Crissy Field and Fort Point AreasPub. L. 108–108, title I, § 1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>