<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ccc–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ccc–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ccc–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ccc_3"><akn:num>460ccc–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ccc–3. Management plan(a) In general(1) No later than January 1, 1997, the Secretary shall develop and transmit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, a general management plan for the conservation area, which shall describe the appropriate uses and development of the conservation area consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.

(2) The management plan described in paragraph (1) shall be developed with full public participation and shall include—(A) an implementation plan for a continuing program of interpretation and public education about the resources and values of the conservation area;

(B) a proposal for administrative and public facilities to be developed, expanded, or improved for the conservation area including the Red Rock Canyon visitors center, to accommodate visitors to the conservation area;

(C) a cultural resources management plan for the conservation area prepared in consultation with the Nevada State Historic Preservation Officer, with emphasis on the preservation of the resources in the conservation area and the interpretive, educational, and long-term scientific uses of these resources, giving priority to the enforcement of the Archaeological Resources Protection Act of 1979 (16 U.S.C. 470aa et seq.) and the National Historic Preservation Act 11 See References in Text note below. within the conservation area;

(D) a wildlife resource management plan for the conservation area prepared in consultation with appropriate departments of the State of Nevada and using previous studies of the area; and

(E) a recreation management plan, including nonmotorized dispersed recreation opportunities for the conservation area in consultation with appropriate departments of the State of Nevada.



(b) Wilderness study areasSubject to section 460ccc–5 of this title, nothing in this subchapter is intended to alter the requirements o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ccc_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ccc_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness study areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wilderness study areas Subject to section 460ccc–5 of this title, nothing in this subchapter is intended to alter the requirements of section 1782 of title 43, or section 5(a) of the National Forest and Public Lands of Nevada Enhancement Act of 1988 (102 Stat. 2751), as those requirements apply to the lands within, or adjacent to the conservation area as of November 16, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>