<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dd–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dd–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dd–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460dd_2"><akn:num>460dd–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460dd–2. Public lands(a) Withdrawal from location, entry, and patent under Federal mining laws; removal of mineralsThe lands within the recreation area, subject to valid existing rights, are withdrawn from location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws. Under such regulations as he deems appropriate, the Secretary shall permit the removal of the nonleasable minerals from lands or interests in lands within the national recreation area in the manner prescribed by section 387 of title 43, and he shall permit the removal of leasable minerals from lands or interests in lands within the recreation area in accordance with the Mineral Leasing Act of February 25, 1920, as amended (30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.), or the Acquired Lands Mineral Leasing Act of August 7, 1947 (30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.), if he finds that such disposition would not have significant adverse effects on the Glen Canyon project or on the administration of the national recreation area pursuant to this subchapter.


(b) Disposition of funds from permits and leasesAll receipts derived from permits and leases issued on lands in the recreation area under the Mineral Leasing Act of February 25, 1920, as amended [30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.], or the Act of August 7, 1947 [30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.], shall be disposed of as provided in the applicable Act; and receipts from the disposition of nonleasable minerals within the recreation area shall be disposed of in the same manner as moneys received from the sale of public lands.


(Pub. L. 92–593, § 3, Oct. 27, 1972, 86 Stat. 1312.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Mineral Leasing Act of February 25, 1920, as amended, referred to in text, is act Feb. 25, 1920, ch. 85, 41 Stat. 437, known as the Mineral Leasing Act, which is classified generally to chapter 3A (§ 181 et seq.) of Title 30. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 181 of Title 30 and Tables.
The Acquired Lands Mineral Leasing Act of August </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dd_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal from location, entry, and patent under Federal mining laws; removal of minerals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal from location, entry, and patent under Federal mining laws; removal of minerals The lands within the recreation area, subject to valid existing rights, are withdrawn from location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws. Under such regulations as he deems appropriate, the Secretary shall permit the removal of the nonleasable minerals from lands or interests in lands within the national recreation area in the manner prescribed by section 387 of title 43, and he shall permit the removal of leasable minerals from lands or interests in lands within the recreation area in accordance with the Mineral Leasing Act of February 25, 1920, as amended (30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.), or the Acquired Lands Mineral Leasing Act of August 7, 1947 (30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.), if he finds that such disposition would not have significant adverse effects on the Glen Canyon project or on the administration of the national recreation area pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dd_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of funds from permits and leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition of funds from permits and leases All receipts derived from permits and leases issued on lands in the recreation area under the Mineral Leasing Act of February 25, 1920, as amended [30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.], or the Act of August 7, 1947 [30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.], shall be disposed of as provided in the applicable Act; and receipts from the disposition of nonleasable minerals within the recreation area shall be disposed of in the same manner as moneys received from the sale of public lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>