<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dddd–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dddd–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460dddd–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460dddd_1"><akn:num>460dddd–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Recreation Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460dddd–1. Management of Recreation Area(a) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Recreation Area—(1) in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the purposes for which the Recreation Area is established; and

(2) in accordance with—(A) this section;

(B) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); and

(C) other applicable laws.



(b) UsesThe Secretary shall allow only uses of the Recreation Area that are consistent with the purposes for which the Recreation Area is established.


(c) Management Plan(1) In generalNot later than 5 years after March 12, 2019, the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Recreation Area.


(2) RequirementsThe Management Plan shall—(A) describe the appropriate uses and management of the Recreation Area;

(B) be developed with extensive public input;

(C) take into consideration any information developed in studies of the land within the Recreation Area; and

(D) be developed fully consistent with the settlement agreement entered into on January 13, 2017, in the case in the United States District Court for the District of Utah styled “Southern Utah Wilderness Alliance, et al. v. U.S. Department of the Interior, et al.” and numbered 2:12–cv–257 DAK.



(d) Motorized vehicles; new roads(1) Motorized vehiclesExcept as needed for emergency response or administrative purposes, the use of motorized vehicles in the Recreation Area shall be permitted only on roads and motorized routes designated in the Management Plan for the use of motorized vehicles.


(2) New roadsNo new permanent or temporary roads or other motorized vehicle routes shall be constructed within the Recreation Area after March 12, 2019.


(3) Existing roads(A) In generalNecessary maintenance or repairs to existing roads designated in the Management Plan for the use of motorized vehicles, including necessary repairs to keep existing roads free of debris or other s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall administer the Recreation Area—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses The Secretary shall allow only uses of the Recreation Area that are consistent with the purposes for which the Recreation Area is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motorized vehicles; new roads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Motorized vehicles; new roads</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cold War sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cold War sites The Secretary shall manage the Recreation Area in a manner that educates the public about Cold War and historic uranium mine sites in the Recreation Area, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers necessary to protect public health and safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Incorporation of acquired land and interests Any land or interest in land located within the boundary of the Recreation Area that is acquired by the United States after March 12, 2019, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Recreation Area, including any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States within the Recreation Area after March 12, 2019, is withdrawn from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of nonmotorized recreation opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Study of nonmotorized recreation opportunities Not later than 2 years after March 12, 2019, the Secretary, in consultation with interested parties, shall conduct a study of nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities, including bicycle trails, within the Recreation Area, consistent with the purposes of the Recreation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460dddd_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative agreement The Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement with the State in accordance with section 307(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1737(b)) and other applicable laws to provide for the protection, management, and maintenance of the Recreation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>