<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ee"><akn:num>460ee</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ee. Establishment(a) “Secretary” defined; statement of purposes; boundaries; acquisition of outside sites for administrative, visitor orientation, and recreation facilitiesAs used in this section the term “Secretary” shall mean the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers. The Secretary, in accordance with the national recreation area concept included in the interagency report prepared pursuant to section 218 of the Flood Control Act of 1968 (Public Law 90–483) by the Corps of Engineers, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture, as modified by this section, is authorized and directed to establish on the Big South Fork of the Cumberland River in Kentucky and Tennessee the Big South Fork National River and Recreation Area (hereafter in this section referred to as the “National Area”) for the purposes of conserving and interpreting an area containing unique cultural, historic, geologic, fish and wildlife, archeologic, scenic, and recreational values, preserving as a natural, free-flowing stream the Big South Fork of the Cumberland River, major portions of its Clear Fork and New River stems, and portions of their various tributaries for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations, the preservation of the natural integrity of the scenic gorges and valleys, and the development of the area’s potential for healthful outdoor recreation. The boundaries shall be as generally depicted on the drawing prepared by the Corps of Engineers and entitled “Big South Fork National River and Recreation Area” identified as map number BSF–NRRA(1)(A) and dated October 1972, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the District Engineer, U.S. Army Engineer District, Nashville, Tennessee. The Secretary may acquire sites at locations outside such boundaries, as he determines necessary, for administrative and visitor orientation facilities. The Secretary may also acquire a site outside such bound</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Secretary” defined; statement of purposes; boundaries; acquisition of outside sites for administrative, visitor orientation, and recreation facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Secretary” defined; statement of purposes; boundaries; acquisition of outside sites for administrative, visitor orientation, and recreation facilities As used in this section the term “Secretary” shall mean the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers. The Secretary, in accordance with the national recreation area concept included in the interagency report prepared pursuant to section 218 of the Flood Control Act of 1968 (Public Law 90–483) by the Corps of Engineers, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture, as modified by this section, is authorized and directed to establish on the Big South Fork of the Cumberland River in Kentucky and Tennessee the Big South Fork National River and Recreation Area (hereafter in this section referred to as the “National Area”) for the purposes of conserving and interpreting an area containing unique cultural, historic, geologic, fish and wildlife, archeologic, scenic, and recreational values, preservin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of responsibility for planning, acquisition, and development, and administrative jurisdiction to Secretary of the Interior; boundary revisions; acreage limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of responsibility for planning, acquisition, and development, and administrative jurisdiction to Secretary of the Interior; boundary revisions; acreage limitation Effective upon November 15, 1990, responsibility for all planning, acquisition, and development, as well as administrative jurisdiction over all Federal lands, water, interests therein, and improvements thereon, within the National Area is hereby transferred to the Secretary of the Interior. The Secretary may complete all acquisition and development activities in progress on November 15, 1990, and the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior may, by mutual agreement, provide for an orderly and phased assumption of responsibilities (including but not limited to land acquisition and the construction of necessary access roads, day-use facilities, campground facilities, lodges, and administrative buildings) and available funds by the Secretary of the Interior in furtherance of the purposes of this section. The Sec</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property; tracts; exchange and disposal of property; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; residential property, right of use and occupancy; fair market value; transfer or assignment; lifetime residence of tenant or spouse; accrual of obligation or rental to United States; “improved property” defined; mineral rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition of property; tracts; exchange and disposal of property; transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary; residential property, right of use and occupancy; fair market value; transfer or assignment; lifetime residence of tenant or spouse; accrual of obligation or rental to United States; “improved property” defined; mineral rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping; rules and regulations after consultations with State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hunting, fishing, and trapping; rules and regulations after consultations with State agencies The Secretary, and the Secretary of the Interior after jurisdiction over the National Area has been transferred to him under subsection (b) of this section, shall permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on lands and waters under his jurisdiction within the boundaries of the National Area in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws, except that he may designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting, fishing, or trapping shall be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, fish or wildlife management, or public use and enjoyment. Except in emergencies, any rules and regulations of the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to this subsection shall be put into effect only after consultation with the appropriate State agency responsible for hunting, fishing, and trapping activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gorge areas division: restrictions, limited motorboat access, operation and maintenance of rail line, access routes, maintenance of roads for nonvehicular traffic, ingress and egress of residents, protection of values; adjacent areas division: restrictions, boundaries; Rugby area; Federal consultations with involved agencies respecting development and management of adjacent National Area; Blue Heron Mine community, restoration; rail and alternative transportation study; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Gorge areas division: restrictions, limited motorboat access, operation and maintenance of rail line, access routes, maintenance of roads for nonvehicular traffic, ingress and egress of residents, protection of values; adjacent areas division: restrictions, boundaries; Rugby area; Federal consultations with involved agencies respecting development and management of adjacent National Area; Blue Heron Mine community, restoration; rail and alternative transportation study; report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal power and water resources projects; license and other restrictions; limitations inapplicable to external areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal power and water resources projects; license and other restrictions; limitations inapplicable to external areas The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall not license the construction of any dam, water conduit, reservoir, powerhouse, transmission line, or other project works under the Federal Power Act (41 Stat. 1063) as amended (16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.), within or directly affecting the National Area and no department or agency of the United States shall assist by loan, grant, license, or otherwise in the construction of any water resources project that would have a direct and adverse effect on the values for which the National Area was established. Nothing contained in the preceding sentence shall preclude licensing of, or assistance to, developments below or above the National Area or on any stream tributary thereto which will not invade the National Area or unreasonably diminish the scenic, recreation, and fish and wildlife values present in the area on March 7, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation facilities; study and establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transportation facilities; study and establishment The Secretary shall study transportation facilities in the region served by the National Area and shall establish transportation facilities to enhance public access to the National Area. In this connection the Secretary is authorized to acquire and maintain public roads, other than State highways, necessary to serve the public use facilities within the National Area, and to establish and maintain, at Federal cost an interior and circulating road system sufficient to meet the purposes of this section. Any existing public road, which at the time of its acquisition continues to be a necessary and essential part of the county highway system, may, upon mutual agreement between the Secretary and the owner of such road, be relocated outside of the National Area and if not so relocated such road shall be maintained at Federal expense and kept open at all times for general travel purposes. Nothing in this subsection shall abrogate the right</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>New River plan and programs; transmittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) New River plan and programs; transmittal to Congress In furtherance of the purpose of this subsection the Secretary in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the heads of other Federal departments and agencies involved, and the State of Tennessee and its political subdivisions, shall formulate a comprehensive plan for that portion of the New River that lies upstream from United States Highway Numbered 27. Such plan shall include, among other things, programs to enhance the environment and conserve and develop natural resources, and to minimize siltation and acid mine drainage. Such plan, with recommendations, including those as to costs and administrative responsibilities, shall be completed and transmitted to the Congress within one year from March 7, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water quality protection; interagency cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Water quality protection; interagency cooperation The Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, after jurisdiction over the National Area has been transferred to him under subsection (b) of this subsection,44 So in original. Probably should be “section,”. shall consult and cooperate with other departments and agencies of the United States and the States of Tennessee and Kentucky in the development of measures and programs to protect and enhance water quality within the National Area and to insure that such programs for the protection and enhancement of water quality do not diminish other values that are to be protected under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ee_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Real and personal property tax losses; reimbursement; authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Real and personal property tax losses; reimbursement; authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>