<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ffff–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ffff–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ffff–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ffff_2"><akn:num>460ffff–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ffff–2. Management plan(a) In generalNot later than 3 years after March 12, 2019, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Scenic Area.


(b) ConsultationIn developing the management plan, the Secretary shall consult with—(1) appropriate State, Tribal, and local governmental entities, including Inyo County and the Tribe;

(2) utilities, including Southern California Edison Company and the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power;

(3) the Alabama Hills Stewardship Group; and

(4) members of the public.


(c) RequirementIn accordance with this subchapter, the management plan shall include provisions for maintenance of existing public utility and other rights-of-way within the Scenic Area.


(d) IncorporationIn developing the management plan, in accordance with this section, the Secretary may allow casual use mining limited to the use of hand tools, metal detectors, hand-fed dry washers, vacuum cleaners, gold pans, small sluices, and similar items.


(e) Interim managementPending completion of the management plan, the Secretary shall manage the Scenic Area in accordance with section 460ffff–1(b) of this title.


(Pub. L. 103–433, title XIV, § 1403, as added Pub. L. 116–9, title I, § 1441, Mar. 12, 2019, 133 Stat. 709.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definition of “Secretary” as used in this section, see section 3 of Pub. L. 103–433, set out as a note under section 410aaa of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ffff_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 3 years after March 12, 2019, in accordance with subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Scenic Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ffff_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In developing the management plan, the Secretary shall consult with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ffff_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement In accordance with this subchapter, the management plan shall include provisions for maintenance of existing public utility and other rights-of-way within the Scenic Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ffff_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Incorporation In developing the management plan, in accordance with this section, the Secretary may allow casual use mining limited to the use of hand tools, metal detectors, hand-fed dry washers, vacuum cleaners, gold pans, small sluices, and similar items.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ffff_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interim management Pending completion of the management plan, the Secretary shall manage the Scenic Area in accordance with section 460ffff–1(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>