<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460hhhh" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460hhhh/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460hhhh/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460hhhh"><akn:num>460hhhh</akn:num><akn:heading>Numunaa Nobe National Conservation Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460hhhh. Numunaa Nobe National Conservation Area(1) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) Conservation AreaThe term “Conservation Area” means the Numunaa Nobe National Conservation Area established by paragraph (2).


(B) Management planThe term “management plan” means the management plan for the Conservation Area developed under paragraph (3)(B).


(C) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.



(2) Establishment(A) In generalTo conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the cultural, archaeological, natural, wilderness, scientific, geological, historical, biological, wildlife, educational, recreational, and scenic resources of the Conservation Area, subject to valid existing rights, there is established the Numunaa Nobe National Conservation Area in the State of Nevada, to be administered by the Secretary.


(B) Area included(i) In generalThe Conservation Area shall consist of approximately 160,224 acres of public land in Churchill County, Nevada, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Churchill County Proposed Fallon Range Training Complex Modernization and Lands Bill” and dated November 30, 2022.


(ii) Availability of mapThe map described in clause (i) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.




(3) Management(A) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Conservation Area in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the Conservation Area—(i) in accordance with—(I) this section;

(II) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); and

(III) any other applicable law; and


(ii) as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System.


(B) Management plan(i) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 23, 2022, the Secretary shall develop a management plan for the Conservation Area.


(ii) ConsultationIn developing the management plan, the Secretary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Uses The Secretary shall allow only those uses of the Conservation Area that the Secretary determines would further the purposes of the Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motorized vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Motorized vehicles Except as needed for administrative purposes, planned military activities authorized by paragraph (3)(B)(iii)(III), or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized vehicles in the Conservation Area shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for the use of motorized vehicles by the management plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Grazing In the case of land included in the Conservation Area on which the Secretary permitted, as of December 23, 2022, livestock grazing, the livestock grazing shall be allowed to continue, subject to applicable laws (including regulations).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>No buffer zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) No buffer zones</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460hhhh_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two pars. (10) have been enacted. Military overflights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Nothing in this section restricts or precludes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>