<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460iii–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460iii–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460iii–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460iii_3"><akn:num>460iii–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Management and use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460iii–3. Management and use(a) In general(1)(A) Within 1 year after August 4, 1993, the Secretary shall make any revisions in the existing management plan for the conservation area as necessary to assure its conformance with this subchapter, and no later than January 1, 1996, shall finalize a new management plan for the conservation area.

(B) Thereafter, the Secretary shall review the plan at least once every 5 years and shall make such revisions as may be necessary or appropriate.

(C) In reviewing and revising the plan, the Secretary shall provide for appropriate public participation.


(2) Except as otherwise specifically provided in section 460iii–2(d) of this title and subsections (d), (e), and (f) of this section, the Secretary shall allow only such uses of lands in the conservation area as the Secretary determines will further the purposes for which the conservation area is established.


(b) Management guidanceAfter each review pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall make such revisions as may be needed so that the plan and management program to implement the plan include, in addition to any other necessary or appropriate provisions, provisions for—(1) protection for the raptor populations and habitats and the scientific, cultural, and educational resources and values of the public lands in the conservation area;

(2) identifying levels of continued military use of the Orchard Training Area compatible with paragraph (1) of this subsection;

(3) public use of the conservation area consistent with the purposes of this subchapter;

(4) interpretive and educational opportunities for the public;

(5) a program for continued scientific investigation and study to provide information to support sound management in accordance with this subchapter, to advance knowledge of raptor species and the resources and values of the conservation area, and to provide a process for transferring to other areas of the public lands and elsewhere this knowledge and managem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management guidance After each review pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall make such revisions as may be needed so that the plan and management program to implement the plan include, in addition to any other necessary or appropriate provisions, provisions for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visitors center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Visitors center The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, is authorized to establish, in cooperation with other public or private entities as the Secretary may deem appropriate, a visitors center designed to interpret the history and the geological, ecological, natural, cultural, and other resources of the conservation area and the biology of the raptors and their relationships to man.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visitors use of area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Visitors use of area In addition to the visitors center, the Secretary may provide for visitor use of the public lands in the conservation area to such extent and in such manner as the Secretary considers consistent with the protection of raptors and raptor habitat, public safety, and the purposes for which the conservation area is established. To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall make available to visitors and other members of the public a map of the conservation area and such other educational and interpretive materials as may be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Guard use of area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Guard use of area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Livestock grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Livestock grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cooperative agreements The Secretary is authorized to provide technical assistance to, and to enter into such cooperative agreements and contracts with, the State of Idaho and with local governments and private entities as the Secretary deems necessary or desirable to carry out the purposes and policies of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Agricultural practices Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as constituting a grant of authority to the Secretary to restrict recognized agricultural practices or other activities on private land adjacent to or within the conservation area boundary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460iii_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hydroelectric facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Hydroelectric facilities Notwithstanding any provision of this subchapter, or regulations and management plans undertaken pursuant to its provisions, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall retain its current jurisdiction concerning all aspects of the continued and future operation of hydroelectric facilities, licensed or relicensed under the Federal Power Act (16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.), located within the boundaries of the conservation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>