<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ii–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ii–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ii–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ii_5"><akn:num>460ii–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Chattahoochee River National Recreation Area Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ii–5. Chattahoochee River National Recreation Area Advisory Commission(a) Establishment; duties; membership: voting members and Park Superintendent as nonvoting member; ChairmanThere is hereby established the Chattahoochee River National Recreation Area Advisory Commission (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Advisory Commission”) to advise the Secretary regarding the management and operation of the area, protection of resources with 11 So in original. Probably should be “within”. the recreation area, and the priority of lands to be acquired within the recreation area. The Advisory Commission shall be composed of the following thirteen voting members appointed by the Secretary:(1) four members appointed from among individuals recommended by local governments—(A) one of whom shall be recommended by the Board of County Commissioners of Forsyth County;

(B) one of whom shall be recommended by the Board of County Commissioners of Fulton County;

(C) one of whom shall be recommended by the Board of County Commissioners of Cobb County; and

(D) one of whom shall be recommended by the Board of County Commissioners of Gwinnett County;


(2) one member appointed from among individuals recommended by the Governor of Georgia;

(3) one member appointed from among individuals recommended by the Atlanta Regional Commission;

(4) four members appointed from among individuals recommended by a coalition of citizens public interest groups, recreational users, and environmental organizations concerned with the protection and preservation of the Chattahoochee River;

(5) one member appointed from among individuals recommended by the Business Council of Georgia or by a local chamber of commerce in the vicinity of the recreation area; and

(6) two members who represent the general public, at least one of whom shall be a resident of one of the counties referred to in paragraph (1).


In addition, the Park Superintendent for the recreation area shall serve as a nonvotin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ii_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; duties; membership: voting members and Park Superintendent as nonvoting member; Chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; duties; membership: voting members and Park Superintendent as nonvoting member; Chairman There is hereby established the Chattahoochee River National Recreation Area Advisory Commission (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Advisory Commission”) to advise the Secretary regarding the management and operation of the area, protection of resources with 11 So in original. Probably should be “within”. the recreation area, and the priority of lands to be acquired within the recreation area. The Advisory Commission shall be composed of the following thirteen voting members appointed by the Secretary: In addition, the Park Superintendent for the recreation area shall serve as a nonvoting member of the Advisory Commission. The Advisory Commission shall designate one of its members as Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ii_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of office; reappointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of office; reappointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ii_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Meetings The Advisory Commission shall meet on a regular basis. Notice of meetings and agenda shall be published in local newspapers which have a distribution which generally covers the area affected by the park. Commission meetings shall be held at locations and in such a manner as to insure adequate public involvement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ii_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses Members of the Commission shall serve without compensation as such, but the Secretary may pay expenses reasonably incurred in carrying out their responsibilities under this subchapter on vouchers signed by the Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ii_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination The Advisory Commission shall terminate on the date ten years after October 30, 1984.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>