<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460kk" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460kk/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460kk/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460kk"><akn:num>460kk</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460kk. Establishment(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) there are significant scenic, recreational, educational, scientific, natural, archeological, and public health benefits provided by the Santa Monica Mountains and adjacent coastline area;

(2) there is a national interest in protecting and preserving these benefits for the residents of and visitors to the area; and

(3) the State of California and its local units of government have authority to prevent or minimize adverse uses of the Santa Monica Mountains and adjacent coastline area and can, to a great extent, protect the health, safety, and general welfare by the use of such authority.


(b) Establishment; managementThere is hereby established the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area (hereinafter referred to as the “recreation area”). The Secretary shall manage the recreation area in a manner which will preserve and enhance its scenic, natural, and historical setting and its public health value as an airshed for the Southern California metropolitan area while providing for the recreational and educational need of the visiting public.


(c) Description; boundary revisions: notice to Congressional committees, publication in Federal Register; acquisition of property: manner, transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary, exchange of lands with city of Los Angeles, development of municipal cultural resource management program; Nike Site transfer to Secretary(1) The recreation area shall consist of the lands and waters and interests generally depicted as the recreation area on the map entitled “Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area and Santa Monica Mountains Zone, California, Boundary Map”, numbered 80,047–C and dated August 2001, which shall be on file and available for inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, Washington, District of Columbia, and in the offices of the General Services Administration in the Federal Of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment; management There is hereby established the Santa Monica Mountains National Recreation Area (hereinafter referred to as the “recreation area”). The Secretary shall manage the recreation area in a manner which will preserve and enhance its scenic, natural, and historical setting and its public health value as an airshed for the Southern California metropolitan area while providing for the recreational and educational need of the visiting public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description; boundary revisions: notice to Congressional committees, publication in Federal Register; acquisition of property: manner, transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary, exchange of lands with city of Los Angeles, development of municipal cultural resource management program; Nike Site transfer to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Description; boundary revisions: notice to Congressional committees, publication in Federal Register; acquisition of property: manner, transfer from Federal agency to administrative jurisdiction of Secretary, exchange of lands with city of Los Angeles, development of municipal cultural resource management program; Nike Site transfer to Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and revision of areas: public ownership for critical purposes; land and area plan: submission to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identification and revision of areas: public ownership for critical purposes; land and area plan: submission to Congressional committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved property and scenic easement acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Improved property and scenic easement acquisitions With respect to improved properties, as defined in this section, fee title shall not be acquired unless the Secretary finds that such lands are being used, or are threatened with uses, which are detrimental to the purposes of the recreation area, or unless each acquisition is necessary to fulfill the purposes of this section. The Secretary may acquire scenic easements to such improved property or such other interests as, in his judgment are necessary for the purposes of the recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Improved property” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Improved property” defined For the purposes of this section, the term “improved property” means— In determining when and to what extent a property is to be treated as “improved property” for purposes of this section, the Secretary shall take into consideration the manner of use of such buildings and lands prior to January 1, 1978, and shall designate such lands as are reasonably necessary for the continued enjoyment of the property in the same manner and to the same extent as existed prior to such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for fixed term of years or life; election of term; fair market value; termination; notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Owner’s reservation of right of use and occupancy for fixed term of years or life; election of term; fair market value; termination; notification The owner of an improved property, as defined in this section, on the date of its acquisition, as a condition of such acquisition, may retain for herself or himself, her or his heirs and assigns, a right of use and occupancy of the improved property for noncommercial residential or agriculture purposes, as the case may be, for a definite term of not more than twenty-five years, or, in lieu thereof, for a term ending at the death of the owner or the death of her or his spouse, whichever is later. The owner shall elect the term to be reserved. Unless the property is wholly or partially donated, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of its acquisition, less the fair market value on that date of the right retained by the owner. A right retained by the owner pursuant to this section shall be sub</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hardship sale offers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Hardship sale offers In exercising the authority to acquire property under this section, the Secretary shall give prompt and careful consideration to any offer made by an individual owning property within the recreation area to sell such property, if such individual notifies the Secretary that the continued ownership of such property is causing, or would result in, undue hardship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administration The Secretary shall administer the recreation area in accordance with this Act and provisions of laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.).11 See References in Text note below. In the administration of the recreation area, the Secretary may utilize such statutory authority available for the conservation and management of wildlife and natural resources as appropriate to carry out the purpose of this section. The fragile resource areas of the recreation area shall be administered on a low-intensity basis, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460kk_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements for rescue, fire prevention and firefighting, and law enforcement services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative agreements for rescue, fire prevention and firefighting, and law enforcement services The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the State of California, or any political subdivision thereof, for the rendering, on a reimbursable basis, of rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement services and cooperative assistance by nearby law enforcement and fire preventive agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>