<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460lll_22"><akn:num>460lll–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460lll–22. Advisory Board(a) EstablishmentNot later than 90 days after the date of transfer pursuant to section 460lll–41 of this title, the Secretary shall establish the Land Between the Lakes Advisory Board.


(b) MembershipThe Advisory Board shall be composed of 13 members, of whom—(1) 4 individuals shall be appointed by the Secretary, including—(A) 2 residents of the State of Kentucky; and

(B) 2 residents of the State of Tennessee;


(2) 2 individuals shall be appointed by the Kentucky Fish and Wildlife Commissioner or designee;

(3) 1 individual shall be appointed by the Tennessee Fish and Wildlife Commission or designee; and

(4) 2 individuals shall be appointed by appropriate officials of each of the 3 counties containing the Recreation Area.


(c) Term(1) In generalThe term of a member of the Advisory Board shall be 5 years.


(2) Nonconsecutive termsMembers of the Advisory Board may serve multiple terms, but may not serve consecutive terms.



(d) ChairpersonThe Regional Forester shall serve as chairperson of the Advisory Board.


(e) Rules of procedureThe Secretary shall prescribe the rules of procedure for the Advisory Board.


(f) FunctionsThe Advisory Board shall advise the Secretary on—(1) means of promoting public participation for the land and resource management plan for the Recreation Area;

(2) environmental education;

(3) an annual work plan for recreation and environment education areas in the Recreation Area, including the heritage program, with the nonappropriated amounts in the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund;

(4) an annual forest management and harvest plan for the Recreation Area; and

(5) the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund.


(g) Meetings(1) FrequencyThe Advisory Board shall meet at least twice each year.


(2) Public meetingA meeting of the Advisory Board shall be open to the general public.


(3) Notice of meetingsThe chairperson, through the placement of notices in local news media, on a public website of the Departm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Not later than 90 days after the date of transfer pursuant to section 460lll–41 of this title, the Secretary shall establish the Land Between the Lakes Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Advisory Board shall be composed of 13 members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chairperson The Regional Forester shall serve as chairperson of the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules of procedure The Secretary shall prescribe the rules of procedure for the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Functions The Advisory Board shall advise the Secretary on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_22_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No termination Section 1013(a) of title 5 shall not apply to the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>