<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–45" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–45/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–45/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460lll_45"><akn:num>460lll–45</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460lll–45. Transfer of personal property(a) Subject property(1) InventoryNot later than 60 days after the date of transfer pursuant to section 460lll–41 of this title, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall provide the Secretary with an inventory of all property and facilities at the Recreation Area.


(2) Availability for transfer(A) In generalAll Tennessee Valley Authority property associated with the administration of the Recreation Area, including any property purchased with Federal funds appropriated for the management of the Tennessee Valley Authority land, shall be available for transfer to the Secretary.


(B) Property includedProperty under subparagraph (A) includes buildings, office furniture and supplies, computers, office equipment, buildings, vehicles, tools, equipment, maintenance supplies, boats, engines, and publications.



(3) Exclusion of propertyAt the request of the authorized representative of the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Secretary may exclude movable property from transfer based on a showing by the Tennessee Valley Authority that the property is vital to the mission of the Tennessee Valley Authority and cannot be replaced in a cost-effective manner, if the Secretary determines that the property is not needed for management of the Recreation Area.



(b) DesignationPursuant to such procedures as may be prescribed in the memorandum of agreement entered into under section 460lll–43 of this title, the Secretary shall identify and designate, in writing, all Tennessee Valley Authority property to be transferred to the Secretary.


(c) Facilitation of transferThe Tennessee Valley Authority shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use current personnel to facilitate the transfer of necessary property and facilities to the Secretary, including replacement of signs and insignia, repainting of vehicles, printing of public information, and training of new personnel. Funding for these costs shall be derived from funding described in section 460lll–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_45_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subject property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_45_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation Pursuant to such procedures as may be prescribed in the memorandum of agreement entered into under section 460lll–43 of this title, the Secretary shall identify and designate, in writing, all Tennessee Valley Authority property to be transferred to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_45_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilitation of transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilitation of transfer The Tennessee Valley Authority shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use current personnel to facilitate the transfer of necessary property and facilities to the Secretary, including replacement of signs and insignia, repainting of vehicles, printing of public information, and training of new personnel. Funding for these costs shall be derived from funding described in section 460lll–49 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_45_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surplus property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Surplus property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>