<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–24" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–24/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–24/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460lll_24"><akn:num>460lll–24</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460lll–24. Disposition of receipts(a) In generalAll amounts received from charges, use fees, and natural resource utilization, including timber and agricultural receipts, shall be deposited in a special fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the “Land Between the Lakes Management Fund”.


(b) UseAmounts in the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further appropriation, for construction, improvement, or maintenance in the Recreation Area.


(c) Restriction on use of FundExcept as provided in subsection (b), amounts in the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund shall not be used for management of the Recreation Area, including salaries and expenses.


(Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title V, § 524], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–231, 2681–315; Pub. L. 117–328, div. DD, title II, § 201(e), Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5582.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsecs. (b), (c). Pub. L. 117–328 added subsecs. (b) and (c) and struck out former subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (b) read as follows: “Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further Act of appropriation, for the management of the Recreation Area, including payment of salaries and expenses.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_24_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general All amounts received from charges, use fees, and natural resource utilization, including timber and agricultural receipts, shall be deposited in a special fund in the Treasury of the United States to be known as the “Land Between the Lakes Management Fund”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_24_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use Amounts in the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund shall be available to the Secretary until expended, without further appropriation, for construction, improvement, or maintenance in the Recreation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_24_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on use of Fund Except as provided in subsection (b), amounts in the Land Between the Lakes Management Fund shall not be used for management of the Recreation Area, including salaries and expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>