<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–47" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–47/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460lll–47/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460lll_47"><akn:num>460lll–47</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460lll–47. Personnel(a) In general(1) HiringNotwithstanding section 3503 of title 5, and subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may—(A) appoint, hire, and discharge officers and employees to administer the Recreation Area; and

(B) pay the officers and employees at levels that are commensurate with levels at other units of the National Forest System.


(2) Interim retention of eligible employees(A) In generalFor a period of not less than 5 months after the effective date of transfer to the Forest Service—(i) all eligible employees shall be retained in the employment of the Tennessee Valley Authority;

(ii) those eligible employees shall be considered to be placed on detail to the Secretary and shall be subject to the direction of the Secretary; and

(iii) the Secretary shall reimburse the Tennessee Valley Authority for the amount of the basic pay and all other compensation of those eligible employees.


(B) Notice to employeesThe Secretary shall provide eligible employees a written notice of not less than 60 days before termination.


(C) Termination for causeSubparagraph (A) does not preclude a termination for cause during the period described in subparagraph (A).




(b) Applications for transfer and appointmentAn eligible employee shall have the right to apply for employment by the Secretary under procedures for transfer and appointment of Federal employees outside the Department of Agriculture.


(c) Hiring by Secretary(1) In generalSubject to subsection (b), in filling personnel positions within the Recreation Area, the Secretary shall follow all laws (including regulations) and policies applicable to the Department of Agriculture.


(2) Notification and hiringNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary—(A) shall notify all eligible employees of all openings for positions with the Forest Service at the Recreation Area before notifying other individuals or considering applications by other individuals for the positions; and

(B) after applications by eligibl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_47_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_47_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for transfer and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications for transfer and appointment An eligible employee shall have the right to apply for employment by the Secretary under procedures for transfer and appointment of Federal employees outside the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_47_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hiring by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_47_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to positions in other units of Tennessee Valley Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer to positions in other units of Tennessee Valley Authority The Tennessee Valley Authority—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460lll_47_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee benefit transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employee benefit transition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>