<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460mmm–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460mmm–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460mmm–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460mmm_4"><akn:num>460mmm–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460mmm–4. Management(a) Conservation AreaThe Secretary shall manage the Conservation Area in a manner that—(1) conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the Conservation Area specified in section 460mmm(b) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “460mmm(a)”. of this title; and

(2) is in accordance with—(A) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); and

(B) other applicable law, including this subchapter.



(b) UsesThe Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Conservation Area as the Secretary determines will further the purposes for which the Conservation Area is established.


(c) WithdrawalsSubject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness and all land and interests in land acquired for the Conservation Area or the Wilderness by the United States are withdrawn from—(1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;

(2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and

(3) the operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws, and all amendments thereto.


Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect discretionary authority of the Secretary under other Federal laws to grant, issue, or renew rights-of-way or other land use authorizations consistent with the other provisions of this subchapter.

(d) Off-highway vehicle use(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), use of motorized vehicles in the Conservation Area—(A) before the effective date of a management plan under subsection (h), shall be allowed only on roads and trails designated for use of motor vehicles in the management plan that applies on October 24, 2000, to the public lands in the Conservation Area; and

(B) after the effective date of a management plan under subsection (h), shall be allowed only on roads and trails designated for use of motor vehicles in that management plan.


(2) Administrative and emergency res</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conservation Area The Secretary shall manage the Conservation Area in a manner that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Conservation Area as the Secretary determines will further the purposes for which the Conservation Area is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withdrawals Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness and all land and interests in land acquired for the Conservation Area or the Wilderness by the United States are withdrawn from— Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect discretionary authority of the Secretary under other Federal laws to grant, issue, or renew rights-of-way or other land use authorizations consistent with the other provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Off-highway vehicle use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Off-highway vehicle use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Wilderness Subject to valid existing rights, lands designated as wilderness by this subchapter shall be managed by the Secretary, as appropriate, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.) and this subchapter, except that, with respect to any wilderness areas designated by this subchapter, any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of the Wilderness Act shall be deemed to be a reference to October 24, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, trapping, and fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hunting, trapping, and fishing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>No buffer zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No buffer zones The Congress does not intend for the establishment of the Conservation Area or the Wilderness to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around the Conservation Area or the Wilderness. The fact that there may be activities or uses on lands outside the Conservation Area or the Wilderness that would not be allowed in the Conservation Area or the Wilderness shall not preclude such activities or uses on such lands up to the boundary of the Conservation Area or the Wilderness consistent with other applicable laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460mmm_4_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Acquisition of land</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>