<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–62" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–62/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–62/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_62"><akn:num>460nnn–62</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Wilderness Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–62. Administration of Wilderness Area(a) General ruleThe Secretary shall administer the Wilderness Area in accordance with this part and the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.). Any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act (or any similar reference) shall be deemed to be a reference to October 30, 2000.


(b) Wilderness boundaries along roadsWhere a wilderness boundary exists along a road, the wilderness boundary shall be set back from the centerline of the road, consistent with the Bureau of Land Management’s guidelines as established in its Wilderness Management Policy.


(c) Access to non-Federal landsThe Secretary shall provide reasonable access to private lands within the boundaries of the Wilderness Area, as provided in section 460nnn–22(d) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “460nnn–22(e)”. of this title.


(d) Grazing(1) AdministrationExcept as provided in section 460nnn–23(e)(2) of this title, grazing of livestock shall be administered in accordance with the provision of section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)), in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, and in accordance with the guidelines set forth in Appendices A and B of House Report 101–405 of the 101st Congress.


(2) Retirement of certain permitsThe Secretary shall permanently retire all grazing permits applicable to certain lands in the Wilderness Area, as depicted on the map referred to in section 460nnn–11(a) of this title, and livestock shall be excluded from these lands.



(Pub. L. 106–399, title II, § 202, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1666.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Wilderness Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 88–577, Sept. 3, 1964, 78 Stat. 890, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1131 of this title and Tables.
The effective date of the Wilderness Act, referre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_62_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The Secretary shall administer the Wilderness Area in accordance with this part and the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.). Any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act (or any similar reference) shall be deemed to be a reference to October 30, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_62_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness boundaries along roads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wilderness boundaries along roads Where a wilderness boundary exists along a road, the wilderness boundary shall be set back from the centerline of the road, consistent with the Bureau of Land Management’s guidelines as established in its Wilderness Management Policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_62_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to non-Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Access to non-Federal lands The Secretary shall provide reasonable access to private lands within the boundaries of the Wilderness Area, as provided in section 460nnn–22(d) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “460nnn–22(e)”. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_62_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>