<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–23" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–23/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–23/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_23"><akn:num>460nnn–23</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–23. Land use authorities(a) In generalThe Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area as the Secretary finds will further the purposes for which the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is established.


(b) Commercial timber(1) ProhibitionThe Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area shall not be made available for commercial timber harvest.


(2) Limited exceptionThe Secretary may authorize the removal of trees from Federal lands in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area only if the Secretary determines that the removal is clearly needed for purposes of ecological restoration and maintenance or for public safety. Except in the Wilderness Area and the wilderness study areas referred to in section 460nnn–64(a) of this title, the Secretary may authorize the sale of products resulting from the authorized removal of trees under this paragraph.



(c) Juniper managementThe Secretary shall emphasize the restoration of the historic fire regime in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area and the resulting native vegetation communities through active management of Western Juniper on a landscape level. Management measures shall include the use of natural and prescribed burning.


(d) Hunting, fishing, and trapping(1) AuthorizationThe Secretary shall permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the United States and the State of Oregon.


(2) Area and time limitationsAfter consultation with the Oregon Department of Fish and Wildlife, the Secretary may designate zones where, and establish periods when, hunting, trapping or fishing is prohibited on Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment.



(e) Grazing(1) Continuation of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area as the Secretary finds will further the purposes for which the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial timber</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commercial timber</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Juniper management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Juniper management The Secretary shall emphasize the restoration of the historic fire regime in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area and the resulting native vegetation communities through active management of Western Juniper on a landscape level. Management measures shall include the use of natural and prescribed burning.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on construction of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on construction of facilities No new facilities may be constructed on Federal lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area unless the Secretary determines that the structure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_23_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal lands and interests in lands included in the Cooperative Management and Protection Areas are hereby withdrawn from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, except in the case of land exchanges if the Secretary determines that the exchange furthers the purpose and objectives specified in section 460nnn–12 of this title and so certifies to Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>