<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–64" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–64/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–64/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_64"><akn:num>460nnn–64</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of wilderness study areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–64. Treatment of wilderness study areas(a) Status unaffectedExcept as provided in section 460nnn–92 of this title, any wilderness study area, or portion of a wilderness study area, within the boundaries of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area, but not included in the Wilderness Area, shall remain a wilderness study area notwithstanding the enactment of this subchapter.


(b) ManagementThe wilderness study areas referred to in subsection (a) shall continue to be managed under section 1782(c) of title 43 in a manner so as not to impair the suitability of the areas for preservation as wilderness.


(c) Expansion of Basque Hills Wilderness Study AreaThe boundaries of the Basque Hills Wilderness Study Area are hereby expanded to include the Federal lands within sections 8, 16, 17, 21, 22, and 27 of township 36 south, range 31 east, Willamette Meridian. These lands shall be managed under section 1782(c) of title 43 to protect and enhance the wilderness values of these lands.


(Pub. L. 106–399, title II, § 204, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1667.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 106–399, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1655, known as the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Act of 2000, which is classified generally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 460nnn of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_64_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Status unaffected Except as provided in section 460nnn–92 of this title, any wilderness study area, or portion of a wilderness study area, within the boundaries of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area, but not included in the Wilderness Area, shall remain a wilderness study area notwithstanding the enactment of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_64_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management The wilderness study areas referred to in subsection (a) shall continue to be managed under section 1782(c) of title 43 in a manner so as not to impair the suitability of the areas for preservation as wilderness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_64_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of Basque Hills Wilderness Study Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expansion of Basque Hills Wilderness Study Area The boundaries of the Basque Hills Wilderness Study Area are hereby expanded to include the Federal lands within sections 8, 16, 17, 21, 22, and 27 of township 36 south, range 31 east, Willamette Meridian. These lands shall be managed under section 1782(c) of title 43 to protect and enhance the wilderness values of these lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>