<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_1"><akn:num>460nnn–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps and legal descriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–1. Maps and legal descriptions(a) Preparation and submissionAs soon as practicable after October 30, 2000, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress maps and legal descriptions of the following:(1) The Cooperative Management and Protection Area.

(2) The Wilderness Area.

(3) The wild and scenic river segments and redband trout reserve designated by part C.

(4) The mineral withdrawal area designated by part D.

(5) The wildlands juniper management area established by part E.

(6) The land exchanges required by part F.


(b) Legal effect and correctionThe maps and legal descriptions referred to in subsection (a) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter, except the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in such maps and legal descriptions.


(c) Public availabilityCopies of the maps and legal descriptions referred to in subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management and in the appropriate office of the Bureau of Land Management in the State of Oregon.


(Pub. L. 106–399, § 3, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1657.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 106–399, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1655, known as the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Act of 2000, which is classified generally to this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 460nnn of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation and submission As soon as practicable after October 30, 2000, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress maps and legal descriptions of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal effect and correction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Legal effect and correction The maps and legal descriptions referred to in subsection (a) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter, except the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in such maps and legal descriptions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public availability Copies of the maps and legal descriptions referred to in subsection (a) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management and in the appropriate office of the Bureau of Land Management in the State of Oregon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>