<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–41" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–41/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–41/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_41"><akn:num>460nnn–41</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative management agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–41. Cooperative management agreements(a) Cooperative effortsTo further the purposes and objectives for which the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is designated, the Secretary may work with non-Federal landowners and other parties who voluntarily agree to participate in the cooperative management of Federal and non-Federal lands in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area.


(b) Agreements authorizedThe Secretary may enter into a cooperative management agreement with any party to provide for the cooperative conservation and management of the Federal and non-Federal lands subject to the agreement.


(c) Other participantsWith the consent of the landowners involved, the Secretary may permit permittees, special-use permit holders, other Federal and State agencies, and interested members of the public to participate in a cooperative management agreement as appropriate to achieve the resource or land use management objectives of the agreement.


(d) Tribal cultural site protectionThe Secretary may enter into agreements with the Burns Paiute Tribe to protect cultural sites in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area of importance to the tribe.


(Pub. L. 106–399, title I, § 121, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1663.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_41_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperative efforts To further the purposes and objectives for which the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is designated, the Secretary may work with non-Federal landowners and other parties who voluntarily agree to participate in the cooperative management of Federal and non-Federal lands in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_41_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements authorized The Secretary may enter into a cooperative management agreement with any party to provide for the cooperative conservation and management of the Federal and non-Federal lands subject to the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_41_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other participants With the consent of the landowners involved, the Secretary may permit permittees, special-use permit holders, other Federal and State agencies, and interested members of the public to participate in a cooperative management agreement as appropriate to achieve the resource or land use management objectives of the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_41_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal cultural site protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tribal cultural site protection The Secretary may enter into agreements with the Burns Paiute Tribe to protect cultural sites in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area of importance to the tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>