<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn"><akn:num>460nnn</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Advisory councilThe term “advisory council” means the Steens Mountain Advisory Council established by part D.11 See References in Text note below.


(2) Cooperative management agreementAn agreement to plan or implement (or both) cooperative recreation, ecological, grazing, fishery, vegetation, prescribed fire, cultural site protection, wildfire or other measures to beneficially meet public use needs and the public land and private land objectives of this subchapter.


(3) Cooperative Management and Protection AreaThe term “Cooperative Management and Protection Area” means the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area designated by part A.


(4) Easements(A) Conservation easementThe term “conservation easement” means a binding contractual agreement between the Secretary and a landowner in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area under which the landowner, permanently or during a time period specified in the agreement, agrees to conserve or restore habitat, open space, scenic, or other ecological resource values on the land covered by the easement.


(B) Nondevelopment easementThe term “nondevelopment easement” means a binding contractual agreement between the Secretary and a landowner in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area that will, permanently or during a time period specified in the agreement—(i) prevent or restrict development on the land covered by the easement; or

(ii) protect open space or viewshed.



(5) Ecological integrityThe term “ecological integrity” means a landscape where ecological processes are functioning to maintain the structure, composition, activity, and resilience of the landscape over time, including—(A) a complex of plant communities, habitats and conditions representative of variable and sustainable successional conditions; and

(B) the maintenance of biological diversity, soil fertility, and genetic interchange.


(6) Management planThe term “management plan” m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Advisory council The term “advisory council” means the Steens Mountain Advisory Council established by part D.11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative management agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cooperative management agreement An agreement to plan or implement (or both) cooperative recreation, ecological, grazing, fishery, vegetation, prescribed fire, cultural site protection, wildfire or other measures to beneficially meet public use needs and the public land and private land objectives of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Management and Protection Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Cooperative Management and Protection Area The term “Cooperative Management and Protection Area” means the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area designated by part A.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Easements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ecological integrity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Ecological integrity The term “ecological integrity” means a landscape where ecological processes are functioning to maintain the structure, composition, activity, and resilience of the landscape over time, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Management plan The term “management plan” means the management plan for the Cooperative Management and Protection Area and the Wilderness Area required to be prepared by section 460nnn–21(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redband Trout Reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Redband Trout Reserve The term “Redband Trout Reserve” means the Donner und Blitzen Redband Trout Reserve designated by section 460nnn–72 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Science committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Science committee The term “science committee” means the committee of independent scientists appointed under section 460nnn–53 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Wilderness Area The term “Wilderness Area” means the Steens Mountain Wilderness Area designated by part B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>