<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460n–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460n–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460n–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460n_8"><akn:num>460n–8</akn:num><akn:heading>United States magistrate judge: appointment; functions; probation; fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460n–8. United States magistrate judge: appointment; functions; probation; fees
A United States magistrate judge shall be appointed for that portion of the Lake Mead National Recreation Area that is situated in Mohave County, Arizona. Such magistrate judge shall be appointed by the United States district court having jurisdiction thereover, and the magistrate judge shall serve as directed by such court, as well as pursuant to, and within the limits of, the authority of said court.
The functions of the magistrate judge shall include the trial and sentencing of persons charged with the commission of misdemeanors and infractions as defined in section 3581 of title 18. The exercise of additional functions by the magistrate judge shall be consistent with and be carried out in accordance with the authority, laws, and regulations, of general application to United States magistrate judges. The probation laws shall be applicable to persons tried by the magistrate judge and he shall have power to grant probation. The magistrate judge shall receive the fees, and none other, provided by law for like or similar services.
(Pub. L. 88–639, § 9, Oct. 8, 1964, 78 Stat. 1041; Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 222, Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2028; Pub. L. 100–702, title IV, § 404(c), Nov. 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 4651; Pub. L. 101–650, title III, § 321, Dec. 1, 1990, 104 Stat. 5117.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–702 struck out after second sentence of second par. “The provisions of title 18, section 3402, and the rules of procedure and practice prescribed by the Supreme Court pursuant thereto, shall apply to all cases handled by such magistrate.”
1984—Pub. L. 98–473, § 222(a), substituted “magistrate” for “commissioner” wherever appearing in first par.
Pub. L. 98–473, § 222(b), substituted provisions relating to trial and sentencing of persons charged with misdemeanors and infractions as defined in section 3581 of title 18, for provisions relating to trial and sentencing of persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>