<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_11"><akn:num>460nnn–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–11. Designation of Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area(a) DesignationThe Secretary shall designate the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area consisting of approximately 425,550 acres of Federal land located in Harney County, Oregon, in the vicinity of Steens Mountain, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Steens Mountain Boundary Map” and dated September 18, 2000.


(b) Contents of mapIn addition to the general boundaries of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area, the map referred to in subsection (a) also depicts the general boundaries of the following:(1) The no livestock grazing area described in section 460nnn–23(e) of this title.

(2) The mineral withdrawal area designated by part D.

(3) The wildlands juniper management area established by part E.


(Pub. L. 106–399, title I, § 101, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1658.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation The Secretary shall designate the Steens Mountain Cooperative Management and Protection Area consisting of approximately 425,550 acres of Federal land located in Harney County, Oregon, in the vicinity of Steens Mountain, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Steens Mountain Boundary Map” and dated September 18, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of map In addition to the general boundaries of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area, the map referred to in subsection (a) also depicts the general boundaries of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>