<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460nnn–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460nnn_12"><akn:num>460nnn–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and objectives of Cooperative Management and Protection Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460nnn–12. Purpose and objectives of Cooperative Management and Protection Area(a) PurposeThe purpose of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is to conserve, protect, and manage the long-term ecological integrity of Steens Mountain for future and present generations.


(b) ObjectivesTo further the purpose specified in subsection (a), and consistent with such purpose, the Secretary shall manage the Cooperative Management and Protection Area for the benefit of present and future generations—(1) to maintain and enhance cooperative and innovative management projects, programs and agreements between tribal, public, and private interests in the Cooperative Management and Protection Area;

(2) to promote grazing, recreation, historic, and other uses that are sustainable;

(3) to conserve, protect and to ensure traditional access to cultural, gathering, religious, and archaeological sites by the Burns Paiute Tribe on Federal lands and to promote cooperation with private landowners;

(4) to ensure the conservation, protection, and improved management of the ecological, social, and economic environment of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area, including geological, biological, wildlife, riparian, and scenic resources; and

(5) to promote and foster cooperation, communication, and understanding and to reduce conflict between Steens Mountain users and interests.


(Pub. L. 106–399, title I, § 102, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1658.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of the Cooperative Management and Protection Area is to conserve, protect, and manage the long-term ecological integrity of Steens Mountain for future and present generations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460nnn_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Objectives To further the purpose specified in subsection (a), and consistent with such purpose, the Secretary shall manage the Cooperative Management and Protection Area for the benefit of present and future generations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>