<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460oo" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460oo/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460oo/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460oo"><akn:num>460oo</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460oo. Establishment(a) In generalIn order to conserve, protect, and manage, in a substantially undeveloped condition, certain National Forest System lands in the State of Oregon having unique geographic, topographic, biological, ecological features and possessing significant scenic, wildlife, dispersed recreation, and watershed values, there is hereby established, within the Umpqua, Willamette, Winema and Deschutes National Forests, the Oregon Cascades Recreation Area (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “recreation area”).


(b) AdministrationThe recreation area shall comprise approximately one hundred fifty-six thousand nine hundred acres as generally depicted on a map entitled “Oregon Cascades Recreation Area” dated March 1984. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer and manage the recreation area in accordance with the laws and regulations applicable to the National Forest System so as to enhance scenic and watershed values, wildlife habitat, and dispersed recreation.


(c) Management planThe recreation area shall be managed in accordance with plans prepared in subsection (g) to:(1) provide a range of recreation opportunities from primitive to full service developed campgrounds;

(2) provide access for use by the public;

(3) to the extent practicable, maintain the natural and scenic character of the area; and

(4) provide for the use of motorized recreation vehicles.


(d) Mining(1) Subject to valid existing rights, all mining claims located within the recreation area shall be subject to such reasonable regulations as the Secretary may prescribe to insure that mining activities will, to the maximum extent practicable, be consistent with the purposes for which the recreation area is established. Any patent issued after June 26, 1984, shall convey title only to the minerals together with the right to use the surface of lands for mining purposes subjec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to conserve, protect, and manage, in a substantially undeveloped condition, certain National Forest System lands in the State of Oregon having unique geographic, topographic, biological, ecological features and possessing significant scenic, wildlife, dispersed recreation, and watershed values, there is hereby established, within the Umpqua, Willamette, Winema and Deschutes National Forests, the Oregon Cascades Recreation Area (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “recreation area”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration The recreation area shall comprise approximately one hundred fifty-six thousand nine hundred acres as generally depicted on a map entitled “Oregon Cascades Recreation Area” dated March 1984. Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall administer and manage the recreation area in accordance with the laws and regulations applicable to the National Forest System so as to enhance scenic and watershed values, wildlife habitat, and dispersed recreation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management plan The recreation area shall be managed in accordance with plans prepared in subsection (g) to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mining</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mining</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of limited activities and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allowance of limited activities and facilities Within the recreation area, the Secretary may permit, under appropriate regulations those limited activities and facilities which he determines necessary for resource protection and management and for visitor safety and comfort, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wilderness lands The following lands within the recreation area are hereby designated as wilderness and therefore as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and shall, notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, be administered by the Secretary in accordance with the applicable provisions of the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.]: Certain lands in the Umpqua, Willamette, and Winema National Forests which comprise approximately fifty-five thousand one hundred acres, are generally depicted on a map dated March 1984, entitled “Mount Thielsen Wilderness—Proposed”, and which shall be known as the Mount Thielsen Wilderness; and certain lands in the Willamette and Deschutes National Forests, which comprise approximately fifteen thousand seven hundred acres, are generally depicted on a map dated March 1984, entitled “Diamond Peak Wilderness Additions—Proposed”, and which are hereby incorporated in, and which shall be deemed to be a part of, the Diamond Pea</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460oo_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest plans; integrated management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Forest plans; integrated management plans Management direction for the recreation area shall be developed in either the forest plans developed for the Umpqua, Winema, Deschutes and Willamette Forests in accordance with section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974, as amended [16 U.S.C. 1604], or in an integrated management plan that shall be prepared within three years from June 26, 1984, and revised in accordance with the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974, as amended [16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.]. Any plan developed by the Secretary for the recreation area shall identify and designate specific and appropriate areas and routes for the use of motorized recreation vehicles within the recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>