<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ppp–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ppp–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ppp–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ppp_6"><akn:num>460ppp–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ppp–6. Wilderness(a) DesignationIn furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act of 1964 (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.), the following lands in the State of Nevada are designated as wilderness, and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:(1) Certain lands in the Black Rock Desert Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 315,700 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Black Rock Desert Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the Black Rock Desert Wilderness.

(2) Certain lands in the Pahute Peak Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 57,400 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Pahute Peak Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the Pahute Peak Wilderness.

(3) Certain lands in the North Black Rock Range Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 30,800 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “North Black Rock Range Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the North Black Rock Range Wilderness.

(4) Certain lands in the East Fork High Rock Canyon Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 52,800 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “East Fork High Rock Canyon Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the East Fork High Rock Canyon Wilderness.

(5) Certain lands in the High Rock Lake Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 59,300 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “High Rock Lake Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the High Rock Lake Wilderness.

(6) Certain lands in the Little High Rock Canyon Wilderness Study Area comprised of approximately 48,700 acres, as generally depicted on a map entitled “Little High Rock Canyon Wilderness—Proposed” and dated October 3, 2001, and which shall be known as the Little High Rock Canyon Wilderness.

(7) Certain lands in the High Rock C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act of 1964 (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.), the following lands in the State of Nevada are designated as wilderness, and, therefore, as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of wilderness areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration of wilderness areas Subject to valid existing rights, each wilderness area designated by this subchapter shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.], except that any reference in such provisions to the effective date of the Wilderness Act shall be deemed to be a reference to December 21, 2000, and any reference to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be deemed to be a reference to the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps and legal description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maps and legal description As soon as practicable after December 21, 2000, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a map and legal description of the wilderness areas designated under this subchapter. The map and legal description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subchapter, except the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in such map and legal description. Copies of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grazing Within the wilderness areas designated under subsection (a), the grazing of livestock, where established prior to December 21, 2000, shall be permitted to continue subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary deems necessary, as long as such regulations, policies, and practices fully conform with and implement the intent of Congress regarding grazing in such areas as such intent is expressed in the Wilderness Act and section 101(f) of Public Law 101–628.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, trapping, and fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hunting, trapping, and fishing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wildland fire protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wildland fire protection Nothing in this subchapter or the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.) precludes a Federal, State, or local agency from conducting wildland fire management operations (including prescribed burns) within the areas designated as wilderness under subsection (a), subject to any conditions that the Secretary considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ppp_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness study release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Wilderness study release Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>