<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460qqq_4"><akn:num>460qqq–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of Federal parcel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460qqq–4. Sale of Federal parcel(a) In generalNotwithstanding sections 1712 and 1713 of title 43 and subject to valid existing rights, not later than 1 year after November 6, 2002, the Secretary shall convey to the highest qualified bidder all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal parcel.


(b) Disposition of proceedsOf the gross proceeds from the conveyance of land under subsection (a)—(1) 5 percent shall be available to the State for use in the general education program of the State; and

(2) the remainder shall be deposited in the special account established under the Southern Nevada Public Lands Management Act of 1998 (Public Law 105–263; 112 Stat. 2345), to be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation for—(A) the construction and operation of facilities to support the management of the Conservation Area;

(B) the construction and repair of trails and roads in the Conservation Area authorized under the management plan;

(C) research on and interpretation of the archaeological and geological resources of the Conservation Area;

(D) conservation and research relating to the Conservation Area; and

(E) any other purpose that the Secretary determines to be consistent with the purpose described in section 460qqq of this title.



(Pub. L. 107–282, title VI, § 606, Nov. 6, 2002, 116 Stat. 2012.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Southern Nevada Public Lands Management Act of 1998, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), probably means the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998, Pub. L. 105–263, Oct. 19, 1998, 112 Stat. 2343, which amended section 460ccc–1 of this title and section 6901 of Title 31, Money and Finance, and enacted provisions set out as a note under section 6901 of Title 31. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1998 Amendment note set out under section 6901 of Title 31 and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding sections 1712 and 1713 of title 43 and subject to valid existing rights, not later than 1 year after November 6, 2002, the Secretary shall convey to the highest qualified bidder all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal parcel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition of proceeds Of the gross proceeds from the conveyance of land under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>