<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460qqq–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460qqq_3"><akn:num>460qqq–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460qqq–3. Management(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall manage the Conservation Area—(1) in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the Conservation Area; and

(2) in accordance with—(A) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); and

(B) other applicable law, including this Act.



(b) Management plan(1) In generalNot later than 3 years after November 6, 2002, the Secretary, in consultation with the State, the city of Henderson, the County, and any other interested persons, shall develop a management plan for the Conservation Area.


(2) RequirementsThe management plan shall—(A) describe the appropriate uses and management of the Conservation Area;

(B)(i) authorize the use of motorized vehicles in the Conservation Area—(I) for installing, repairing, maintaining, and reconstructing water development projects, including guzzlers, that would enhance the Conservation Area by promoting healthy, viable, and more naturally distributed wildlife populations; and

(II) subject to any limitations that are not more restrictive than the limitations on such uses authorized in wilderness areas under section 208; 11 See References in Text note below. and


(ii) include or provide recommendations on ways of minimizing the visual impacts of such activities on the Conservation Area;


(C) include a plan for litter cleanup and public lands awareness campaign on public lands in and around the Conservation Area; and

(D) include a recommendation on the location for a right-of-way for a rural roadway to provide the city of Henderson with access to the Conservation Area, in accordance with the application numbered N–65874.



(c) UsesThe Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Conservation Area that the Secretary determines will further the purpose described in section 460qqq of this title.


(d) Motorized vehiclesExcept as needed for administrative purposes or to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall manage the Conservation Area—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uses The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Conservation Area that the Secretary determines will further the purpose described in section 460qqq of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motorized vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Motorized vehicles Except as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized vehicles in the Conservation Area shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for the use of motorized vehicles by the management plan developed under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460qqq_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No buffer zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No buffer zones</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>