<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460rr–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460rr–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460rr–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460rr_2"><akn:num>460rr–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460rr–2. Administration(a) ObjectivesSubject to valid existing rights, the Pine Ridge National Recreation Area designated by this subchapter shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the national forests in a manner compatible with the following objectives:(1) the continuation of existing primitive and semiprimitive recreational use in a natural environment;

(2) preservation and protection of forest, aquatic and grassland habitat;

(3) protection and conservation of special areas having uncommon or outstanding wilderness, biological, geological, recreational, cultural, historical or archeological, and scientific, or other values contributing to the public benefit;

(4) the continuation of existing livestock grazing uses;

(5) the control of noxious weeds and insects and prevention of their spreading onto the nearby private and Federal lands; and

(6) the control of fires and prevention of their spreading onto nearby private and Federal lands.


(b) Fire control; Memorandum of AgreementThe Secretary shall enter into a Memorandum of Agreement with local and State firefighting agencies and individuals to assure the best utilization of the firefighting resources available in the nearby communities for control of fire in the national recreation area.


(c) Hunting, fishing, and trappingThe Secretary shall permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on lands and waters under the Secretary’s jurisdiction within the boundaries of the national recreation area designated by this subchapter in accordance with applicable laws of the United States and the State of Nebraska.


(d) Mining and mineral leasing lawsSubject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands within the national recreation area are hereby withdrawn from location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws, and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing and all amendments thereto.


(e) State </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Objectives Subject to valid existing rights, the Pine Ridge National Recreation Area designated by this subchapter shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in accordance with the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the national forests in a manner compatible with the following objectives:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire control; Memorandum of Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fire control; Memorandum of Agreement The Secretary shall enter into a Memorandum of Agreement with local and State firefighting agencies and individuals to assure the best utilization of the firefighting resources available in the nearby communities for control of fire in the national recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting, fishing, and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hunting, fishing, and trapping The Secretary shall permit hunting, fishing, and trapping on lands and waters under the Secretary’s jurisdiction within the boundaries of the national recreation area designated by this subchapter in accordance with applicable laws of the United States and the State of Nebraska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mining and mineral leasing laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mining and mineral leasing laws Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands within the national recreation area are hereby withdrawn from location, entry, and patent under the United States mining laws, and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing and all amendments thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State responsibilities with respect to wildlife and fish unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State responsibilities with respect to wildlife and fish unaffected Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State of Nebraska with respect to wildlife and fish in the national recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Comprehensive management plan Within eighteen months after October 20, 1986, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs and the Committee on Agriculture of the United States House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate a comprehensive management plan for the national recreation area designated by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460rr_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation in development of management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public participation in development of management plan In conducting the reviews and preparing the comprehensive management plan required by subsection (d),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (f),”. the Secretary shall provide for full public participation, and shall consider the views of all interested agencies, organizations, and individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>