<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ss–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ss–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ss–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ss_3"><akn:num>460ss–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Klamath River Basin Fisheries Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ss–3. Klamath River Basin Fisheries Task Force(a) EstablishmentThere is established a Klamath River Basin Fisheries Task Force (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Task Force”).


(b) FunctionsThe Task Force—(1) shall assist the Secretary in the formulation, coordination, and implementation of the program;

(2) shall assist, and coordinate its activities with, Federal, State, and local governmental or private anadromous fish restoration projects within the Area;

(3) shall conduct any other activity that is necessary to accomplish the objectives of the program; and

(4) may act as an advisor to the Council.


(c) Membership and appointmentThe Task Force is composed of 14 members as follows:(1) A representative, who shall be appointed by the Governor of California, of each of the following:(A) The commercial salmon fishing industry.

(B) The in-river sport fishing community.

(C) The California Department of Fish and Game.


(2) A representative of the Hoopa Indian Tribe who shall be appointed by the Hoopa Valley Business Council.

(3) A representative of the Department of the Interior who shall be appointed by the Secretary.

(4) A representative of the National Marine Fisheries Service who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce.

(5) A representative of the Department of Agriculture who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Agriculture.

(6) A representative of the Oregon Department of Fish and Wildlife who shall be appointed by the Governor of Oregon.

(7) One individual who shall be appointed by the Board of Supervisors of Del Norte County, California.

(8) One individual who shall be appointed by the Board of Supervisors of Siskiyou County, California.

(9) One individual who shall be appointed by the Board of Supervisors of Humboldt County, California.

(10) One individual who shall be appointed by the Board of Supervisors of Trinity County, California.

(11) A representative of the Karuk Tribe, who shall be appointed by the governin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a Klamath River Basin Fisheries Task Force (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Task Force”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Task Force—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership and appointment The Task Force is composed of 14 members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council membership not a bar to Task Force appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Council membership not a bar to Task Force appointment An individual who is a member of the Council is not ineligible for appointment as a member of the Task Force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transaction of business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transaction of business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff and administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Staff and administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members who are Federal or State employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Members who are Federal or State employees Any Task Force member who is an officer or employee of the United States, the State of California, or the State of Oregon at the time of appointment to the Task Force shall cease to be a member of the Task Force within 14 days of the date on which he ceases to be so employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ss_3_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership increase upon program expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Membership increase upon program expansion At such time as the program is expanded to include portions of the Klamath River upstream from the Iron Gate dam, membership on the Task Force shall be increased to include the following—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>