<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460sss" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460sss/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460sss/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460sss"><akn:num>460sss</akn:num><akn:heading>Cow Mountain Recreation Area, Lake and Mendocino Counties, California</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460sss. Cow Mountain Recreation Area, Lake and Mendocino Counties, California(a) EstablishmentIn order to enhance the recreational and scenic values of the Cow Mountain area in Lake and Mendocino Counties, California, while conserving the wildlife and other natural resource values of the area, there is hereby established the Cow Mountain Recreation Area (in this section referred to as the “recreation area”) consisting of approximately 51,513 acres of land in such counties, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Cow Mountain Recreation Area” and dated July 22, 2006, including the following:(1) The “South Cow Mountain OHV Management Area”, as generally depicted on the map.

(2) The “North Cow Mountain Recreation Area”, as generally depicted on the map.


(b) Legal descriptions; correction of errors(1) Preparation and submissionAs soon as practicable after October 17, 2006, the Secretary of the Interior shall prepare a map and legal descriptions of the boundaries of the recreation area. The Secretary shall submit the map and legal descriptions to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.


(2) Legal effectThe map and legal descriptions of the recreation area shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal descriptions. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.



(c) Administration(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Interior shall administer the recreation area in accordance with this section and the laws and regulations generally applicable to the public lands, including the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.).


(2) Existing rightsThe establishment of the recreation area shall be subject to all valid existing rights.



(d) Recreational activities(1) In general</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to enhance the recreational and scenic values of the Cow Mountain area in Lake and Mendocino Counties, California, while conserving the wildlife and other natural resource values of the area, there is hereby established the Cow Mountain Recreation Area (in this section referred to as the “recreation area”) consisting of approximately 51,513 acres of land in such counties, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Cow Mountain Recreation Area” and dated July 22, 2006, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal descriptions; correction of errors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Legal descriptions; correction of errors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreational activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recreational activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to private property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Access to private property The Secretary of the Interior shall provide any owner of private property within the boundaries of the recreation area adequate access to the property to ensure the reasonable use and enjoyment of the property by the owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Land acquisition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460sss_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjacent management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjacent management Nothing in this section creates protective perimeters or buffer zones around the recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>