<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460s–15" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460s–15/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460s–15/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460s_15"><akn:num>460s–15</akn:num><akn:heading>Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore boundary revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460s–15. Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore boundary revision(a) TransferAs soon as practicable after November 25, 2002, the Administrator of General Services may transfer to the Secretary, without consideration, administrative jurisdiction over, and management of, the public land.


(b) Boundary revisionThe boundary of the Lakeshore is revised to include the public land transferred under subsection (a).


(c) Availability of mapThe map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.


(d) AdministrationThe Secretary may administer the public land transferred under section 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a)—(1) as part of the Lakeshore; and

(2) in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).


(e) Access to aids to navigationThe Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary, may access the front and rear range lights on the public land for the purposes of servicing, operating, maintaining, and repairing those lights.


(f) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) LakeshoreThe term “Lakeshore” means the Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore in the State of Michigan.


(2) MapThe term “map” means the map entitled “Proposed Addition to Pictured Rocks National Lakeshore”, numbered 625/80048, and dated April 2002.


(3) Public landThe term “public land” means the approximately .32 acres of United States Coast Guard land and improvements to the land, including the United States Coast Guard Auxiliary Operations Station and the front and rear range lights, as depicted on the map.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.



(g) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $225,000 to restore, preserve, and maintain the public land transferred under subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 437, Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2129.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Omnibu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer As soon as practicable after November 25, 2002, the Administrator of General Services may transfer to the Secretary, without consideration, administrative jurisdiction over, and management of, the public land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boundary revision The boundary of the Lakeshore is revised to include the public land transferred under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of map The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration The Secretary may administer the public land transferred under section 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to aids to navigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Access to aids to navigation The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary, may access the front and rear range lights on the public land for the purposes of servicing, operating, maintaining, and repairing those lights.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460s_15_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $225,000 to restore, preserve, and maintain the public land transferred under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>