<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460tt" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460tt/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460tt/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460tt"><akn:num>460tt</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross Florida Barge Canal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460tt. Cross Florida Barge Canal(a) DeauthorizationThe barge canal project located between the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “project”), as described in the Act of July 23, 1942 (56 Stat. 703), shall be deauthorized by operation of law immediately upon the Governor and Cabinet of the State of Florida adopting a resolution specifically agreeing on behalf of the State of Florida (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “State”) to all of the terms of the agreement prescribed in subsection (b).


(b) Transfer of project landsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is, subject to the provisions of subsections (d) and (e), directed to transfer to the State all lands and interests in lands acquired by the Secretary and facilities completed for the project in subsection (a), without consideration, if the State agrees to each of the following:(1) The State shall agree to hold the United States harmless from all claims arising from or through the operations of the lands and facilities conveyed by the United States.

(2) The State shall agree to preserve and maintain a greenway corridor which shall be open to the public for compatible recreation and conservation activities and which shall be continuous, except for areas referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (C) of this paragraph, along the project route over lands acquired by the Secretary or by the State or State Canal Authority, or lands acquired along the project route in the future by the State or State Canal Authority, to the maximum width possible, as determined in the management plan to be developed by the State for former project lands. Such greenway corridor shall not be less than 300 yards wide, except for the following areas:(A) Any area of the project corridor where, as of November 28, 1990, no land is owned by the State or State Canal Authority.

(B) Any area of the project corridor where, as of November 28, 1990, the land owned by </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deauthorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deauthorization The barge canal project located between the Gulf of Mexico and the Atlantic Ocean (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “project”), as described in the Act of July 23, 1942 (56 Stat. 703), shall be deauthorized by operation of law immediately upon the Governor and Cabinet of the State of Florida adopting a resolution specifically agreeing on behalf of the State of Florida (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “State”) to all of the terms of the agreement prescribed in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of project lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of project lands Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is, subject to the provisions of subsections (d) and (e), directed to transfer to the State all lands and interests in lands acquired by the Secretary and facilities completed for the project in subsection (a), without consideration, if the State agrees to each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time of transfer Actual transfer of lands and management responsibilities under this section shall not occur on the constructed portions of the project lying between the Atlantic Ocean and the Eureka Lock and Dam, inclusive, and between the Gulf of Mexico and the Inglis Lock and Dam, inclusive, until the last day of the 24-month period beginning on November 28, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management pending transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Management pending transfer In the 24-month period following November 28, 1990, the Secretary shall carry out any and all programmed maintenance on the portions of the project outlined in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract for continued O&amp;M</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contract for continued O&amp;M</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460tt_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Survey The exact acreage and legal description of the real property to be transferred pursuant to this section shall be determined by a survey which is satisfactory to the Secretary and to the State. The cost of such survey shall be borne by the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>