<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–20" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–20/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–20/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460u_20"><akn:num>460u–20</akn:num><akn:heading>Paul H. Douglas Ecological and Recreational Unit and Center for Environmental Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460u–20. Paul H. Douglas Ecological and Recreational Unit and Center for Environmental Education(a) Dedication of ParkThe Indiana Dunes National Park is hereby dedicated to the memory of Paul H. Douglas in grateful recognition of his leadership in the effort to protect, preserve, and enhance the natural, scientific, historic, and recreational value of the Park for the use, enjoyment, and edification of present and future generations.


(b) EstablishmentTo further accomplish the purposes of subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall designate the west unit of the Park as the “Paul H. Douglas Ecological and Recreational Unit” and shall, subject to appropriations being granted, design and construct a suitable structure or designate an existing structure within the Park to be known as the “Paul H. Douglas Center for Environmental Education” which shall provide facilities designed primarily to familiarize students and other visitors with, among other things: (1) the natural history of the Park and its association with the natural history of the Great Lakes region; (2) the evolution of human activities in the area; and (3) the historical features which led to the establishment of the Park by the Congress of the United States.


(c) Preparation of informative materialsTo inform the public of the contributions of Paul H. Douglas to the creation of the Park, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide such signs, markers, maps, interpretive materials, literature, and programs as he deems appropriate.


(Pub. L. 89–761, § 20, as added Pub. L. 96–612, § 1(1), Dec. 28, 1980, 94 Stat. 3575; amended Pub. L. 116–6, div. E, title I, § 115(a)(1), Feb. 15, 2019, 133 Stat. 232.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2019—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–6 substituted “National Park” for “National Lakeshore” and “Park” for “lakeshore”.
Subsecs. (b), (c). Pub. L. 116–6, § 115(a)(1)(B), substituted “Park” for “lakeshore” wherever appearing.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_20_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dedication of Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Dedication of Park The Indiana Dunes National Park is hereby dedicated to the memory of Paul H. Douglas in grateful recognition of his leadership in the effort to protect, preserve, and enhance the natural, scientific, historic, and recreational value of the Park for the use, enjoyment, and edification of present and future generations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_20_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment To further accomplish the purposes of subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall designate the west unit of the Park as the “Paul H. Douglas Ecological and Recreational Unit” and shall, subject to appropriations being granted, design and construct a suitable structure or designate an existing structure within the Park to be known as the “Paul H. Douglas Center for Environmental Education” which shall provide facilities designed primarily to familiarize students and other visitors with, among other things: (1) the natural history of the Park and its association with the natural history of the Great Lakes region; (2) the evolution of human activities in the area; and (3) the historical features which led to the establishment of the Park by the Congress of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_20_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of informative materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preparation of informative materials To inform the public of the contributions of Paul H. Douglas to the creation of the Park, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide such signs, markers, maps, interpretive materials, literature, and programs as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>