<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460u_7"><akn:num>460u–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Indiana Dunes National Park Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460u–7. Indiana Dunes National Park Advisory Commission(a) Establishment; terminationThere is hereby established an Indiana Dunes National Park Advisory Commission. Said Commission shall terminate on September 30, 1985.


(b) Membership; appointment; term of office; recommendation or designation of appointeesThe Commission shall be composed of thirteen members, each appointed for a term of two years by the Secretary, as follows: (1) one member who is a year-round resident of Porter County to be appointed from recommendations made by the commissioners of such county; (2) one member who is a year-round resident of the town of Beverly Shores to be appointed from the recommendations made by the board of trustees of such town; (3) one member who is a year-round resident of the towns of Porter, Dune Acres, Pines, Chesterton, Ogden Dunes, or the village of Tremont, such member to be appointed from recommendations made by the boards of trustees or the trustee of the affected town or township; (4) two members who are year-round residents of the city of Michigan City to be appointed from recommendations made by such city; (5) two members to be appointed from recommendations made by the Governor of the State of Indiana; (6) one member to be designated by the Secretary; (7) two members who are year-round residents of the city of Gary to be appointed from recommendations made by the mayor of such city; (8) one member to be appointed from recommendations made by a regional planning agency established under the authority of the laws of the State of Indiana and composed of representatives of local and county governments in northwestern Indiana; (9) one member who is a year-round resident of the city of Portage to be appointed from recommendations made by the mayor of such city; and (10) one member who holds a reservation of use and occupancy and is a year-round resident within the Park to be designated by the Secretary.


(c) Chairman; vacanciesThe Secretary shall designate one m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; termination There is hereby established an Indiana Dunes National Park Advisory Commission. Said Commission shall terminate on September 30, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; appointment; term of office; recommendation or designation of appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; appointment; term of office; recommendation or designation of appointees The Commission shall be composed of thirteen members, each appointed for a term of two years by the Secretary, as follows: (1) one member who is a year-round resident of Porter County to be appointed from recommendations made by the commissioners of such county; (2) one member who is a year-round resident of the town of Beverly Shores to be appointed from the recommendations made by the board of trustees of such town; (3) one member who is a year-round resident of the towns of Porter, Dune Acres, Pines, Chesterton, Ogden Dunes, or the village of Tremont, such member to be appointed from recommendations made by the boards of trustees or the trustee of the affected town or township; (4) two members who are year-round residents of the city of Michigan City to be appointed from recommendations made by such city; (5) two members to be appointed from recommendations made by the Governor of the State of I</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairman; vacancies The Secretary shall designate one member to be Chairman. Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses; vouchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses; vouchers A member of the Commission shall serve without compensation as such. The Secretary is authorized to pay the expense reasonably incurred by the Commission in carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter on vouchers signed by the Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation of Secretary with Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation of Secretary with Commission The Secretary or his designee shall, from time to time, consult with the Commission with respect to matters relating to the development of the Indiana Dunes National Park and with respect to the provisions of sections 460u–3, 460u–4,11 See References in Text note below. and 460u–5 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposal of industrial solid wastes; identification of acceptable areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disposal of industrial solid wastes; identification of acceptable areas The Advisory Commission is authorized to assist with the identification of economically and environmentally acceptable areas, outside of the boundaries of the Park, for the handling and disposal of industrial solid wastes produced by the coal-fired powerplant in Porter County, Indiana, section 21, township 37 north, range 6 west.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>