<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460uu_22"><akn:num>460uu–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460uu–22. Management(a) Provisions applicableThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall manage the conservation area to protect the resources specified in section 460uu–21 of this title and in accordance with this subchapter, the Federal Land Management and Policy 11 So in original. See References in Text note below. Act of 1976 [43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.] and other applicable provisions of law, including those provisions relating to grazing on public lands.


(b) Hunting and trappingThe Secretary shall permit hunting and trapping within the conservation area in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the United States and the State of New Mexico; except that the Secretary, after consultation with the New Mexico Department of Game and Fish, may issue regulations designating zones where and establishing periods when no hunting or trapping shall be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment.


(c) Prohibition of collection of green or dead wood for commercial purposesCollection of green or dead wood for sale or other commercial purposes shall not be permitted in the conservation area.


(d) GrazingExcept as otherwise provided in section 460uu–32(b) of this title, within the conservation area the grazing of livestock shall be permitted to continue, pursuant to applicable Federal law, including this subchapter, and subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary deems necessary.


(Pub. L. 100–225, title III, § 302, Dec. 31, 1987, 101 Stat. 1541.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Land Management and Policy Act of 1976, referred to in subsec. (a), probably means the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, Pub. L. 94–579, Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2743, which is classified principally to chapter 35 (§ 1701 et seq.) of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provisions applicable The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, shall manage the conservation area to protect the resources specified in section 460uu–21 of this title and in accordance with this subchapter, the Federal Land Management and Policy 11 So in original. See References in Text note below. Act of 1976 [43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.] and other applicable provisions of law, including those provisions relating to grazing on public lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting and trapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hunting and trapping The Secretary shall permit hunting and trapping within the conservation area in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the United States and the State of New Mexico; except that the Secretary, after consultation with the New Mexico Department of Game and Fish, may issue regulations designating zones where and establishing periods when no hunting or trapping shall be permitted for reasons of public safety, administration, or public use and enjoyment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_22_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of collection of green or dead wood for commercial purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition of collection of green or dead wood for commercial purposes Collection of green or dead wood for sale or other commercial purposes shall not be permitted in the conservation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_22_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grazing Except as otherwise provided in section 460uu–32(b) of this title, within the conservation area the grazing of livestock shall be permitted to continue, pursuant to applicable Federal law, including this subchapter, and subject to such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>