<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–46" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–46/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460uu–46/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460uu_46"><akn:num>460uu–46</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges and acquisitions generally; withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460uu–46. Exchanges and acquisitions generally; withdrawal(a) Exchanges on basis of equal value; cash equalization; exceptionsAll exchanges pursuant to this subchapter shall be made in a manner consistent with applicable provisions of law, including this subchapter, and unless otherwise specified in this subchapter shall be on the basis of equal value; either party to an exchange may pay or accept cash in order to equalize the value of the property exchange, except that if the parties agree to an exchange and the Secretary determines it is in the public interest, such exchange may be made for other than equal value.


(b) “Public lands” definedFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “public lands” shall have the same meaning as such term has when used in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 [43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.].


(c) Incorporation and management of after-acquired landsExcept as otherwise provided in section 460uu–45 of this title, any lands or interests therein within the boundaries of the monument or conservation area which after December 31, 1987, may be acquired by the United States shall be incorporated into the monument or conservation area, as the case may be, and managed accordingly, and all provisions of this subchapter and other laws applicable to the monument or the conservation area, as the case may be, shall apply to such incorporated lands.


(d) Prohibition on transfer of lands out of Federal ownership; withdrawal of lands from all forms of entry(1) Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, no federally-owned lands located within the boundaries of the monument or the conservation area shall be transferred out of Federal ownership, or be placed in trust for any Indian tribe or group, by exchange or otherwise.

(2) Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, and subject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands within the monument and the conservation area and all lands and interests therein which are acquired on and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges on basis of equal value; cash equalization; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exchanges on basis of equal value; cash equalization; exceptions All exchanges pursuant to this subchapter shall be made in a manner consistent with applicable provisions of law, including this subchapter, and unless otherwise specified in this subchapter shall be on the basis of equal value; either party to an exchange may pay or accept cash in order to equalize the value of the property exchange, except that if the parties agree to an exchange and the Secretary determines it is in the public interest, such exchange may be made for other than equal value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Public lands” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Public lands” defined For purposes of this subchapter, the term “public lands” shall have the same meaning as such term has when used in the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 [43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation and management of after-acquired lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Incorporation and management of after-acquired lands Except as otherwise provided in section 460uu–45 of this title, any lands or interests therein within the boundaries of the monument or conservation area which after December 31, 1987, may be acquired by the United States shall be incorporated into the monument or conservation area, as the case may be, and managed accordingly, and all provisions of this subchapter and other laws applicable to the monument or the conservation area, as the case may be, shall apply to such incorporated lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on transfer of lands out of Federal ownership; withdrawal of lands from all forms of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on transfer of lands out of Federal ownership; withdrawal of lands from all forms of entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrepancies in citation of acreage; maps as controlling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discrepancies in citation of acreage; maps as controlling The acreages cited in this subchapter are approximate, and in the event of discrepancies between cited acreages and the lands depicted on referenced maps, the maps shall control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of lands proposed for donation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Acceptance of lands proposed for donation The Secretary is authorized to accept any lands contiguous to the boundaries of the Pecos National Monument (as such boundaries were established on December 31, 1987) which may be proposed for donation to the United States. If acceptance of such lands proposed for donation would be in furtherance of the purposes for which the Pecos National Monument was established, the Secretary shall accept such lands, and upon such acceptance such lands shall be incorporated into such monument and managed accordingly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460uu_46_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redesignation and revision of boundaries of Capulin Mountain National Monument</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Redesignation and revision of boundaries of Capulin Mountain National Monument</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>