<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460u–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460u_5"><akn:num>460u–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner’s retention of right of use and occupancy for residential purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460u–5. Owner’s retention of right of use and occupancy for residential purposes(a) Election; conveyance or lease of right; adjustment of compensation; retained rights(1) Except for owners described in paragraph (2) and owners of improved property within the area on the map referred to in section 460u–3 of this title, dated December 1980, and numbered 626–91014, as area II–B, any owner or owners of record of improved property may retain a right of use and occupancy of said improved property for noncommercial residential purposes for a term (A) ending on his or her death or the death of his or her spouse, whichever occurs last, or (B) for a fixed term not to extend beyond September 30, 2010, or such lesser term as the owner or owners may elect at the time of acquisition by the Secretary. In the case of improved property within the boundaries of the map dated December 1980 and numbered 626–91014 the retention of a retained right under clause numbered (A) shall only be available to homeowners of record as of October 1, 1980, who have attained the age of majority as of that date and make a bona fide written offer not later than October 1, 1985, to sell to the Secretary. Where any such owner retains a right of use and occupancy as herein provided, such right during its existence may be conveyed or leased for noncommercial residential purposes. The Secretary shall pay to the owner the fair market value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the fair market value on such date of the right retained by the owner.

(2)(A) In the case of property included within the boundaries of the Park after 1980, any owner or owners of record of improved property may retain a right of use and occupancy for noncommercial residential purposes for a term ending at either of the following:(i) A fixed term not to extend beyond September 30, 2010, or such lesser fixed term as the owner or owners may elect at the time of acquisition.

(ii) A term ending at the death of any owner </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election; conveyance or lease of right; adjustment of compensation; retained rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election; conveyance or lease of right; adjustment of compensation; retained rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of use and occupancy; pre-October 18, 1976, standards of use and occupancy to remain in effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of use and occupancy; pre- Upon his determination that the property, or any portion thereof, has ceased to be used in accordance with the applicable terms and conditions, the Secretary may terminate a right of use and occupancy. Nonpayment of property taxes, validly assessed, on any retained right of use and occupancy shall also be grounds for termination of such right by the Secretary. In the event the Secretary terminates a right of use and occupancy under this subsection he shall pay to the owners of the retained right so terminated an amount equal to the fair market value of the portion of said right which remained unexpired on the date of termination. With respect to any right of use and occupancy in existence on the effective date of this sentence, standards for retention of such rights in effect at the time such rights were reserved shall constitute the terms and conditions referred to in section 460u–3 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460u_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of use and occupancy rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extension of use and occupancy rights With respect to improved properties acquired prior to December 28, 1980, and upon which a valid existing right of use and occupancy has been reserved for a term of not more than twenty years, the Secretary may, in his discretion, extend the term of such retained right for a period of not more than nine years upon receipt of payment prior to September 30, 1983, from the holder of the retained right. The amount of such payment shall be equivalent to the amount discounted from the purchase price paid by the Secretary for the identical period of time under the terms of the original sale adjusted by a general index adopted by the Secretary reflecting overall value trends within Indiana Dunes National Park between the time of the original sale and the time of the retained right of extension offered by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>