<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460vv–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460vv–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460vv–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460vv_4"><akn:num>460vv–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilderness review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460vv–4. Wilderness review(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) the Department of Agriculture has completed the second roadless area review and evaluation program (RARE II); and

(2) the Congress has made its own review and examination of National Forest System roadless areas in Oklahoma and of the environmental impacts associated with alternative allocations of such areas.


(b) Congressional determination and directionOn the basis of such review, the Congress hereby determines and directs that—(1) without passing on the questions of the legal and factual sufficiency of the RARE II Final Environmental Impact Statement (dated January 1979) with respect to National Forest System lands in States other than Oklahoma, such statement shall not be subject to judicial review with respect to National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma;

(2) with respect to the National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma which were reviewed by the Department of Agriculture in the second roadless area review and evaluation (RARE II) and those lands referred to in subsection (d), that review and evaluation or reference shall be deemed for the purposes of the initial land management plans required for such lands by the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, to be an adequate consideration of the suitability of such lands for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System and the Department of Agriculture shall not be required to review the wilderness option prior to the revision of the plans, but shall review the wilderness option when the plans are revised, which revisions will ordinarily occur on a ten-year cycle, or at least every fifteen years, unless, prior to such time the Secretary of Agriculture finds that conditions in a unit have significantly changed;

(3) areas in the State of Oklahoma reviewed in such final environmental statement or reference</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460vv_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460vv_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional determination and direction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional determination and direction On the basis of such review, the Congress hereby determines and directs that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460vv_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of term As used in this section, and as provided in section 6 of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 [16 U.S.C. 1604], as amended by the National Forest Management Act of 1976, the term “revision” shall not include an “amendment” to a plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460vv_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application of provisions The provisions of this section shall also apply to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>