<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460w"><akn:num>460w</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460w. Establishment; boundaries
In order to conserve and develop for the benefit, inspiration, education, recreational use, and enjoyment of the public certain significant islands, shoreline, and light stations of the United States and their related geographic, scenic, historic, and scientific values, there is hereby established the Apostle Islands National Lakeshore (hereinafter referred to as the “lakeshore”) in Ashland and Bayfield Counties, Wisconsin, consisting of:(a) In generalThe area generally depicted on the map entitled “Apostle Islands National Lakeshore”, numbered NL–AI–91,000, sheets 1 and 2, and dated June 1970.


(b) Long Island additionApproximately 200 acres of land at the mouth of Chequamegon Bay known as “Long Island”, as depicted on the map numbered NL–AI–91,001 and dated December, 1985.


(c) Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light(1) The Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light generally depicted on the map titled “Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light Addition to Apostle Islands National Lakeshore” and dated February 11, 2014, located at the end of the breakwater on Chequamegon Bay, Wisconsin.

(2) Congress does not intend for the designation of the property under paragraph (1) to create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the boundary of that property.



The maps shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Director, National Park Service, Department of the Interior.
(Pub. L. 91–424, § 1, Sept. 26, 1970, 84 Stat. 880; Pub. L. 99–497, § 1(1), Oct. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 1267; Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3030(1), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3766.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Pub. L. 113–291, § 3030(1)(A), in introductory provisions, substituted “islands, shoreline, and light stations” for “islands and shoreline” and inserted “historic,” after “scenic,”.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 113–291, § 3030(1)(B), substituted “The area” for “the area” and period at end for “; and”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 113–291, § 3030(1)(C), substituted</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The area generally depicted on the map entitled “Apostle Islands National Lakeshore”, numbered NL–AI–91,000, sheets 1 and 2, and dated June 1970.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long Island addition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Long Island addition Approximately 200 acres of land at the mouth of Chequamegon Bay known as “Long Island”, as depicted on the map numbered NL–AI–91,001 and dated December, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>