<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ww–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ww–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460ww–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460ww_2"><akn:num>460ww–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460ww–2. Miscellaneous(a) Lands and watersThe Secretary may acquire lands or interests in lands within the boundaries of the recreation area by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange. When any tract of land is only partly within such boundaries, the Secretary may acquire all or any portion of the land outside of such boundaries in order to minimize the payment of severance costs.


(b) JurisdictionLands, waters and interests therein within the recreation area which are administered by any other agency of the United States and which are not identified under section 460ww–1 of this title as directly related to the Summersville project and essential to the operation of that project shall be transferred without reimbursement to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary.


(c) Protection of existing projectNothing in this Act shall impair or affect the requirements of section 1102 of Public Law 99–662 or otherwise affect the authorities of any department or agency of the United States to carry out the project purposes of the Summersville project, including recreation. In releasing water from such project, in order to protect public health and safety and to provide for enjoyment of the resources within the recreation area, other departments and agencies of the United States shall cooperate with the Secretary to facilitate and enhance whitewater recreational use and other recreational use of the recreation area.


(Pub. L. 100–534, title II, § 203, Oct. 26, 1988, 102 Stat. 2704.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is Pub. L. 100–534, Oct. 26, 1988, 102 Stat. 2699, known as the West Virginia National Interest River Conservation Act of 1987, which enacted this subchapter and sections 410eeee–12 to 410eeee–15 of this title, amended sections 410eeee–1 and 1274 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 410eeee–1 and 1274 of this title. For complete classification of this Act </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ww_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands and waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lands and waters The Secretary may acquire lands or interests in lands within the boundaries of the recreation area by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange. When any tract of land is only partly within such boundaries, the Secretary may acquire all or any portion of the land outside of such boundaries in order to minimize the payment of severance costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ww_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Jurisdiction Lands, waters and interests therein within the recreation area which are administered by any other agency of the United States and which are not identified under section 460ww–1 of this title as directly related to the Summersville project and essential to the operation of that project shall be transferred without reimbursement to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460ww_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of existing project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection of existing project Nothing in this Act shall impair or affect the requirements of section 1102 of Public Law 99–662 or otherwise affect the authorities of any department or agency of the United States to carry out the project purposes of the Summersville project, including recreation. In releasing water from such project, in order to protect public health and safety and to provide for enjoyment of the resources within the recreation area, other departments and agencies of the United States shall cooperate with the Secretary to facilitate and enhance whitewater recreational use and other recreational use of the recreation area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>