<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460w–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460w_5"><akn:num>460w–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration, protection, and development of lakeshore by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460w–5. Administration, protection, and development of lakeshore by Secretary(a) In generalThe lakeshore shall be administered, protected, and developed in accordance with this section and the provisions of the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4),11 See References in Text note below. as amended and supplemented; and section 101511 of title 54, except that any other statutory authority available to the Secretary for the conservation and management of natural resources may be utilized to the extent he finds such authority will further the purposes of this subchapter.


(b) Federal useNotwithstanding subsection (c) of section 460w of this title—(1) the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may operate, maintain, keep, locate, inspect, repair, and replace any Federal aid to navigation located at the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light for as long as such aid is needed for navigational purposes; and

(2) in carrying out the activities described in paragraph (1), such Secretary may enter, at any time, the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light or any Federal aid to navigation at the Ashland Harbor Breakwater Light, for as long as such aid is needed for navigational purposes, without notice to the extent that it is not possible to provide advance notice.


(c) Clarification of authorityPursuant to existing authorities, the Secretary may enter into agreements with the City of Ashland, County of Ashland, and County of Bayfield, Wisconsin, for the purpose of cooperative law enforcement and emergency services within the boundaries of the lakeshore.


(Pub. L. 91–424, § 6, Sept. 26, 1970, 84 Stat. 881; Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXX, § 3030(2), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3766.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4), referred to in subsec. (a), is act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, 39 Stat. 535, known as the National Park Service Organic Act, which enacted sections 1, 2, 3, and 4 of this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The lakeshore shall be administered, protected, and developed in accordance with this section and the provisions of the Act of August 25, 1916 (39 Stat. 535; 16 U.S.C. 1, 2–4),11 See References in Text note below. as amended and supplemented; and section 101511 of title 54, except that any other statutory authority available to the Secretary for the conservation and management of natural resources may be utilized to the extent he finds such authority will further the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal use Notwithstanding subsection (c) of section 460w of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460w_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Clarification of authority Pursuant to existing authorities, the Secretary may enter into agreements with the City of Ashland, County of Ashland, and County of Bayfield, Wisconsin, for the purpose of cooperative law enforcement and emergency services within the boundaries of the lakeshore.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>