<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460x_9"><akn:num>460x–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of retention of residential use in improved lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460x–9. Right of retention of residential use in improved lands(a) Limited term; conforming use; payment for right; sale or lease of rightAny owner or owners of improved property situated within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary may, as a condition of such acquisition, retain, for a term of not to exceed twenty-five years, or for a term ending at the death of such owner or owners, the right of use and occupancy of such property for any residential purpose which is not incompatible with the purposes of this subchapter, or which does not impair the usefulness and attractiveness of the area designated for inclusion. The Secretary shall pay to the owner the value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the value on such date of the right retained by the owner. Where any such owner retains a right of use and occupancy as herein provided, such right during its existence may be conveyed or leased for noncommercial residential purposes in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(b) Option to retain use of land; notice to Secretary; paymentAny person who is—(1) an owner of improved property described in section 460x–10(a)(2) of this title which is situated within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary; or

(2) an occupier of improved property described in section 460x–10(a)(2) of this title which is situated within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary, in situations where the fee ownership of such improved property has been heretofore acquired by the United States (whether by donation, purchase, condemnation, exchange or otherwise);


may retain, for a term not to exceed twenty-five years from January 1, 1973, or for a term ending on the death of such owner or occupier, the right of use or occupancy of such property for any residential purpose which is not incompati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited term; conforming use; payment for right; sale or lease of right</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limited term; conforming use; payment for right; sale or lease of right Any owner or owners of improved property situated within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore on the date of its acquisition by the Secretary may, as a condition of such acquisition, retain, for a term of not to exceed twenty-five years, or for a term ending at the death of such owner or owners, the right of use and occupancy of such property for any residential purpose which is not incompatible with the purposes of this subchapter, or which does not impair the usefulness and attractiveness of the area designated for inclusion. The Secretary shall pay to the owner the value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the value on such date of the right retained by the owner. Where any such owner retains a right of use and occupancy as herein provided, such right during its existence may be conveyed or leased for noncommercial residential purposes in accordance with the provisions of this</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Option to retain use of land; notice to Secretary; payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Option to retain use of land; notice to Secretary; payment Any person who is— may retain, for a term not to exceed twenty-five years from January 1, 1973, or for a term ending on the death of such owner or occupier, the right of use or occupancy of such property for any residential purpose which is not incompatible with the purposes of this subchapter or which does not impair the usefulness and attractiveness of the area designated for inclusion. Such owner or occupier must notify the Secretary of any intention to exercise such option within 60 days after receipt of the notice referred to in section 460x–10(c)(3) of this title. In situations where the United States has not heretofore acquired fee title to the improved property, the Secretary shall pay to the owner the value of the property on the date of such acquisition, less the value on such date of the right retained by the owner. In situations where the United States has heretofore acquired fee title to the improved property, </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use in instrument evidencing right; Secretary’s power of termination of right</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on use in instrument evidencing right; Secretary’s power of termination of right Any deed or other instrument used to transfer title to property, with respect to which a right of use and occupancy is retained under this section, and any instrument evidencing any right of use and occupancy retained by any occupier under this section, shall provide that such property shall not be used for any purpose which is incompatible with purposes of this subchapter, or which impairs the usefulness and attractiveness of such area, and if it should be so used, that the Secretary many 11 So in original. Probably should be “may”. terminate such right. In the event the Secretary exercises his power of termination under this subsection he shall pay to the owner of the right terminated an amount equal to the value of that portion of such right which remained unexpired on the date of such termination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of right to member of immediate family; owner option to terminate; payment by Secretary; “member of the immediate family” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of right to member of immediate family; owner option to terminate; payment by Secretary; “member of the immediate family” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>