<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460xxx" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460xxx/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460xxx/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460xxx"><akn:num>460xxx</akn:num><akn:heading>Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460xxx. Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Management planThe term “management plan” means the management plan for the National Conservation Area developed by the Secretary under subsection (d)(1).


(2) National Conservation AreaThe term “National Conservation Area” means the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area that—(A) consists of approximately 68,083 acres of public land in the County, as generally depicted on the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area Map; and

(B) is established by subsection (c).



(c) EstablishmentSubject to valid existing rights, there is established in the State the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area.


(d) Management plan(1) In generalNot later than 3 years after March 30, 2009, and in accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the National Conservation Area.


(2) ConsultationIn developing the management plan required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with—(A) appropriate State, tribal, and local governmental entities; and

(B) members of the public.


(3) Motorized vehiclesIn developing the management plan required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall incorporate the restrictions on motorized vehicles described in subsection (e)(3).



(e) Management(1) In generalThe Secretary shall manage the National Conservation Area—(A) in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the National Conservation Area; and

(B) in accordance with—(i) the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.);

(ii) this section; and

(iii) any other applicable law </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment Subject to valid existing rights, there is established in the State the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Incorporation of acquired land and interests Any land or interest in land that is located in the National Conservation Area that is acquired by the United States shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460xxx_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>