<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460x–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460x_8"><akn:num>460x–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Zoning bylaws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460x–8. Zoning bylaws(a) Authority of Secretary to assist any township or county in or adjacent to lakeshore; payments for technical aidThe Secretary shall, at the request of any township or county in or adjacent to the lakeshore affected by this subchapter, assist and consult with the appropriate officers and employees of such township or county in establishing zoning bylaws for the purpose of this subchapter. Such assistance may include payments to the county or township for technical aid.


(b) Suspension of condemnation power over improved propertyNo improved property within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore shall be acquired by the Secretary by condemnation so long as the affected county or township has in force and applicable thereto a duly adopted, valid zoning bylaw approved by the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section and the use of improved property is in compliance therewith. In the event that the affected county or township does not have in effect and applicable to any improved property a duly adopted, valid zoning bylaw so approved, the Secretary shall be prohibited from acquiring such property by condemnation, if the owner thereof notifies the Secretary in writing of such owner’s agreement to use his property in a manner consistent with the applicable standard set forth in subsection (d) of this section, and such prohibition against condemnation shall remain in effect for so long as such property is so used.


(c) Notification of owner by Secretary of use of property inconsistent with applicable bylaws or standards; requirements of notice; discontinuance of use by owner; condemnation upon failure to discontinue useIf the Secretary determines that any such property referred to in subsection (b) of this section covered by any such bylaw is being used in a way which is not in substantial compliance with such bylaw, or that any such property referred to in subsection (b) with respect to which an ag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary to assist any township or county in or adjacent to lakeshore; payments for technical aid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary to assist any township or county in or adjacent to lakeshore; payments for technical aid The Secretary shall, at the request of any township or county in or adjacent to the lakeshore affected by this subchapter, assist and consult with the appropriate officers and employees of such township or county in establishing zoning bylaws for the purpose of this subchapter. Such assistance may include payments to the county or township for technical aid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of condemnation power over improved property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Suspension of condemnation power over improved property No improved property within the area designated for inclusion in the lakeshore shall be acquired by the Secretary by condemnation so long as the affected county or township has in force and applicable thereto a duly adopted, valid zoning bylaw approved by the Secretary in accordance with the provisions of subsection (d) of this section and the use of improved property is in compliance therewith. In the event that the affected county or township does not have in effect and applicable to any improved property a duly adopted, valid zoning bylaw so approved, the Secretary shall be prohibited from acquiring such property by condemnation, if the owner thereof notifies the Secretary in writing of such owner’s agreement to use his property in a manner consistent with the applicable standard set forth in subsection (d) of this section, and such prohibition against condemnation shall remain in effect for so long as such property is so u</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of owner by Secretary of use of property inconsistent with applicable bylaws or standards; requirements of notice; discontinuance of use by owner; condemnation upon failure to discontinue use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of owner by Secretary of use of property inconsistent with applicable bylaws or standards; requirements of notice; discontinuance of use by owner; condemnation upon failure to discontinue use If the Secretary determines that any such property referred to in subsection (b) of this section covered by any such bylaw is being used in a way which is not in substantial compliance with such bylaw, or that any such property referred to in subsection (b) with respect to which an agreement has been made is being used in a manner which is not substantially consistent with such applicable standards, he shall so notify the owner of any such property in writing. Such notice shall contain a detailed statement as to why the Secretary believes that such use is not in substantial compliance with such zoning bylaw or why such use is not substantially consistent with such applicable standards, as the case may be. Any such owner shall have sixty days following the receipt by him of that wr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for approval by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions for approval by Secretary Any zoning bylaw or amendment thereto submitted to the Secretary for approval for the purposes of this subchapter shall be approved by him if such bylaw or amendment contains provisions which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460x_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal or revocation of approval by Secretary; retroactive effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal or revocation of approval by Secretary; retroactive effect The approval of any bylaw or amendment pursuant to subsection (d) shall not be withdrawn or revoked by the Secretary for so long as such bylaw or amendment remains in effect as approved. Any such bylaw or amendment so approved shall not be retroactive in its application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>