<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460y–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460y–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460y–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460y_1"><akn:num>460y–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460y–1. Management of lands(a) Utilization and development of resourcesIn the management of lands in the area, the Secretary shall utilize and develop the resources in such a manner as to satisfy all legitimate requirements for the available resources as fully as possible without undue denial of any of such requirements and without undue impairment of any of the resources, taking into consideration total requirement and total availability of resources, irrespective of ownership or location.


(b) Plan of land use, development, and managementThe policy set forth in subsection (a) implies—(1) that there will be a comprehensive, balanced, and coordinated plan of land use, development, and management of the Area, and that such plan will be based on an inventory and evaluation of the available resources and requirements for such resources, and on the topography and other features of the Area.

(2) that the plan will indicate the primary or dominant uses which will be permitted on various portions of the Area.

(3) that the plan will be based on a weighing of the relative values to be obtained by utilization and development of the resources for alternative possible uses, and will be made with the object of obtaining the greatest values on a continuing basis, and that due consideration will be given to intangible values as well as to tangible values such as dollar return or production per unit.

(4) that secondary or collateral uses may be permitted to the extent that such uses are compatible with and do not unduly impair the primary or dominant uses, according to a seasonal schedule or otherwise.

(5) that management of the renewable resources will be such as to obtain a sustained, regular, or periodic yield or supply of products or services without impairment of the productivity, or the enjoyment or carrying capacity of the land.

(6) that the plan will be reviewed and reevaluated periodically.

(7) that the resources to be considered are all the natural resources incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460y_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization and development of resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Utilization and development of resources In the management of lands in the area, the Secretary shall utilize and develop the resources in such a manner as to satisfy all legitimate requirements for the available resources as fully as possible without undue denial of any of such requirements and without undue impairment of any of the resources, taking into consideration total requirement and total availability of resources, irrespective of ownership or location.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460y_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan of land use, development, and management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plan of land use, development, and management The policy set forth in subsection (a) implies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>