<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460zzz–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460zzz–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/460zzz–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_460zzz_4"><akn:num>460zzz–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Conservation Area and Wilderness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 460zzz–4. Management of Conservation Area and Wilderness(a) WithdrawalSubject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness and all land and interests in land acquired by the United States within the Conservation Area or the Wilderness is withdrawn from—(1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;

(2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and

(3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.


(b) Grazing(1) Grazing in Conservation AreaExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall issue and administer any grazing leases or permits in the Conservation Area in accordance with the laws (including regulations) applicable to the issuance and administration of such leases and permits on other land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management.


(2) Grazing in WildernessThe grazing of livestock in the Wilderness, if established as of March 30, 2009, shall be permitted to continue—(A) subject to any reasonable regulations, policies, and practices that the Secretary determines to be necessary; and

(B) in accordance with—(i) section 1133(d)(4) of this title; and

(ii) the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of the report of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress (H. Rept. 101–405).




(c) No buffer zones(1) In generalNothing in this subchapter creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Conservation Area.


(2) Activities outside Conservation AreaThe fact that an activity or use on land outside the Conservation Area can be seen or heard within the Conservation Area shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the Conservation Area.



(d) Acquisition of land(1) In generalThe Secretary may acquire non-Federal land within the boundaries of the Conservation Area or the Wilderness only through exchange, donation, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Conservation Area and the Wilderness and all land and interests in land acquired by the United States within the Conservation Area or the Wilderness is withdrawn from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grazing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No buffer zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No buffer zones</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acquisition of land</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire, insects, and diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fire, insects, and diseases Subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be desirable and appropriate, the Secretary may undertake such measures as are necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Access The Secretary shall continue to provide private landowners adequate access to inholdings in the Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Invasive species and noxious weeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Invasive species and noxious weeds In accordance with any applicable laws and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be desirable and appropriate, the Secretary may prescribe measures to control nonnative invasive plants and noxious weeds within the Conservation Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Water rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect Nothing in this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_460zzz_4_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valid existing rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Valid existing rights The designation of the Conservation Area and Wilderness is subject to valid rights in existence on March 30, 2009.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>