<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470aaa–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470aaa–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470aaa–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_470aaa_3"><akn:num>470aaa–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of paleontological resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 470aaa–3. Collection of paleontological resources(a) Permit requirement(1) In generalExcept as provided in this chapter, a paleontological resource may not be collected from Federal land without a permit issued under this chapter by the Secretary.


(2) Casual collecting exceptionThe Secretary shall allow casual collecting without a permit on Federal land controlled or administered by the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Forest Service, where such collection is consistent with the laws governing the management of those Federal land 11 So in original. Probably should be “lands”. and this chapter.


(3) Previous permit exceptionNothing in this section shall affect a valid permit issued prior to March 30, 2009.



(b) Criteria for issuance of a permitThe Secretary may issue a permit for the collection of a paleontological resource pursuant to an application if the Secretary determines that—(1) the applicant is qualified to carry out the permitted activity;

(2) the permitted activity is undertaken for the purpose of furthering paleontological knowledge or for public education;

(3) the permitted activity is consistent with any management plan applicable to the Federal land concerned; and

(4) the proposed methods of collecting will not threaten significant natural or cultural resources.


(c) Permit specificationsA permit for the collection of a paleontological resource issued under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Every permit shall include requirements that—(1) the paleontological resource that is collected from Federal land under the permit will remain the property of the United States;

(2) the paleontological resource and copies of associated records will be preserved for the public in an approved repository, to be made available for scientific research and public education; and

(3) specific locality data will not be released by the permi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470aaa_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permit requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470aaa_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for issuance of a permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria for issuance of a permit The Secretary may issue a permit for the collection of a paleontological resource pursuant to an application if the Secretary determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470aaa_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit specifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Permit specifications A permit for the collection of a paleontological resource issued under this section shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Every permit shall include requirements that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470aaa_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification, suspension, and revocation of permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Modification, suspension, and revocation of permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470aaa_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area closures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Area closures In order to protect paleontological or other resources or to provide for public safety, the Secretary may restrict access to or close areas under the Secretary’s jurisdiction to the collection of paleontological resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>