<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470ii" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470ii/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/470ii/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_470ii"><akn:num>470ii</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations; intergovernmental coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 470ii. Rules and regulations; intergovernmental coordination(a) Promulgation; effective dateThe Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture and Defense and the Chairman of the Board of the Tennessee Valley Authority, after consultation with other Federal land managers, Indian tribes, representatives of concerned State agencies, and after public notice and hearing, shall promulgate such uniform rules and regulations as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such rules and regulations may be promulgated only after consideration of the provisions of the American Indian Religious Freedom Act (92 Stat. 469; 42 U.S.C. 1996 [, 1996a]). Each uniform rule or regulation promulgated under this chapter shall be submitted on the same calendar day to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, and no such uniform rule or regulation may take effect before the expiration of a period of ninety calendar days following the date of its submission to such Committees.


(b) Federal land managers’ rulesEach Federal land manager shall promulgate such rules and regulations, consistent with the uniform rules and regulations under subsection (a), as may be appropriate for the carrying out of his functions and authorities under this chapter.


(c) Federal land managers’ public awareness program of archaeological resources on public lands and Indian landsEach Federal land manager shall establish a program to increase public awareness of the significance of the archaeological resources located on public lands and Indian lands and the need to protect such resources.


(Pub. L. 96–95, § 10, Oct. 31, 1979, 93 Stat. 727; Pub. L. 100–588, § 1(d), Nov. 3, 1988, 102 Stat. 2983; Pub. L. 103–437, § 6(d)(30), Nov. 2, 1994, 108 Stat. 4584; Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title VIII, § 814(d)(2)(A), Nov. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 4196.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Ameri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470ii_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation; effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promulgation; effective date The Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture and Defense and the Chairman of the Board of the Tennessee Valley Authority, after consultation with other Federal land managers, Indian tribes, representatives of concerned State agencies, and after public notice and hearing, shall promulgate such uniform rules and regulations as may be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such rules and regulations may be promulgated only after consideration of the provisions of the American Indian Religious Freedom Act (92 Stat. 469; 42 U.S.C. 1996 [, 1996a]). Each uniform rule or regulation promulgated under this chapter shall be submitted on the same calendar day to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and to the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, and no such uniform rule or regulation may take effect before the expiration of a period of ninety calendar days following the da</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470ii_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal land managers’ rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal land managers’ rules Each Federal land manager shall promulgate such rules and regulations, consistent with the uniform rules and regulations under subsection (a), as may be appropriate for the carrying out of his functions and authorities under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470ii_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal land managers’ public awareness program of archaeological resources on public lands and Indian lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal land managers’ public awareness program of archaeological resources on public lands and Indian lands Each Federal land manager shall establish a program to increase public awareness of the significance of the archaeological resources located on public lands and Indian lands and the need to protect such resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>