<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/471j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/471j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/471j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_471j"><akn:num>471j</akn:num><akn:heading>Headwaters Forest and Elk River Property acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 471j. Headwaters Forest and Elk River Property acquisition(a) AuthorizationSubject to the terms and conditions of this section, up to $250,000,000 from the Land and Water Conservation Fund is authorized to be appropriated to acquire lands referenced in the Agreement of September 28, 1996, which consist of approximately 4,500 acres commonly referred to as the “Headwaters Forest”, approximately 1,125 acres referred to as the “Elk Head Forest”, and approximately 9,600 acres referred to as the “Elk River Property”, which are located in Humboldt County, California. This section is the sole authorization for the acquisition of such property, which is the subject of the Agreement dated September 28, 1996 between the United States of America (hereinafter “United States”), the State of California, MAXXAM, Inc., and the Pacific Lumber Company. Of the entire Elk River Property, the United States and the State of California are to retain approximately 1,845 acres and transfer the remaining approximately 7,755 acres of Elk River Property to the Pacific Lumber Company. The property to be acquired and retained by the United States and the State of California is that property that is the subject of the Agreement of September 28, 1996 as generally depicted on maps labeled as sheets 1 through 7 of Township 3 and 4 North, Ranges 1 East and 1 West, of the Humboldt Meridian, California, titled “Dependent Resurvey and Tract Survey”, as approved by Lance J. Bishop, Chief Cadastral Surveyor—California, on August 29, 1997. Such maps shall be on file in the Office of the Chief Cadastral Surveyor, Bureau of Land Management, Sacramento, California. The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make such typographical and other corrections to this description as are mutually agreed upon by the parties to the Agreement of September 28, 1996. The land retained by the United States and the State of California (approximately 7,470 acres) shall hereafter be the “Headwaters Forest”. Any funds appr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization Subject to the terms and conditions of this section, up to $250,000,000 from the Land and Water Conservation Fund is authorized to be appropriated to acquire lands referenced in the Agreement of September 28, 1996, which consist of approximately 4,500 acres commonly referred to as the “Headwaters Forest”, approximately 1,125 acres referred to as the “Elk Head Forest”, and approximately 9,600 acres referred to as the “Elk River Property”, which are located in Humboldt County, California. This section is the sole authorization for the acquisition of such property, which is the subject of the Agreement dated September 28, 1996 between the United States of America (hereinafter “United States”), the State of California, MAXXAM, Inc., and the Pacific Lumber Company. Of the entire Elk River Property, the United States and the State of California are to retain approximately 1,845 acres and transfer the remaining approximately 7,755 acres of Elk River Property to the Pacific L</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective period of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective period of authorization The authorization in subsection (a) expires March 1, 1999 and shall become effective only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amount paid by the United States to acquire identified lands and interests in lands referred to in subsection (a) may differ from the value contained in the appraisal required by subsection (b)(5) if the Secretary of the Interior certifies, in writing, to Congress that such action is in the best interest of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Habitat conservation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Habitat conservation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to Humboldt County</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment to Humboldt County Within 30 days of the acquisition of the Headwaters Forest, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide a $10,000,000 direct payment to Humboldt County, California.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment in lieu of taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payment in lieu of taxes The Federal portion of the Headwaters Forest acquired pursuant to this section shall be entitlement land under section 6905 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Out-year budget limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Out-year budget limitations The following funding limitations and parameters shall apply to the Headwaters Forest acquired under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Headwaters Forest Management Trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Headwaters Forest Management Trust The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, with the written concurrence of the Governor of the State of California, to establish a Headwaters Forest Management Trust (“Trust”) for the management of the Headwaters Forest as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_471j_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>