<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4722" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4722/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4722/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4722"><akn:num>4722</akn:num><akn:heading>Aquatic nuisance species program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4722. Aquatic nuisance species program(a) In generalThe Task Force shall develop and implement a program for waters of the United States to prevent introduction and dispersal of aquatic nuisance species; to monitor, control and study such species; and to disseminate related information.


(b) ContentThe program developed under subsection (a) shall—(1) identify the goals, priorities, and approaches for aquatic nuisance species prevention, monitoring, control, education and research to be conducted or funded by the Federal Government;

(2) describe the specific prevention, monitoring, control, education and research activities to be conducted by each Task Force member;

(3) coordinate aquatic nuisance species programs and activities of Task Force members and affected State agencies;

(4) describe the role of each Task Force member in implementing the elements of the program as set forth in this subchapter;

(5) include recommendations for funding to implement elements of the program; and

(6) develop a demonstration program of prevention, monitoring, control, education and research for the zebra mussel, to be implemented in the Great Lakes and any other waters infested, or likely to become infested in the near future, by the zebra mussel.


(c) Prevention(1) In generalThe Task Force shall establish and implement measures, within the program developed under subsection (a), to minimize the risk of introduction of aquatic nuisance species to waters of the United States, including—(A) identification of pathways by which aquatic organisms are introduced to waters of the United States;

(B) assessment of the risk that an aquatic organism carried by an identified pathway may become an aquatic nuisance species; and

(C) evaluation of whether measures to prevent introductions of aquatic nuisance species are effective and environmentally sound.


(2) ImplementationWhenever the Task Force determines that there is a substantial risk of unintentional introduction of an aquatic n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Task Force shall develop and implement a program for waters of the United States to prevent introduction and dispersal of aquatic nuisance species; to monitor, control and study such species; and to disseminate related information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Content The program developed under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prevention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monitoring The Task Force shall establish and implement monitoring measures, within the program developed under subsection (a), to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Control</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance The Task Force shall, within the program developed under subsection (a), provide technical assistance to State and local governments and persons to minimize the environmental, public health, and safety risks associated with aquatic nuisance species, including an early warning system for advance notice of possible infestations and appropriate responses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Education The Task Force shall, with the program developed under subsection (a), establish and implement educational programs through Sea Grant Marine Advisory Services and any other available resources that it determines to be appropriate to inform the general public, State governments, governments of political subdivisions of States, and industrial and recreational users of aquatic resources in connection with matters concerning the identification of aquatic nuisance species, and control methods for such species, including the prevention of the further distribution of such species.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Zebra mussel demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Zebra mussel demonstration program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4722_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>