<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4730" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4730/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4730/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4730"><akn:num>4730</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Invasive Species Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4730. Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Invasive Species Program(1) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(B) Aquatic nuisance speciesThe term “aquatic nuisance species” has the meaning given that term in subsection (p)(1) of section 1322 of title 33.


(C) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Great Lakes National Program Office established by section 1268(b) of title 33.


(D) Great Lakes and Lake Champlain SystemsThe term “Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Systems” includes—(i) Lake Champlain; and

(ii) all bodies of water (including wetlands) within—(I) the Great Lakes System (as defined in section 1268(a)(3) of title 33); or

(II) the Lake Champlain drainage basin (as defined in section 1270(g) of title 33).



(E) ProgramThe term “Program” means the Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Invasive Species Program established under paragraph (2)(A).



(2) Establishment of program(A) In generalThe Administrator shall establish within the Great Lakes National Program Office a program, to be known as the “Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Invasive Species Program”—(i) in collaboration with—(I) the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;

(II) the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;

(III) the Director of the United States Geological Survey; and

(IV) the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating; and


(ii) in consultation with—(I) the head of Great Lakes Aquatic Nonindigenous Species Information System of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and

(II) the head of Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.



(B) PurposesThe purposes of the Program shall be—(i) to monitor for the introduction and spread of aquatic nuisance species into or within the Great Lakes and Lake Champlain Systems;

(ii) to detect newly introduced</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Establishment of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methodology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Methodology The Program shall seek—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Collaboration In carrying out and developing the Program, the Director shall collaborate with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Data availability The Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4730_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>