<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4741" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4741/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/4741/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4741"><akn:num>4741</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4741. Authorization of appropriations(a) Prevention of unintentional introductionsThere are authorized to be appropriated to develop and implement the provisions of subchapter II—(1) $500,000 until the end of fiscal year 1992 to the Secretary to carry out sections 4711 11 See References in Text note below. and 4712(a)(3) of this title;

(2) $2,000,000 until the end of fiscal year 1992 to the Director and Under Secretary to carry out the studies under sections 4712(a)(1) and 4712(a)(2 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by a closing parenthesis. of this title;

(3) to the Secretary to carry out section 4711 1 of this title—(A) $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1997 and 1998; and

(B) $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 through 2002;


(4) for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002, to carry out paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 4712(b) of this title—(A) $1,000,000 to the Department of the Interior, to be used by the Director; and

(B) $1,000,000 to the Secretary; and


(5) for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002—(A) $3,000,000, which shall be made available from funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated if such funds are so authorized, to the Under Secretary to carry out section 4712(e) of this title; and

(B) $500,000 to the Secretary to carry out section 4712(f) of this title.



(b) Task Force and aquatic nuisance species programThere are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002 to develop and implement the provisions of subchapter III—(1) $6,000,000 to the Department of the Interior, to be used by the Director to carry out sections 4722 and 4728 of this title;

(2) $1,000,000 to the Department of Commerce, to be used by the Under Secretary to carry out section 4722 of this title;

(3) $1,625,000, which shall be made available from funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated if such funds are so authorized, to fund aquatic nuisance species prevention and control research under section 4722(i) of this tit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of unintentional introductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prevention of unintentional introductions There are authorized to be appropriated to develop and implement the provisions of subchapter II—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force and aquatic nuisance species program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Task Force and aquatic nuisance species program There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002 to develop and implement the provisions of subchapter III—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for State management programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants for State management programs There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 1997 through 2002 $4,000,000 to the Department of the Interior, to be used by the Director for making grants under section 4724 of this title, of which $1,500,000 shall be used by the Director, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary, for management of aquatic nuisance vegetation species.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intentional introductions policy review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Intentional introductions policy review There are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 1991, $500,000 to the Director and the Under Secretary to conduct the intentional introduction policy review under section 4727 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ballast water management demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ballast water management demonstration program There are authorized to be appropriated $2,500,000 to carry out section 4714 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4741_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Research There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director $1,000,000 to carry out research on the prevention, monitoring, and control of aquatic nuisance species in Narragansett Bay, Rhode Island. The funds shall be made available for use by the Department of Environmental Management of the State of Rhode Island.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>