<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/482b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/482b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/482b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_482b"><akn:num>482b</akn:num><akn:heading>Mount Hood National Forest; mining rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 482b. Mount Hood National Forest; mining rights
On and after May 11, 1934, mining locations made under the United States mining laws upon lands within the Mount Hood National Forest in the State of Oregon shall confer on the locator the right to occupy and use so much of the surface of the land covered by the location as may be reasonably necessary to carry on prospecting and mining, including the taking of mineral deposits and timber required by or in the mining operations, and no permit shall be required or charge made for such use or occupancy: Provided, however, That the cutting and removal of timber, except where clearing is necessary in connection with mining operations or to provide space for buildings or structures used in connection with mining operations, shall be conducted in accordance with the rules for timber cutting on adjoining national-forest land, and no use of the surface of the claim or the resources therefrom not reasonably required for carrying on mining or prospecting shall be allowed except under the national-forest rules and regulations, nor shall the locator prevent or obstruct other occupancy of the surface or use of surface resources under authority of national-forest regulations, or permits issued thereunder, if such occupancy or use is not in conflict with mineral development.
(May 11, 1934, ch. 280, § 1, 48 Stat. 773.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Bull Run Watershed Management UnitPub. L. 95–200, Nov. 23, 1977, 91 Stat. 1425, as amended by Pub. L. 104–208, div. B, title VI, §§ 601 to 604, Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–541; Pub. L. 104–333, div. I, title X, § 1026(a), Nov. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 4228; Pub. L. 107–30, §§ 1, 2(a), (c), Aug. 20, 2001, 115 Stat. 210, 211, provided that:
“preamble“The Congress finds that an area of land in the State of Oregon known variously as the Bull Run National Forest and the Bull Run Forest Reserve is presently the source of the sole domestic water supply for the city of Portland, Oregon (</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>