<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_497b"><akn:num>497b</akn:num><akn:heading>Ski area permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 497b. Ski area permits(a) Law applicable to permitsThe provisions of the Act of March 4, 1915 (16 U.S.C. 497) notwithstanding, the term and acreage of permits for the operation of ski areas and associated facilities on National Forest System lands shall on and after October 22, 1986, be governed by this section and other applicable law.


(b) AuthorityThe Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as “the Secretary”) is authorized to issue permits (hereinafter referred to as “ski area permits”) for the use and occupancy of suitable lands within the National Forest System for skiing and other snow sports and recreational uses authorized by this section. A ski area permit—(1) may be issued for a term not to exceed 40 years;

(2) shall ordinarily be issued for a term of 40 years (unless the Secretary determines that the facilities or operations are of a scale or nature as are not likely to require long-term financing or operation), or that there are public policy reasons specific to a particular permit for a shorter term;

(3) shall encompass such acreage as the Secretary determines sufficient and appropriate to accommodate the permittee’s needs for ski operations and appropriate ancillary facilities;

(4) may be renewed at the discretion of the Secretary;

(5) may be cancelled by the Secretary in whole or in part for any violation of the permit terms or conditions, for nonpayment of permit fees, or upon the determination by the Secretary in his planning for the uses of the national forests that the permitted area is needed for higher public purposes;

(6) may be modified from time to time by the Secretary to accommodate changes in plans or operations in accordance with the provisions of applicable law;

(7) shall be subject to such reasonable terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate; and

(8) shall be subject to a permit fee based on fair market value in accordance with applicable law.


(c) Other recreational uses(1) Authority of SecretarySubj</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law applicable to permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law applicable to permits The provisions of the Act of March 4, 1915 (16 U.S.C. 497) notwithstanding, the term and acreage of permits for the operation of ski areas and associated facilities on National Forest System lands shall on and after October 22, 1986, be governed by this section and other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority The Secretary of Agriculture (hereinafter referred to as “the Secretary”) is authorized to issue permits (hereinafter referred to as “ski area permits”) for the use and occupancy of suitable lands within the National Forest System for skiing and other snow sports and recreational uses authorized by this section. A ski area permit—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other recreational uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other recreational uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations Not later than 2 years after November 7, 2011, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction with Secretary’s duties under other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction with Secretary’s duties under other laws Nothing in this section shall be deemed to amend, modify or otherwise affect the Secretary’s duties under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) and the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.), including his duties to involve the public in his decisionmaking and planning for the national forests.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>