<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/497e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_497e"><akn:num>497e</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing Forest Service administration of rights-of-way and land uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 497e. Enhancing Forest Service administration of rights-of-way and land uses(a) Program requiredFor fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a program for the purpose of enhancing Forest Service administration of rights-of-way and other land uses.


(b) Deposit of feesSubject to subsections (a) and (f), each fiscal year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall deposit into a special account established in the Treasury all fees collected by the Secretary to recover the costs of processing applications for, and monitoring compliance with, authorizations to use and occupy National Forest System lands pursuant to section 185(l) of title 30, section 1764(g) of title 43, section 9701 of title 31, and section 306109 of title 54.


(c) Use of retained amountsAmounts deposited pursuant to subsection (b) shall be available, without further appropriation, for expenditure by the Secretary of Agriculture to cover costs incurred by the Forest Service for the processing of applications for special use authorizations and for monitoring activities undertaken in connection with such authorizations. Amounts in the special account shall remain available for such purposes until expended.


(d) Reporting requirementIn the budget justification documents submitted by the Secretary of Agriculture in support of the President’s budget for a fiscal year under section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary shall include a description of the purposes for which amounts were expended from the special account during the preceding fiscal year, including the amounts expended for each purpose, and a description of the purposes for which amounts are proposed to be expended from the special account during the next fiscal year, including the amounts proposed to be expended for each purpose.


(e) Definition of authorizationFor purposes of this section, the term “authorizations” means special use authorizations issued under subpart B of part 251 of title 36, Code </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required For fiscal year 2014 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a program for the purpose of enhancing Forest Service administration of rights-of-way and other land uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposit of fees Subject to subsections (a) and (f), each fiscal year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall deposit into a special account established in the Treasury all fees collected by the Secretary to recover the costs of processing applications for, and monitoring compliance with, authorizations to use and occupy National Forest System lands pursuant to section 185(l) of title 30, section 1764(g) of title 43, section 9701 of title 31, and section 306109 of title 54.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of retained amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of retained amounts Amounts deposited pursuant to subsection (b) shall be available, without further appropriation, for expenditure by the Secretary of Agriculture to cover costs incurred by the Forest Service for the processing of applications for special use authorizations and for monitoring activities undertaken in connection with such authorizations. Amounts in the special account shall remain available for such purposes until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting requirement In the budget justification documents submitted by the Secretary of Agriculture in support of the President’s budget for a fiscal year under section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary shall include a description of the purposes for which amounts were expended from the special account during the preceding fiscal year, including the amounts expended for each purpose, and a description of the purposes for which amounts are proposed to be expended from the special account during the next fiscal year, including the amounts proposed to be expended for each purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definition of authorization For purposes of this section, the term “authorizations” means special use authorizations issued under subpart B of part 251 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_497e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation This section shall take effect upon promulgation of Forest Service regulations for the collection of fees for processing of special use authorizations and for related monitoring activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>