<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5007"><akn:num>5007</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5007. Cooperation with other agencies(a) In generalAny agency of the Federal Government is authorized, upon request of the Commission, to cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs, and to furnish, on a reimbursable basis, facilities and personnel for the purpose of assisting the Commission in carrying out its duties under the Convention. Such agency may accept reimbursement from the Commission.


(b) Functions of Secretary of CommerceIn carrying out the provisions of the Convention and this chapter, the Secretary of Commerce may arrange for cooperation with agencies of the United States, the States, private institutions and organizations, and agencies of the government of any Party, to conduct scientific and other programs, and may execute such memoranda as may be necessary to reflect such agreements.


(Pub. L. 102–567, title VIII, § 808, Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4312; Pub. L. 102–587, title VIII, § 8008, Nov. 4, 1992, 106 Stat. 5101; Pub. L. 106–562, title III, § 304(a), Dec. 23, 2000, 114 Stat. 2806.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Title VIII of Pub. L. 102–567 and Pub. L. 102–587 enacted identical sections. Title VIII of Pub. L. 102–587 was repealed by Pub. L. 106–562.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any agency of the Federal Government is authorized, upon request of the Commission, to cooperate in the conduct of scientific and other programs, and to furnish, on a reimbursable basis, facilities and personnel for the purpose of assisting the Commission in carrying out its duties under the Convention. Such agency may accept reimbursement from the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Secretary of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions of Secretary of Commerce In carrying out the provisions of the Convention and this chapter, the Secretary of Commerce may arrange for cooperation with agencies of the United States, the States, private institutions and organizations, and agencies of the government of any Party, to conduct scientific and other programs, and may execute such memoranda as may be necessary to reflect such agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>