<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5008"><akn:num>5008</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5008. Enforcement provisions(a) Duties of Secretaries of Commerce and TransportationThis chapter shall be enforced by the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Transportation. Such Secretaries may by agreement utilize, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, the personnel, services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal agency, including all elements of the Department of Defense, and of any State agency, in the performance of such duties. Such Secretaries shall, and the head of any Federal or State agency that has entered into an agreement with either such Secretary under the preceding sentence may (if the agreement so provides), authorize officers to enforce the provisions of the Convention, this chapter, and regulations issued under this chapter. Any such agreement or contract entered into pursuant to this section shall be effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.


(b) District court jurisdictionThe district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any case or controversy arising under the provisions of this chapter.


(c) Powers of enforcement officersAuthorized officers may, shoreward of the outer boundary of the exclusive economic zone, or during hot pursuit from the zone—(1) with or without a warrant or other process—(A) arrest any person, if the officer has reasonable cause to believe that such person has committed an act prohibited by section 5009 of this title;

(B) board, and search or inspect, any fishing vessel subject to the provisions of the Convention and this chapter;

(C) seize any fishing vessel (together with its fishing gear, furniture, appurtenances, stores, and cargo) used or employed in, or with respect to which it reasonably appears that such vessel was used or employed in, the violation of any provision of the Convention, this chapter, or regulations issued under this chapter;

(D) seize any fish (wherever found</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretaries of Commerce and Transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duties of Secretaries of Commerce and Transportation This chapter shall be enforced by the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Transportation. Such Secretaries may by agreement utilize, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, the personnel, services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal agency, including all elements of the Department of Defense, and of any State agency, in the performance of such duties. Such Secretaries shall, and the head of any Federal or State agency that has entered into an agreement with either such Secretary under the preceding sentence may (if the agreement so provides), authorize officers to enforce the provisions of the Convention, this chapter, and regulations issued under this chapter. Any such agreement or contract entered into pursuant to this section shall be effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>District court jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) District court jurisdiction The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any case or controversy arising under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of enforcement officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers of enforcement officers Authorized officers may, shoreward of the outer boundary of the exclusive economic zone, or during hot pursuit from the zone—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>