<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5106"><akn:num>5106</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5106. Secretarial action(a) Secretarial review of Commission determination of noncomplianceWithin 30 days after receiving a notification from the Commission under section 5105(b) of this title and after review of the Commission’s determination of noncompliance, the Secretary shall make a finding on—(1) whether the State in question has failed to carry out its responsibility under section 5104 of this title; and

(2) if so, whether the measures that the State has failed to implement and enforce are necessary for the conservation of the fishery in question.


(b) Consideration of commentsIn making a finding under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—(A) give careful consideration to the comments of the State that the Commission has determined under section 5105(a) of this title is not in compliance with a coastal fishery management plan, and provide such State, upon request, with the opportunity to meet with and present its comments directly to the Secretary; and

(B) solicit and consider the comments of the Commission and the appropriate Councils.


(c) Moratorium(1) Upon making a finding under subsection (a) that a State has failed to carry out its responsibility under section 5104 of this title and that the measures it failed to implement and enforce are necessary for conservation, the Secretary shall declare a moratorium on fishing in the fishery in question within the waters of the noncomplying State. The Secretary shall specify the moratorium’s effective date, which shall be any date within 6 months after declaration of the moratorium.

(2) If after a moratorium is declared under paragraph (1) the Secretary is notified by the Commission that the Commission is withdrawing under section 5105(c) of this title the determination of noncompliance, the Secretary shall immediately determine whether the State is in compliance with the applicable plan. If so, the moratorium shall be terminated.


(d) Implementing regulationsThe Secretary may issue regulations necessary t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial review of Commission determination of noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Secretarial review of Commission determination of noncompliance Within 30 days after receiving a notification from the Commission under section 5105(b) of this title and after review of the Commission’s determination of noncompliance, the Secretary shall make a finding on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of comments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consideration of comments In making a finding under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Moratorium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Moratorium</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementing regulations The Secretary may issue regulations necessary to implement this section. Such regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts during moratorium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited acts during moratorium During the time in which a moratorium under this section is in effect, it is unlawful for any person to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil and criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil and criminal penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil forfeitures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Civil forfeitures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Enforcement A person authorized by the Secretary or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may take any action to enforce a moratorium declared under subsection (c) of this section that an officer authorized by the Secretary under section 311(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1861(b)) may take to enforce that Act [16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.]. The Secretary may, by agreement, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, utilize the personnel, services, equipment (including aircraft and vessels), and facilities of any other Federal department or agency and of any agency of a State in carrying out that enforcement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>