<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5202"><akn:num>5202</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5202. Civil penalties(a) In generalA person who violates section 5201 of this title shall be assessed a civil penalty in an amount computed under subsection (b).


(b) Computation of penaltyThe penalty shall be—(1) not more than $10,000, if the violation involved the use of force or violence, or the threatened use of force or violence, against the person or property of another person; and

(2) not more than $5,000 for any other violation.


(c) Relationship to other penaltiesThe penalties established by this section shall be in addition to other criminal or civil penalties that may be levied against the person as a result of an activity in violation of section 5201 of this title.


(d) ProcedureUpon receipt of—(1) a written complaint from an officer, employee, or agent of the Forest Service, Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, United States Fish and Wildlife Service, or other Federal agency that a person violated section 5201 of this title; or

(2) a sworn affidavit from an individual and a determination by the Secretary that the statement contains sufficient factual allegations to create a reasonable belief that a violation of section 5201 of this title has occurred;


the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to institute a civil action for the imposition and collection of the civil penalty under this section.

(e) Use of penalty money collectedAfter deduction of costs attributable to collection, money collected from penalties shall be—(1) deposited into the trust fund established pursuant to the Act entitled “An Act to provide that the United States shall aid the States in wildlife-restoration projects, and for other purposes”, approved September 2, 1937 (16 U.S.C. 669) (commonly known as the “Pitman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act”), to support the activities authorized by such Act and undertaken by State wildlife management agencies; or

(2) used in such other manner as the Secretary determines will enhance the fundi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5202_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A person who violates section 5201 of this title shall be assessed a civil penalty in an amount computed under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5202_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of penalty The penalty shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5202_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Relationship to other penalties The penalties established by this section shall be in addition to other criminal or civil penalties that may be levied against the person as a result of an activity in violation of section 5201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5202_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedure Upon receipt of— the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to institute a civil action for the imposition and collection of the civil penalty under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5202_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of penalty money collected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of penalty money collected After deduction of costs attributable to collection, money collected from penalties shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>