<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/521a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/521a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/521a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_521a"><akn:num>521a</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration, management, and consolidation of certain lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 521a. Administration, management, and consolidation of certain lands
In order to facilitate the administration, management, and consolidation of the national forests, all lands of the United States within the exterior boundaries of national forests which were or hereafter are acquired for or in connection with the national forests or transferred to the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, for administration and protection substantially in accordance with national forest regulations, policies, and procedures, excepting (a) lands reserved from the public domain or acquired pursuant to laws authorizing the exchange of land or timber reserved from or part of the public domain, and (b) lands within the official limits of towns or cities, notwithstanding the provisions of any other Act, are made subject to the Weeks Act of March 1, 1911 (36 Stat. 961), as amended, and to all laws, rules, and regulations applicable to national forest lands acquired thereunder: Provided, That nothing in this section shall be construed as (1) affecting the status of lands administered by the Secretary of Agriculture under the Act of June 24, 1954 (68 Stat. 270), and which are revested Oregon and California Railroad grant lands, administered as national forest lands, or (2) changing the disposition of revenues from or authorizing the exchange of the lands, or the timber thereon, described in the Act of February 11, 1920 (ch. 69, 41 Stat. 405), the Act of September 22, 1922 (ch. 407, 42 Stat. 1019), and the Act of June 4, 1936 (ch. 494, 49 Stat. 1460).
(Pub. L. 85–862, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1571.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Weeks Act of March 1, 1911, referred to in text, is act Mar. 1, 1911, ch. 186, 36 Stat. 961, which enacted former sections 513 and 514 and sections 515 to 519, 521, 552, and 563 of this title and amended sections 480 and 500 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 552 of this title</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>