<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/5304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5304"><akn:num>5304</akn:num><akn:heading>Rhinoceros and tiger conservation assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5304. Rhinoceros and tiger conservation assistance(a) In generalThe Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations and in consultation with the Administrator, shall use amounts in the Fund to provide financial assistance for projects for the conservation of rhinoceros and tigers.


(b) Project proposalA country whose activities directly or indirectly affect rhinoceros or tiger populations, the CITES Secretariat, or any other person may submit to the Secretary a project proposal under this section. Each proposal shall—(1) name the individual responsible for conducting the project;

(2) state the purposes of the project succinctly;

(3) describe the qualifications of the individuals who will conduct the project;

(4) estimate the funds and time required to complete the project;

(5) provide evidence of support of the project by appropriate governmental entities of countries in which the project will be conducted, if the Secretary determines that the support is required for the success of the project; and

(6) provide any other information the Secretary considers to be necessary for evaluating the eligibility of the project for funding under this chapter.


(c) Project review and approvalWithin 30 days of receiving a final project proposal, the Secretary shall provide a copy of the proposal to the Administrator. The Secretary shall review each final project proposal to determine if it meets the criteria set forth in subsection (d). Not later than 6 months after receiving a final project proposal, and subject to the availability of funds, the Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall approve or disapprove the proposal and provide written notification to the person who submitted the proposal and to the Administrator.


(d) Criteria for approvalThe Secretary may approve a project under this section if the project will enhance programs for conservation of rhinoceros or tigers by assisting efforts to—(1) implement conservation programs;

(2) enha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, subject to the availability of appropriations and in consultation with the Administrator, shall use amounts in the Fund to provide financial assistance for projects for the conservation of rhinoceros and tigers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project proposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Project proposal A country whose activities directly or indirectly affect rhinoceros or tiger populations, the CITES Secretariat, or any other person may submit to the Secretary a project proposal under this section. Each proposal shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project review and approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Project review and approval Within 30 days of receiving a final project proposal, the Secretary shall provide a copy of the proposal to the Administrator. The Secretary shall review each final project proposal to determine if it meets the criteria set forth in subsection (d). Not later than 6 months after receiving a final project proposal, and subject to the availability of funds, the Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, shall approve or disapprove the proposal and provide written notification to the person who submitted the proposal and to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for approval The Secretary may approve a project under this section if the project will enhance programs for conservation of rhinoceros or tigers by assisting efforts to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project sustainability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Project sustainability To the maximum extent practical, in determining whether to approve project proposals under this section, the Secretary shall give consideration to projects which will enhance sustainable conservation programs to ensure effective long-term conservation of rhinoceros and tigers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Project reporting Each person that receives assistance under this section for a project shall provide periodic reports, as the Secretary considers necessary, to the Secretary and the Administrator. Each report shall include all information requested by the Secretary, after consulting with the Administrator, for evaluating the progress and success of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Multiyear grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>