<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/535a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/535a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/535a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_535a"><akn:num>535a</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest development roads: prohibition on credits; inclusion of construction costs in notice of sale;</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 535a. Forest development roads: prohibition on credits; inclusion of construction costs in notice of sale; special election by small business concerns; construction standards; authorization of harvesting; treatment of road value(a) Prohibition on timber purchaser road creditsIn financing any forest development road pursuant to section 535 of this title, the Secretary of Agriculture may not provide effective credit for road construction to any purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products.


(b) Construction of roads by timber purchasers(1) Whenever the Secretary of Agriculture makes a determination that a forest development road referred to in subsection (a) shall be constructed or paid for, in whole or in part, by a purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products, the Secretary shall include notice of the determination in the notice of sale of the timber or other forest products. The notice of sale shall contain, or announce the availability of, sufficient information related to the road described in the notice to permit a prospective bidder on the sale to calculate the likely cost that would be incurred by the bidder to construct or finance the construction of the road so that the bidder may reflect such cost in the bid.

(2) If there is an increase or decrease in the cost of roads constructed by the timber purchaser, caused by variations in quantities, changes or modifications subsequent to the sale of timber made in accordance with applicable timber sale contract provisions, then an adjustment to the price paid for timber harvested by the purchaser shall be made. The adjustment shall be applied by the Secretary as soon as practicable after any such design change is implemented.


(c) Special election by small business concerns(1) A notice of sale referred to in subsection (b) containing specified road construction of $50,000 or more, shall give a purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products that qualifies as a “small</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on timber purchaser road credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on timber purchaser road credits In financing any forest development road pursuant to section 535 of this title, the Secretary of Agriculture may not provide effective credit for road construction to any purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of roads by timber purchasers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction of roads by timber purchasers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special election by small business concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special election by small business concerns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of harvesting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of harvesting In each sale of national forest timber or other forest products referred to in this section, the Secretary of Agriculture is encouraged to authorize harvest of the timber or other forest products in a unit included in the sale as soon as road work for that unit is completed and the road work is approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction standard For any forest development road that is to be constructed or paid for by a purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products, the Secretary of Agriculture may not require the purchaser to design, construct, or maintain the road (or pay for the design, construction, or maintenance of the road) to a standard higher than the standard, consistent with applicable environmental laws and regulations, that is sufficient for the harvesting and removal of the timber or other forest products, unless the Secretary bears that part of the cost necessary to meet the higher standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of road value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of road value For any forest development road that is constructed or paid for by a purchaser of national forest timber or other forest products, the estimated cost of the road construction, including subsequent design changes, shall be considered to be money received for purposes of the payments required to be made under section 500 of this title. To the extent that the appraised value of road construction determined under this subsection reflects funds contributed by the Secretary of Agriculture to build the road to a higher standard pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary shall modify the appraisal of the road construction to exclude the effect of the Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>