<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539l_4"><akn:num>539l–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Other administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539l–4. Other administrative provisions(a) Buffer zonesThe designation by this Act or by amendments made by this Act of wilderness areas and the Protection Area in the State of Colorado shall not create or imply the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around any wilderness area or the Protection Area. The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area or Protection Area shall not, of itself, preclude such activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area or the Protection Area.


(b) Rollins Pass RoadIf requested by one or more of the Colorado Counties of Grand, Gilpin, and Boulder, the Secretary shall provide technical assistance and otherwise cooperate with respect to repairing the Rollins Pass road in those counties sufficiently to allow two-wheel-drive vehicles to travel between Colorado State Highway 119 and U.S. Highway 40. If this road is repaired to such extent, the Secretary shall close the motorized roads and trails on Forest Service land indicated on the map entitled “Rollins Pass Road Reopening: Attendant Road and Trail Closures”, dated September 2001.


(Pub. L. 107–216, § 7, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1060.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 107–216, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1055, which is classified principally to sections 539l to 539l–5 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 539l of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buffer zones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Buffer zones The designation by this Act or by amendments made by this Act of wilderness areas and the Protection Area in the State of Colorado shall not create or imply the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around any wilderness area or the Protection Area. The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area or Protection Area shall not, of itself, preclude such activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area or the Protection Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rollins Pass Road</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rollins Pass Road If requested by one or more of the Colorado Counties of Grand, Gilpin, and Boulder, the Secretary shall provide technical assistance and otherwise cooperate with respect to repairing the Rollins Pass road in those counties sufficiently to allow two-wheel-drive vehicles to travel between Colorado State Highway 119 and U.S. Highway 40. If this road is repaired to such extent, the Secretary shall close the motorized roads and trails on Forest Service land indicated on the map entitled “Rollins Pass Road Reopening: Attendant Road and Trail Closures”, dated September 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>