<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539l"><akn:num>539l</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of James Peak Protection Area, Colorado</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539l. Designation of James Peak Protection Area, Colorado(a) Findings and purpose(1) FindingsThe Congress finds the following:(A) The lands covered by this section include important resources and values, including wildlife habitat, clean water, open space, and opportunities for solitude.

(B) These lands also include areas that are suitable for recreational uses, including use of snowmobiles in times of adequate snow cover as well as use of other motorized and nonmotorized mechanical devices.

(C) These lands should be managed in a way that affords permanent protection to their resources and values while permitting continued recreational uses in appropriate locales and subject to appropriate regulations.


(2) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide for management of certain lands in the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest in a manner consistent with the 1997 Revised Land and Resources Management Plan for this forest in order to protect the natural qualities of these areas.



(b) DesignationThe approximately 16,000 acres of land in the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed James Peak Protection Area”, dated September 2001, are hereby designated as the James Peak Protection Area (hereafter in this Act referred to as the “Protection Area”).


(c) Map and boundary descriptionAs soon as practicable after August 21, 2002, the Secretary shall file with the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and a boundary description of the Protection Area. The map and boundary description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map and boundary description. The map and boundary description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief of the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, and in the office of the F</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings and purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation The approximately 16,000 acres of land in the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed James Peak Protection Area”, dated September 2001, are hereby designated as the James Peak Protection Area (hereafter in this Act referred to as the “Protection Area”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Map and boundary description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Map and boundary description As soon as practicable after August 21, 2002, the Secretary shall file with the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and a boundary description of the Protection Area. The map and boundary description shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map and boundary description. The map and boundary description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief of the Forest Service, Department of Agriculture, and in the office of the Forest Supervisor of the Arapaho/Roosevelt National Forest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issues related to water</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Issues related to water</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>