<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539m_2"><akn:num>539m–2</akn:num><akn:heading>T’uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539m–2. T’uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area(a) EstablishmentThe T’uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area is established within the Cibola National Forest and the Sandia Mountain Wilderness as depicted on the map—(1) to recognize and protect in perpetuity the rights and interests of the Pueblo in and to the Area, as specified in section 539m–3(a) of this title;

(2) to preserve in perpetuity the national forest and wilderness character of the Area; and

(3) to recognize and protect in perpetuity the longstanding use and enjoyment of the Area by the public.


(b) Administration and applicable law(1) In generalThe Secretary shall continue to administer the Area as part of the National Forest System subject to and consistent with the provisions of sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title affecting management of the Area.


(2) Traditional or cultural usesTraditional or cultural uses by Pueblo members and members of other federally-recognized Indian tribes authorized to use the Area by the Pueblo under section 539m–3(a)(4) of this title shall not be restricted except by—(A) the Wilderness Act (16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.) (including regulations promulgated under that Act) as in effect on February 20, 2003; and

(B) applicable Federal wildlife protection laws, as provided in section 539m–4(a)(2) of this title.


(3) Later enactmentsTo the extent that any law enacted or amended after February 20, 2003, is inconsistent with sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title, the law shall not apply to the Area unless expressly made applicable by Congress.


(4) TrustThe use of the word “Trust” in the name of the Area—(A) is in recognition of the specific rights and interests of the Pueblo in the Area; and

(B) does not confer on the Pueblo the ownership interest that exists in a case in which the Secretary of the Interior accepts the title to land held in trust for the benefit of an Indian tribe.



(c) Map(1) FilingAs soon as practicable after February 20, 2003, the Secretary shall file t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The T’uf Shur Bien Preservation Trust Area is established within the Cibola National Forest and the Sandia Mountain Wilderness as depicted on the map—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and applicable law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration and applicable law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Map</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No conveyance of title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No conveyance of title No right, title, or interest of the United States in or to the Area or any part of the Area shall be conveyed to or exchanged with any person, trust, or governmental entity, including the Pueblo, without specific authorization of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No modification of boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No modification of boundaries Establishment of the Area shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>