<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539m_6"><akn:num>539m–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction over the Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539m–6. Jurisdiction over the Area(a) Criminal jurisdiction(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, jurisdiction over crimes committed in the Area shall be allocated as provided in this paragraph.11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection.”


(2) Jurisdiction of the PuebloThe Pueblo shall have jurisdiction over an offense committed by a member of the Pueblo or of another federally-recognized Indian tribe who is present in the Area with the permission of the Pueblo under section 539m–3(a)(4) of this title.


(3) Jurisdiction of the United StatesThe United States shall have jurisdiction over—(A) an offense described in section 1153 of title 18 committed by a member of the Pueblo or another federally-recognized Indian tribe;

(B) an offense committed by any person in violation of the laws (including regulations) pertaining to the protection and management of national forests;

(C) enforcement of Federal criminal laws of general applicability; and

(D) any other offense committed by a member of the Pueblo against a person not a member of the Pueblo.


(4) Jurisdiction of the State of New MexicoThe State of New Mexico shall have jurisdiction over an offense under the law of the State committed by a person not a member of the Pueblo.


(5) Overlapping jurisdictionTo the extent that the respective allocations of jurisdiction over the Area under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) overlap, the governments shall have concurrent jurisdiction.


(6) Federal use of State lawUnder the jurisdiction of the United States described in paragraph (3)(D), Federal law shall incorporate any offense defined and punishable under State law that is not so defined under Federal law.



(b) Civil jurisdiction(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the United States, the State of New Mexico, and local public bodies shall have the same civil adjudicatory, regulatory, and taxing jurisdiction over the Area as was exercised by those entities on the day before </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criminal jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>