<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539m_11"><akn:num>539m–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to contributions and land exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539m–11. Provisions relating to contributions and land exchange(a) Contributions(1) In generalThe Secretary may accept contributions from the Pueblo, or from other persons or governmental entities—(A) to perform and complete a survey of the Area; or

(B) to carry out any other project or activity for the benefit of the Area in accordance with sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title.


(2) DeadlineNot later than 1 year after February 20, 2003, the Secretary shall complete the survey of the Area under paragraph (1)(A).



(b) Land exchange(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after February 20, 2003, after consultation with the Pueblo, the Secretary shall, in accordance with applicable laws, prepare and offer a land exchange of National Forest land outside the Area and contiguous to the northern boundary of the Pueblo’s Reservation within sections 3, 10, 11, and 14 of T12N, R4E, N.M.P.M., Sandoval County, New Mexico excluding wilderness land, for land owned by the Pueblo in the Evergreen Hills subdivision in Sandoval County contiguous to National Forest land, and the La Luz tract in Bernalillo County.


(2) Acceptance of paymentNotwithstanding section 1716(b) of title 43, the Secretary may either make or accept a cash equalization payment in excess of 25 percent of the total value of the land or interests transferred out of Federal ownership.


(3) Funds receivedAny funds received by the Secretary as a result of the exchange shall be deposited in the fund established under section 484a of this title, and shall be available to purchase non-Federal land within or adjacent to the National Forests in the State of New Mexico.


(4) Treatment of land exchanged or conveyedAll land exchanged or conveyed to the Pueblo is declared to be held in trust for the Pueblo by the United States and added to the Pueblo’s Reservation subject to all existing and outstanding rights and shall, as a condition of the title to be conveyed, remain in its natural state and shall not be subject t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land exchange</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition and other compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Land acquisition and other compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of certain costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement of certain costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>