<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539m–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539m_8"><akn:num>539m–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Extinguishment of claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539m–8. Extinguishment of claims(a) In generalExcept for the rights and interests in and to the Area specifically recognized in sections 539m–2, 539m–3, 539m–5, 539m–6, and 539m–7 of this title, all Pueblo claims to right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, in and to land within the Area, any part thereof, and property interests therein, as well as related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished. The United States’ title to the Area is confirmed.


(b) SubdivisionsAny Pueblo claims to right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, in and to the subdivisions and property interests therein (except for land owned in fee by the Pueblo as of February 20, 2003), as well as related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished.


(c) Special use and crest facilities areasAny Pueblo right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, and related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished in and to—(1) the land described in the special use permit; and

(2) the land on which the crest facilities are located.


(d) Pueblo agreementAs provided in the Settlement Agreement, the Pueblo has agreed to the relinquishment and extinguishment of those claims, rights, titles and interests extinguished pursuant to subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsections”. (a), (b), and (c).


(e) ConsiderationThe recognition of the Pueblo’s rights and interests in sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title constitutes adequate consideration for the Pueblo’s agreement to the extinguishment of the Pueblo’s claims in this section and the right-of-way grants contained in section 539m–7 of this title, and it is the intent of Congress that those rights and interests may only be diminished by a future Act of Congress specifically authorizing diminishment of such rights, with express reference to sections 53</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except for the rights and interests in and to the Area specifically recognized in sections 539m–2, 539m–3, 539m–5, 539m–6, and 539m–7 of this title, all Pueblo claims to right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, in and to land within the Area, any part thereof, and property interests therein, as well as related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished. The United States’ title to the Area is confirmed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subdivisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subdivisions Any Pueblo claims to right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, in and to the subdivisions and property interests therein (except for land owned in fee by the Pueblo as of February 20, 2003), as well as related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special use and crest facilities areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special use and crest facilities areas Any Pueblo right, title and interest of any kind, including aboriginal claims, and related boundary, survey, trespass, and monetary damage claims, are permanently extinguished in and to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pueblo agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pueblo agreement As provided in the Settlement Agreement, the Pueblo has agreed to the relinquishment and extinguishment of those claims, rights, titles and interests extinguished pursuant to subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsections”. (a), (b), and (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539m_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consideration The recognition of the Pueblo’s rights and interests in sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title constitutes adequate consideration for the Pueblo’s agreement to the extinguishment of the Pueblo’s claims in this section and the right-of-way grants contained in section 539m–7 of this title, and it is the intent of Congress that those rights and interests may only be diminished by a future Act of Congress specifically authorizing diminishment of such rights, with express reference to sections 539m to 539m–12 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>