<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539o"><akn:num>539o</akn:num><akn:heading>Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539o. Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest(a) DesignationTo conserve and protect the Ancient Bristlecone Pines by maintaining near-natural conditions and to ensure the survival of the Pines for the purposes of public enjoyment and scientific study, the approximately 31,700 acres of public land in the State, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest—Proposed” and dated July 16, 2008, is designated as the “Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest”.


(b) Map and legal description(1) In generalAs soon as practicable, but not later than 3 years after March 30, 2009, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of the Forest with—(A) the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and

(B) the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.


(2) Force of lawThe map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subtitle, except that the Secretary may correct any errors in the map and legal description.


(3) Public availabilityThe map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.



(c) Management(1) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Forest—(A) in a manner that—(i) protect 11 So in original. Probably should be “protects”. the resources and values of the area in accordance with the purposes for which the Forest is established, as described in subsection (a); and

(ii) promotes the objectives of the applicable management plan (as in effect on March 30, 2009), including objectives relating to—(I) the protection of bristlecone pines for public enjoyment and scientific study;

(II) the recognition of the botanical, scenic, and historical values of the area; and

(III) the maintenance of near-natural conditions by ensuring that all activities are subordinate to the needs of protecting and preserving bristlecone pines and wood remnants; and



(B</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation To conserve and protect the Ancient Bristlecone Pines by maintaining near-natural conditions and to ensure the survival of the Pines for the purposes of public enjoyment and scientific study, the approximately 31,700 acres of public land in the State, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest—Proposed” and dated July 16, 2008, is designated as the “Ancient Bristlecone Pine Forest”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Map and legal description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Map and legal description</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>