<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539q"><akn:num>539q</akn:num><akn:heading>Hermosa Creek watershed protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539q. Hermosa Creek watershed protection(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) CityThe term “City” means the city of Durango, Colorado.


(2) CountyThe term “County” means La Plata County, Colorado.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(4) Special Management AreaThe term “Special Management Area” means the Hermosa Creek Special Management Area designated by subsection (b)(1).


(5) StateThe term “State” means the State of Colorado.



(b) Designation of Hermosa Creek Special Management Area(1) DesignationSubject to valid existing rights, certain Federal land in the San Juan National Forest comprising approximately 70,650 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Proposed Hermosa Creek Special Management Area and Proposed Hermosa Creek Wilderness Area” and dated November 12, 2014, is designated as the “Hermosa Creek Special Management Area”.


(2) PurposeThe purpose of the Special Management Area is to conserve and protect for the benefit of present and future generations the watershed, geological, cultural, natural, scientific, recreational, wildlife, riparian, historical, educational, and scenic resources of the Special Management Area.


(3) Administration(A) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Special Management Area—(i) in a manner that conserves, protects, and manages the resources of the Special Management Area described in paragraph (2); and

(ii) in accordance with—(I) the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.);

(II) this Act; and

(III) any other applicable laws.



(B) Uses(i) In generalThe Secretary shall allow only such uses of the Special Management Area as the Secretary determines would further the purposes 11 So in original. Probably should be “purpose”. described in paragraph (2).


(ii) Motorized and mechanized vehicles(I) In generalExcept as provided in subclause (II) and as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized or mechaniz</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Hermosa Creek Special Management Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of Hermosa Creek Special Management Area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hermosa Creek Wilderness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hermosa Creek Wilderness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Durango Area mineral withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Durango Area mineral withdrawal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of Bureau of Land Management land to County</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conveyance of Bureau of Land Management land to County</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Molas Pass Recreation Area; Wilderness Study Area release; Wilderness Study Area transfer of administrative jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Molas Pass Recreation Area; Wilderness Study Area release; Wilderness Study Area transfer of administrative jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) General provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>