<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/539r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_539r"><akn:num>539r</akn:num><akn:heading>Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area and wilderness additions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 539r. Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area and wilderness additions(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Conservation Management AreaThe term “Conservation Management Area” means the Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area established by subsection (b)(1)(A).


(2) DecommissionThe term “decommission” means—(A) to reestablish vegetation on a road; and

(B) to restore any natural drainage, watershed function, or other ecological processes that are disrupted or adversely impacted by the road by removing or hydrologically disconnecting the road prism.


(3) DistrictThe term “district” means the Rocky Mountain Ranger District of the Lewis and Clark National Forest.


(4) MapThe term “map” means the map entitled “Rocky Mountain Front Heritage Act” and dated October 27, 2011.


(5) Nonmotorized recreation trailThe term “nonmotorized recreation trail” means a trail designed for hiking, bicycling, or equestrian use.


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means—(A) with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Agriculture; and

(B) with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Interior.


(7) StateThe term “State” means the State of Montana.



(b) Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area(1) Establishment(A) In generalSubject to valid existing rights, there is established the Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area in the State.


(B) Area includedThe Conservation Management Area shall consist of approximately 195,073 acres of Federal land managed by the Forest Service and 13,087 acres of Federal land managed by the Bureau of Land Management in the State, as generally depicted on the map.


(C) Incorporation of acquired land and interestsAny land or interest in land that is located in the Conservation Management Area and is acquired by the United States from a willing seller shall—(i) become part of the Conservation Management Area; and

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rocky Mountain Front Conservation Management Area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of wilderness additions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of wilderness additions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps and legal descriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maps and legal descriptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noxious weed management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Noxious weed management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonmotorized recreation opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nonmotorized recreation opportunities Not later than 2 years after December 19, 2014, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with interested parties, shall conduct a study to improve nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness within the district.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of fish and wildlife; hunting and fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Management of fish and wildlife; hunting and fishing Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction of the State with respect to fish and wildlife management (including the regulation of hunting and fishing) on public land in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overflights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Overflights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of wilderness study areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Release of wilderness study areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_539r_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment update</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Assessment update</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>