<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/541b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/541b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/541b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_541b"><akn:num>541b</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries of scenic-research area; adjustments to subarea boundaries; development of management pla</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 541b. Boundaries of scenic-research area; adjustments to subarea boundaries; development of management plan; establishment of subareas; management objectives(a) Boundaries; adjustments to boundaries of sub­areasThe boundaries of the Area, and the boundaries of the subareas included therein, shall be those shown on the map entitled “Proposed Cascade Head Scenic-Research Area”, dated June 1974, which is on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief, Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture: Provided, That, from time to time, the Secretary may, after public hearing or other appropriate means for public participation, make adjustments in the boundaries of subareas to reflect changing natural conditions or to provide for more effective management of the Area and each of the subareas in accordance with the purposes and provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Management plan; development; time; contentsAs soon as practicable after December 22, 1974, the Secretary shall, with provisions for appropriate public participation in the planning process, develop a comprehensive management plan for the Area. Said plan shall prescribe specific management objectives and management controls necessary for the protection, management, and development of the Area and each of the subareas established pursuant to subsection (c) hereof.


(c) Subareas; establishment; management objectivesWithin the Area, the following subareas shall be established and shall be managed in accord with the following primary management objectives which shall be supplemental to the general management objectives applicable to the entire Area:(1) Estuary and Associated Wetlands Sub-area: An area managed to protect and perpetuate the fish and wildlife, scenic, and research-education values, while allowing dispersed recreation use, such as sport fishing, nonmotorized pleasure boating, waterfowl hunting, and other uses which the Secretary determines are compatible with the protec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries; adjustments to boundaries of sub­areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Boundaries; adjustments to boundaries of sub­areas The boundaries of the Area, and the boundaries of the subareas included therein, shall be those shown on the map entitled “Proposed Cascade Head Scenic-Research Area”, dated June 1974, which is on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief, Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture: Provided, That, from time to time, the Secretary may, after public hearing or other appropriate means for public participation, make adjustments in the boundaries of subareas to reflect changing natural conditions or to provide for more effective management of the Area and each of the subareas in accordance with the purposes and provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan; development; time; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management plan; development; time; contents As soon as practicable after December 22, 1974, the Secretary shall, with provisions for appropriate public participation in the planning process, develop a comprehensive management plan for the Area. Said plan shall prescribe specific management objectives and management controls necessary for the protection, management, and development of the Area and each of the subareas established pursuant to subsection (c) hereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subareas; establishment; management objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subareas; establishment; management objectives Within the Area, the following subareas shall be established and shall be managed in accord with the following primary management objectives which shall be supplemental to the general management objectives applicable to the entire Area:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>