<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544c"><akn:num>544c</akn:num><akn:heading>Columbia River Gorge Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544c. Columbia River Gorge Commission(a) Establishment and membership of Commission(1) To achieve the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title and to facilitate cooperation among the States of Oregon and Washington, and with the United States of America, the consent of Congress is given for an agreement described in sections 544 to 544p of this title pursuant to which, within one year after November 17, 1986—(A) the States of Oregon and Washington shall establish by way of an interstate agreement a regional agency known as the Columbia River Gorge Commission, and shall incorporate sections 544 to 544p of this title by specific reference in such agreement. The Commission shall carry out its functions and responsibilities in accordance with the provisions of the interstate agreement and of sections 544 to 544p of this title and shall not be considered an agency or instrumentality of the United States for the purpose of any Federal law;

(B) the States of Oregon and Washington shall provide to the Commission, State agencies, and the counties under State law the authority to carry out their respective functions and responsibilities in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection; and

(C) the States of Oregon and Washington shall appoint members of the Commission as provided in clauses (i) through (iii), subject to applicable State law: Provided, That the Governor of either State may extend the time for appointment of Commission members ninety days to provide more time for the States and counties to make such appointments. Membership of the Commission shall be as follows:(i) six members, comprised of one resident from each of the following counties: Hood River, Multnomah, and Wasco Counties, Oregon, and Clark, Klickitat, and Skamania Counties, Washington, to be appointed by the governing body of each of the respective counties: Provided, That in the event the governing body of a county fails to make such appointment, the Governor of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and membership of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and membership of Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable law For the purposes of providing a uniform system of laws, which, in addition to sections 544 to 544p of this title, are applicable to the Commission, the Commission shall adopt regulations relating to administrative procedure, the making of contracts, conflicts-of-interest, financial disclosure, open meetings of the Commission, advisory committees, and disclosure of information consistent with the more restrictive statutory provisions of either State. Regulations applicable to financial disclosure under this subsection shall be applied to members of the Commission without regard to the duration of their service on the Commission or the amount of compensation received for such service. No contract, obligation, or other action of the Commission shall be an obligation of the United States or an obligation secured by the full faith and credit of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to Commission Upon the request of the Commission, the Secretary and other Federal agencies are authorized to provide information, personnel, property, and services on a reimbursable basis, and the Secretary is authorized to provide technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis, to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its functions and responsibilities pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advisory committees The Commission shall establish voluntary technical and citizen advisory committees to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions and responsibilities pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>