<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544d"><akn:num>544d</akn:num><akn:heading>Scenic area management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544d. Scenic area management plan(a) StudiesWithin one year after the date the Commission is established, it shall, in cooperation with the Secretary, complete the following studies for use in preparing the management plan:(1) Resource inventoryThe Commission shall complete a resource inventory. The resource inventory shall—(A) document all existing land uses, natural features and limitations, scenic, natural, cultural, archaeological and recreation and economic resources and activities: Provided, That the location of any Indian burial grounds, village sites, and other areas of archaeological or religious significance shall not be made public information and such information shall be used for administrative purposes only; and

(B) incorporate without change the resource inventory developed by the Secretary pursuant to section 544f of this title for the special management areas.


(2) Economic opportunity studyThe Commission shall complete a study to identify opportunities to enhance the economies of communities in the scenic area in a manner consistent with the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.


(3) Recreation assessmentThe Commission shall complete an assessment of recreation resources and opportunities for enhancement of these resources. The recreation assessment shall—(A) designate the location and specify the construction of an interpretive center or other appropriate facility, to be located in the State of Oregon, and of a conference center or other appropriate facility, to be located in the State of Washington;

(B) identify areas within the scenic area that are suitable for other public use facilities, including but not limited to educational and interpretive facilities, campsites, picnic areas, boat launch facilities and river access areas; and

(C) subject to the treaty and other rights of Indian tribes, designate areas to provide increased access for recreation purposes to the Columbia River and its tributaries; and

(D) incorporate withou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Studies Within one year after the date the Commission is established, it shall, in cooperation with the Secretary, complete the following studies for use in preparing the management plan:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land use designations Within two years after the Commission is established, it shall develop land use designations for the use of non-Federal lands within the scenic area. The land use designations shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adoption of management plan Within three years after the date the Commission is established, it shall adopt a management plan for the scenic area. The Commission shall adopt the management plan by a majority vote of the members appointed, including at least three members from each State. The management plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standards for management plan The management plan and all land use ordinances and interim guidelines adopted pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title shall include provisions to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency consultation and public involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Agency consultation and public involvement The Secretary and the Commission shall exercise their responsibilities pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title in consultation with Federal, State, and local governments having jurisdiction within the scenic area or expertise pertaining to its administration and with Indian tribes. The Secretary and the Commission shall conduct public hearings and solicit public comment prior to final adoption of the management plan and the Commission shall conduct public hearings and solicit public comment prior to final adoption of land use ordinances. The Commission and the appropriate county shall promptly notify the Secretary, the States, local governments and Indian tribes of all proposed major development actions and residential development in the scenic area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrence of management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Concurrence of management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Revision of plan No sooner than five years after adoption of the management plan, but at least every ten years, the Commission shall review the management plan to determine whether it should be revised. The Commission shall submit any revised management plan to the Secretary for review and concurrence, in accordance with the provisions of this section for adoption of the management plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amendment of plan If the Commission determines at any time that conditions within the scenic area have significantly changed, it may amend the management plan. The Commission shall submit amendments to the management plan to the Secretary for review, in accordance with the provisions of this section for adoption of the management plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>