<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544f"><akn:num>544f</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of special management areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544f. Administration of special management areas(a) Administration of Federal lands(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. The Secretary shall administer Federal lands within the special management areas in accordance with sections 544 to 544p of this title and other laws, rules and regulations applicable to the national forest system. In addition, the construction of roads and the management, utilization and harvest of timber on Federal lands within the special management areas also shall be subject to Forest Service visual resource management guidelines. The Secretary shall utilize lands acquired through exchange in calculating the allowable sales quantity on the Gifford Pinchot and Mount Hood National Forests.


(b) Withdrawal of Federal landsSubject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands located in the special management areas are hereby withdrawn from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, from location, entry, and patent under the mining laws of the United States, and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing: Provided, That the Secretary may allow the exploration, development, or production of sand, gravel, and crushed rock as necessary to construct, maintain, or reconstruct roads in the special management areas.


(c) Resource inventoryThe Secretary shall complete a resource inventory for the special management areas consistent with the process and substance of the inventory prescribed by section 544d(a)(1) of this title.


(d) Recreation assessmentWithin two years after November 17, 1986, the Secretary shall complete an assessment of recreation resources in the special management areas and opportunities for enhancement of these resources. The recreation assessment shall—(1) identify areas within the special management areas suitable for designation by the Commission pursuant to section 544d of this title for the construction of an interpretive center or other appropri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration of Federal lands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Withdrawal of Federal lands Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal lands located in the special management areas are hereby withdrawn from all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, from location, entry, and patent under the mining laws of the United States, and from disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing: Provided, That the Secretary may allow the exploration, development, or production of sand, gravel, and crushed rock as necessary to construct, maintain, or reconstruct roads in the special management areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Resource inventory The Secretary shall complete a resource inventory for the special management areas consistent with the process and substance of the inventory prescribed by section 544d(a)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recreation assessment Within two years after November 17, 1986, the Secretary shall complete an assessment of recreation resources in the special management areas and opportunities for enhancement of these resources. The recreation assessment shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Land use designations Within three years after November 17, 1986, the Secretary shall develop land use designations for the special management areas. The land use designations shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines for land use ordinances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Guidelines for land use ordinances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. No subsec. (g) has been enacted. Adoption of special management area land use ordinances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Review by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrence by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Concurrence by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544f_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission reconsideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Commission reconsideration Upon receipt of notification of nonconcurrence by the Secretary, the Commission shall resubmit the land use ordinance to the appropriate county. Such county shall within ninety days, reconsider and revise the ordinance and resubmit the ordinance to the Commission for reconsideration in accordance with the provisions of this section. Should the Secretary again deny concurrence, the Commission shall either prepare a land use ordinance for such county pursuant to subsection (l) of this section or, by a two-thirds vote of the membership of the Commission including a majority of the members appointed from each State, determine that the ordinance is consistent with the management plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>