<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544h"><akn:num>544h</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544h. Interim management(a) Interim guidelines(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. Within one hundred eighty days after November 17, 1986, the Secretary shall develop interim guidelines for the scenic area outside urban areas to identify land use activities which are inconsistent with sections 544 to 544p of this title and to govern the authority to acquire land without the consent of the owner provided by subsection (b) of this section. The Secretary shall promptly notify the public of adoption of the interim guidelines and transmit the guidelines to each county. Guidelines adopted by the Secretary pursuant to this subsection shall remain in effect for each county until the Secretary has developed guidelines for the special management areas pursuant to section 544f of this title and the land use ordinances prescribed by section 544e of this title are in effect.


(b) Interim acquisition authority and injunctive reliefPrior to the concurrence by the Secretary of land use ordinances prescribed by section 544f of this title and the approval by the Commission of land use ordinances prescribed by section 544e of this title, the following authorities are granted:(1) The Secretary may acquire by condemnation any land or interest which is being used or threatened to be used in a manner inconsistent with the purposes for which the scenic area was established and which will cause or is likely to cause impacts adversely affecting the scenic, cultural, recreation, and natural resources of the scenic area: Provided, That no lands or interests therein can be acquired by condemnation pursuant to this section if used in the same manner and for the same purposes as used on November 17, 1986, unless such land is used for or interest is in the development of sand, gravel, or crushed rock, or the disposal of refuse: Provided further, That within thirty days of the filing by the Secretary of a complaint for condemnation of any land or interest in the scenic area, outs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interim guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim acquisition authority and injunctive relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interim acquisition authority and injunctive relief Prior to the concurrence by the Secretary of land use ordinances prescribed by section 544f of this title and the approval by the Commission of land use ordinances prescribed by section 544e of this title, the following authorities are granted:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of development action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of development action Prior to the effective date of a land use ordinance for each county pursuant to section 544e of this title, and concurrence of the Secretary on a land use ordinance for each county pursuant to section 544f of this title, the Commission shall review all proposals for major development actions and new residential development in such county in the scenic area, except urban areas. The Commission shall allow major development actions and new residential development only if it determines that such development is consistent with the standards contained in section 544d of this title and the purposes of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>