<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544l"><akn:num>544l</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544l. Implementation measures(a) Assistance to countiesThe Secretary shall provide technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis to counties for the development of land use ordinances prescribed by sections 544e and 544f of this title: Provided, That in the event a county fails to obtain approval by the Commission for a land use ordinance within three years after the date technical assistance is first provided under this subsection for the development of a land use ordinance, the Secretary shall terminate all technical assistance for any participation in the development of such ordinance.


(b) Payment of timber receipts(1) Notwithstanding the provisions of section 500 of this title, that portion of which is paid under such provisions to the State of Oregon with respect to the special management areas within the Mount Hood National Forest, the Gates of the Columbia Gorge Special Management Area, Mount Hood National Forest, and to the State of Washington with respect to the special management areas within the Gifford Pinchot National Forest—(A) not less than 50 per centum shall be expended for the benefit of the public schools of the county which has adopted implementation measures pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title; and

(B) the remainder shall be expended for the benefit of public roads or any public purposes of any county which has adopted implementation measures pursuant to sections 544 to 544p of this title.


(2) Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply—(A) to any amount paid by the Secretary of the Treasury under the provisions of law referred to in subsection (b)(1) at the end of any fiscal year ending before November 17, 1986; or

(B) for a particular county, if the county does not have in effect a land use ordinance which has been found consistent by the Commission and concurred on by the Secretary pursuant to section 544f of this title.



(c) Payments to local governments(1) Subject to section 544n(b) of this title, in the case of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance to counties The Secretary shall provide technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis to counties for the development of land use ordinances prescribed by sections 544e and 544f of this title: Provided, That in the event a county fails to obtain approval by the Commission for a land use ordinance within three years after the date technical assistance is first provided under this subsection for the development of a land use ordinance, the Secretary shall terminate all technical assistance for any participation in the development of such ordinance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of timber receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of timber receipts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to local governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to local governments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal consistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal consistency Except as otherwise provided in subsection (e) or in section 544o of this title, Federal agencies having responsibilities within the scenic area shall exercise such responsibilities consistent with the provisions of sections 544 to 544p of this title as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Federal expenditures affecting the scenic area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on Federal expenditures affecting the scenic area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544l_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of public lands Subject to valid existing rights, all public lands within the scenic area administered by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Land Management are hereby transferred without consideration to the jurisdiction of the Secretary to be managed as National Forest lands in accordance with the provisions of sections 544 to 544p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>