<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/544o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544o"><akn:num>544o</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544o. Savings provisions(a) Effect on rights of Indians, use of water, rivers and streams, interstate compacts, existing transmission facilities, hunting and fishing, forest plans, scenic areasNothing in sections 544 to 544p of this title shall—(1) affect or modify any treaty or other rights of any Indian tribe;

(2) except as provided in section 13(c),11 See References in Text note below. authorize the appropriation or use of water by any Federal, State, or local agency, Indian tribe, or any other entity or individual;

(3) except as provided in section 13(c),1 affect the rights or jurisdictions of the United States, the States, Indian tribes or other entities over waters of any river or stream or over any ground water resource or affect or interfere with transportation activities on any such river or stream;

(4) except as provided in section 13(c),1 alter, establish, or affect the respective rights of the United States, the States, Indian tribes, or any person with respect to any water or water-related right;

(5) alter, amend, repeal, interpret, modify, or be in conflict with any interstate compact made by the States before November 17, 1986;

(6) affect or modify the ability of the Bonneville Power Administration to operate, maintain, and modify existing transmission facilities;

(7) affect lands held in trust by the Secretary of the Interior for Indian tribes or individual members of Indian tribes or other lands acquired by the Army Corps of Engineers and administered by the Secretary of the Interior for the benefit of Indian tribes and individual members of Indian tribes;

(8) affect the laws, rules and regulations pertaining to hunting and fishing under existing State and Federal laws and Indian treaties;

(9) require any revision or amendment of any forest plan adopted pursuant to the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (Act of October 22, 1976, Public Law 94–588, as amended (16 U.S.C. 1600 et seq.)); or

(10) establish protective perimeters or buffer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on rights of Indians, use of water, rivers and streams, interstate compacts, existing transmission facilities, hunting and fishing, forest plans, scenic areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Effect on rights of Indians, use of water, rivers and streams, interstate compacts, existing transmission facilities, hunting and fishing, forest plans, scenic areas Nothing in sections 544 to 544p of this title shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of navigation facilities at Bonneville Dam</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Improvement of navigation facilities at Bonneville Dam Except for the offsite disposal of excavation material, nothing in sections 544 to 544p of this title shall be construed to affect or modify the responsibility of the United States Army Corps of Engineers to improve navigation facilities at Bonneville Dam pursuant to Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and responsibilities of non-Federal timber land owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rights and responsibilities of non-Federal timber land owners Except for the management, utilization, or disposal of timber resources of non-Federal lands within the special management areas, nothing in sections 544 to 544p of this title shall affect the rights and responsibilities of non-Federal timber land owners under the Oregon and Washington Forest Practices Acts or any county regulations which under applicable State law supersede such Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate compacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Interstate compacts Mandatory language in sections 544 to 544p of this title respecting the powers and responsibilities of the Commission shall be interpreted as conditions precedent to congressional consent to the interstate compact described in section 544c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to establish Columbia River Gorge Commission; responsibility of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Failure to establish Columbia River Gorge Commission; responsibility of Secretary In the event that the States of Washington and Oregon fail to comply with the provisions of section 544c of this title, the Secretary shall not be obligated to take actions which are predicated upon the establishment of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_544o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions of Secretary as major Federal actions affecting the environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Actions of Secretary as major Federal actions affecting the environment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>