<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/546a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/546a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/546a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_546a"><akn:num>546a</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 546a. Boundaries(a) Saint Helena IslandThe scenic area shall comprise all of Saint Helena Island, in Lake Michigan, Michigan, and all associated rocks, pinnacles, islands, and islets within one-eighth mile of the shore of Saint Helena Island.


(b) Boundaries of Hiawatha National Forest extendedUpon establishment of the scenic area, the boundaries of the Hiawatha National Forest shall be extended to include all of the lands within the scenic area. All such extended boundaries shall be deemed boundaries in existence as of January 1, 1965, for the purposes of section 100506 of title 54.


(c) Payments to local governmentsSolely for purposes of payments to local governments pursuant to section 6902 of title 31, lands acquired by the United States under sections 546 to 546a–5 of this title shall be treated as entitlement lands.


(Pub. L. 106–431, § 3, Nov. 6, 2000, 114 Stat. 1905; Pub. L. 113–287, § 5(d)(18), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3266.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 113–287 substituted “section 100506 of title 54” for “section 460l–9 of this title”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_546a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Saint Helena Island</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Saint Helena Island The scenic area shall comprise all of Saint Helena Island, in Lake Michigan, Michigan, and all associated rocks, pinnacles, islands, and islets within one-eighth mile of the shore of Saint Helena Island.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_546a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundaries of Hiawatha National Forest extended</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boundaries of Hiawatha National Forest extended Upon establishment of the scenic area, the boundaries of the Hiawatha National Forest shall be extended to include all of the lands within the scenic area. All such extended boundaries shall be deemed boundaries in existence as of January 1, 1965, for the purposes of section 100506 of title 54.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_546a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to local governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to local governments Solely for purposes of payments to local governments pursuant to section 6902 of title 31, lands acquired by the United States under sections 546 to 546a–5 of this title shall be treated as entitlement lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>