<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/552a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/552a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/552a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_552a"><akn:num>552a</akn:num><akn:heading>Restoration of withdrawn national forest lands to appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 552a. Restoration of withdrawn national forest lands to appropriation
The President, upon recommendation of the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture, may, by Executive order, when in his judgment the public interest would best be served thereby and after reasonable notice has been given through the Department of the Interior, restore any reserved national-forest lands covered by a cooperative agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture for the protection of a watershed within a national forest from which water is secured, to appropriation under any applicable public-lands law.
(May 28, 1940, ch. 220, § 1, 54 Stat. 224; Pub. L. 94–579, title VII, § 704(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2792.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The words “restore any of the lands so withdrawn” have been changed to “restore any reserved national-forest lands covered by a cooperative agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture for the protection of a watershed within a national forest from which water is secured” to reflect the change made by Pub. L. 94–579. See 1976 Amendment note below.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–579 struck out everything preceding second proviso which read: “Whenever a municipality obtains its water supply from a national forest and has entered into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary of Agriculture for the protection of the watershed within the national forest from which the water is secured, the President of the United States may, and he is, authorized, upon application by said municipality, and endorsed by the governing board of the county or counties in which the lands concerned are located and approved by the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior, to reserve and set aside from all forms of location, entry, or appropriation any national-forest lands, which are covered by such cooperative agreement, subject, however, to valid, existing rights and claims, and such reservation shall remain in force until revoked by the President or by an Act of Congress: </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>