<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/559d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/559d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/559d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_559d"><akn:num>559d</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 559d. Cooperation with other Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies
For the purposes of sections 559b to 559f of this title, in exercising the authority provided by section 559c of this title—(1) the Forest Service shall cooperate with any other Federal law enforcement agency having primary investigative jurisdiction over the offense committed;

(2) the Secretary may authorize the Forest Service to cooperate with the law enforcement officials of any Federal agency, State, or political subdivision in the investigation of violations of and enforcement of section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 841), other laws and regulations relating to marijuana and other controlled substances, and State drug control laws or ordinances for offenses committed within the National Forest System or which affect the administration of the National Forest System.11 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.

(3) the Forest Service shall cooperate with the Attorney General in carrying out the seizure and forfeiture provisions of section 511 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 881) for violations of the Controlled Substances Act [21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.] relating to offenses committed within the National Forest System, or which affect the administration of the National Forest System;

(4) the Secretary is authorized to designate law enforcement officers of any other Federal agency, when the Secretary determines such designation to be economical and in the public interest, and with the concurrence of that agency, to exercise the powers and authorities of the Forest Service while assisting the Forest Service in the National Forest System, or for activities administered by the Forest Service; and

(5) the Forest Service is authorized to accept law enforcement designation from any other Federal agency or agency of a State or political subdivision thereof for the purpose of cooperating in a multi-agency law enforcement task force investigation o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_559d_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the Forest Service shall cooperate with any other Federal law enforcement agency having primary investigative jurisdiction over the offense committed;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_559d_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the Secretary may authorize the Forest Service to cooperate with the law enforcement officials of any Federal agency, State, or political subdivision in the investigation of violations of and enforcement of section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 841), other laws and regulations relating to marijuana and other controlled substances, and State drug control laws or ordinances for offenses committed within the National Forest System or which affect the administration of the National Forest System.11 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_559d_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) the Forest Service shall cooperate with the Attorney General in carrying out the seizure and forfeiture provisions of section 511 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 881) for violations of the Controlled Substances Act [21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.] relating to offenses committed within the National Forest System, or which affect the administration of the National Forest System;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_559d_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) the Secretary is authorized to designate law enforcement officers of any other Federal agency, when the Secretary determines such designation to be economical and in the public interest, and with the concurrence of that agency, to exercise the powers and authorities of the Forest Service while assisting the Forest Service in the National Forest System, or for activities administered by the Forest Service; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_559d_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) the Forest Service is authorized to accept law enforcement designation from any other Federal agency or agency of a State or political subdivision thereof for the purpose of cooperating in a multi-agency law enforcement task force investigation of violations of the Controlled Substances Act [21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.] and other offenses committed in the course of or in connection with such violations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>