<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/565a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/565a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/565a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_565a_1"><akn:num>565a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements between Secretary of Agriculture and public or private agencies, organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 565a–1. Cooperative agreements between Secretary of Agriculture and public or private agencies, organizations, institutions, and persons covering Forest Service programs; authority; funding
To facilitate the administration of the programs and activities of the Forest Service, the Secretary is authorized to negotiate and enter into cooperative agreements with public or private agencies, organizations, institutions, or persons to construct, operate, and maintain cooperative pollution abatement equipment and facilities, including sanitary landfills, water systems, and sewer systems; to engage in cooperative manpower and job training and development programs; to develop and publish cooperative environmental education and forest history materials; and to perform forestry protection, including fire protection, timber stand improvement, debris removal, and thinning of trees. The Secretary may enter into aforesaid agreements when he determines that the public interest will be benefited and that there exists a mutual interest other than monetary considerations. In such cooperative arrangements, the Secretary is authorized to advance or reimburse funds to cooperators from any Forest Service appropriation available for similar kinds of work or by furnishing or sharing materials, supplies, facilities, or equipment without regard to the provisions of section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31, relating to the advance of public moneys.
(Pub. L. 94–148, § 1, Dec. 12, 1975, 89 Stat. 804.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
“Section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31” substituted in text for “the Act of January 31, 1823 (Rev. Stat. 3648, as amended; 31 U.S.C. 529)” on authority of Pub. L. 97–258, § 4(b), Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 1067, the first section of which enacted Title 31, Money and Finance.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Inapplicability of Chapter 63 of Title 31Chapter 63 of title 31 not applicable to an agreement entered into under this section, see section 1011a(d)(2) of this tit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>