<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/579c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/579c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/579c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_579c_1"><akn:num>579c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest Service interest bearing account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 579c–1. Forest Service interest bearing account(a) Investment authorityAny monies covered into the Treasury under section 579c of this title, including all monies that were previously collected by the United States in a forfeiture, judgment, compromise, or settlement, shall be invested by the Secretary of the Treasury in interest bearing obligations of the United States to the extent the amounts are not, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury, required to meet current withdrawals.


(b) Availability of fundsAny interest earned under subsection (a) shall be available in the same manner as the monies covered into the Treasury under section 579c of this title to cover the costs to the United States specified in section 579c of this title.


(c) Use of fundsAny portion of the monies received or earned under subsection (a) in excess of the amount expended in performing the work necessitated by the action which led to their receipt may be used to cover the other work specified in section 579c of this title.


(d) Effective dateThis section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.


(Pub. L. 117–328, div. G, title IV, § 441, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 4832.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Investment authority Any monies covered into the Treasury under section 579c of this title, including all monies that were previously collected by the United States in a forfeiture, judgment, compromise, or settlement, shall be invested by the Secretary of the Treasury in interest bearing obligations of the United States to the extent the amounts are not, in the judgment of the Secretary of the Treasury, required to meet current withdrawals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of funds Any interest earned under subsection (a) shall be available in the same manner as the monies covered into the Treasury under section 579c of this title to cover the costs to the United States specified in section 579c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds Any portion of the monies received or earned under subsection (a) in excess of the amount expended in performing the work necessitated by the action which led to their receipt may be used to cover the other work specified in section 579c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>