<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_580d"><akn:num>580d</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Forest Service structures or improvements and land by public and private agencies, etc.; term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 580d. Use of Forest Service structures or improvements and land by public and private agencies, etc.; terms
The Secretary of Agriculture, under such regulations as he may prescribe and at rates and for periods not exceeding thirty years as determined by him, is authorized to permit the use by public and private agencies, corporations, firms, associations, or individuals, of structures or improvements under the administrative control of the Forest Service and land used in connection therewith: Provided, That as all or a part of the consideration for permits issued under this section, the Secretary may require the permittees at their expense to renovate, recondition, improve, and maintain the structures and land to a satisfactory standard.
(Apr. 24, 1950, ch. 97, § 7, 64 Stat. 84; Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(e) [title III, § 346], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–231, 2681–298.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–277, which directed the substitution of “renovate, recondition, improve, and maintain” for “recondition and maintain,”, was executed by making the substitution for language which did not include a comma after “maintain” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Authorization for Lease of Forest Service SitesPub. L. 115–334, title VIII, § 8623, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4853, as amended by Pub. L. 118–234, title I, § 151, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2866, provided that:
“(a) Definitions.—In this section:“(1) Administrative site.—“(A) In general.—The term ‘administrative site’ means—“(i) any facility or improvement, including curtilage, that was acquired or is used specifically for purposes of administration of the National Forest System;

“(ii) any Federal land that—     “(I) is associated with a facility or improvement described in clause (i) that was acquired or is used specifically for purposes of administration of Forest Service activities; and

     “(II) underlies or abuts the facility or improvement; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>