<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/580k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_580k"><akn:num>580k</akn:num><akn:heading>Grazing advisory boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 580k. Grazing advisory boards(a) Composition; election meetings(1) To provide national forest grazing permittees means for the expression of their recommendations concerning the management and administration of national forest grazing lands, a local advisory board shall be constituted and elected as hereinafter provided for each national forest or administrative subdivision thereof, whenever a majority of the grazing permittees of such national forest or administrative subdivision so petitions the Secretary of Agriculture. Each elected local advisory board existing for such purpose on April 24, 1950, and recognized as such by the Department of Agriculture, shall continue to be the local advisory board for the unit or area it represents, until replaced by a local advisory board or boards constituted and elected as hereinafter provided.

(2) Each such local advisory board shall be constituted and elected under rules and regulations, consistent herewith, now or hereafter approved by the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall be recognized by him as representing the grazing permittees of the national forest or administrative subdivision thereof for which such local advisory board has been constituted and elected.

(3) Each such local advisory board shall consist of not less than three nor more than twelve members, who shall be national forest grazing permittees in the area for which such board is constituted, elected, and recognized. In addition, a wildlife representative may be appointed as a member of each such board by the State game commission, or the corresponding public body of the State in which the advisory board is located, to advise on wildlife problems.

(4) Each such local advisory board shall meet at least once annually, at a time to be fixed by such board, and at such other time or times as its members may determine, or on the call of the chairman thereof or of the Secretary of Agriculture or his authorized representative.


(b) Advice and recommendations o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_580k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition; election meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Composition; election meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_580k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice and recommendations on matters within jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advice and recommendations on matters within jurisdiction Upon the request of any party affected thereby, the Secretary of Agriculture, or his duly authorized representative, shall refer to the appropriate local advisory board for its advice and recommendations any matter pertaining to (1) the modification of the terms, or the denial of a renewal of, or a reduction in, a grazing permit, or (2) the establishment or modification of an individual or community allotment. In the event the Secretary of Agriculture, or his duly authorized representative, shall overrule, disregard, or modify any such recommendations, he, or such representative, shall furnish in writing to the local advisory board his reasons for such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_580k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification by Secretary of Agriculture of intention to issue regulations; recommendations; written explanation of reasons for overruling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification by Secretary of Agriculture of intention to issue regulations; recommendations; written explanation of reasons for overruling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>