<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_583d"><akn:num>583d</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice; registered mail and publication; costs; contents; request for hearing; time; determination a</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 583d. Notice; registered mail and publication; costs; contents; request for hearing; time; determination and record available for inspection
Before any sustained-yield unit authorized by section 583 or 583b of this title shall be established, and before any cooperative agreement authorized by section 583a or 583c of this title shall be entered into, advance notice thereof shall be given by registered mail or by certified mail to each landowner whose land is proposed to be included and by publication in one or more newspapers of general circulation in the vicinity of the place where the timber is located, and the costs incident to such publication may be paid out of any funds available for the protection or management of the federally owned or administered forest land involved. This notice shall state: (1) the location of the proposed unit; (2) the name of each proposed cooperator; (3) the duration of the proposed cooperative agreement or agreements; (4) the location and estimated quantity of timber on the land of each proposed cooperator and on the Federal land involved; (5) the expected rate of cutting of such timber; and (6) the time and place of a public hearing to be held not less than thirty days after the first publication of said notice for the presentation of the advantages and disadvantages of the proposed action to the community or communities affected.
Before any sale agreement made without competition and involving more than $500 in stumpage value of federally owned or administered timber shall be entered into under this subchapter, advance notice thereof shall be given by publication once weekly for four consecutive weeks in one or more newspapers of general circulation in the vicinity of the place where the timber is located, and the costs incident to such publication may be paid out of any funds available for the protection or management of federally owned or administered forest land within the unit concerned. This notice shall state: (1) the quanti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>