<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/583j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_583j"><akn:num>583j</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purposes of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 583j. Establishment and purposes of Foundation(a) EstablishmentThere is established the National Forest Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the “Foundation”) as a charitable and nonprofit corporation domiciled in the District of Columbia.


(b) PurposesThe purposes of the Foundation are to—(1) encourage, accept, and administer private gifts of money, and of real and personal property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the activities and services of the Forest Service of the Department of Agriculture;

(2) undertake and conduct activities that further the purposes for which units of the National Forest System are established and are administered and that are consistent with approved forest plans; and

(3) undertake, conduct and encourage educational, technical and other assistance, and other activities that support the multiple use, research, cooperative forestry and other programs administered by the Forest Service.


(c) Limitation and conflicts of interests(1) The Foundation shall not participate or intervene in a political campaign on behalf of any candidate for public office.

(2) No director, officer, or employee of the Foundation shall participate, directly or indirectly, in the consideration or determination of any question before the Foundation affecting—(A) the financial interests of the director, officer, or employee; or

(B) the interests of any corporation partnership, entity, or organization in which such director, officer, or employee—(i) is an officer, director, or trustee; or

(ii) has any direct or indirect financial interest.




(Pub. L. 101–593, title IV, § 402, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 2970.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 1993 AmendmentPub. L. 103–106, § 1, Oct. 12, 1993, 107 Stat. 1031, provided that: “This Act [amending sections 583j–3 and 583j–8 of this title and enacting provisions set out as a note under section 583j–3 of this title] may be cited as the ‘National Forest Foundation Act Amendment Act of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_583j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the National Forest Foundation (hereinafter referred to as the “Foundation”) as a charitable and nonprofit corporation domiciled in the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_583j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of the Foundation are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_583j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation and conflicts of interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation and conflicts of interests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>