<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_590c"><akn:num>590c</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions under which benefits of law extended to nongovernment controlled lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 590c. Conditions under which benefits of law extended to nongovernment controlled lands
As a condition to the extending of any benefits under this chapter to any lands not owned or controlled by the United States or any of its agencies, the Secretary of Agriculture may, insofar as he may deem necessary for the purposes of this chapter, require the following:(1) The enactment and reasonable safeguards for the enforcement of State and local laws imposing suitable permanent restrictions on the use of such lands and otherwise providing for the prevention of soil erosion.

(2) Agreements or covenants as to the permanent use of such lands.

(3) Contributions in money, services, materials, or otherwise, to any operations conferring such benefits.

(4)(A) The payment of user fees for conservation planning technical assistance if the Secretary determines that the fees, subject to subparagraph (B), are—(i) reasonable and appropriate;

(ii) assessed for conservation planning technical assistance resulting in the development of a conservation plan; and

(iii) assessed based on the size of the land or the complexity of the resource issues involved.


(B) Fees under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $150 per conservation plan for which technical assistance is provided.

(C) The Secretary may waive fees otherwise required under subparagraph (A) in the case of conservation planning technical assistance provided—(i) to beginning farmers or ranchers (as defined in section 1991(a) of title 7);

(ii) to limited resource farmers or ranchers (as defined by the Secretary);

(iii) to socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers (as defined in section 2003(e) of title 7);

(iv) to qualify for an exemption from ineligibility under section 3812 of this title; or

(v) to comply with Federal, State, or local regulatory requirements.



(Apr. 27, 1935, ch. 85, § 3, 49 Stat. 163; Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title VII, § 705(a), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 1192.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2013—Pub. L. 113</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590c_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The enactment and reasonable safeguards for the enforcement of State and local laws imposing suitable permanent restrictions on the use of such lands and otherwise providing for the prevention of soil erosion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590c_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agreements or covenants as to the permanent use of such lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590c_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Contributions in money, services, materials, or otherwise, to any operations conferring such benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590c_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>