<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_590h"><akn:num>590h</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments and grants of aid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 590h. Payments and grants of aid(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(2), Sept. 27, 1962, 76 Stat. 605

(b) Conservation and environmental assistance(1) Environmental quality incentives programThe Secretary shall provide technical assistance, cost-share payments, and incentive payments to operators through the environmental quality incentives program in accordance with subchapter A of chapter 4 of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 [16 U.S.C. 3839aa et seq.].


(2) to (4) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(A)(i)(I), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1004

(5) State, county, and area committees(A) Appointment of State committeesThe Secretary shall appoint in each State a State committee composed of not fewer than 3 nor more than 5 members who are fairly representative of the farmers in the State. The members of a State committee shall serve at the pleasure of the Secretary for such term as the Secretary may establish.


(B) Establishment and elections for county, area, or local committees(i) Establishment(I) In generalIn each county or area in which activities are carried out under this section, the Secretary shall establish a county or area committee.


(II) Local administrative areasThe Secretary may designate local administrative areas within a county or a larger area under the jurisdiction of a committee established under subclause (I).



(ii) Composition of county, area, or local committees(I) In generalExcept as provided in subclause (II), a committee established under clause (i) shall consist of not fewer than 3 nor more than 5 members that—(aa) are fairly representative of the agricultural producers within the area covered by the county, area, or local committee; and

(bb) are elected by the agricultural producers that participate or cooperate in programs administered within the area under the jurisdiction of the county, area, or local committee.


(II) Combination or consolidation of areasA committee established by combin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 87–703, title I, § 101(2), Sept. 27, 1962, 76 Stat. 605</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation and environmental assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conservation and environmental assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment of acreage allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Apportionment of acreage allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (f) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–127, title III, § 336(a)(1)(A)(ii), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1004</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) to (f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assignment of payments A payment that may be made to a producer under this section may be assigned only in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary. This subsection shall not authorize any suit against or impose any liability on the Secretary, any disbursing agent, or any agency of the United States if payment is made to the producer without regard to the existence of any such assignment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>