<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590q–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590q–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590q–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_590q_3"><akn:num>590q–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical lands resource conservation program in Great Plains area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 590q–3. Critical lands resource conservation program in Great Plains area
Notwithstanding any other provision of law—(a) Authorization for programThe Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to formulate and carry out a program with owners and operators of land in the Great Plains area as described in section 590p(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title to reduce runoff, soil and water erosion, and otherwise to promote the conservation of soil and water resources in such area through the conversion of cropland from soil depleting uses to conserving uses including the production of soil conserving cover crops.


(b) Terms of agreements with owners or operatorsTo effectuate the purposes of the program, the Secretary may enter into an agreement for a two-year period with an owner or operator as described in subsection (a) whereby the owner or operator shall agree to devote to a soil conserving cover crop a specifically designated acreage of cropland on the farm up to 50 per centum of the acreage which had been planted to any soil depleting crop or crops in any of the two years preceding the date of the agreement. The agreement shall be renewable for annual periods thereafter subject to the mutual agreement of the owner or operator and the Secretary. In such agreement, the owner or operator shall agree (1) to plant a legume, or if not adapted to such area, an annual, biennial, or a perennial cover crop, as specified in the agreement; (2) to divert from production such portion of one or more crops designated by the Secretary as the Secretary determines necessary to effectuate the purpose of the program; (3) not to harvest any crop from or graze the designated acreage during the agreement period, unless the Secretary determines that it is necessary to permit grazing or harvesting in order to alleviate damage, hardship, or suffering caused by severe drought, flood, or other natural disaster, and consents to such grazing or harvesting subject to an appropriat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization for program The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to formulate and carry out a program with owners and operators of land in the Great Plains area as described in section 590p(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title to reduce runoff, soil and water erosion, and otherwise to promote the conservation of soil and water resources in such area through the conversion of cropland from soil depleting uses to conserving uses including the production of soil conserving cover crops.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of agreements with owners or operators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of agreements with owners or operators To effectuate the purposes of the program, the Secretary may enter into an agreement for a two-year period with an owner or operator as described in subsection (a) whereby the owner or operator shall agree to devote to a soil conserving cover crop a specifically designated acreage of cropland on the farm up to 50 per centum of the acreage which had been planted to any soil depleting crop or crops in any of the two years preceding the date of the agreement. The agreement shall be renewable for annual periods thereafter subject to the mutual agreement of the owner or operator and the Secretary. In such agreement, the owner or operator shall agree (1) to plant a legume, or if not adapted to such area, an annual, biennial, or a perennial cover crop, as specified in the agreement; (2) to divert from production such portion of one or more crops designated by the Secretary as the Secretary determines necessary to effectuate the purpose of the p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual adjustment payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual adjustment payments In consideration for such agreement, the Secretary shall make annual adjustment payments to the owner or operator for the period of the agreement at such rate or rates not in excess of $30 per acre as the Secretary determines to be fair and reasonable. The Secretary may use an advertising and bid procedure in determining the lands in any area to be covered by agreements and the payment rate therefor. The Secretary and the owner or operator may agree that the annual adjustment payments for the agreement period shall be made either upon approval of the agreement or in such installments as they may agree to be desirable: Provided, That for each year any annual adjustment payment is made in advance of performance, the annual adjustment payment shall be reduced by 5 per centum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination of agreements The Secretary may terminate any agreement under the program, by mutual agreement with the owner or operator, if the Secretary determines that such termination would be in the public interest, and may agree with the owner or operator to such modification of agreements as the Secretary may determine to be desirable to carry out the purposes of the program or facilitate its administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preservation of cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history The Secretary may, to the extent the Secretary deems it desirable, provide by appropriate regulations for preservation of cropland, crop acreage, and allotment history applicable to acreage diverted from the production of crops to establish vegetative cover for the purpose of any Federal program under which such history is used as a basis for an allotment or other limitation or for participation in such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of Federal and non-Federal offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Utilization of Federal and non-Federal offices In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall utilize the services of local, county, and State committees established under section 590h of this title and the technical services of the Soil Conservation Service and soil and water conservation districts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program payments In case any producer who is entitled to any payment under the program dies, becomes incompetent, or disappears before receiving such payment, or is succeeded by another who renders or completes the required performance, the payment shall, without regard to any other provisions of law, be made as the Secretary may determine to be fair and reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenants and sharecroppers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tenants and sharecroppers The Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers, including provision for sharing, on a fair and equitable basis, in payments under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rules and regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_590q_3_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; utilization of Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations; utilization of Commodity Credit Corporation There are authorized to be appropriated for the period beginning October 1, 1977, and ending September 30, 1981, such sums as may be necessary to carry out the program provided for in this section. The Secretary is authorized to utilize the facilities, services, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation in discharging the Secretary’s functions and responsibilities under the program, including payment of costs of administration: Provided, That the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not make any expenditures for such purposes unless the Corporation has received funds to cover such expenditures from appropriations made to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>