<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/590y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_590y"><akn:num>590y</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization and purpose of investigation, construction, and maintenance of projects; title to proj</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 590y. Authorization and purpose of investigation, construction, and maintenance of projects; title to projects; limitation on costs
For the purpose of stabilizing water supply and thereby rehabilitating farmers on the land and providing opportunities for permanent settlement of farm families, the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as “the Secretary”) is authorized to investigate and, upon compliance with the provisions of this subchapter, to construct water conservation and utilization projects in the Great Plains and arid and semiarid areas of the United States, and to operate and maintain each such project in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter; Provided, That the United States shall retain title to the dams, reservoirs, irrigation, and other project works until Congress otherwise provides: And provided further, That expenditures from appropriations made directly pursuant to the authority contained in section 590z–10(1) of this title to meet reimbursable construction costs allocated to irrigation as defined in section 590z–2(b) of this title shall not exceed $2,000,000 for dams and reservoirs in any one project, and that expenditures from appropriations made directly pursuant to the authority contained in section 590z–10(1) of this title to meet costs allocated to flood control by the Secretary after consultation with the Chief of Engineers, Department of the Army, shall not exceed $500,000 on any one project.
(Aug. 11, 1939, ch. 717, § 1, 53 Stat. 1418; Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 861, 54 Stat. 1119; Mar. 7, 1942, ch. 164, 56 Stat. 142; July 16, 1943, ch. 242, § 1, 57 Stat. 566; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1943—Act July 16, 1943, raised amount of expenditures for dams and reservoirs on any one project from $1,000,000 to $2,000,000.
1942—Act Mar. 7, 1942, amended last proviso.
1940—Act Oct. 14, 1940, reenacted section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Departme</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>