<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_620c"><akn:num>620c</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on exports of unprocessed timber from State and other public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 620c. Restriction on exports of unprocessed timber from State and other public lands(a) Order to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public landsExcept as provided in subsection (g), the Secretary of Commerce shall issue orders to prohibit the export from the United States of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, as provided in subsection (b).


(b) Schedule for determination to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands(1) States with annual sales of 400,000,000 board feet or lessWith respect to States with annual sales volumes of 400,000,000 board feet or less, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective June 1, 1993.


(2) States with annual sales of greater than 400,000,000 board feetWith respect to any State with an annual sales volume greater than 400,000,000 board feet, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue an order referred to in subsection (a) to prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the export of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, effective as of November 14, 1997.


(3) Prohibition on substitution(A) ProhibitionSubject to subparagraph (B), each order of the Secretary of Commerce under paragraph (1) or (2) shall also prohibit, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person from purchasing, directly or indirectly, unprocessed timber originating from public lands in a State if—(i) such unprocessed timber would be used in substitution for exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State; or

(ii) such person has, during the preceding 24-month period, exported unprocessed timber originating from private lands in that State.


(B) ExemptionThe prohibitions referred to in subparagraph (A) shall not apply in a State on or after the date on which—(i) the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Order to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands Except as provided in subsection (g), the Secretary of Commerce shall issue orders to prohibit the export from the United States of unprocessed timber originating from public lands, as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule for determination to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Schedule for determination to prohibit export of unprocessed timber originating from State or other public lands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorized State programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prior contracts Nothing in this section shall apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Western red cedar</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Western red cedar Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede section 4606(i) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Presidential authority The President is authorized, after suitable notice and a public comment period of not less than 120 days, to suspend the provisions of this section if a panel of experts has reported to the Dispute Settlement Body of the World Trade Organization (as the term “World Trade Organization” is defined in section 3501(8) of title 19), or a ruling issued under the formal dispute settlement proceeding provided under any other trade agreement finds, that the provisions of this section are in violation of, or inconsistent with, United States obligations under that trade agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal or modifications of State restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Removal or modifications of State restrictions Based upon a determination that it is in the national economic interest, the President may remove or modify any prohibition on exports from public lands in a State if that State petitions the President to remove or modify such prohibition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of prior Federal law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect of prior Federal law No provision of Federal law which imposes requirements with respect to the generation of revenue from State timberlands and was enacted before August 20, 1990, shall be construed to invalidate, supersede, or otherwise affect any action of a State or political subdivision of a State pursuant to sections 620 to 620j of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surplus timber</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Surplus timber The prohibitions on exports contained in orders of the Secretary of Commerce issued under subsection (a) shall not apply to specific quantities of grades and species of unprocessed timber originating from public lands which the Secretary concerned determines by rule to be surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States. Any such determination may, by rule, be withdrawn by the Secretary concerned if the Secretary determines that the affected timber is no longer surplus to the needs of timber manufacturing facilities in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>