<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/620f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_620f"><akn:num>620f</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 620f. Regulations and review(a) Regulations(1) Agriculture and InteriorThe Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall, in consultation, each prescribe new coordinated and consistent regulations to implement sections 620 to 620j of this title on lands which they administer.


(2) CommerceThe Secretary of Commerce shall promulgate such rules and guidelines as may be necessary to carry out sections 620 to 620j of this title.


(3) Deadline(A) In general.—Except as otherwise provided in sections 620 to 620j of this title, regulations and guidelines required under this subsection shall be issued not later than June 1, 1998.

(B) The regulations and guidelines issued under sections 620 to 620j of this title that were in effect prior to September 8, 1995 shall remain in effect until new regulations and guidelines are issued under subparagraph (A).


(4) Painting and branding(A) In generalThe Secretary concerned shall issue regulations that impose reasonable painting, branding, or other forms of marking or tracking requirements on unprocessed timber if—(i) the benefits of the requirements outweigh the cost of complying with the requirements; and

(ii) the Secretary determines that, without the requirements, it is likely that the unprocessed timber—(I) would be exported in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title; or

(II) if the unprocessed timber originated from Federal lands, would be substituted for unprocessed timber originating from private lands west of the 100th Meridian in the contiguous 48 States in violation of sections 620 to 620j of this title.



(B) Minimum sizeThe Secretary concerned shall not impose painting, branding, or other forms of marking or tracking requirements on—(i) the face of a log that is less than 7 inches in diameter; or

(ii) unprocessed timber that is less than 8 feet in length or less than ⅓ sound wood.


(C) Waivers(i) In generalThe Secretary concerned may waive log painting and branding requirements—(I) for a geographic area, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review The Secretaries of Agriculture and Interior shall, in consultation, review the definition of unprocessed timber under section 620e(7) of this title for purposes of sections 620 to 620j of this title and, not later than 18 months after August 20, 1990, submit to the Congress any recommendations they have with respect to such definition. Specifically, the Secretaries shall report on the effects of maintaining 2 size standards under section 620e(B)(ii) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “620e(7)(B)(ii)”. and (iii) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>