<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6232" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6232/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6232/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6232"><akn:num>6232</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for occupancy and use of National Forest System lands and facilities by organizational camps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6232. Fees for occupancy and use of National Forest System lands and facilities by organizational camps(a) Land use fee(1) Percentage of land valueThe Secretary shall charge an annual land use fee for each organizational camp for its occupancy and use of National Forest System lands equal to 5 percent of the product of the following:(A) The total number of acres of National Forest System lands authorized for the organizational camp.

(B) The estimated per-acre market value of land and buildings in the county where the camp is located, as reported in the most recent Census of Agriculture conducted by the National Agricultural Statistics Service.


(2) Annual adjustmentThe land use fee determined under paragraph (1) for an organizational camp shall be adjusted annually by the annual compounded rate of change between the two most recent Censuses of Agriculture.


(3) Reduction in fees(A) Type of participantsThe Secretary shall reduce the land use fee determined under paragraph (1) proportionate to the number of individuals with a disability and children at risk who annually attend the organizational camp.


(B) Type of programsAfter making the reduction required by subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall reduce the remaining land use fee amount by up to 60 percent, proportionate to the number of persons who annually attend the organizational camp who participate in youth programs through organized and supervised social, citizenship, character-building, or faith-based activities oriented to outdoor-recreation experiences.


(C) Relation to minimum feeThe reductions made under this paragraph may not reduce the land use fee for an organizational camp below the minimum land use fee required to be charged under paragraph (4).


(D) Special considerationsFor purposes of determining the amount of the land use fee reduction required under subparagraph (A) or (B), the Secretary may not take into consideration the existence of sponsorships or scholarships to assist persons in at</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6232_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Land use fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6232_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility use fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facility use fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6232_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee related to receipt of other revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fee related to receipt of other revenues If an organizational camp derives revenue from the use of National Forest System lands or authorized facilities described in subsection (b) for purposes other than to introduce young people or individuals with a disability to activities that they may not otherwise experience and to educate them on natural resource issues, the Secretary shall charge, in addition to the land use fee imposed under subsection (a) and the facility use fee imposed under subsection (b), an additional fee equal to 5 percent of that revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6232_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Work-in-lieu program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Work-in-lieu program Subject to subsections (a)(4) and (b)(2), section 539f of this title shall apply to the use fees imposed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>