<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6406" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6406/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6406/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6406"><akn:num>6406</akn:num><akn:heading>Block grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6406. Block grants(a) In generalIn each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2023 and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall provide block grants of financial assistance of not less than $500,000 to each covered State to support management and restoration activities and further the implementation of coral reef action plans in effect under section 6404 of this title by covered States and non-Federal coral reef stewardship partnerships in accordance with this section. The Administrator shall review each covered State’s application for block grant funding to ensure that applications are consistent with applicable action plans and the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.


(b) Responsibilities of the AdministratorThe Administrator is responsible for—(1) providing guidance on the proper documentation of expenditures authorized under this chapter;

(2) issuing annual solicitations to covered States for awards under this section; and

(3) determining the appropriate allocation of additional amounts among covered States in accordance with this section.


(c) Responsibilities of covered StatesEach covered State is responsible for documenting and reporting—(1) such State’s use of Federal funds received under this chapter; and

(2) such expenditures of non-Federal funds made in furtherance of coral reef management and restoration as the Administrator determines appropriate.


(d) Cooperative agreementsSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator may seek to enter into a cooperative agreement with a covered State to fund coral reef conservation and restoration activities in waters managed under the jurisdiction of such covered State that are consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy and any applicable action plan under section 6404 of this title.


(e) All Islands CommitteeThe Administrator may enter into a cooperative agreement with the All Islands Committee of the Task Force to provide support for its</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6406_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2023 and subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall provide block grants of financial assistance of not less than $500,000 to each covered State to support management and restoration activities and further the implementation of coral reef action plans in effect under section 6404 of this title by covered States and non-Federal coral reef stewardship partnerships in accordance with this section. The Administrator shall review each covered State’s application for block grant funding to ensure that applications are consistent with applicable action plans and the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6406_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibilities of the Administrator The Administrator is responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6406_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of covered States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities of covered States Each covered State is responsible for documenting and reporting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6406_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative agreements Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator may seek to enter into a cooperative agreement with a covered State to fund coral reef conservation and restoration activities in waters managed under the jurisdiction of such covered State that are consistent with the National Coral Reef Resilience Strategy and any applicable action plan under section 6404 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6406_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>All Islands Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) All Islands Committee The Administrator may enter into a cooperative agreement with the All Islands Committee of the Task Force to provide support for its activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>