<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6415"><akn:num>6415</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6415. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.


(2) Alaska Native CorporationThe term “Alaska Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term “Native Corporation” in section 1602 of title 43.


(3) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.


(4) ConservationThe term “conservation” means the use of methods and procedures necessary to preserve or sustain native corals and associated species as diverse, viable, and self-perpetuating coral reef ecosystems with minimal impacts from invasive species, including—(A) all activities associated with resource management, such as monitoring, assessment, protection, restoration, sustainable use, management of habitat, and maintenance or augmentation of genetic diversity;

(B) mapping;

(C) scientific expertise and technical assistance in the development and implementation of management strategies for marine protected areas and marine resources required by Federal law;

(D) law enforcement;

(E) conflict resolution initiatives;

(F) community outreach and education; and

(G) promotion of safe and ecologically sound navigation and anchoring.


(5) CoralThe term “coral” means species of the phylum Cnidaria, including—(A) all species of the orders Antipatharia (black corals), Scleractinia (stony corals), Alcyonacea (soft corals, organ pipe corals, gorgonians), and Helioporacea (blue coral), of the class Anthozoa; and

(B) all species of the order Anthoathecata (fire corals and other hydrocorals) of the class Hydrozoa.


(6) Coral productsThe term “coral products” means any living or dead specimens, parts, or derivatives, or any product containing specimens, parts, or derivatives, of any species of coral.


(7) Coral reefThe term “coral</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska Native Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Alaska Native Corporation The term “Alaska Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term “Native Corporation” in section 1602 of title 43.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Conservation The term “conservation” means the use of methods and procedures necessary to preserve or sustain native corals and associated species as diverse, viable, and self-perpetuating coral reef ecosystems with minimal impacts from invasive species, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Coral The term “coral” means species of the phylum Cnidaria, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Coral products The term “coral products” means any living or dead specimens, parts, or derivatives, or any product containing specimens, parts, or derivatives, of any species of coral.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral reef</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Coral reef The term “coral reef” means calcium carbonate structures in the form of a reef or shoal, composed in whole or in part by living coral, skeletal remains of coral, crustose coralline algae, and other associated sessile marine plants and animals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral reef ecosystem</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Coral reef ecosystem The term “coral reef ecosystem” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral reef ecosystem services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Coral reef ecosystem services The term “coral reef ecosystem services” means the attributes and benefits provided by coral reef ecosystems including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6415_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Native entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Covered Native entity The term “covered Native entity” means a Native entity with interests in a coral reef ecosystem.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>