<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6513" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6513/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6513/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6513"><akn:num>6513</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6513. Prioritization(a) In generalIn accordance with the Implementation Plan, the Secretary shall develop an annual program of work for Federal land that gives priority to authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects that provide for the protection of at-risk communities or watersheds or that implement community wildfire protection plans.


(b) Collaboration(1) In generalThe Secretary shall consider recommendations under subsection (a) that are made by at-risk communities that have developed community wildfire protection plans.


(2) ExemptionChapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the planning process and recommendations concerning community wildfire protection plans.



(c) Administration(1) In generalFederal agency involvement in developing a community wildfire protection plan, or a recommendation made in a community wildfire protection plan, shall not be considered a Federal agency action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(2) ComplianceIn implementing authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects on Federal land, the Secretary shall, in accordance with section 6514 of this title, comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).



(d) Funding allocation(1) Federal land(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall use not less than 50 percent of the funds allocated for authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in the wildland-urban interface.


(B) Applicability and allocationThe funding allocation in subparagraph (A) shall apply at the national level. The Secretary may allocate the proportion of funds differently than is required under subparagraph (A) within individual management units as appropriate, in particular to conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects on land described in section 6512(a)(4) of this title.


(C) Wildland-urban interfaceIn the case of an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project for which a decision notice is issued during t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6513_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In accordance with the Implementation Plan, the Secretary shall develop an annual program of work for Federal land that gives priority to authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects that provide for the protection of at-risk communities or watersheds or that implement community wildfire protection plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6513_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collaboration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6513_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6513_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6513_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross-boundary hazardous fuel reduction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross-boundary hazardous fuel reduction projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>