<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6514" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6514/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6514/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6514"><akn:num>6514</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6514. Environmental analysis(a) Authorized hazardous fuel reduction projectsExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Secretary shall conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in accordance with—(1) the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.]; and

(2) other applicable laws.


(b) Environmental assessment or environmental impact statementThe Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)) for each authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.


(c) Consideration of alternatives(1) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (d), in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared under subsection (b), the Secretary shall study, develop, and describe—(A) the proposed agency action;

(B) the alternative of no action; and

(C) an additional action alternative, if the additional alternative—(i) is proposed during scoping or the collaborative process under subsection (f); and

(ii) meets the purpose and need of the project, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Council on Environmental Quality.



(2) Multiple additional alternativesIf more than 1 additional alternative is proposed under paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall—(A) select which additional alternative to consider, which is a choice that is in the sole discretion of the Secretary; and

(B) provide a written record describing the reasons for the selection.



(d) Alternative analysis process for projects in wildland-urban interface(1) Proposed agency action and 1 action alternativeFor an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project that is proposed to be conducted in the wildland-urban interface, the Secretary is not required to study, develop, or describe more than the proposed agency action and 1 action alternative in the environmental assessment or environmental impact statement prepared pur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, the Secretary shall conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessment or environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Environmental assessment or environmental impact statement The Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement pursuant to section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)) for each authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of alternatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consideration of alternatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative analysis process for projects in wildland-urban interface</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Alternative analysis process for projects in wildland-urban interface</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice and meeting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public notice and meeting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public collaboration In order to encourage meaningful public participation during preparation of authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects, the Secretary shall facilitate collaboration among State and local governments and Indian tribes, and participation of interested persons, during the preparation of each authorized fuel reduction project in a manner consistent with the Implementation Plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental analysis and public comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental analysis and public comment In accordance with section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)) and the applicable regulations and administrative guidelines, the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment during the preparation of any environmental assessment or environmental impact statement for an authorized hazardous fuel reduction project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6514_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision document</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Decision document The Secretary shall sign a decision document for authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects and provide notice of the final agency actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>