<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/655" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/655/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/655/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_655"><akn:num>655</akn:num><akn:heading>Agents to be disinterested</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 655. Agents to be disinterested
The persons charged with the management of the seal fisheries in Alaska, and the performance of such other duties as may be assigned to them by the Secretary of the Interior, shall never be interested directly or indirectly in any lease of the right to take seals, nor in any proceeds or profits thereof either as owner, agent, partner, or otherwise.
(R.S. §§ 1973, 1975; Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 7, 32 Stat. 828; Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1, 37 Stat. 736; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(e), eff. July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2731, 53 Stat. 1433.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. §§ 1973, 1975 derived from act Mar. 5, 1872, ch. 31, § 1, 17 Stat. 35.
R.S. § 1973 read as follows: “The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to appoint one agent and three assistant agents, who shall be charged with the management of the seal fisheries in Alaska, and the performance of such other duties as may be assigned to them by the Secretary of the Treasury.”
R.S. § 1975 read as follows: “Such agents shall never be interested, directly or indirectly, in any lease of the right to take seals, nor in any proceeds or profits thereof, either as owner, agent, partner, or otherwise.”
Act. Feb. 14, 1903, transferred jurisdiction, supervision and control over the fur seal, salmon and other fisheries of Alaska from Department of the Treasury to Department of Commerce and Labor.
Act. Mar. 4, 1913, changed designation of Department of Commerce and Labor to Department of Commerce and provided that the Secretary thereof should be called the Secretary of Commerce.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Responsibility for Matters Relating to SealsBureau of Commercial Fisheries within the Fish and Wildlife Service as responsible for matters relating to commercial fisheries and to seals, see section 742b of this title.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>