<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6591a"><akn:num>6591a</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of treatment areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6591a. Designation of treatment areas(a) Definition of declining forest healthIn this section, the term “declining forest health” means a forest that is experiencing—(1) substantially increased tree mortality due to insect or disease infestation; or

(2) dieback due to infestation or defoliation by insects or disease.


(b) Designation of treatment areas(1) Initial areasNot later than 60 days after February 7, 2014, the Secretary shall, if requested by the Governor of the State, designate as part of an insect and disease treatment program 1 or more landscape-scale areas, such as subwatersheds (sixth-level hydrologic units, according to the System of Hydrologic Unit Codes of the United States Geological Survey), in at least 1 national forest in each State that is experiencing an insect or disease epidemic.


(2) Additional areasAfter the end of the 60-day period described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may designate additional landscape-scale areas under this section as needed to address insect or disease threats.



(c) RequirementsTo be designated a landscape-scale area under subsection (b), the area shall be—(1) experiencing declining forest health, based on annual forest health surveys conducted by the Secretary;

(2) at risk of experiencing substantially increased tree mortality over the next 15 years due to insect or disease infestation, based on the most recent National Insect and Disease Risk Map published by the Forest Service; or

(3) in an area in which the risk of hazard trees poses an imminent risk to public infrastructure, health, or safety.


(d) Treatment of areas(1) In generalThe Secretary may carry out priority projects on Federal land in the areas designated under subsection (b)—(A) to reduce the risk or extent of, or increase the resilience to, insect or disease infestation; or

(B) to reduce hazardous fuels.


(2) AuthorityAny project under paragraph (1) for which a public notice to initiate scoping is issued on or before September 30, 2023, m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of declining forest health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of declining forest health In this section, the term “declining forest health” means a forest that is experiencing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of treatment areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of treatment areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements To be designated a landscape-scale area under subsection (b), the area shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tree retention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tree retention The Secretary shall carry out projects under subsection (d) in a manner that maximizes the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote stands that are resilient to insects and disease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>