<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6591b"><akn:num>6591b</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6591b. Administrative review(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (d), a project described in subsection (b) that is conducted in accordance with section 6591a(d) of this title may be—(1) considered an action categorically excluded from the requirements of Public Law 91–190 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.); and

(2) exempt from the special administrative review process under section 6515 of this title.


(b) Collaborative restoration project(1) In generalA project referred to in subsection (a) is a project to carry out forest restoration treatments that—(A) maximizes the retention of old-growth and large trees, as appropriate for the forest type, to the extent that the trees promote stands that are resilient to insects and disease;

(B) considers the best available scientific information to maintain or restore the ecological integrity, including maintaining or restoring structure, function, composition, and connectivity; and

(C) is developed and implemented through a collaborative process that—(i) includes multiple interested persons representing diverse interests; and

(ii)(I) is transparent and nonexclusive; or

(II) meets the requirements for a resource advisory committee under subsections (c) through (f) of section 7125 of this title.




(2) InclusionA project under this subsection may carry out part of a proposal that complies with the eligibility requirements of the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program under section 7303(b) of this title.



(c) Limitations(1) Project sizeA project under this section may not exceed 3000 acres.


(2) LocationA project under this section shall be limited to areas—(A) in the wildland-urban interface; or

(B) Condition Classes 2 or 3 in Fire Regime Groups I, II, or III, outside the wildland-urban interface.


(3) Roads(A) Permanent roads(i) Prohibition on establishmentA project under this section shall not include the establishment of permanent roads.


(ii) Existing roadsThe Secretary may carry out necessary ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (d), a project described in subsection (b) that is conducted in accordance with section 6591a(d) of this title may be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative restoration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collaborative restoration project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusions This section does not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Forest management plans All projects and activities carried out under this section shall be consistent with the land and resource management plan established under section 1604 of this title for the unit of the National Forest System containing the projects and activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice and scoping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public notice and scoping The Secretary shall conduct public notice and scoping for any project or action proposed in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>