<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6591c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6591c"><akn:num>6591c</akn:num><akn:heading>Stewardship end result contracting projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6591c. Stewardship end result contracting projects(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ChiefThe term “Chief” means the Chief of the Forest Service.


(2) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.



(b) ProjectsThe Chief and the Director, via agreement or contract as appropriate, may enter into stewardship contracting projects with private persons or other public or private entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for the national forests and the public lands that meet local and rural community needs.


(c) Land management goalsThe land management goals of a project under subsection (b) may include any of the following:(1) Road and trail maintenance or obliteration to restore or maintain water quality.

(2) Soil productivity, habitat for wildlife and fisheries, or other resource values.

(3) Setting of prescribed fires to improve the composition, structure, condition, and health of stands or to improve wildlife habitat.

(4) Removing vegetation or other activities to promote healthy forest stands, reduce fire hazards, or achieve other land management objectives.

(5) Watershed restoration and maintenance.

(6) Restoration and maintenance of wildlife and fish.

(7) Control of noxious and exotic weeds and reestablishing native plant species.


(d) Agreements or contracts(1) Procurement procedureA source for performance of an agreement or contract under subsection (b) shall be selected on a best-value basis, including consideration of source under other public and private agreements or contracts.


(2) Contract for sale of propertyA contract entered into under this section may, at the discretion of the Secretary of Agriculture, be considered a contract for the sale of property under such terms as the Secretary may prescribe without regard to any other provision of law.


(3) Term(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the Chief and the Director may enter into a contract under subsection (b) in ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Projects The Chief and the Director, via agreement or contract as appropriate, may enter into stewardship contracting projects with private persons or other public or private entities to perform services to achieve land management goals for the national forests and the public lands that meet local and rural community needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land management goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Land management goals The land management goals of a project under subsection (b) may include any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements or contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agreements or contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Receipts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs of removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Costs of removal Notwithstanding the fact that a contractor did not harvest the timber, the Chief may collect deposits from a contractor covering the costs of removal of timber or other forest products under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance and payment guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Performance and payment guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation ceilings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cancellation ceilings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Monitoring and evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6591c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reporting Not later than 1 year after February 7, 2014, and annually thereafter, the Chief and the Director shall submit to the congressional committees described in subsection (h)(2) a report on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>