<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6592d"><akn:num>6592d</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6592d. Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ChiefsThe term “Chiefs” means the Chief of the Forest Service and the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service.


(2) Eligible activityThe term “eligible activity” means an activity—(A) to reduce the risk of wildfire;

(B) to protect water quality and supply; or

(C) to improve wildlife habitat for at-risk species.


(3) ProgramThe term “Program” means the Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program established under subsection (b)(1).


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(5) Wildland-urban interfaceThe term “wildland-urban interface” has the meaning given the term in section 6511 of this title.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a Joint Chiefs Landscape Restoration Partnership program to improve the health and resilience of forest landscapes across National Forest System land and State, Tribal, and private land.


(2) AdministrationThe Secretary shall administer the Program by coordinating eligible activities conducted on National Forest System land and State, Tribal, or private land across a forest landscape to improve the health and resilience of the forest landscape by—(A) assisting producers and landowners in implementing eligible activities on eligible private or Tribal land using the applicable programs and authorities administered by the Chief of the Natural Resources Conservation Service under title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.), not including the conservation reserve program established under subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle D of that title (16 U.S.C. 3831 et seq.); and

(B) conducting eligible activities on National Forest System land or assisting landowners in implementing eligible activities on State, Tribal, or private land using the applicable programs and authorities administered by the Chief of the Forest Service.



(c) Selection</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection of eligible activities The appropriate Regional Forester and State Conservationist shall jointly submit to the Chiefs on an annual basis proposals for eligible activities under the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation criteria In evaluating and selecting proposals submitted under subsection (c), the Chiefs shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Outreach The Secretary shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusions An eligible activity may not be carried out under the Program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>