<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6592c"><akn:num>6592c</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6592c. Emergency actions(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Authorized emergency actionThe term “authorized emergency action” means an action carried out pursuant to an emergency situation determination issued under this section to mitigate the harm to life, property, or important natural or cultural resources on National Forest System land or adjacent land.


(2) Emergency situationThe term “emergency situation” means a situation on National Forest System land for which immediate implementation of 1 or more authorized emergency actions is necessary to achieve 1 or more of the following results:(A) Relief from hazards threatening human health and safety.

(B) Mitigation of threats to natural resources on National Forest System land or adjacent land.


(3) Emergency situation determinationThe term “emergency situation determination” means a determination made by the Secretary under subsection (b)(1)(A).


(4) Land and resource management planThe term “land and resource management plan” means a plan developed under section 1604 of this title.


(5) National Forest System landThe term “National Forest System land” means land of the National Forest System (as defined in section 1609(a) of this title).


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.



(b) Authorized emergency actions to respond to emergency situations(1) Determination(A) In generalThe Secretary may make a determination that an emergency situation exists with respect to National Forest System land.


(B) ReviewAn emergency situation determination shall not be subject to objection under the predecisional administrative review processes under part 218 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).


(C) Basis of determinationAn emergency situation determination shall be based on an examination of the relevant information.



(2) Authorized emergency actionsAfter making an emergency situation determination with respect to National Forest System land, the Secret</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized emergency actions to respond to emergency situations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorized emergency actions to respond to emergency situations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental analysis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review of authorized emergency actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative review of authorized emergency actions An authorized emergency action carried out under this section shall not be subject to objection under the predecisional administrative review processes established under section 6515 of this title and section 428 of the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012 (16 U.S.C. 6515 note; Public Law 112–74).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of emergency actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial review of emergency actions A court shall not enjoin an authorized emergency action under this section if the court determines that the plaintiff is unable to demonstrate that the claim of the plaintiff is likely to succeed on the merits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification and guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification and guidance The Secretary shall provide notification and guidance to each local field office of the Forest Service to ensure awareness of, compliance with, and appropriate use of the authorized emergency action authority under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>