<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6592b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6592b"><akn:num>6592b</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fuel breaks in forests and other wildland vegetation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6592b. Establishment of fuel breaks in forests and other wildland vegetation(a) Definition of Secretary concernedIn this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—(1) the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land; and

(2) the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands (as defined in section 1702 of title 43) administered by the Bureau of Land Management.


(b) Categorical exclusion establishedForest management activities described in subsection (c) are a category of actions designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) if the categorical exclusion is documented through a supporting record and decision memorandum.


(c) Forest management activities designated for categorical exclusion(1) In generalThe category of forest management activities designated under subsection (b) for a categorical exclusion are forest management activities described in paragraph (2) that are carried out by the Secretary concerned on public lands (as defined in section 1702 of title 43) administered by the Bureau of Land Management or National Forest System land the primary purpose of which is to establish and maintain linear fuel breaks that are—(A) up to 1,000 feet in width contiguous with or incorporating existing linear features, such as roads, water infrastructure, transmission and distribution lines, and pipelines of any length on Federal land; and

(B) intended to reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire on Federal land or catastrophic wildfire for an adjacent at-risk community.


(2) ActivitiesSubject to paragraph (3), the forest management activities that may be carried out pursuant to the categorical exclusion established under subsection (b) are—(A) mowing or masticating;

(B) thinning by manual and mechanical cutting;

(C) piling, yarding, and removal of slash or hazar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Secretary concerned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of Secretary concerned In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categorical exclusion established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Categorical exclusion established Forest management activities described in subsection (c) are a category of actions designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) if the categorical exclusion is documented through a supporting record and decision memorandum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest management activities designated for categorical exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Forest management activities designated for categorical exclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acreage and location limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acreage and location limitations Treatments of vegetation in linear fuel breaks covered by the categorical exclusion established under subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Roads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Roads</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6592b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public collaboration To encourage meaningful public participation during the preparation of a project under this section, the Secretary concerned shall facilitate, during the preparation of each project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>