<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/666c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/666c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/666c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_666c_1"><akn:num>666c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of water, oceans, coasts, and wildlife from invasive species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 666c–1. Protection of water, oceans, coasts, and wildlife from invasive species(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ControlThe term “control”, with respect to an invasive species, means the eradication, suppression, or reduction of the population of the invasive species within the area in which the invasive species is present.


(2) EcosystemThe term “ecosystem” means the complex of a community of organisms and the environment of the organisms.


(3) Eligible StateThe term “eligible State” means any of— 11 So in original.(A) a State;

(B) the District of Columbia;

(C) the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico;

(D) Guam;

(E) American Samoa;

(F) the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands; and

(G) the United States Virgin Islands.


(4) Invasive species(A) In generalThe term “invasive species” means an alien species, the introduction of which causes, or is likely to cause, economic or environmental harm or harm to human health.


(B) Associated definitionFor purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “alien species”, with respect to a particular ecosystem, means any species (including the seeds, eggs, spores, or other biological material of the species that are capable of propagating the species) that is not native to the affected ecosystem.



(5) Manage; managementThe terms “manage” and “management”, with respect to an invasive species, mean the active implementation of any activity—(A) to reduce or stop the spread of the invasive species; and

(B) to inhibit further infestations of the invasive species, the spread of the invasive species, or harm caused by the invasive species, including investigations regarding methods for early detection and rapid response, prevention, control, or management of the invasive species.


(6) PreventThe term “prevent”, with respect to an invasive species, means—(A) to hinder the introduction of the invasive species onto land or water; or

(B) to impede the spread of the invasive species within land or water by inspecting, intercepting, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control and management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Control and management Each Secretary concerned shall plan and carry out activities on land directly managed by the Secretary concerned to protect water and wildlife by controlling and managing invasive species—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Strategic plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-effective methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cost-effective methods In selecting a method to be used to control or manage an invasive species as part of a specific control or management project conducted as part of a strategic plan developed under subsection (c), the Secretary concerned shall prioritize the use of methods that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparative economic assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Comparative economic assessment To achieve compliance with subsection (d), the Secretary concerned shall require a comparative economic assessment of invasive species control and management methods to be conducted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expedited action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Allocation of funding Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, the Secretary concerned shall use not less than 75 percent for on-the-ground control and management of invasive species, which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations, outreach, and public awareness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Investigations, outreach, and public awareness Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, the Secretary concerned may use not more than 15 percent for investigations, development activities, and outreach and public awareness efforts to address invasive species control and management needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administrative costs Of the amount appropriated or otherwise made available to each Secretary concerned for a fiscal year for programs that address or include protection of land or water from an invasive species, not more than 10 percent may be used for administrative costs incurred to carry out those programs, including costs relating to oversight and management of the programs, recordkeeping, and implementation of the strategic plan developed under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666c_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reporting requirements Not later than 60 days after the end of the second fiscal year beginning after March 12, 2019, each Secretary concerned shall submit to Congress a report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>