<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_667h"><akn:num>667h</akn:num><akn:heading>Chronic Wasting Disease Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 667h. Chronic Wasting Disease Task Force(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) CervidThe term “cervid” means any species within the family Cervidae.


(2) Chronic wasting diseaseThe term “chronic wasting disease” means the animal disease afflicting deer, elk, and moose populations that—(A) is a transmissible disease of the nervous system resulting in distinctive lesions in the brain; and

(B) belongs to the group of diseases known as transmissible spongiform encephalopathies, which group includes scrapie, bovine spongiform encephalopathy, and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.


(3) SecretariesThe term “Secretaries” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, acting jointly.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretaries shall establish within the United States Fish and Wildlife Service a task force, to be known as the “Chronic Wasting Disease Task Force” (referred to in this subsection as the “Task Force”).


(2) DutiesThe Task Force shall—(A) collaborate with foreign governments to share research, coordinate efforts, and discuss best management practices to reduce, minimize, prevent, or eliminate chronic wasting disease in the United States;

(B) develop recommendations, including recommendations based on findings of the study conducted under subsection (c), and a set of best practices regarding—(i) the interstate coordination of practices to prevent the new introduction of chronic wasting disease;

(ii) the prioritization and coordination of the future study of chronic wasting disease, based on evolving research needs;

(iii) ways to leverage the collective resources of Federal, State, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, and foreign governments, and resources from private, nongovernmental entities, to address chronic wasting disease</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chronic wasting disease transmission in cervidae resource study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chronic wasting disease transmission in cervidae resource study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>