<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/667i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_667i"><akn:num>667i</akn:num><akn:heading>Chronic wasting disease research and management program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 667i. Chronic wasting disease research and management program(a) Research program(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall offer to enter into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments, as authorized under 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “section”. 8312 of title 7, with eligible entities to conduct research on the transmission of, resistance to, and diagnosis of chronic wasting disease.


(2) Criteria for selectionIn entering into cooperative agreements or other legal instruments pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that shall conduct research relating to—(A)(i) methods and products to effectively detect infectious chronic wasting disease prions in live cervids, cervid excreta, the environment, and inorganic surfaces, and to decontaminate such infectious prions; or

(ii) testing methods that significantly improve sensitivity and accelerate timelines for test results on non-live cervids;


(B) the long-term suppression or eradication of chronic wasting disease; or 22 So in original.

(C) determination markers for genetic resistance to chronic wasting disease and strategies for using genetic resistance to combat the spread of the disease;

(D) sustainable cervid harvest management practices to reduce chronic wasting disease occurrence and to prevent or limit spatial spread of chronic wasting disease; or

(E) factors contributing to local emergence of chronic wasting disease, increased prevalence of chronic wasting disease, and distribution of chronic wasting disease, including mechanisms of disease transmission and effective barriers to transmission.


(3) Size of awardsTo the maximum extent practicable, individual cooperative agreements or other legal instruments entered into under paragraph (1) shall be not less than two percent and not mo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for State efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Support for State efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of herd certification program standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of herd certification program standards Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting public feedback on potential updates and improvements to the chronic wasting disease herd certification program standards with special consideration given to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs Of the funds made available under subsection (e) for a fiscal year to carry out this section, the Secretary may use not more than 10 percent of such funds for administrative costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as interfering with, or otherwise affecting, the authority of the Federal Government or States to manage wildlife and livestock on land within their respective jurisdictions, including managing, surveying, and monitoring the incidence of chronic wasting disease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>