<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/668dd" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/668dd/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/668dd/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_668dd"><akn:num>668dd</akn:num><akn:heading>National Wildlife Refuge System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 668dd. National Wildlife Refuge System(a) Designation; administration; continuance of resources-management-programs for refuge lands in Alaska; disposal of acquired lands; proceeds(1) For the purpose of consolidating the authorities relating to the various categories of areas that are administered by the Secretary for the conservation of fish and wildlife, including species that are threatened with extinction, all lands, waters, and interests therein administered by the Secretary as wildlife refuges, areas for the protection and conservation of fish and wildlife that are threatened with extinction, wildlife ranges, game ranges, wildlife management areas, or waterfowl production areas are hereby designated as the “National Wildlife Refuge System” (referred to herein as the “System”), which shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and shall be administered by the Secretary through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. With respect to refuge lands in the State of Alaska, those programs relating to the management of resources for which any other agency of the Federal Government exercises administrative responsibility through cooperative agreement shall remain in effect, subject to the direct supervision of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, as long as such agency agrees to exercise such responsibility.

(2) The mission of the System is to administer a national network of lands and waters for the conservation, management, and where appropriate, restoration of the fish, wildlife, and plant resources and their habitats within the United States for the benefit of present and future generations of Americans.

(3) With respect to the System, it is the policy of the United States that—(A) each refuge shall be managed to fulfill the mission of the System, as well as the specific purposes for which that refuge was established;

(B) compatible wildlife-dependent recreation is a legitimate and appropriate general public use of the System, directly rel</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation; administration; continuance of resources-management-programs for refuge lands in Alaska; disposal of acquired lands; proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation; administration; continuance of resources-management-programs for refuge lands in Alaska; disposal of acquired lands; proceeds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration; public accommodations contracts; acceptance and use of funds; exchange of properties; cash equalization payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration; public accommodations contracts; acceptance and use of funds; exchange of properties; cash equalization payments In administering the System, the Secretary is authorized to take the following actions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited and permitted activities; application of mining and mineral leasing laws, hunting or fishing regulations, and State laws or regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibited and permitted activities; application of mining and mineral leasing laws, hunting or fishing regulations, and State laws or regulations No person shall disturb, injure, cut, burn, remove, destroy, or possess any real or personal property of the United States, including natural growth, in any area of the System; or take or possess any fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or nest or egg thereof within any such area; or enter, use, or otherwise occupy any such area for any purpose; unless such activities are performed by persons authorized to manage such area, or unless such activities are permitted either under subsection (d) of this section or by express provision of the law, proclamation, Executive order, or public land order establishing the area, or amendment thereof: Provided, That the United States mining and mineral leasing laws shall continue to apply to any lands within the System to the same extent they apply prior to Octob</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of areas; administration of migratory bird sanctuaries as game taking areas; rights of way, easements, and reservations; payment of fair market value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of areas; administration of migratory bird sanctuaries as game taking areas; rights of way, easements, and reservations; payment of fair market value</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refuge conservation planning program for non-Alaskan refuge lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Refuge conservation planning program for non-Alaskan refuge lands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement provision; arrests, searches, and seizures; custody of property; forfeitures; disposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Enforcement provision; arrests, searches, and seizures; custody of property; forfeitures; disposition Any person authorized by the Secretary to enforce the provisions of this Act or any regulations issued thereunder, may, without a warrant, arrest any person violating this Act or regulations in his presence or view, and may execute any warrant or other process issued by an officer or court of competent jurisdiction to enforce the provisions of this Act or regulations, and may with a search warrant search for and seize any property, fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or nest or egg thereof, taken or possessed in violation of this Act or the regulations issued thereunder. Any property, fish, bird, mammal, or other wild vertebrate or invertebrate animals or part or egg thereof seized with or without a search warrant shall be held by such person or by a United States marshal, and upon conviction, shall be forfeited to the United States and disp</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; continuation, modification, or rescission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations; continuation, modification, or rescission Regulations applicable to areas of the System that are in effect on October 15, 1966, shall continue in effect until modified or rescinded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>National conservation recreational area provisions; amendment, repeal, or modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) National conservation recreational area provisions; amendment, repeal, or modification Nothing in this section shall be construed to amend, repeal, or otherwise modify the provision of the Act of September 28, 1962 (76 Stat. 653; 16 U.S.C. 460k—460k–4) which authorizes the Secretary to administer the areas within the System for public recreation. The provisions of this section relating to recreation shall be administered in accordance with the provisions of said Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_668dd_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from State water laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption from State water laws Nothing in this Act shall constitute an express or implied claim or denial on the part of the Federal Government as to exemption from State water laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>