<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_669b"><akn:num>669b</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 669b. Authorization of appropriations(a) In general(1) An amount equal to all revenues accruing each fiscal year (beginning with the fiscal year 1975) from any tax imposed on specified articles by sections 4161(b) and 4181 of title 26, shall, subject to the exemptions in section 4182 of such title, be covered into the Federal aid to wildlife restoration fund in the Treasury (hereinafter referred to as the “fund”) and is authorized to be appropriated and made available until expended to carry out the purposes of this chapter. So much of such appropriations apportioned to any State for any fiscal year as remains unexpended at the close thereof is authorized to be made available for expenditure in that State until the close of the succeeding fiscal year. Any amount apportioned to any State under the provisions of this chapter which is unexpended or unobligated at the end of the period during which it is available for expenditure on any project is authorized to be made available for expenditure by the Secretary of the Interior in carrying out the provisions of the Migratory Bird Conservation Act [16 U.S.C. 715 et seq.].

(2) There is established in the Federal aid to wildlife restoration fund a subaccount to be known as the “Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account”. There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account $50,000,000 in fiscal year 2001 for apportionment in accordance with this chapter to carry out State wildlife conservation and restoration programs. Further, interest on amounts transferred shall be treated in a manner consistent with 16 U.S.C. 669(b)(1)).11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (1) of subsection (b)”.


(b) Investment of unexpended amounts(1) The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest in interest-bearing obligations of the United States such portion of the fund as is not, in his judgment, required for meeting a current year’s withdrawals. For purposes of such investm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of unexpended amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investment of unexpended amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of amounts in State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Obligation of amounts in State Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, with respect to amounts transferred to the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account, so much of such amounts apportioned to any State for any fiscal year as remains unexpended at the close thereof shall remain available for obligation in that State until the close of the second succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>