<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/669g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_669g"><akn:num>669g</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of projects; expenditures for management of wildlife areas and resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 669g. Maintenance of projects; expenditures for management of wildlife areas and resources(a) Maintenance of wildlife-restoration projects established under the provisions of this chapter shall be the duty of the States in accordance with their respective laws. Beginning July 1, 1945, the term “wildlife-restoration project”, as defined in section 669a of this title, shall include maintenance of completed projects. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, funds apportioned to a State under this chapter may be expended by the State for management (exclusive of law enforcement) of wildlife areas and resources. Funds from the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account may be used for a wildlife conservation education program, except that no such funds may be used for education efforts, projects, or programs that promote or encourage opposition to the regulated taking of wildlife.

(b) Expenditures for Management of Wildlife Areas and Resources.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), each State may use the funds apportioned to it under section 669c(c) of this title to pay up to 75 per centum of the costs of a hunter safety program and the operation and maintenance of public target ranges.

(2) Exception.—Notwithstanding the limitation described in paragraph (1), a State may pay up to 90 percent of the cost of acquiring land for, expanding, or constructing a public target range.

(3) Non-federal share.—The non-Federal share of such costs may be derived from license fees paid by hunters, but not from other Federal grant programs.

(4) Regulations.—The Secretary shall issue not later than the 120th day after the effective date of this subsection such regulations as he deems advisable relative to the criteria for the establishment of hunter safety programs and public target ranges under this subsection.


(Sept. 2, 1937, ch. 899, § 8, 50 Stat. 919; July 24, 1946, ch. 605, § 2, 60 Stat. 656; Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 861, § 2, 69 Stat. 698; Pub. L. 91</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maintenance of wildlife-restoration projects established under the provisions of this chapter shall be the duty of the States in accordance with their respective laws. Beginning July 1, 1945, the term “wildlife-restoration project”, as defined in section 669a of this title, shall include maintenance of completed projects. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, funds apportioned to a State under this chapter may be expended by the State for management (exclusive of law enforcement) of wildlife areas and resources. Funds from the Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account may be used for a wildlife conservation education program, except that no such funds may be used for education efforts, projects, or programs that promote or encourage opposition to the regulated taking of wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures for Management of Wildlife Areas and Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>