<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6704"><akn:num>6704</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6704. Establishment of Institutes(a) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall—(1) not later than 180 days after October 5, 2004, establish Institutes to promote the use of adaptive ecosystem management to reduce the risk of wildfires, and restore the health of forest and woodland ecosystems, in the interior West; and

(2) provide assistance to the Institutes to promote the use of collaborative processes and adaptive ecosystem management in accordance with paragraph (1).


(b) Location(1) Existing InstitutesThe Secretary may designate an institute in existence on October 5, 2004, to serve as an Institute established under this chapter.


(2) StatesOf the Institutes established under this chapter, the Secretary shall establish 1 Institute in each of—(A) the State of Arizona, to be located at Northern Arizona University;

(B) the State of New Mexico, to be located at New Mexico Highlands University, while engaging the full resources of the consortium of universities represented in the Institute of Natural Resource Analysis and Management (INRAM); and

(C) the State of Colorado.



(c) DutiesEach Institute shall—(1) develop, conduct research on, transfer, promote, and monitor restoration-based hazardous fuel reduction treatments to reduce the risk of severe wildfires and improve the health of dry forest and woodland ecosystems in the interior West;

(2) synthesize and adapt scientific findings from conventional research to implement restoration-based hazardous fuel reduction treatments on a landscape scale using an adaptive ecosystem management framework;

(3) translate for and transfer to affected entities any scientific and interdisciplinary knowledge about restoration-based hazardous fuel reduction treatments;

(4) assist affected entities with the design of adaptive management approaches (including monitoring) for the implementation of restoration-based hazardous fuel reduction treatments; and

(5) provide peer-reviewed an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Location</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties Each Institute shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualifications Each Institute shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cooperation Each Institute may cooperate with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual work plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual work plans As a condition of the receipt of funds made available under this chapter, for each fiscal year, each Institute shall develop in consultation with the Secretary, for review by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, an annual work plan that includes assurances, satisfactory to the Secretaries, that the proposed work of the Institute will serve the informational needs of affected entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of additional Institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Establishment of additional Institutes If after 2 years after October 5, 2004, the Secretary finds that the Institute model established at the locations named in subsection (b)(2) would be constructive for other interior West States, the Secretary may establish 1 institute in each of those States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>