<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_670a"><akn:num>670a</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative plan for conservation and rehabilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 670a. Cooperative plan for conservation and rehabilitation(a) Authority of Secretary of Defense(1) Program(A) In generalThe Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide for the conservation and rehabilitation of natural resources on military installations.


(B) Integrated natural resources management plan(i) To facilitate the program, the Secretary of each military department shall prepare and implement an integrated natural resources management plan for each military installation in the United States under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, unless the Secretary determines that the absence of significant natural resources on a particular installation makes preparation of such a plan inappropriate.

(ii) The Secretary of a military department may, subject to the availability of appropriations, develop and implement an integrated natural resources management plan for a State-owned National Guard installation. Such a plan shall be developed and implemented in coordination with the chief executive officer of the State in which the State-owned National Guard installation is located. Such a plan is deemed, for purposes of any other provision of law, to be for lands or other geographical areas owned or controlled by the Department of Defense, or designated for its use.



(2) Cooperative preparationThe Secretary of a military department shall prepare each integrated natural resources management plan for which the Secretary is responsible in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the head of each appropriate State fish and wildlife agency for the State in which the military installation or State-owned National Guard installation concerned is located. Consistent with paragraph (4), the resulting plan for the military installation or State-owned National Guard installation shall reflect the mutual agreement of the parties concerning conservation, protection, and management</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary of Defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required elements of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required elements of plans Consistent with the use of military installations and State-owned National Guard installations to ensure the preparedness of the Armed Forces, each integrated natural resources management plan prepared under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions on sale and lease of lands unless effects compatible with plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibitions on sale and lease of lands unless effects compatible with plan After an integrated natural resources management plan is agreed to under subsection (a)— unless the effects of that sale or leasing are compatible with the purposes of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation and enforcement of integrated natural resources management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation and enforcement of integrated natural resources management plans With regard to the implementation and enforcement of integrated natural resources management plans agreed to under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability of other laws Integrated natural resources management plans agreed to under the authority of this section and section 670b of this title shall not be deemed to be, nor treated as, cooperative agreements to which chapter 63 of title 31 applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reviews and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for invasive species management for military installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program for invasive species management for military installations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>