<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_670b"><akn:num>670b</akn:num><akn:heading>Migratory game birds; hunting permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 670b. Migratory game birds; hunting permits(a) Integrated natural resources management planThe Secretary of Defense in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency is authorized to carry out a program for the conservation, restoration and management of migratory game birds on military installations, including the issuance of special hunting permits and the collection of fees therefor, in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency.


(b) Applicability of other lawsPossession of a special permit for hunting migratory game birds issued pursuant to this subchapter shall not relieve the permittee of the requirements of the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act as amended [16 U.S.C. 718 et seq.] nor of the requirements pertaining to State law set forth in Public Law 85–337.


(Pub. L. 86–797, title I, § 102, formerly § 2, Sept. 15, 1960, 74 Stat. 1053; renumbered title I, § 102, and amended Pub. L. 93–452, § 3(1), (3), Oct. 18, 1974, 88 Stat. 1375; Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXIX, §§ 2904(b)(5), 2913(5), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 2018, 2022; Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(2), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1353.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act, referred to in subsec. (b), subsequently renamed the Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamp Act, is act Mar. 16, 1934, ch. 71, 48 Stat. 452, which is classified generally to subchapter IV (§ 718 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 718 of this title and Tables.
Public Law 85–337, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 85–337, Feb. 28, 1958, 72 Stat. 28, which is classified to section 2671 of Title 10, Armed Forces, section 472 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works [now 40 U.S.C. 102], and sections </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated natural resources management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Integrated natural resources management plan The Secretary of Defense in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency is authorized to carry out a program for the conservation, restoration and management of migratory game birds on military installations, including the issuance of special hunting permits and the collection of fees therefor, in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior and the appropriate State agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability of other laws Possession of a special permit for hunting migratory game birds issued pursuant to this subchapter shall not relieve the permittee of the requirements of the Migratory Bird Hunting Stamp Act as amended [16 U.S.C. 718 et seq.] nor of the requirements pertaining to State law set forth in Public Law 85–337.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>