<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_670c"><akn:num>670c</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for public outdoor recreation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 670c. Program for public outdoor recreation(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary of Defense is also authorized to carry out a program for the development, enhancement, operation, and maintenance of public outdoor recreation resources at military installations in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the appropriate State agency designated by the State in which the installations are located.


(b) Access for disabled veterans, military dependents with disabilities, and other persons with disabilities(1) In developing facilities and conducting programs for public outdoor recreation at military installations, consistent with the primary military mission of the installations, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure, to the extent reasonably practicable, that outdoor recreation opportunities (including fishing, hunting, trapping, wildlife viewing, boating, and camping) made available to the public also provide access for persons described in paragraph (2) when topographic, vegetative, and water resources allow access for such persons without substantial modification to the natural environment.

(2) Persons referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:(A) Disabled veterans.

(B) Military dependents with disabilities.

(C) Other persons with disabilities, when access to a military installation for such persons and other civilians is not otherwise restricted.


(3) The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this subsection in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, national service, military, and veterans organizations, and sporting organizations in the private sector that participate in outdoor recreation projects for persons described in paragraph (2).


(c) Acceptance of donationsIn connection with the facilities and programs for public outdoor recreation at military installations, in particular the requirement under subsection (b)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary of Defense is also authorized to carry out a program for the development, enhancement, operation, and maintenance of public outdoor recreation resources at military installations in accordance with an integrated natural resources management plan mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the appropriate State agency designated by the State in which the installations are located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access for disabled veterans, military dependents with disabilities, and other persons with disabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access for disabled veterans, military dependents with disabilities, and other persons with disabilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acceptance of donations In connection with the facilities and programs for public outdoor recreation at military installations, in particular the requirement under subsection (b) to provide access for persons described in paragraph (2) of such subsection, the Secretary of Defense may accept—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of volunteers A volunteer under subsection (c) shall not be considered to be a Federal employee and shall not be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment, including those relating to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave, unemployment compensation, and Federal employee benefits, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>