<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_670i"><akn:num>670i</akn:num><akn:heading>Public land management area stamps for hunting, trapping, and fishing on public lands subject to pro</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 670i. Public land management area stamps for hunting, trapping, and fishing on public lands subject to programs(a) Agreements to require stampsAny State agency may agree with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (or with the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, if within the State concerned all conservation and rehabilitation programs under this subchapter will be implemented by him) that no individual will be permitted to hunt, trap, or fish on any public land within the State which is subject to a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter unless at the time such individual is engaged in such activity he has on his person a valid public land management area stamp issued pursuant to this section.


(b) Conditions for agreementsAny agreement made pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to require the issuance of public land management area stamps shall be subject to the following conditions:(1) Such stamps shall be issued, sold, and the fees therefor collected, by the State agency or by the authorized agents of such agency.

(2) Notice of the requirement to possess such stamps shall be displayed prominently in all places where State hunting, trapping, or fishing licenses are sold. To the maximum extent practicable, the sale of such stamps shall be combined with the sale of such State hunting, trapping, and fishing licenses.

(3) Except for expenses incurred in the printing, issuing, or selling of such stamps, the fees collected for such stamps by the State agency shall be utilized in carrying out conservation and rehabilitation programs implemented under this subchapter in the State concerned. Such fees may be used by the State agency to acquire lands or interests therein from willing sellers or donors to provide public access to program lands that have no existing public access for enhancement of outdoor recreation and wildlife conservation: Provided, That the Se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements to require stamps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreements to require stamps Any State agency may agree with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (or with the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, as the case may be, if within the State concerned all conservation and rehabilitation programs under this subchapter will be implemented by him) that no individual will be permitted to hunt, trap, or fish on any public land within the State which is subject to a conservation and rehabilitation program implemented under this subchapter unless at the time such individual is engaged in such activity he has on his person a valid public land management area stamp issued pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_670i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conditions for agreements Any agreement made pursuant to subsection (a) of this section to require the issuance of public land management area stamps shall be subject to the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>