<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/670l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_670l"><akn:num>670l</akn:num><akn:heading>Stamp requirements not applicable to Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management lands; authorized </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 670l. Stamp requirements not applicable to Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management lands; authorized fees
Notwithstanding any other provision in this subchapter, section 670i of this title shall not apply to land which is, or hereafter may be, within or designated as Forest Service land or as Bureau of Land Management land of any State in which all Federal lands therein comprise 60 percent or more of the total area of such State; except that in any such State, any appropriate State agency may agree with the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, or both, as the case may be, to collect a fee as specified in such agreement at the point of sale of regular licenses to hunt, trap, or fish in such State, the proceeds of which shall be utilized in carrying out conservation and rehabilitation programs implemented under this subchapter in the State concerned and for no other purpose.
(Pub. L. 86–797, title II, § 206, as added Pub. L. 93–452, § 2, Oct. 18, 1974, 88 Stat. 1374; amended Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 312(b)(12), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1355.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2011—Pub. L. 112–81 inserted section catchline.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>