<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6801" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6801/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6801/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6801"><akn:num>6801</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6801. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Entrance feeThe term “entrance fee” means the recreation fee authorized to be charged to enter onto lands managed by the National Park Service or the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.


(2) Expanded amenity recreation feeThe term “expanded amenity recreation fee” means the recreation fee authorized by section 6802(g) of this title.


(3) Federal land management agencyThe term “Federal land management agency” means the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Forest Service.


(4) Federal recreational lands and watersThe term “Federal recreational lands and waters” means lands or waters managed by a Federal land management agency.


(5) National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands PassThe term “National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass” means the interagency national pass authorized by section 6804 of this title.


(6) PassholderThe term “passholder” means the person who is issued a recreation pass.


(7) Recreation feeThe term “recreation fee” means an entrance fee, standard amenity recreation fee, expanded amenity recreation fee, or special recreation permit fee.


(8) Recreation passThe term “recreation pass” means the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass or one of the other recreation passes available as authorized by section 6804 of this title.


(9) Recreation service providerThe term “recreation service provider” means a person that provides recreational services to the public under a special recreation permit under clause (iii) or (iv) of paragraph (13)(A).


(10) SecretariesThe term “Secretaries” means the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture acting jointly.


(11) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means—(A) the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to a Federal land management agency (other than the Forest Service); and

(B) the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to the For</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entrance fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Entrance fee The term “entrance fee” means the recreation fee authorized to be charged to enter onto lands managed by the National Park Service or the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded amenity recreation fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Expanded amenity recreation fee The term “expanded amenity recreation fee” means the recreation fee authorized by section 6802(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal land management agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Federal land management agency The term “Federal land management agency” means the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Forest Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal recreational lands and waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Federal recreational lands and waters The term “Federal recreational lands and waters” means lands or waters managed by a Federal land management agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass The term “National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass” means the interagency national pass authorized by section 6804 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Passholder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Passholder The term “passholder” means the person who is issued a recreation pass.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Recreation fee The term “recreation fee” means an entrance fee, standard amenity recreation fee, expanded amenity recreation fee, or special recreation permit fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation pass</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Recreation pass The term “recreation pass” means the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass or one of the other recreation passes available as authorized by section 6804 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation service provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Recreation service provider The term “recreation service provider” means a person that provides recreational services to the public under a special recreation permit under clause (iii) or (iv) of paragraph (13)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6801_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Secretaries The term “Secretaries” means the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture acting jointly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>