<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6802"><akn:num>6802</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation fee authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6802. Recreation fee authority(a) Authority of SecretaryBeginning in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter, the Secretary may establish, modify, charge, and collect recreation fees at Federal recreational lands and waters as provided for in this section.


(b) Basis for recreation feesRecreation fees shall be established in a manner consistent with the following criteria:(1) The amount of the recreation fee shall be commensurate with the benefits and services provided to the visitor.

(2) The Secretary shall consider the aggregate effect of recreation fees on recreation users and recreation service providers.

(3) The Secretary shall consider comparable fees charged elsewhere and by other public agencies and by nearby private sector operators.

(4) The Secretary shall consider the public policy or management objectives served by the recreation fee.

(5) The Secretary shall obtain input from the appropriate Recreation Resource Advisory Committee, as provided in section 6803(d) of this title.

(6) The Secretary shall consider such other factors or criteria as determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(c) Special considerationsThe Secretary shall establish the minimum number of recreation fees and shall avoid the collection of multiple or layered recreation fees for similar uses, activities, or programs.


(d) Limitations on recreation fees(1) Prohibition on fees for certain activities or servicesThe Secretary shall not charge any standard amenity recreation fee or expanded amenity recreation fee for Federal recreational lands and waters administered by the Bureau of Land Management, the Forest Service, or the Bureau of Reclamation under this chapter for any of the following:(A) Solely for parking, undesignated parking, or picnicking along roads or trailsides.

(B) For general access unless specifically authorized under this section.

(C) For dispersed areas with low or no investment unless specifically authorized under this section.

(D) For persons who are driving throu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary Beginning in fiscal year 2005 and thereafter, the Secretary may establish, modify, charge, and collect recreation fees at Federal recreational lands and waters as provided for in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis for recreation fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis for recreation fees Recreation fees shall be established in a manner consistent with the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special considerations The Secretary shall establish the minimum number of recreation fees and shall avoid the collection of multiple or layered recreation fees for similar uses, activities, or programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on recreation fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on recreation fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entrance fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Entrance fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard amenity recreation fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Standard amenity recreation fee Except as limited by subsection (d), the Secretary may charge a standard amenity recreation fee for Federal recreational lands and waters under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the Forest Service, but only at the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded amenity recreation fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Expanded amenity recreation fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special recreation permits and fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special recreation permits and fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of recreation fees and use of recreation fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure of recreation fees and use of recreation fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Online payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Online payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>