<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6803"><akn:num>6803</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6803. Public participation(a) In generalAs required in this section, the Secretary shall provide the public with opportunities to participate in the development of or changing of a recreation fee established under this chapter.


(b) Advance noticeThe Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register of the establishment of a new recreation fee area for each agency 6 months before establishment. The Secretary shall publish notice of a new recreation fee or a change to an existing recreation fee established under this chapter in local newspapers and publications located near the site at which the recreation fee would be established or changed.


(c) Public involvementBefore establishing any new recreation fee area, the Secretary shall provide opportunity for public involvement by—(1) establishing guidelines for public involvement;

(2) establishing guidelines on how agencies will demonstrate on an annual basis how they have provided information to the public on the use of recreation fee revenues; and

(3) publishing the guidelines in paragraphs (1) and (2) in the Federal Register.


(d) Recreation Resource Advisory Committee(1) Establishment(A) Authority to establishExcept as provided in subparagraphs (C) and (D), the Secretary or the Secretaries shall establish a Recreation Resource Advisory Committee in each State or region for Federal recreational lands and waters managed by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management to perform the duties described in paragraph (2).


(B) Number of CommitteesThe Secretary may have as many additional Recreation Resource Advisory Committees in a State or region as the Secretary considers necessary for the effective operation of this chapter.


(C) ExceptionThe Secretary shall not establish a Recreation Resource Advisory Committee in a State if the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Governor of the State, that sufficient interest does not exist to ensure that participation on the Committee is balanced in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As required in this section, the Secretary shall provide the public with opportunities to participate in the development of or changing of a recreation fee established under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advance notice The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register of the establishment of a new recreation fee area for each agency 6 months before establishment. The Secretary shall publish notice of a new recreation fee or a change to an existing recreation fee established under this chapter in local newspapers and publications located near the site at which the recreation fee would be established or changed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public involvement Before establishing any new recreation fee area, the Secretary shall provide opportunity for public involvement by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation Resource Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recreation Resource Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>