<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6804"><akn:num>6804</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation passes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6804. Recreation passes(a) America the Beautiful—the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass(1) Availability and useThe Secretaries shall establish, and may charge a fee for, an interagency national pass to be known as the “America the Beautiful—the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass”, which shall cover the entrance fee and standard amenity recreation fee for all Federal recreational lands and waters for which an entrance fee or a standard amenity recreation fee is charged.


(2) Image competition for recreation passThe Secretaries shall hold an annual competition to select the image to be used on the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass for a year. The competition shall be open to the public and used as a means to educate the American people about Federal recreational lands and waters.


(3) Notice of establishmentThe Secretaries shall publish a notice in the Federal Register when the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass is first established and available for purchase.


(4) DurationThe National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass shall be valid for a period of 12 months from the date of the issuance of the recreation pass to a passholder, except in the case of the age discount and lifetime passes issued under subsection (b).


(5) PriceThe Secretaries shall establish the price at which the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass will be sold to the public.


(6) Sales locations and marketing(A) In generalThe Secretaries shall sell or otherwise make available the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass—(i) at all Federal recreational lands and waters at which—(I) an entrance fee or a standard amenity recreation fee is charged; and

(II) such sales or distribution of the Pass is feasible;


(ii) at such other locations as the Secretaries consider appropriate and feasible; and

(iii) through a prominent link to a centralized pass sale system on the website of each of the Federal land</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>America the Beautiful—the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) America the Beautiful—the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free and discounted passes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Free and discounted passes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Site-specific agency passes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Site-specific agency passes The Secretary may establish and charge a fee for a site-specific pass that will cover the entrance fee or standard amenity recreation fee for particular Federal recreational lands and waters for a specified period not to exceed 12 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional multientity passes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regional multientity passes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discounted or free admission days or use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discounted or free admission days or use The Secretary may provide for a discounted or free admission day or use of Federal recreational lands and waters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on existing passports and permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on existing passports and permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>