<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6806"><akn:num>6806</akn:num><akn:heading>Special account and distribution of fees and revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6806. Special account and distribution of fees and revenues(a) Special accountThe Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a special account in the Treasury for each Federal land management agency.


(b) DepositsSubject to subsections (c), (d), and (e), revenues collected by each Federal land management agency under this chapter shall—(1) be deposited in its special account; and

(2) remain available for expenditure, without further appropriation, until expended.


(c) Distribution of recreation fees and single-site agency pass revenues(1) Local distribution of funds(A) Retention of revenuesNot less than 80 percent of the recreation fees and site-specific agency pass revenues collected at a specific unit or area of a Federal land management agency shall remain available for expenditure, without further appropriation, until expended at that unit or area.


(B) ReductionThe Secretary may reduce the percentage allocation otherwise applicable under subparagraph (A) to a unit or area of a Federal land management agency, but not below 60 percent, for a fiscal year if the Secretary determines that the revenues collected at the unit or area exceed the reasonable needs of the unit or area for which expenditures may be made for that fiscal year.



(2) Agency-wide distribution of fundsThe balance of the recreation fees and site-specific agency pass revenues collected at a specific unit or area of a Federal land management and not distributed in accordance with paragraph (1) shall remain available to that Federal land management agency for expenditure on an agency-wide basis, without further appropriation, until expended.


(3) Other amountsOther amounts collected at other locations, including recreation fees collected by other entities or for a reservation service, shall remain available, without further appropriation, until expended in accordance with guidelines established by the Secretary.



(d) Distribution of National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass revenue</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Special account The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a special account in the Treasury for each Federal land management agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposits Subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e), revenues collected by each Federal land management agency under this chapter shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6806_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of recreation fees and single-site agency pass revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution of recreation fees and single-site agency pass revenues</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6806_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distribution of National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass revenues Revenues collected from the sale of the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass shall be deposited in the special accounts established for the Federal land management agencies in accordance with the guidelines issued under section 6804(a)(7) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6806_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of regional multientity pass revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of regional multientity pass revenues Revenues collected from the sale of a regional multientity pass authorized under section 6804(d) of this title shall be deposited in each participating Federal land management agency’s special account in accordance with the terms of the region multientity pass agreement for the regional multientity pass.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>