<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/6901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6901"><akn:num>6901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6901. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) 1982 ConventionThe term “1982 Convention” means the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982.


(2) AgreementThe term “Agreement” means the Agreement for the Implementation of the Provisions of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982 relating to the Conservation and Management of Straddling Fish Stocks and Highly Migratory Fish Stocks.


(3) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Commission for the Conservation and Management of Highly Migratory Fish Stocks in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean established in accordance with this Convention.


(4) Convention areaThe term “convention area” means all waters of the Pacific Ocean bounded to the south and to the east by the following line:
From the south coast of Australia due south along the 141th meridian of east longitude to its intersection with the 55th parallel of south latitude; thence due east along the 55th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 150th meridian of east longitude; thence due south along the 150th meridian of east longitude to its intersection with the 60th parallel of south latitude; thence due east along the 60th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 130th meridian of west longitude; thence due north along the 130th meridian of west longitude to its intersection with the 4th parallel of south latitude; thence due west along the 4th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 150th meridian of west longitude; thence due north along the 150th meridian of west longitude.


(5) Exclusive economic zoneThe term “exclusive economic zone” means the zone established by Presidential Proclamation Numbered 5030 of March 10, 1983.


(6) FishingThe term “fishing” means—(A) searching for, catching, taking, or harvesting fish;

(B) attempting to search for, catch, take, or harvest fish;

(C) engaging in any other activity which can reasonably be expected to resul</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>1982 Convention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) 1982 Convention The term “1982 Convention” means the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agreement The term “Agreement” means the Agreement for the Implementation of the Provisions of the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea of 10 December 1982 relating to the Conservation and Management of Straddling Fish Stocks and Highly Migratory Fish Stocks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Commission The term “Commission” means the Commission for the Conservation and Management of Highly Migratory Fish Stocks in the Western and Central Pacific Ocean established in accordance with this Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convention area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Convention area The term “convention area” means all waters of the Pacific Ocean bounded to the south and to the east by the following line:
From the south coast of Australia due south along the 141th meridian of east longitude to its intersection with the 55th parallel of south latitude; thence due east along the 55th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 150th meridian of east longitude; thence due south along the 150th meridian of east longitude to its intersection with the 60th parallel of south latitude; thence due east along the 60th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 130th meridian of west longitude; thence due north along the 130th meridian of west longitude to its intersection with the 4th parallel of south latitude; thence due west along the 4th parallel of south latitude to its intersection with the 150th meridian of west longitude; thence due north along the 150th meridian of west longitude.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive economic zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Exclusive economic zone The term “exclusive economic zone” means the zone established by Presidential Proclamation Numbered 5030 of March 10, 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Fishing The term “fishing” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishing vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Fishing vessel The term “fishing vessel” means any vessel used or intended for use for the purpose of fishing, including support ships, carrier vessels, and any other vessel directly involved in such fishing operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Highly migratory fish stocks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Highly migratory fish stocks The term “highly migratory fish stocks” means all fish stocks of the species listed in Annex 1 of the 1982 Convention, except sauries, occurring in the Convention Area,11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. and such other species of fish as the Commission may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6901_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>