<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_695b"><akn:num>695b</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of certain statutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 695b. Applicability of certain statutes
Sections 715g to 715i and 715l to 715n of this title are made applicable for the purposes of sections 695 to 695c of this title in the same manner and to the same extent as though they were enacted as part of sections 695 to 695c of this title, except that lands acquired hereunder may be administered primarily as wildlife management areas not subject to the prohibition against the taking of birds or nests or the eggs thereof, as contained in section 715i of this title, and hunting thereon may be regulated, at the option of the Fish and Game Commission of the State of California, in such cooperative manner as is deemed necessary to carry out the purposes of sections 695 to 695c of this title subject, however, to the provisions of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of July 3, 1918 [16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.].
(May 18, 1948, ch. 303, § 3, 62 Stat. 239.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Migratory Bird Treaty Act of July 3, 1918, referred to in text, is act July 3, 1918, ch. 128, 40 Stat. 755, which is classified generally to subchapter II of chapter 7 (§ 703 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 710 of this title and Tables.
Sections 715l and 715m of this title, referred to in text, were repealed by Pub. L. 89–669, § 7(d), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 930. See section 668d(f) and (e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>