<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_695m"><akn:num>695m</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual percentage payments of net revenues from leases of Klamath project lands on pro rata basis; l</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 695m. Annual percentage payments of net revenues from leases of Klamath project lands on pro rata basis; limitation on payments; priority of use of net revenues
Subject to conditions hereafter prescribed, and pursuant to such regulations as may be issued by the Secretary, 25 per centum of the net revenues collected during each fiscal year from the leasing of Klamath project reserved Federal lands within the Executive order boundaries of the Lower Klamath National Wildlife Refuge and the Tule Lake National Wildlife Refuge shall be paid annually by the Secretary, without further authorization, for each full fiscal year after September 2, 1964 to the counties in which such refuges are located, such payments to be made on a pro rata basis to each county based upon the refuge acreage in each county: Provided, That the total annual payment per acre to each county shall not exceed 50 per centum of the average per acre tax levied on similar lands in private ownership in each county, as determined by the Secretary: Provided further, That no such payments shall be made which will reduce the credits or the payments to be made pursuant to contractual obligations of the United States with the Tulelake Irrigation District or the payments to the Klamath Drainage District as full reimbursement for the construction of irrigation facilities within said district, and that the priority of use of the total net revenues collected from the leasing of the lands described in this section shall be (1) to credit or pay from each revenues to the Tulelake Irrigation District the amounts already committed to such payment or credit; (2) to pay from such revenues to the Klamath Drainage District the sum of $197,315; and (3) to pay from such revenues to the counties the amounts prescribed by this section.
(Pub. L. 88–567, § 3, Sept. 2, 1964, 78 Stat. 850.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>