<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/695p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_695p"><akn:num>695p</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of waters to maintain sump levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 695p. Regulation of waters to maintain sump levels
In carrying out the obligations of the United States under any migratory bird treaty, the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (40 Stat. 755), as amended [16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.], or the Migratory Bird Conservation Act (45 Stat. 1222), as amended [16 U.S.C. 715 et seq.], waters under the control of the Secretary of the Interior shall be regulated, subject to valid existing rights, to maintain sump levels in the Tule Lake National Wildlife Refuge at levels established by regulations issued by the Secretary pursuant to the contract between the United States and the Tulelake Irrigation District, dated September 10, 1956, or any amendment thereof. Such regulations shall accommodate to the maximum extent practicable waterfowl management needs.
(Pub. L. 88–567, § 6, Sept. 2, 1964, 78 Stat. 851.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Migratory Bird Treaty Act (40 Stat. 755), referred to in text, is act July 3, 1918, ch. 128, 40 Stat. 755, which is classified generally to subchapter II of chapter 7 (§ 703 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 710 of this title and Tables.
The Migratory Bird Conservation Act (45 Stat. 1222), as amended, referred to in text, is act Feb. 18, 1929, ch. 257, 45 Stat. 1222, which is classified generally to subchapter III (§ 715 et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 715 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>