<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/696" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/696/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/696/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_696"><akn:num>696</akn:num><akn:heading>National Key Deer Refuge; establishment; acquisition of property: exchanges, cash equalization payme</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 696. National Key Deer Refuge; establishment; acquisition of property: exchanges, cash equalization payments; administration
In order to protect and preserve in the national interest the key deer and other wildlife resources in the Florida Keys, the Secretary of the Interior is authorized to acquire by purchase, lease, exchange, and donations, including the use of donated funds, such lands or interests therein in townships 65 and 66 south, ranges 28, 29, and 30 east, Monroe County, Florida, as he shall find to be suitable for the conservation and management of the said key deer and other wildlife: Provided, That no lands within a one thousand-foot zone adjacent to either side of United States Highway Numbered 1 in Monroe County shall be acquired for the Key Deer National Wildlife Refuge by condemnation. The Secretary, in the exercise of his exchange authority, may accept title to any non-Federal property in townships 65 and 66 south, ranges 28, 29, and 30 east, Monroe County, Florida, and in exchange therefor convey to the grantor of such property any federally owned property in the State of Florida under his jurisdiction which he classifies as suitable for exchange or other disposal. The values of the properties so exchanged either shall be approximately equal, or if they are not approximately equal the values shall be equalized by the payment of cash to the grantor or to the Secretary as the circumstances require. The properties so acquired shall constitute the National Key Deer Refuge, and shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior in accordance with the laws and regulations relating to the national wildlife refuges, including, but not limited to, sections 664, 666a, and 666b of this title, relating to the conservation of wildlife, fish, and game.
(Pub. L. 85–164, § 1, Aug. 22, 1957, 71 Stat. 412; Pub. L. 89–669, § 10(a), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 930.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1966—Pub. L. 89–669 struck out one thousand acres limitation on acquisit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>