<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698"><akn:num>698</akn:num><akn:heading>Big Thicket National Preserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698. Big Thicket National Preserve(a) EstablishmentIn order to assure the preservation, conservation, and protection of the natural, scenic, and recreational values of a significant portion of the Big Thicket area in the State of Texas and to provide for the enhancement and public enjoyment thereof, the Big Thicket National Preserve is hereby established.


(b) Location; boundaries; publication in Federal RegisterThe Big Thicket National Preserve (hereafter referred to as the “preserve”) shall include the units generally depicted on the map entitled “Big Thicket National Preserve”, dated October 1992, and numbered 175–80008, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and the offices of the Superintendent of the preserve. After advising the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, in writing, the Secretary of the Interior (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may make minor revisions of the boundaries of the preserve when necessary by publication of a revised drawing or other boundary description in the Federal Register. The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable, but no later than six months after October 11, 1974, publish a detailed description of the boundaries of the preserve in the Federal Register. In establishing such boundaries, the Secretary shall locate stream corridor unit boundaries referenced from the stream bank on each side thereof and he shall further make every reasonable effort to exclude from the units hereafter described any improved year-round residential properties which he determines, in his discretion, are not necessary for the protection of the values of the area or for its proper administration. The preserve shall consist of the following units:
Big Sandy Creek unit, Polk County, Texas, comprising approximately fourteen thousand thre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to assure the preservation, conservation, and protection of the natural, scenic, and recreational values of a significant portion of the Big Thicket area in the State of Texas and to provide for the enhancement and public enjoyment thereof, the Big Thicket National Preserve is hereby established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location; boundaries; publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Location; boundaries; publication in Federal Register The Big Thicket National Preserve (hereafter referred to as the “preserve”) shall include the units generally depicted on the map entitled “Big Thicket National Preserve”, dated October 1992, and numbered 175–80008, which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the offices of the National Park Service, Department of the Interior, and the offices of the Superintendent of the preserve. After advising the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the United States House of Representatives, in writing, the Secretary of the Interior (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) may make minor revisions of the boundaries of the preserve when necessary by publication of a revised drawing or other boundary description in the Federal Register. The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable, but no later than six months after October 11, 1974, publish a detail</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods of acquisition of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Methods of acquisition of land The Secretary is authorized to acquire by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, transfer from any other Federal agency, or exchange, any lands, waters, or interests therein which are located within the boundaries of the preserve: Provided, That privately owned lands located within the Village Creek Corridor, Big Sandy Corridor, and Canyonlands units may be acquired only with the consent of the owner: Provided further, That the Secretary may acquire lands owned by commercial timber companies only by donation or exchange: Provided further, That any lands owned by the State of Texas, or any political subdivisions thereof may be acquired by donation only. The Secretary may also acquire, by any of the above methods, approximately 15 acres of land outside of the boundaries of the preserve in the vicinity of the intersection of United States Highway 69 and State Farm-Market Road 420, in Hardin County, Texas, for purposes of a visitor contact</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exchanges of land Within sixty days after July 1, 1993, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall identify lands within their jurisdiction located within the vicinity of the preserve which may be suitable for exchange for commercial timber lands within the preserve. In so doing, the Secretary of Agriculture shall seek to identify for exchange National Forest lands that are near or adjacent to private lands that are already owned by the commercial timber companies. Such National Forest lands shall be located in the Sabine National Forest in Sabine County, Texas, in the Davy Crockett National Forest south of Texas State Highway 7, or in other sites deemed mutually agreeable, and within reasonable distance of the timber companies’ existing mills. In exercising this exchange authority, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture may utilize any authorities or procedures otherwise available to them in connection with land exchanges, and which are not inconsistent with the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Springs Youth Camp</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Indian Springs Youth Camp With respect to the thirty-seven-acre area owned by the Louisiana-Pacific Corporation or its subsidiary, Kirby Forest Industries, Inc., on Big Sandy Creek in Hardin County, Texas, and now utilized as part of the Indian Springs Youth Camp (H.G. King Abstract 822), the Secretary shall not acquire such area without the consent of the owner so long as the area is used exclusively as a youth camp.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>