<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698a"><akn:num>698a</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of property for Big Thicket Preserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698a. Acquisition of property for Big Thicket Preserve(a) Mineral rights; easements; improved propertiesThe Secretary shall, immediately after the publication of the boundaries of the preserve, commence negotiations for the acquisition of the lands located therein: Provided, That he shall not acquire the mineral estate in any property or existing easements for public utilities, pipelines or railroads without the consent of the owner unless, in his judgment, he first determines that such property or estate is subject to, or threatened with, uses which are, or would be, detrimental to the purposes and objectives of sections 698 to 698e of this title: Provided further, That the Secretary, insofar as is reasonably possible, may avoid the acquisition of improved properties, as defined in sections 698 to 698e of this title, and shall make every effort to minimize the acquisition of land where he finds it necessary to acquire properties containing improvements.


(b) Plan to Congressional committees; time; contentsWithin one year after October 11, 1974, the Secretary shall submit, in writing, to the Committee 11 So in original. Probably should be “Committees”. on Interior and Insular Affairs and to the Committees on Appropriations of the United States Congress a detailed plan which shall indicate:(i) the lands and areas which he deems essential to the protection and public enjoyment of this preserve,

(ii) the lands which he has previously acquired by purchase, donation, exchange or transfer for administration for the purpose of this preserve, and

(iii) the annual acquisition program (including the level of funding) which he recommends for the ensuing five fiscal years.


(c) Completion of land acquisition program; timeIt is the express intent of the Congress that the Secretary should substantially complete the land acquisition program contemplated by sections 698 to 698e of this title within six years after October 11, 1974.


(Pub. L. 93–439, § 2, Oct. 11, 1974, 88 St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mineral rights; easements; improved properties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mineral rights; easements; improved properties The Secretary shall, immediately after the publication of the boundaries of the preserve, commence negotiations for the acquisition of the lands located therein: Provided, That he shall not acquire the mineral estate in any property or existing easements for public utilities, pipelines or railroads without the consent of the owner unless, in his judgment, he first determines that such property or estate is subject to, or threatened with, uses which are, or would be, detrimental to the purposes and objectives of sections 698 to 698e of this title: Provided further, That the Secretary, insofar as is reasonably possible, may avoid the acquisition of improved properties, as defined in sections 698 to 698e of this title, and shall make every effort to minimize the acquisition of land where he finds it necessary to acquire properties containing improvements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan to Congressional committees; time; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plan to Congressional committees; time; contents Within one year after October 11, 1974, the Secretary shall submit, in writing, to the Committee 11 So in original. Probably should be “Committees”. on Interior and Insular Affairs and to the Committees on Appropriations of the United States Congress a detailed plan which shall indicate:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Completion of land acquisition program; time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Completion of land acquisition program; time It is the express intent of the Congress that the Secretary should substantially complete the land acquisition program contemplated by sections 698 to 698e of this title within six years after October 11, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>