<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698r"><akn:num>698r</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698r. Administration(a) In generalThe Preserve shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with sections 698q to 698t of this title and in accordance with the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—(1) the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.); 11 See References in Text note below. and

(2) the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the preservation of historic American sites, buildings, objects, and antiquities of national significance, and for other purposes”, approved August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1


(b) Hunting and fishing(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary shall permit hunting, trapping, and fishing on lands and waters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the Preserve in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws.


(2) Time and place restrictionsSubject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers necessary in furtherance of sections 698q to 698t of this title, and after consultation with the Department of Conservation and Natural Resources of the State of Alabama and owners of lands adjacent to the Preserve, the Secretary may designate zones where, and establish periods when, the activities described in paragraph (1) will not be permitted within the Preserve for reasons of public safety, administration, fish and wildlife habitat, or public use and enjoyment.


(3) Restrictions in boundary areasAfter consultation with the Department of Conservation and Natural Resources of the State of Alabama and with the owners of lands adjacent to the Preserve, the Secretary may restrict hunting in areas within the Preserve that are adjacent to the boundaries of the Preserve where the restriction is necessary or appropriate to protect public safety.


(4) Congressional intentNothing in sections 698q to 698t of this title is intended to affect the jurisdiction or responsibilit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Preserve shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with sections 698q to 698t of this title and in accordance with the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hunting and fishing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hunting and fishing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water resources projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Water resources projects Subsection (a) of section 1278 of this title shall apply to that portion of the Little River that flows through the Preserve in the same manner and to the same extent as such subsection applies to the rivers referred to in such subsection. The application of such subsection to the Preserve shall not affect any determination of the value of the lands, waters, or interests in lands and waters within the boundaries of the Preserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements with State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative agreements with State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>DeSoto State Park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) DeSoto State Park If lands within DeSoto State Park are acquired by the Secretary, at the request of the Department of Conservation and Natural Resources of the State of Alabama, the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the Department for the continued management by the Department of the lodge and other facilities that, as of October 21, 1992, are part of DeSoto State Park. The cooperative agreement shall provide for the management and operation of the lodge and facilities in a manner that, to the maximum extent practicable, is consistent with similar operations elsewhere in the National Park System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public involvement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698r_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Green Pitcher Plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Green Pitcher Plant Upon the transfer by Alabama Power Company to the United States of any lands within the boundaries of the Preserve that contain the Green Pitcher Plant (Sarracenia oreophila), all rights and obligations of Alabama Power Company under the agreement entered into between the company and the Department of the Interior (including the United States Fish and Wildlife Service) on May 12, 1983, in settlement of the action brought on September 24, 1980, against the Secretary and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service in the United States District Court for the Northern District of Alabama (Civil Action No. CV 80–C–1242–M), shall be extinguished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>