<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698u_5"><akn:num>698u–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698u–5. Advisory Committee(a) EstablishmentThere is established an advisory committee to be known as the “Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Advisory Committee”.


(b) DutiesThe Advisory Committee shall advise the Secretary and the Director of the National Park Service concerning the development, management, and interpretation of the Preserve. In carrying out those duties, the Advisory Committee shall provide timely advice to the Secretary and the Director during the preparation of the general management plan under section 698u–3(g) of this title.


(c) MembershipThe Advisory Committee shall consist of 13 members, who shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows:(1) Three members shall be representatives of the Trust.

(2) Three members shall be representatives of local landowners, cattle ranchers, or other agricultural interests.

(3) Three members shall be representatives of conservation or historic preservation interests.

(4)(A) One member shall be selected from a list of persons recommended by the Chase County Commission in the State of Kansas.

(B) One member shall be selected from a list of persons recommended by appropriate officials of Strong City, Kansas, and Cottonwood Falls, Kansas.

(C) One member shall be selected from a list of persons recommended by the Governor of the State of Kansas.


(5) One member shall be a range management specialist representing institutions of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20) in the State of Kansas.


(d) Terms(1) In generalEach member of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed to serve for a term of 3 years, except that the initial members shall be appointed as follows:(A) Four members shall be appointed, one each from paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c), to serve for a term of 3 years.

(B) Four members shall be appointed, one each from paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c), to serve for a term of 4 years.

(C) Five members shall be appointed, one each from para</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established an advisory committee to be known as the “Tallgrass Prairie National Preserve Advisory Committee”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Advisory Committee shall advise the Secretary and the Director of the National Park Service concerning the development, management, and interpretation of the Preserve. In carrying out those duties, the Advisory Committee shall provide timely advice to the Secretary and the Director during the preparation of the general management plan under section 698u–3(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership The Advisory Committee shall consist of 13 members, who shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chairperson The members of the Advisory Committee shall select 1 of the members to serve as Chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Meetings Meetings of the Advisory Committee shall be held at the call of the Chairperson or the majority of the Advisory Committee. Meetings shall be held at such locations and in such a manner as to ensure adequate opportunity for public involvement. In compliance with the requirements of chapter 10 of title 5, the Advisory Committee shall choose an appropriate means of providing interested members of the public advance notice of scheduled meetings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Quorum A majority of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compensation Each member of the Advisory Committee shall serve without compensation, except that while engaged in official business of the Advisory Committee, the member shall be entitled to travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in Government service under section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_5_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Charter The rechartering provisions of section 1013(b) of title 5 shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>