<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698u–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698u_3"><akn:num>698u–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of National Preserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698u–3. Administration of National Preserve(a) In generalThe Secretary shall administer the Preserve in accordance with sections 698u to 698u–7 of this title, the cooperative agreements described in subsection (f)(1), and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1, 2 through 4) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1


(b) Application of regulationsWith the consent of a private owner of land within the boundaries of the Preserve, the regulations issued by the Secretary concerning the National Park Service that provide for the proper use, management, and protection of persons, property, and natural and cultural resources shall apply to the private land.


(c) FacilitiesFor purposes of carrying out the duties of the Secretary under sections 698u to 698u–7 of this title relating to the Preserve, the Secretary may, with the consent of a landowner, directly or by contract, construct, reconstruct, rehabilitate, or develop essential buildings, structures, and related facilities including roads, trails, and other interpretive facilities on real property that is not owned by the Federal Government and is located within the Preserve.


(d) Liability(1) Liability of the United States and its officers and employeesExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection, the liability of the United States is subject to the terms and conditions of the Federal Tort Claims Act, as amended, 28 U.S.C. 2671 et seq., with respect to the claims arising by virtue of the Secretary’s administration of the Preserve pursuant to sections 698u to 698u–7 of this title.


(2) Liability of landowners(A) The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, under such terms and conditions as he deems appropriate, to include in any cooperative agreement entered into in accor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall administer the Preserve in accordance with sections 698u to 698u–7 of this title, the cooperative agreements described in subsection (f)(1), and the provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1, 2 through 4) 11 See References in Text note below. and the Act of August 21, 1935 (49 Stat. 666; 16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of regulations With the consent of a private owner of land within the boundaries of the Preserve, the regulations issued by the Secretary concerning the National Park Service that provide for the proper use, management, and protection of persons, property, and natural and cultural resources shall apply to the private land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilities For purposes of carrying out the duties of the Secretary under sections 698u to 698u–7 of this title relating to the Preserve, the Secretary may, with the consent of a landowner, directly or by contract, construct, reconstruct, rehabilitate, or develop essential buildings, structures, and related facilities including roads, trails, and other interpretive facilities on real property that is not owned by the Federal Government and is located within the Preserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unit of National Park System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unit of National Park System The Preserve shall be a unit of the National Park System for all purposes, including the purpose of exercising authority to charge entrance and admission fees under section 100904 of title 54.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement and donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agreement and donations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698u_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>General management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) General management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>