<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698v–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698v–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698v–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698v_11"><akn:num>698v–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Valles Caldera National Preserve, New Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698v–11. Valles Caldera National Preserve, New Mexico(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible employeeThe term “eligible employee” means a person who was a full-time or part-time employee of the Trust during the 180-day period immediately preceding December 19, 2014.


(2) FundThe term “Fund” means the Valles Caldera Fund established by section 106(h)(2) of the Valles Caldera Preservation Act.


(3) PreserveThe term “Preserve” means the Valles Caldera National Preserve in the State.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(5) StateThe term “State” means the State of New Mexico.


(6) TrustThe term “Trust” means the Valles Caldera Trust established by section 106(a) of the Valles Caldera Preservation Act.



(b) Designation of Valles Caldera National Preserve as a unit of the National Park System(1) In generalTo protect, preserve, and restore the fish, wildlife, watershed, natural, scientific, scenic, geologic, historic, cultural, archaeological, and recreational values of the area, the Valles Caldera National Preserve is designated as a unit of the National Park System.


(2) Boundary(A) In generalThe boundary of the Preserve shall consist of approximately 89,900 acres of land as depicted on the map entitled “Valles Caldera National Preserve Proposed Boundary”, numbered P80/102,036C, and dated November 4, 2014.


(B) Availability of mapThe map described in subparagraph (A) shall be on file and available for public inspection in appropriate offices of the National Park Service.



(3) Management(A) Applicable lawThe Secretary shall administer the Preserve in accordance with—(i) this section; and

(ii) the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—(I) the National Park Service Organic Act (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.); 11 See References in Text note below. and

(II) the Act of August 21, 1935 (16 U.S.C. 461 et seq.).1



(B) Management coordinationThe Secretary may coordinate the management and operations</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698v_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698v_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Valles Caldera National Preserve as a unit of the National Park System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of Valles Caldera National Preserve as a unit of the National Park System</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698v_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of administrative jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698v_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repeal of Valles Caldera Preservation Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repeal of Valles Caldera Preservation Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>