<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698w" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698w/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/698w/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_698w"><akn:num>698w</akn:num><akn:heading>Special management requirements for Federal lands recently added to Craters of the Moon National Mon</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 698w. Special management requirements for Federal lands recently added to Craters of the Moon National Monument, Idaho(a) RedesignationThe approximately 410,000 acres of land added to the Craters of the Moon National Monument by Presidential Proclamation 7373 of November 9, 2000, and identified on the map accompanying the Proclamation for administration by the National Park Service, shall, on and after August 21, 2002, be known as the “Craters of the Moon National Preserve”.


(b) Administration(1) In generalExcept as provided by paragraph (2), the Craters of the Moon National Preserve shall be administered in accordance with—(A) Presidential Proclamation 7373 of November 9, 2000;

(B) the Act of June 8, 1906,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. (commonly referred to as the “Antiquities Act”; 34 Stat. 225; 16 U.S.C. 431); 22 See References in Text note below. and

(C) the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including the Act entitled “An Act to establish a National Park Service, and for other purposes”, approved August 25, 1916 (16 U.S.C. 1 et seq.).2


(2) HuntingThe Secretary of the Interior shall permit hunting on lands within the Craters of the Moon National Preserve in accordance with the applicable laws of the United States and the State of Idaho. The Secretary, in consultation with the State of Idaho, may designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting may be permitted for reasons of public safety, protection of the area’s resources, administration, or public use and enjoyment. Except in emergencies, any regulations prescribing such restrictions relating to hunting shall be put into effect only after consultation with the State of Idaho.



(Pub. L. 107–213, § 1, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1052.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextPresidential Proclamation 7373, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b)(1)(A), appears in the item for Craters of the Moon National Monument, Idaho, in the table under the h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698w_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redesignation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Redesignation The approximately 410,000 acres of land added to the Craters of the Moon National Monument by Presidential Proclamation 7373 of November 9, 2000, and identified on the map accompanying the Proclamation for administration by the National Park Service, shall, on and after August 21, 2002, be known as the “Craters of the Moon National Preserve”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_698w_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>