<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7003"><akn:num>7003</akn:num><akn:heading>United States representation on the scientific review group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7003. United States representation on the scientific review group(a) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint no more than 2 scientific experts to serve on the scientific review group. An individual shall not be eligible to serve on the scientific review group while serving on the joint technical committee.


(b) TermAn individual appointed under subsection (a) shall be appointed for a term of not to exceed 4 years, but shall be eligible for reappointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of a term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed to serve for the remainder of that term.


(c) Joint appointmentsIn addition to individuals appointed under subsection (a), the Secretary, jointly with the Government of Canada, may appoint to the scientific review group, from a list of names provided by the advisory panel—(1) up to 2 independent members of the scientific review group; and

(2) 2 public advisors.


(Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 604, Jan. 12, 2007, 120 Stat. 3645.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint no more than 2 scientific experts to serve on the scientific review group. An individual shall not be eligible to serve on the scientific review group while serving on the joint technical committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term An individual appointed under subsection (a) shall be appointed for a term of not to exceed 4 years, but shall be eligible for reappointment. An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of a term of office of that individual’s predecessor shall be appointed to serve for the remainder of that term.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint appointments In addition to individuals appointed under subsection (a), the Secretary, jointly with the Government of Canada, may appoint to the scientific review group, from a list of names provided by the advisory panel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>