<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7008"><akn:num>7008</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7008. Administrative matters(a) Employment statusIndividuals appointed under section 7002, 7003, 7004, or 7005 of this title, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.


(b) Compensation(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), an individual appointed under this chapter shall receive no compensation for the individual’s service as a representative, alternate representative, scientific expert, or advisory panel member under this chapter.


(2) Scientific review groupNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary may employ and fix the compensation of an individual appointed under section 7003(a) of this title to serve as a scientific expert on the scientific review group who is not employed by the United States Government, a State government, or an Indian tribal government in accordance with section 3109 of title 5.



(c) Travel expensesExcept as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary shall pay the necessary travel expenses of individuals appointed under this chapter in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5.


(d) Joint appointeesWith respect to the 2 independent members of the scientific review group and the 2 public advisors to the scientific review group jointly appointed under section 7003(c) of this title, and the 1 independent member to the joint technical committee jointly appointed under section 7004(b) of this title, the Secretary may pay up to 50 percent of—(1) any compensation paid to such individuals; and

(2) the necessary travel expenses of such individuals.


(Pub. L. 109–479, title VI, § 609, Jan. 12, 2007, 120 Stat. 3647; Pub. L. 111–348, title III, § 302(b), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3672.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2011—Subsec. (a).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employment status Individuals appointed under section 7002, 7003, 7004, or 7005 of this title, other than officers or employees of the United States Government, shall not be considered to be Federal employees while performing such service, except for purposes of injury compensation or tort claims liability as provided in chapter 81 of title 5 and chapter 171 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Travel expenses Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary shall pay the necessary travel expenses of individuals appointed under this chapter in accordance with the Federal Travel Regulations and sections 5701, 5702, 5704 through 5708, and 5731 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Joint appointees With respect to the 2 independent members of the scientific review group and the 2 public advisors to the scientific review group jointly appointed under section 7003(c) of this title, and the 1 independent member to the joint technical committee jointly appointed under section 7004(b) of this title, the Secretary may pay up to 50 percent of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>