<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7121"><akn:num>7121</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7121. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Participating countyThe term “participating county” means an eligible county that elects under section 7112(d) of this title to expend a portion of the Federal funds received under section 7112 of this title in accordance with this subchapter.


(2) Project fundsThe term “project funds” means all funds an eligible county elects under section 7112(d) of this title to reserve for expenditure in accordance with this subchapter.


(3) Resource advisory committeeThe term “resource advisory committee” means—(A) an advisory committee established by the Secretary concerned under section 7125 of this title; or

(B) an advisory committee determined by the Secretary concerned to meet the requirements of section 7125 of this title.


(4) Resource management planThe term “resource management plan” means—(A) a land use plan prepared by the Bureau of Land Management for units of the Federal land described in section 7102(7)(B) of this title pursuant to section 1712 of title 43; or

(B) a land and resource management plan prepared by the Forest Service for units of the National Forest System pursuant to section 1604 of this title.


(Pub. L. 106–393, title II, § 201, as added Pub. L. 110–343, div. C, title VI, § 601(a), Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3900.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 201 of Pub. L. 106–393 was set out in a note under section 500 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 110–343, div. C, title VI, § 601(a), Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3893.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7121_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating county</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Participating county The term “participating county” means an eligible county that elects under section 7112(d) of this title to expend a portion of the Federal funds received under section 7112 of this title in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7121_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Project funds The term “project funds” means all funds an eligible county elects under section 7112(d) of this title to reserve for expenditure in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7121_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource advisory committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Resource advisory committee The term “resource advisory committee” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7121_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Resource management plan The term “resource management plan” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>