<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7123" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7123/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7123/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7123"><akn:num>7123</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of project proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7123. Submission of project proposals(a) Submission of project proposals to Secretary concerned(1) Projects funded using project fundsNot later than September 30 of each fiscal year (or a later date specified by the Secretary concerned for the fiscal year), each resource advisory committee shall submit to the Secretary concerned a description of any projects that the resource advisory committee proposes the Secretary undertake using any project funds reserved by eligible counties in the area in which the resource advisory committee has geographic jurisdiction.


(2) Projects funded using other fundsA resource advisory committee may submit to the Secretary concerned a description of any projects that the committee proposes the Secretary undertake using funds from State or local governments, or from the private sector, other than project funds and funds appropriated and otherwise available to do similar work.


(3) Joint projectsParticipating counties or other persons may propose to pool project funds or other funds, described in paragraph (2), and jointly propose a project or group of projects to a resource advisory committee established under section 7125 of this title.



(b) Required description of projectsIn submitting proposed projects to the Secretary concerned under subsection (a), a resource advisory committee shall include in the description of each proposed project the following information:(1) The purpose of the project and a description of how the project will meet the purposes of this subchapter.

(2) The anticipated duration of the project.

(3) The anticipated cost of the project.

(4) The proposed source of funding for the project, whether project funds or other funds.

(5)(A) Expected outcomes, including how the project will meet or exceed desired ecological conditions, maintenance objectives, or stewardship objectives.

(B) An estimate of the amount of any timber, forage, and other commodities and other economic activity, including jobs generated,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7123_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of project proposals to Secretary concerned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of project proposals to Secretary concerned</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7123_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required description of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required description of projects In submitting proposed projects to the Secretary concerned under subsection (a), a resource advisory committee shall include in the description of each proposed project the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7123_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized projects Projects proposed under subsection (a) shall be consistent with section 7101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>