<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7124"><akn:num>7124</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and approval of projects by Secretary concerned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7124. Evaluation and approval of projects by Secretary concerned(a) Conditions for approval of proposed projectThe Secretary concerned may make a decision to approve a project submitted by a resource advisory committee under section 7123 of this title only if the proposed project satisfies each of the following conditions:(1) The project complies with all applicable Federal laws (including regulations).

(2) The project is consistent with the applicable resource management plan and with any watershed or subsequent plan developed pursuant to the resource management plan and approved by the Secretary concerned.

(3) The project has been approved by the resource advisory committee in accordance with section 7125 of this title, including the procedures issued under subsection (e) of that section.

(4) A project description has been submitted by the resource advisory committee to the Secretary concerned in accordance with section 7123 of this title.

(5) The project will improve the maintenance of existing infrastructure, implement stewardship objectives that enhance forest ecosystems, and restore and improve land health and water quality.


(b) Environmental reviews(1) Request for payment by countyThe Secretary concerned may request the resource advisory committee submitting a proposed project to agree to the use of project funds to pay for any environmental review, consultation, or compliance with applicable environmental laws required in connection with the project.


(2) Conduct of environmental reviewIf a payment is requested under paragraph (1) and the resource advisory committee agrees to the expenditure of funds for this purpose, the Secretary concerned shall conduct environmental review, consultation, or other compliance responsibilities in accordance with Federal laws (including regulations).


(3) Effect of refusal to pay(A) In generalIf a resource advisory committee does not agree to the expenditure of funds under paragraph (1), the project shall be deemed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for approval of proposed project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions for approval of proposed project The Secretary concerned may make a decision to approve a project submitted by a resource advisory committee under section 7123 of this title only if the proposed project satisfies each of the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Environmental reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions of Secretary concerned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Decisions of Secretary concerned</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source and conduct of project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Source and conduct of project Once the Secretary concerned accepts a project for review under section 7123 of this title, the acceptance shall be deemed a Federal action for all purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of approved projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation of approved projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7124_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for project funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirements for project funds The Secretary shall ensure that at least 50 percent of all project funds be used for projects that are primarily dedicated—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>