<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7125" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7125/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7125/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7125"><akn:num>7125</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7125. Resource advisory committees(a) Establishment and purpose of resource advisory committees(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary concerned shall establish and maintain resource advisory committees to perform the duties in subsection (b), except as provided in paragraph (4).


(2) PurposeThe purpose of a resource advisory committee shall be—(A) to improve collaborative relationships; and

(B) to provide advice and recommendations to the land management agencies consistent with the purposes of this subchapter.


(3) Access to resource advisory committeesTo ensure that each unit of Federal land has access to a resource advisory committee, and that there is sufficient interest in participation on a committee to ensure that membership can be balanced in terms of the points of view represented and the functions to be performed, the Secretary concerned may,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. establish resource advisory committees for part of, or 1 or more, units of Federal land.


(4) Existing advisory committees(A) In generalAn advisory committee that meets the requirements of this section, a resource advisory committee established before December 20, 2023, or an advisory committee determined by the Secretary concerned before December 20, 2023, to meet the requirements of this section may be deemed by the Secretary concerned to be a resource advisory committee for the purposes of this subchapter.


(B) CharterA charter for a committee described in subparagraph (A) that was filed on or before December 20, 2023, shall be considered to be filed for purposes of this chapter.


(C) Bureau of land management advisory committeesThe Secretary of the Interior may deem a resource advisory committee meeting the requirements of subpart 1784 of part 1780 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations, as a resource advisory committee for the purposes of this subchapter.




(b) DutiesA resource advisory committee shall—(1) review projects proposed under this subchapter b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose of resource advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and purpose of resource advisory committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties A resource advisory committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of advisory committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Composition of advisory committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Approval procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other committee authorities and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other committee authorities and requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7125_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource advisory committee appointment pilot programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Resource advisory committee appointment pilot programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>