<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7143"><akn:num>7143</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7143. Certification(a) In generalNot later than February 1 of the year after the year in which any county funds were expended by a participating county, the appropriate official of the participating county shall submit to the Secretary concerned a certification that the county funds expended in the applicable year have been used for the uses authorized under section 7142(a) of this title, including a description of the amounts expended and the uses for which the amounts were expended.


(b) ReviewThe Secretary concerned shall review the certifications submitted under subsection (a) as the Secretary concerned determines to be appropriate.


(Pub. L. 106–393, title III, § 303, as added Pub. L. 110–343, div. C, title VI, § 601(a), Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3910.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 303 of Pub. L. 106–393 was set out in a note under section 500 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 110–343, div. C, title VI, § 601(a), Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3893.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than February 1 of the year after the year in which any county funds were expended by a participating county, the appropriate official of the participating county shall submit to the Secretary concerned a certification that the county funds expended in the applicable year have been used for the uses authorized under section 7142(a) of this title, including a description of the amounts expended and the uses for which the amounts were expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review The Secretary concerned shall review the certifications submitted under subsection (a) as the Secretary concerned determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>