<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_715d"><akn:num>715d</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase or rental of approved areas or interests therein; gifts and devises; United States lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 715d. Purchase or rental of approved areas or interests therein; gifts and devises; United States lands
The Secretary of the Interior may—(1) purchase or rent such areas or interests therein as have been approved for purchase or rental by the Commission at the price or prices fixed by the Commission; and

(2) acquire, by gift or devise, any area or interests therein;


which he determines to be suitable for use as an inviolate sanctuary, or for any other management purpose, for migratory birds. The Secretary may pay, when deemed necessary by him and from moneys authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this subchapter (A) the purchase or rental price of any such area or interest therein, and (B) the expenses incident to the location, examination, survey, and acquisition of title (including options) of any such area or interest therein. No lands acquired, held, or used by the United States for military purposes shall be subject to any provisions of this subchapter.
(Feb. 18, 1929, ch. 257, § 5, 45 Stat. 1223; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2731, 53 Stat. 1433; Pub. L. 95–616, § 5(a), Nov. 8, 1978, 92 Stat. 3113.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Pub. L. 95–616 incorporated existing provisions in pars. (1) and (2) and cls. (A) and (B), made provisions applicable to interests in approved areas, and inserted authority for purchase or acquisition for other management purposes.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Transfer of functions of Secretary of Agriculture to Secretary of the Interior by Reorg. Plan No. II of 1939, see Transfer of Functions note set out under section 715a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715d_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) purchase or rent such areas or interests therein as have been approved for purchase or rental by the Commission at the price or prices fixed by the Commission; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715d_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) acquire, by gift or devise, any area or interests therein;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>