<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_715i"><akn:num>715i</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 715i. Administration(a) Treaty obligations; rules and regulationsAreas of lands, waters, or interests therein acquired or reserved pursuant to this subchapter shall, unless otherwise provided by law, be administered by the Secretary of the Interior under rules and regulations prescribed by him to conserve and protect migratory birds in accordance with treaty obligations with Mexico, Canada, Japan, and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, and other species of wildlife found thereon, including species that are listed pursuant to section 1533 of this title as endangered species or threatened species, and to restore or develop adequate wildlife habitat.


(b) Management and public and private agency agreements authorizationIn administering such areas, the Secretary is authorized to manage timber, range, and agricultural crops; to manage other species of animals, including but not limited to fenced range animals, with the objectives of perpetuating, distributing, and utilizing the resources; and to enter into agreements with public and private agencies.


(Feb. 18, 1929, ch. 257, § 10, 45 Stat. 1224; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 4(f), eff. July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2731, 53 Stat. 1433; Pub. L. 89–669, § 7(b), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 929; Pub. L. 93–205, § 13(b), Dec. 28, 1973, 87 Stat. 902; Pub. L. 95–616, § 5(b), Nov. 8, 1978, 92 Stat. 3114.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 95–616 provided for treaty obligations with Japan and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics.
1973—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 93–205 substituted “listed pursuant to section 1533 of this title as endangered species or threatened species,” for “threatened with extinction,”.
1966—Subsecs. (a), (b). Pub. L. 89–669 added subsecs. (a) and (b). Former paragraph prohibited acts on acquired areas and is now covered by section 668dd(c) and (d)(1) of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1973 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 93–205 effective Dec. 28, 1973, see secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treaty obligations; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treaty obligations; rules and regulations Areas of lands, waters, or interests therein acquired or reserved pursuant to this subchapter shall, unless otherwise provided by law, be administered by the Secretary of the Interior under rules and regulations prescribed by him to conserve and protect migratory birds in accordance with treaty obligations with Mexico, Canada, Japan, and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, and other species of wildlife found thereon, including species that are listed pursuant to section 1533 of this title as endangered species or threatened species, and to restore or develop adequate wildlife habitat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management and public and private agency agreements authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management and public and private agency agreements authorization In administering such areas, the Secretary is authorized to manage timber, range, and agricultural crops; to manage other species of animals, including but not limited to fenced range animals, with the objectives of perpetuating, distributing, and utilizing the resources; and to enter into agreements with public and private agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>