<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/715s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_715s"><akn:num>715s</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of local governments in revenue from areas administered by the United States Fish and </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 715s. Participation of local governments in revenue from areas administered by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service(a) Separate fund in the United States Treasury; availability of funds until expended; “National Wildlife Refuge System” definedBeginning with the next full fiscal year and for each fiscal year thereafter, all revenues received by the Secretary of the Interior from the sale or other disposition of animals, salmonoid carcassas,11 So in original. Probably should be “carcasses,”. timber, hay, grass, or other products of the soil, minerals, shells, sand, or gravel, from other privileges, or from leases for public accommodations or facilities incidental to but not in conflict with the basic purposes for which those areas of the National Wildlife Refuge System were established, during each fiscal year in connection with the operation and management of those areas of the National Wildlife Refuge System, National Fish Hatcheries, or other areas, that are solely or primarily administered by him, through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall be covered into the United States Treasury and be reserved in a separate fund for disposition as hereafter prescribed. Amounts in the fund shall remain available until expended, and may be expended by the Secretary without further appropriation in the manner hereafter prescribed. The National Wildlife Refuge System (hereafter referred to as the “System”) includes those lands and waters administered by the Secretary as wildlife refuges, lands acquired or reserved for the protection and conservation of fish and wildlife that are listed pursuant to section 1533 of this title as endangered species or threatened species, wildlife ranges, game ranges, wildlife management areas, and waterfowl production areas established under any law, proclamation, Executive, or public land order.


(b) Deduction of expensesThe Secretary may pay from the fund any necessary expenses incurred by him in connection with the revenu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate fund in the United States Treasury; availability of funds until expended; “National Wildlife Refuge System” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Separate fund in the United States Treasury; availability of funds until expended; “National Wildlife Refuge System” defined Beginning with the next full fiscal year and for each fiscal year thereafter, all revenues received by the Secretary of the Interior from the sale or other disposition of animals, salmonoid carcassas,11 So in original. Probably should be “carcasses,”. timber, hay, grass, or other products of the soil, minerals, shells, sand, or gravel, from other privileges, or from leases for public accommodations or facilities incidental to but not in conflict with the basic purposes for which those areas of the National Wildlife Refuge System were established, during each fiscal year in connection with the operation and management of those areas of the National Wildlife Refuge System, National Fish Hatcheries, or other areas, that are solely or primarily administered by him, through the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall be covered into the United States Treasu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deduction of expenses The Secretary may pay from the fund any necessary expenses incurred by him in connection with the revenue-producing and revenue-sharing measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment to counties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations equal to difference between amount of net receipts and aggregate amount of required payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations equal to difference between amount of net receipts and aggregate amount of required payments If the net receipts in the fund which are attributable to revenue collections for any fiscal year do not equal the aggregate amount of payments required to be made for such fiscal year under subsection (c) to counties, there are authorized to be appropriated to the fund an amount equal to the difference between the total amount of net receipts and such aggregate amount of payments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer and use of excess of net receipts over aggregate amount of required payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer and use of excess of net receipts over aggregate amount of required payments If the net receipts in the fund which are attributable to revenue collections for any fiscal year exceed the aggregate amount of payments required to be made for such fiscal year under subsection (c) to counties, the amount of such excess shall be transferred to the Migratory Bird Conservation Fund for use in the acquisition of suitable areas for migratory bird refuges under the provisions of the Migratory Bird Conservation Act (16 U.S.C. 715–715r).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms, conditions, and regulations for execution of revenue producing activities; disposal of animals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Terms, conditions, and regulations for execution of revenue producing activities; disposal of animals The Secretary shall carry out any revenue producing activity referred to in subsection (a)(1), (2), and (3) within any fee area or reserve area subject to such terms, conditions, or regulations, including sales in the open markets, as the Secretary determines to be in the best interest of the United States. The Secretary may, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, dispose of animals which are surplus to any such area by exchange of the same or other kinds, gift or loan to public institutions for exhibition or propagation purposes, and for the advancement of knowledge and the dissemination of information relating to the conservation of wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_715s_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>