<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/718b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/718b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/718b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_718b"><akn:num>718b</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales; fund disposition; unsold stamps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 718b. Sales; fund disposition; unsold stamps(a) Sales(1) In generalThe stamps required under section 718a of this title shall be sold by the Postal Service and may be sold by the Department of the Interior, pursuant to regulations promulgated jointly by the Postal Service and the Secretary, at—(A) any post office; and

(B) such other establishments, facilities, or locations as the Postal Service or the Secretary (or a designee) may direct or authorize.


(2) ProceedsThe funds received from the sale of stamps under this subchapter by the Department of the Interior shall be deposited in the Migratory Bird Conservation Fund in accordance with section 718d of this title.


(3) Minimum and maximum valuesExcept as provided in subsection (b), the Postal Service shall collect the full face value of each stamp sold under this section for the applicable hunting year.


(4) ValidityNo stamp sold under this subchapter shall be valid under any circumstances to authorize the taking of migratory waterfowl except—(A) in compliance with Federal and State laws (including regulations);

(B) on the condition that the individual so taking the waterfowl wrote the signature of the individual in ink across the face of the stamp prior to the taking; and

(C) during the hunting year for which the stamp was issued.


(5) Unused stamps(A) Definition of retail dealerIn this paragraph, the term “retail dealer” means—(i) any individual or entity that is regularly engaged in the business of retailing hunting or fishing equipment; and

(ii) any individual or entity duly authorized to act as an agent of a State or political subdivision of a State for the sale of State or county hunting or fishing licenses.


(B) Redemption of unused stampsThe Department of the Interior, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Secretary, shall provide for the redemption, on or before the 30th day of June of each year, of unused stamps issued for the year under this subchapter that—(i) were sold on consignment to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost of stamps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost of stamps The Postal Service shall collect $10.00 for each stamp sold under the provisions of this section for hunting years 1987 and 1988, $12.50 for hunting years 1989 and 1990, $15.00 for hunting years 1991 through 2013, and $25 for each hunting year thereafter, if the Secretary determines, at any time before February 1 of the calendar year in which such hunting year begins, that all sums in the Migratory Bird Conservation Fund available for obligation and attributable to— have been obligated for expenditure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in price of stamp</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduction in price of stamp The Secretary may reduce the price of each stamp sold under the provisions of this section for a hunting year if the Secretary determines that the increase in the price of the stamp after hunting year 2013 resulted in a reduction in revenues deposited into the fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>