<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/719" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/719/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/719/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_719"><akn:num>719</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 719. Establishment of Program(a) In generalThe Secretary of the Interior (in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) may carry out in accordance with this subchapter a program to be known as the “Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program” (in this subchapter referred to as the “Program”) to accomplish the goals of—(1) providing to school children environmental education opportunities relating to the conservation and management of migratory birds; and

(2) increasing the capacity for schools, States, and other educational programs to conduct conservation and education programs.


(b) Program featuresThe Program shall consist of—(1) conducting in all interested States the activities which on the day before October 6, 1994, are conducted under the program known as the Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program;

(2) other activities authorized under the Program by this subchapter or any other Act; and

(3) any other activity necessary to carry out the conservation and education goals of the Program.


(c) Effort to conduct Program in all States(1) In generalThe Secretary shall take appropriate steps to seek to conduct the Program in all of the States.


(2) Annual reportThe Secretary shall annually submit a report to the Congress on the status of the Program in each of the States.



(Pub. L. 103–340, § 2, Oct. 6, 1994, 108 Stat. 3119; Pub. L. 106–316, § 2(1), Oct. 19, 2000, 114 Stat. 1276.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2000—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 106–316 struck out “50” before “States” in pars. (1) and (2).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2006 AmendmentPub. L. 109–166, § 1, Jan. 10, 2006, 119 Stat. 3576, provided that: “This Act [amending sections 719a and 719c of this title and provisions listed in a table of National Wildlife Refuges set out under section 668dd of this title] may be cited as the ‘Junior Duck Stamp Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2005’.”


Short TitlePub. L. 103–340, § 1, Oct. 6, 1994, 108 Stat. 3119, p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of the Interior (in this subchapter referred to as the “Secretary”) may carry out in accordance with this subchapter a program to be known as the “Junior Duck Stamp Conservation and Design Program” (in this subchapter referred to as the “Program”) to accomplish the goals of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program features</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program features The Program shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effort to conduct Program in all States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effort to conduct Program in all States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>