<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7409" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7409/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7409/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7409"><akn:num>7409</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7409. Relationship to other laws(a) In generalNothing in this chapter shall be construed to displace any requirements imposed by the customs laws of the United States or any other laws or regulations enforced or administered by the Secretary of Homeland Security. Where more stringent requirements regarding port entry or access to port services exist under other Federal law, those more stringent requirements shall apply. Nothing in this chapter shall affect a vessel’s entry into port, in accordance with international law, for reasons of force majeure or distress.


(b) United States obligations under international lawThis chapter shall be interpreted and applied in accordance with United States obligations under international law.


(Pub. L. 114–81, title III, § 310, Nov. 5, 2015, 129 Stat. 669.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to displace any requirements imposed by the customs laws of the United States or any other laws or regulations enforced or administered by the Secretary of Homeland Security. Where more stringent requirements regarding port entry or access to port services exist under other Federal law, those more stringent requirements shall apply. Nothing in this chapter shall affect a vessel’s entry into port, in accordance with international law, for reasons of force majeure or distress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States obligations under international law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States obligations under international law This chapter shall be interpreted and applied in accordance with United States obligations under international law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>