<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/742c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/742c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/742c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_742c"><akn:num>742c</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans for financing or refinancing of cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 742c. Loans for financing or refinancing of cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repairing, or operating commercial fishing vessels or gear(a) AuthorizationThe Secretary of the Interior is authorized, under such rules and regulations and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to make loans for financing or refinancing of the cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repairing, or operating new or used commercial fishing vessels or gear.


(b) ConditionsAny loans made under the provisions of this section shall be subject to the following restrictions:(1) Bear an interest rate of not less than (a) a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the average market yield on outstanding Treasury obligations of comparable maturity, plus (b) such additional charge, if any, toward covering other costs of the program as the Secretary may determine to be consistent with its purpose.

(2) Mature in not more than ten years, except that where a loan is for all or part of the costs of constructing a new fishing vessel, such period may be fourteen years.

(3) No financial assistance shall be extended pursuant to this section unless reasonable financial assistance applied for is not otherwise available on reasonable terms.

(4) Loans shall be approved only upon the furnishing of such security or other reasonable assurance of repayment as the Secretary may require considering the objectives of this section which are to upgrade commercial fishing vessels and gear and to provide reasonable financial assistance not otherwise available to commercial fishermen. The proposed collateral for a loan must be of such a nature that, when considered with the integrity and ability of the management, and the applicant’s past and prospective earnings, repayment of the loan will be reasonably assured.

(5) The applicant shall possess the ability, experience, resources, and other qualifications necessary to enable him </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_742c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The Secretary of the Interior is authorized, under such rules and regulations and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to make loans for financing or refinancing of the cost of purchasing, constructing, equipping, maintaining, repairing, or operating new or used commercial fishing vessels or gear.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_742c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conditions Any loans made under the provisions of this section shall be subject to the following restrictions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_742c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fisheries loan fund; interest payments on appropriations available as capital to the fund less average undispersed cash balance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fisheries loan fund; interest payments on appropriations available as capital to the fund less average undispersed cash balance There is created a fisheries loan fund, which shall be used by the Secretary as a revolving fund to make loans for financing and refinancing under this section. Any funds received by the Secretary on or before September 30, 1986, in payment of principal or interest on any loans so made shall be deposited in the fund and be available for making additional loans under this section. Any funds received in the fisheries loan fund after September 30, 1986, shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts. There is authorized to be appropriated to the fisheries loan fund the sum of $20,000,000 to provide initial capital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_742c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of loan contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Modification of loan contract The Secretary, subject to the specific limitations in this section, may consent to the modification, with respect to the rate of interest, time of payment of any installment of principal, or security, of any loan contract to which he is a party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_742c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chartering vessels; loans to Alaskan earthquake victims; termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chartering vessels; loans to Alaskan earthquake victims; termination date The Secretary is authorized under such terms and conditions and pursuant to regulations prescribed by him to use the funds appropriated under this section to make loans to commercial fishermen for the purpose of chartering fishing vessels pending the construction or repair of vessels lost, destroyed, or damaged by the earthquake of March 27, 1964, and subsequent tidal waves related thereto: Provided, That any loans made under this subsection shall only be repaid from the net profits of the operations of such chartered vessels, which profits shall be reduced by such reasonable amount as determined by the Secretary for the salary of the fishermen chartering such vessels. The funds authorized herein shall not be available for such loans after June 30, 1966.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>