<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/758c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/758c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/758c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_758c"><akn:num>758c</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for research laboratory, experiment stations, dock and storehouse fa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 758c. Authorization of appropriations for research laboratory, experiment stations, dock and storehouse facilities, vessels, etc., for activities in the Pacific Ocean; transfer of surplus vessels
There is hereby authorized to be appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as may be necessary for the construction, including architectural services, and for furnishings and equipment of a fishery research laboratory and experiment stations in the State of Hawaii and necessary substations at suitable locations, together with suitable dock and storehouse facilities to be used in conjunction with the operation of research and experimental fishing vessels and for the procurement and for the modification, refitting, and equipment of two experimental high-sea fishing vessels, together with all necessary gear and appurtenances, and of one multiple purpose high-seas fishing and oceanographical research vessel, together with all necessary gear and appurtenances, including necessary naval architectural and engineering services: Provided, however, That no part of said appropriation shall be expended for the acquisition of lands for sites for said laboratory, experiment station, or substations in the State of Hawaii: Provided further, That there are authorized to be transferred to the Secretary of Commerce not to exceed three surplus vessels suitable for conversion and use in oceanographic and biological research and exploratory fishing, by any disposal agency of the Government without reimbursement or transfer of funds.
(Aug. 4, 1947, ch. 451, § 4, 61 Stat. 726; Pub. L. 86–624, § 11(d), July 12, 1960, 74 Stat. 412; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. Oct. 3, 1970, 35 F.R. 15627, 84 Stat. 2090.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1960—Pub. L. 86–624 substituted “State of Hawaii” for “Hawaiian Islands” and for “Territory of Hawaii”.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Transfer of functions to Secretary of Commerce from Secretary of the Interior</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>