<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7601"><akn:num>7601</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7601. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(2) Co-Chairs of the Task ForceThe term “Co-Chairs of the Task Force” means the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Attorney General, as established pursuant to Executive Order 13648.


(3) Community conservationThe term “community conservation” means an approach to conservation involving local communities that recognizes the rights of local people to manage, or benefit directly and indirectly from wildlife and other natural resources in a long-term biologically viable manner and includes—(A) devolving management and governance to local communities to create positive conditions for resource use that takes into account current and future ecological requirements; and

(B) building the capacity of communities for conservation and natural resource management.


(4) Country of concernThe term “country of concern” means a foreign country specially designated by the Secretary of State pursuant to section 7621(b) of this title as a major source of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, a major transit point of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, or a major consumer of wildlife trafficking products, in which—(A) the government has actively engaged in, or knowingly profited from, the trafficking of protected species; or

(B) the government facilitates such trafficking through conduct that may include a persistent failure to make serious and sustained efforts to prevent and prosecute such trafficking.


(5) Focus countryThe term “focus country” refers to a foreign country determined by the Secretary of State to be a major source of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, a major transit </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Co-Chairs of the Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Co-Chairs of the Task Force The term “Co-Chairs of the Task Force” means the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Attorney General, as established pursuant to Executive Order 13648.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Community conservation The term “community conservation” means an approach to conservation involving local communities that recognizes the rights of local people to manage, or benefit directly and indirectly from wildlife and other natural resources in a long-term biologically viable manner and includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country of concern</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Country of concern The term “country of concern” means a foreign country specially designated by the Secretary of State pursuant to section 7621(b) of this title as a major source of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, a major transit point of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, or a major consumer of wildlife trafficking products, in which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Focus country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Focus country The term “focus country” refers to a foreign country determined by the Secretary of State to be a major source of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, a major transit point of wildlife trafficking products or their derivatives, or a major consumer of wildlife trafficking products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense article; defense service; significant military equipment; training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Defense article; defense service; significant military equipment; training The terms “defense article”, “defense service”, “significant military equipment”, and “training” have the meanings given such terms in section 2794 of title 22.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Implementation Plan The term “Implementation Plan” means the Implementation Plan for the National Strategy for Combating Wildlife Trafficking released on February 11, 2015, a modification of that plan, or a successor plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) National Strategy The term “National Strategy” means the National Strategy for Combating Wildlife Trafficking published on February 11, 2014, a modification of that strategy, or a successor strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>National wildlife services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) National wildlife services The term “national wildlife services” refers to the ministries and government bodies designated to manage matters pertaining to wildlife management, including poaching or trafficking, in a focus country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7601_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Security force The term “security force” means a military, law enforcement, gendarmerie, park ranger, or any other security force with a responsibility for protecting wildlife and natural habitats.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>