<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7631"><akn:num>7631</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7631. Presidential Task Force on Wildlife Trafficking(a) ResponsibilitiesIn addition to the functions required by Executive Order 13648 (78 Fed. Reg. 40621), the Task Force shall be informed by the Secretary of State’s annual report required under section 7621 of this title and considering all available information, ensure that relevant United States Government agencies—(1) collaborate, to the greatest extent practicable, with the national wildlife services, or other relevant bodies of each focus country to prepare, not later than 90 days after the date of submission of the report required under section 7621(a) of this title, a United States mission assessment of the threats to wildlife in that focus country and an assessment of the capacity of that country to address wildlife trafficking;

(2) collaborate, to the greatest extent practicable, with relevant ministries, national wildlife services, or other relevant bodies of each focus country to prepare, not later than 180 days after preparation of the assessment referred to in paragraph (1), a United States mission strategic plan that includes recommendations for addressing wildlife trafficking, taking into account any regional or national strategies for addressing wildlife trafficking in a focus country developed before the preparation of such assessment;

(3) coordinate efforts among United States Federal agencies and non-Federal partners, including missions, domestic and international organizations, the private sector, and other global partners, to implement the strategic plans required by paragraph (2) in each focus country;

(4) not less frequently than annually, consult and coordinate with stakeholders qualified to provide advice, assistance, and information regarding effective support for anti-poaching activities, coordination of regional law enforcement efforts, development of and support for effective legal enforcement mechanisms, and development of strategies to reduce illicit trade and reduce consumer d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Responsibilities In addition to the functions required by Executive Order 13648 (78 Fed. Reg. 40621), the Task Force shall be informed by the Secretary of State’s annual report required under section 7621 of this title and considering all available information, ensure that relevant United States Government agencies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duplication and efficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duplication and efficiency The Task Force shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency with agency responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consistency with agency responsibilities The Task Force shall carry out its responsibilities under this chapter in a manner consistent with the authorities and responsibilities of agencies represented on the Task Force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force strategic review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Task Force strategic review One year after October 7, 2016, and biennially thereafter, the Task Force shall submit a strategic assessment of its work and provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees that shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of Task Force The statutory authorization for the Task Force provided by this chapter shall terminate on September 30, 2028 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>