<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7641" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7641/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7641/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7641"><akn:num>7641</akn:num><akn:heading>Anti-poaching programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7641. Anti-poaching programs(a) Wildlife law enforcement professional training and coordination activitiesThe Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in collaboration with the heads of other relevant United States agencies and nongovernmental partners where appropriate, may provide assistance to focus countries to carry out the recommendations made in the strategic plan required by section 7631(a)(2) of this title, among other goals, to improve the effectiveness of wildlife law enforcement in regions and countries that have demonstrated capacity, willingness, and need for assistance.


(b) Sense of Congress regarding security assistance to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching in AfricaIt is the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to provide defense articles (not including significant military equipment), defense services, and related training to appropriate security forces of countries of Africa for the purposes of countering wildlife trafficking and poaching.


(Pub. L. 114–231, title IV, § 401, Oct. 7, 2016, 130 Stat. 954.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7641_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wildlife law enforcement professional training and coordination activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Wildlife law enforcement professional training and coordination activities The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in collaboration with the heads of other relevant United States agencies and nongovernmental partners where appropriate, may provide assistance to focus countries to carry out the recommendations made in the strategic plan required by section 7631(a)(2) of this title, among other goals, to improve the effectiveness of wildlife law enforcement in regions and countries that have demonstrated capacity, willingness, and need for assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7641_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress regarding security assistance to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching in Africa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress regarding security assistance to counter wildlife trafficking and poaching in Africa It is the sense of Congress that the United States should continue to provide defense articles (not including significant military equipment), defense services, and related training to appropriate security forces of countries of Africa for the purposes of countering wildlife trafficking and poaching.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>