<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/777c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/777c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/777c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_777c"><akn:num>777c</akn:num><akn:heading>Division of annual appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 777c. Division of annual appropriations(a) In generalFor each fiscal year through fiscal year 2026, the balance of each annual appropriation made in accordance with the provisions of section 777b of this title remaining after the distributions for administrative expenses and other purposes under subsection (b) and for activities under section 777m(e) of this title shall be distributed as follows:(1) Coastal wetlandsAn amount equal to 18.673 percent to the Secretary of the Interior for distribution as provided in the Coastal Wetlands Planning, Protection,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. and Restoration Act (16 U.S.C. 3951 et seq.).


(2) Boating safetyAn amount equal to 17.315 percent to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating for State recreational boating safety programs under section 13107 of title 46.


(3) Boating infrastructure improvement(A) In generalAn amount equal to 4 percent to the Secretary of the Interior for qualified projects under section 5604(c) of the Clean Vessel Act of 1992 (33 U.S.C. 1322 note) and section 777g–1(d) of this title.


(B) LimitationNot more than 75 percent of the amount under subparagraph (A) shall be available for projects under either of the sections referred to in subparagraph (A).



(4) National outreach and communicationsAn amount equal to 2.0 percent to the Secretary of the Interior for the National Outreach and Communications Program under section 777g(d) of this title. Such amounts shall remain available for 3 fiscal years, after which any portion thereof that is unobligated by the Secretary for that program may be expended by the Secretary under subsection (c) of this section.



(b) Set-aside for expenses for administration of this chapter(1) In general(A) Set-aside for administrationFrom the annual appropriation made in accordance with section 777b of this title, for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2026, the Secretary of the Interior may use no more than the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For each fiscal year through fiscal year 2026, the balance of each annual appropriation made in accordance with the provisions of section 777b of this title remaining after the distributions for administrative expenses and other purposes under subsection (b) and for activities under section 777m(e) of this title shall be distributed as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set-aside for expenses for administration of this chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Set-aside for expenses for administration of this chapter</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment among States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Apportionment among States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unallocated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unallocated funds So much of any sum not allocated under the provisions of this section for any fiscal year is hereby authorized to be made available for expenditure to carry out the purposes of this chapter until the close of the succeeding fiscal year. The term fiscal year as used in this section shall be a period of twelve consecutive months from October 1 through the succeeding September 30, except that the period for enumeration of persons holding licenses to fish shall be a State’s fiscal or license year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses for administration of certain programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expenses for administration of certain programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_777c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of certain funds Amounts available under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (a) that are unobligated by the Secretary of the Interior after 3 fiscal years shall be transferred to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating and shall be expended for State recreational boating safety programs under section 13107(a) of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>