<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7913" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7913/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/7913/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7913"><akn:num>7913</akn:num><akn:heading>Closure of Federal land to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7913. Closure of Federal land to hunting, fishing, and recreational shooting(a) Authorization(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2) and in accordance with section 1732(b) of title 43, the Secretary concerned may designate any area on Federal land in which, and establish any period during which, for reasons of public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable laws, no hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting shall be permitted.


(2) RequirementIn making a designation under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall designate the smallest area for the least amount of time that is required for public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable laws.



(b) Closure procedures(1) In generalExcept in an emergency, before permanently or temporarily closing any Federal land to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting, the Secretary concerned shall—(A) consult with State fish and wildlife agencies; and

(B) provide public notice and opportunity for comment under paragraph (2).


(2) Public notice and comment(A) In generalPublic notice and comment shall include—(i) a notice of intent—(I) published in advance of the public comment period for the closure—(aa) in the Federal Register;

(bb) on the website of the applicable Federal agency;

(cc) on the website of the Federal land unit, if available; and

(dd) in at least 1 local newspaper;


(II) made available in advance of the public comment period to local offices, chapters, and affiliate organizations in the vicinity of the closure that are signatories to the memorandum of understanding entitled “Federal Lands Hunting, Fishing, and Shooting Sports Roundtable Memorandum of Understanding”; and

(III) that describes—(aa) the proposed closure; and

(bb) the justification for the proposed closure, including an explanation of the reasons and necessity for the decision to close the area to hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting; and



(ii) an opportunity for public comment for a period of—(I) not l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7913_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7913_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closure procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Closure procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7913_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary closures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary closures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7913_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting On an annual basis, the Secretaries concerned shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7913_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application This section shall not apply if the closure is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>