<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_797b"><akn:num>797b</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty to keep Congress fully and currently informed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 797b. Duty to keep Congress fully and currently informed
The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall keep the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the United States House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the United States Senate fully and currently informed regarding actions of the Commission with respect to the provisions of Part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.].
(Pub. L. 99–495, § 16, Oct. 16, 1986, 100 Stat. 1259.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Power Act, referred to in text, is act June 10, 1920, ch. 285, 41 Stat. 1063. Part I of the Federal Power Act is classified generally to this subchapter (§ 791a et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 791a of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Electric Consumers Protection Act of 1986, and not as part of the Federal Power Act which generally comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives by section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14, set out as a note preceding section 21 of Title 2, The Congress. Committee on Commerce of House of Representatives changed to Committee on Energy and Commerce of House of Representatives, and jurisdiction over matters relating to securities and exchanges and insurance generally transferred to Committee on Financial Services of House of Representatives by House Resolution No. 5, One Hundred Seventh Congress, Jan. 3, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>