<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/797d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_797d"><akn:num>797d</akn:num><akn:heading>Third party contracting by FERC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 797d. Third party contracting by FERC(a) Environmental impact statementsWhere the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission is required to prepare a draft or final environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 and following) in connection with an application for a license under part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], the Commission may permit, at the election of the applicant, a contractor, consultant or other person funded by the applicant and chosen by the Commission from among a list of such individuals or companies determined by the Commission to be qualified to do such work, to prepare such statement for the Commission. The contractor shall execute a disclosure statement prepared by the Commission specifying that it has no financial or other interest in the outcome of the project. The Commission shall establish the scope of work and procedures to assure that the contractor, consultant or other person has no financial or other potential conflict of interest in the outcome of the proceeding. Nothing herein shall affect the Commission’s responsibility to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.


(b) Environmental assessmentsWhere an environmental assessment is required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 and following) in connection with an application for a license under part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], the Commission may permit an applicant, or a contractor, consultant or other person selected by the applicant, to prepare such environmental assessment. The Commission shall institute procedures, including pre-application consultations, to advise potential applicants of studies or other information foreseeably required by the Commission. The Commission may allow the filing of such applicant-prepared environmental assessments as part of the application. Nothing herein shall affect the Commission’s responsibility to comply w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_797d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental impact statements Where the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission is required to prepare a draft or final environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 and following) in connection with an application for a license under part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], the Commission may permit, at the election of the applicant, a contractor, consultant or other person funded by the applicant and chosen by the Commission from among a list of such individuals or companies determined by the Commission to be qualified to do such work, to prepare such statement for the Commission. The contractor shall execute a disclosure statement prepared by the Commission specifying that it has no financial or other interest in the outcome of the project. The Commission shall establish the scope of work and procedures to assure that the contractor, consultant or other person has no financial or other potential conflict of int</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_797d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Environmental assessments Where an environmental assessment is required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 and following) in connection with an application for a license under part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], the Commission may permit an applicant, or a contractor, consultant or other person selected by the applicant, to prepare such environmental assessment. The Commission shall institute procedures, including pre-application consultations, to advise potential applicants of studies or other information foreseeably required by the Commission. The Commission may allow the filing of such applicant-prepared environmental assessments as part of the application. Nothing herein shall affect the Commission’s responsibility to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_797d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effective date This section shall take effect with respect to license applications filed after October 24, 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>