<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/799" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/799/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/799/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_799"><akn:num>799</akn:num><akn:heading>License; duration, conditions, revocation, alteration, or surrender</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 799. License; duration, conditions, revocation, alteration, or surrender
Licenses under this subchapter shall be issued for a period not exceeding fifty years. Each such license shall be conditioned upon acceptance by the licensee of all of the terms and conditions of this chapter and such further conditions, if any, as the Commission shall prescribe in conformity with this chapter, which said terms and conditions and the acceptance thereof shall be expressed in said license. Licenses may be revoked only for the reasons and in the manner prescribed under the provisions of this chapter, and may be altered or surrendered only upon mutual agreement between the licensee and the Commission after thirty days’ public notice.
(June 10, 1920, ch. 285, pt. I, § 6, 41 Stat. 1067; renumbered pt. I and amended, Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 687, title II, §§ 204, 212, 49 Stat. 841, 847; Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(i)(6), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 676; Pub. L. 104–316, title I, § 108(a), Oct. 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 3832; Pub. L. 105–192, § 2, July 14, 1998, 112 Stat. 625.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–192 inserted at end “Licenses may be revoked only for the reasons and in the manner prescribed under the provisions of this chapter, and may be altered or surrendered only upon mutual agreement between the licensee and the Commission after thirty days’ public notice.”
1996—Pub. L. 104–316 struck out at end “Licenses may be revoked only for the reasons and in the manner prescribed under the provisions of this chapter, and may be altered or surrendered only upon mutual agreement between the licensee and the Commission after thirty days’ public notice.”
Pub. L. 104–106 struck out at end “Copies of all licenses issued under the provisions of this subchapter and calling for the payment of annual charges shall be deposited with the General Accounting Office, in compliance with section 20 of title 41.”
1935—Act Aug. 26, 1935, § 204, amended section generally, substitutin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>