<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/79k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/79k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/79k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_79k"><akn:num>79k</akn:num><akn:heading>Mitigation of adverse economic impacts to local economy resulting from additional lands; analysis of</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 79k. Mitigation of adverse economic impacts to local economy resulting from additional lands; analysis of Federal actions necessary or desirable; consultations and considerations by Secretaries concerned; reports to Congress; implementation of programs; funding requirements(a) The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, and Labor, shall conduct an analysis of appropriate Federal actions that may be necessary or desirable to mitigate any adverse economic impacts to public and private segments of the local economy, other than the owners of properties taken by this Act, as a result of the addition of property to Redwood National Park under sections 79b and 79c of this title. The Secretaries shall also consider the benefits of making grants or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements with the State of California or Del Norte and Humboldt Counties as provided by subsection (b) for the purpose of development and implementation of a program of forest resource improvement and utilization, including, but not limited to, reforestation, erosion control, and other forest land conservation measures, fisheries and fish and wildlife habitat improvements, and wood energy facilities. Not later than January 1, 1979, the Secretary shall submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate a report of his analysis, including his recommendations with respect to actions that should be taken to mitigate any significant short-term and long-term adverse effects on the local economy caused by such addition.

(b) The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary, and pursuant to his study, shall apply such existing programs as are necessary and appropriate to further mitigate identified employment and other adverse economic impacts on public and private segments of the local economy, other than with regard to the payment of just compensation to the owners of properties taken by</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, and Labor, shall conduct an analysis of appropriate Federal actions that may be necessary or desirable to mitigate any adverse economic impacts to public and private segments of the local economy, other than the owners of properties taken by this Act, as a result of the addition of property to Redwood National Park under sections 79b and 79c of this title. The Secretaries shall also consider the benefits of making grants or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements with the State of California or Del Norte and Humboldt Counties as provided by subsection (b) for the purpose of development and implementation of a program of forest resource improvement and utilization, including, but not limited to, reforestation, erosion control, and other forest land conservation measures, fisheries and fish and wildlife habitat improvements, and wood energy facilities. Not later than January 1, 1979, the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary, and pursuant to his study, shall apply such existing programs as are necessary and appropriate to further mitigate identified employment and other adverse economic impacts on public and private segments of the local economy, other than with regard to the payment of just compensation to the owners of properties taken by this Act and by the Act of October 2, 1968 [16 U.S.C. 79a et seq.]. In addition to the land rehabilitation and employment provisions of this Act, which should have a substantial positive economic effect on the local economy, the Secretaries of Commerce and Labor are further authorized and directed to implement existing authorities to establish employment programs, pursuant to such grants, contracts and cooperative agreements with agencies of the Federal Executive, the State of California, any political or governmental subdivision thereof, any corporation, not-for-profit corporat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>