<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_803"><akn:num>803</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of license generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 803. Conditions of license generally
All licenses issued under this subchapter shall be on the following conditions:(a) Modification of plans; factors considered to secure adaptability of project; recommendations for proposed terms and conditions(1) That the project adopted, including the maps, plans, and specifications, shall be such as in the judgment of the Commission will be best adapted to a comprehensive plan for improving or developing a waterway or waterways for the use or benefit of interstate or foreign commerce, for the improvement and utilization of water-power development, for the adequate protection, mitigation, and enhancement of fish and wildlife (including related spawning grounds and habitat), and for other beneficial public uses, including irrigation, flood control, water supply, and recreational and other purposes referred to in section 797(e) of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “; and”. if necessary in order to secure such plan the Commission shall have authority to require the modification of any project and of the plans and specifications of the project works before approval.

(2) In order to ensure that the project adopted will be best adapted to the comprehensive plan described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall consider each of the following:(A) The extent to which the project is consistent with a comprehensive plan (where one exists) for improving, developing, or conserving a waterway or waterways affected by the project that is prepared by—(i) an agency established pursuant to Federal law that has the authority to prepare such a plan; or

(ii) the State in which the facility is or will be located.


(B) The recommendations of Federal and State agencies exercising administration over flood control, navigation, irrigation, recreation, cultural and other relevant resources of the State in which the project is located, and the recommendations (including fish and wildlife recommendations) of Indian tribes affe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of plans; factors considered to secure adaptability of project; recommendations for proposed terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Modification of plans; factors considered to secure adaptability of project; recommendations for proposed terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alterations in project works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alterations in project works That except when emergency shall require for the protection of navigation, life, health, or property, no substantial alteration or addition not in conformity with the approved plans shall be made to any dam or other project works constructed hereunder of an installed capacity in excess of two thousand horsepower without the prior approval of the Commission; and any emergency alteration or addition so made shall thereafter be subject to such modification and change as the Commission may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and repair of project works; liability of licensee for damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maintenance and repair of project works; liability of licensee for damages That the licensee shall maintain the project works in a condition of repair adequate for the purposes of navigation and for the efficient operation of said works in the development and transmission of power, shall make all necessary renewals and replacements, shall establish and maintain adequate depreciation reserves for such purposes, shall so maintain, and operate said works as not to impair navigation, and shall conform to such rules and regulations as the Commission may from time to time prescribe for the protection of life, health, and property. Each licensee hereunder shall be liable for all damages occasioned to the property of others by the construction, maintenance, or operation of the project works or of the works appurtenant or accessory thereto, constructed under the license and in no event shall the United States be liable therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amortization reserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amortization reserves That after the first twenty years of operation, out of surplus earned thereafter, if any, accumulated in excess of a specified reasonable rate of return upon the net investment of a licensee in any project or projects under license, the licensee shall establish and maintain amortization reserves, which reserves shall, in the discretion of the Commission, be held until the termination of the license or be applied from time to time in reduction of the net investment. Such specified rate of return and the proportion of such surplus earnings to be paid into and held in such reserves shall be set forth in the license. For any new license issued under section 808 of this title, the amortization reserves under this subsection shall be maintained on and after the effective date of such new license.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual charges payable by licensees; maximum rates; application; review and report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual charges payable by licensees; maximum rates; application; review and report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement by licensee of other licensees, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reimbursement by licensee of other licensees, etc. That whenever any licensee hereunder is directly benefited by the construction work of another licensee, a permittee, or of the United States of a storage reservoir or other headwater improvement, the Commission shall require as a condition of the license that the licensee so benefited shall reimburse the owner of such reservoir or other improvements for such part of the annual charges for interest, maintenance, and depreciation thereon as the Commission may deem equitable. The proportion of such charges to be paid by any licensee shall be determined by the Commission. The licensees or permittees affected shall pay to the United States the cost of making such determination as fixed by the Commission.
Whenever such reservoir or other improvement is constructed by the United States the Commission shall assess similar charges against any licensee directly benefited thereby, and any amount so assessed shall be paid into the Treasury of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions in discretion of commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conditions in discretion of commission Such other conditions not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter as the commission may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monopolistic combinations; prevention or minimization of anticompetitive conduct; action by Commission regarding license and operation and maintenance of project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Monopolistic combinations; prevention or minimization of anticompetitive conduct; action by Commission regarding license and operation and maintenance of project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Waiver of conditions In issuing licenses for a minor part only of a complete project, or for a complete project of not more than two thousand horsepower installed capacity, the Commission may in its discretion waive such conditions, provisions, and requirements of this subchapter, except the license period of fifty years, as it may deem to be to the public interest to waive under the circumstances: Provided, That the provisions hereof shall not apply to annual charges for use of lands within Indian reservations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife protection, mitigation and enhancement; consideration of recommendations; findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fish and wildlife protection, mitigation and enhancement; consideration of recommendations; findings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>