<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8041" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8041/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8041/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8041"><akn:num>8041</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8041. Authorization of appropriations(a) FundingAmounts made available to carry out this chapter shall be derived from amounts appropriated to the relevant agencies and departments.


(b) No increase in contributionsNothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an increase in required or voluntary contributions paid by the United States to any multilateral or international organization.


(Pub. L. 116–92, div. C, title XXXV, § 3571, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 2010.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle C of title XXXV of div. C of Pub. L. 116–92, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1997, known as the Maritime Security and Fisheries Enforcement Act and also as the Maritime SAFE Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 8001 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8041_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Funding Amounts made available to carry out this chapter shall be derived from amounts appropriated to the relevant agencies and departments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8041_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No increase in contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No increase in contributions Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an increase in required or voluntary contributions paid by the United States to any multilateral or international organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>