<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/81h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/81h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/81h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_81h"><akn:num>81h</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil and criminal jurisdiction; legislative authority of State over park</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 81h. Civil and criminal jurisdiction; legislative authority of State over park
Nothing in this subchapter shall be held to deprive the State of Virginia, or any political subdivision thereof, of its civil and criminal jurisdiction in and over the areas included in said national park, nor shall this subchapter in any way impair or affect the rights of citizenship of any resident therein; and save and except as the consent of the State of Virginia may be hereafter given, the legislative authority of said State in and over all areas included within said national park shall not be diminished or affected by the creation of said national park, nor by the terms and provisions of this subchapter: Provided, That any rules and regulations authorized in section 81g of this title, and in the Act therein referred to,11 See References in Text note below. shall not apply to any property of a public nature in the city of Williamsburg, other than property of the United States.
(July 3, 1930, ch. 837, § 6, 46 Stat. 856; June 5, 1936, ch. 525, § 2, 49 Stat. 1483.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Act referred to in section 81g of this title, referred to in text, is act Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, 39 Stat. 535, known as the National Park Service Organic Act. See References in Text note set out under section 81g of this title.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 443e of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Act June 5, 1936, changed “Colonial National Monument” to “Colonial National Historical Park”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>