<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8210" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8210/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8210/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8210"><akn:num>8210</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of this chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8210. Effect of this chapter(a) Water rightsNothing in this chapter—(1) establishes any express or implied reserved water right in the United States for any purpose;

(2) affects any water right in existence on October 30, 2020;

(3) preempts or affects any State water law or interstate compact governing water; or

(4) affects any Federal or State law in existence on October 30, 2020, regarding water quality or water quantity.


(b) Authority to acquire water rights or rights to propertyOnly a State, local government, or other non-Federal entity may acquire, under State law, water rights or rights to property with funds made available through section 8212 of this title.


(c) State authorityNothing in this chapter—(1) affects the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of a State to manage, control, or regulate fish and wildlife under the laws and regulations of the State; or

(2) authorizes the Secretary to control or regulate within a State the fishing or hunting of fish and wildlife.


(d) Effect on Indian TribesNothing in this chapter abrogates, abridges, affects, modifies, supersedes, or alters any right of an Indian Tribe recognized by treaty or any other means, including—(1) an agreement between the Indian Tribe and the United States;

(2) Federal law (including regulations);

(3) an Executive order; or

(4) a judicial decree.


(e) Adjudication of water rightsNothing in this chapter diminishes or affects the ability of the Secretary to join an adjudication of rights to the use of water pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 666 of title 43.


(f) Department of Commerce authorityNothing in this chapter affects the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of the Department of Commerce to manage, control, or regulate fish or fish habitats under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.).


(g) Effect on other authorities(1) Private property protectionNothing in this chapter permits the use of funds m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Water rights Nothing in this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to acquire water rights or rights to property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to acquire water rights or rights to property Only a State, local government, or other non-Federal entity may acquire, under State law, water rights or rights to property with funds made available through section 8212 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State authority Nothing in this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on Indian Tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect on Indian Tribes Nothing in this chapter abrogates, abridges, affects, modifies, supersedes, or alters any right of an Indian Tribe recognized by treaty or any other means, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudication of water rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Adjudication of water rights Nothing in this chapter diminishes or affects the ability of the Secretary to join an adjudication of rights to the use of water pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 666 of title 43.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Commerce authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Department of Commerce authority Nothing in this chapter affects the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of the Department of Commerce to manage, control, or regulate fish or fish habitats under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8210_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>