<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8212"><akn:num>8212</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8212. Funding(a) Authorization of appropriations(1) Fish habitat Partnerships and conservation projectsThere is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $7,200,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030 to provide funds for Partnership operations under section 8204 of this title and fish habitat conservation projects approved under section 8205(f) of this title, of which 5 percent is authorized only for projects carried out by Indian Tribes.


(2) Administrative and planning expensesThere is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030 an amount equal to 5 percent of the amount appropriated for the applicable fiscal year pursuant to paragraph (1)—(A) for administrative and planning expenses under this chapter; and

(B) to carry out section 8209 of this title.


(3) Technical and scientific assistanceThere is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030 to carry out, and provide technical and scientific assistance under, section 8206 of this title—(A) $400,000 to the Secretary for use by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;

(B) $400,000 to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Assistant Administrator for use by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;

(C) $400,000 to the Environmental Protection Agency Assistant Administrator for use by the Environmental Protection Agency;

(D) $400,000 to the Secretary for use by the United States Geological Survey; and

(E) $400,000 to the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, for use by the Forest Service.



(b) Agreements and grantsThe Secretary may—(1) on the recommendation of the Board, and notwithstanding sections 6304 and 6305 of title 31 and the Federal Financial Assistance Management Improvement Act of 1999 (31 U.S.C. 6101 note; Public Law 106–107), enter into a grant agreement, cooperative agreement, or contract with a Partnership or other entity to provide funds auth</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements and grants The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Donations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>