<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_823c"><akn:num>823c</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska State jurisdiction over small hydroelectric projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 823c. Alaska State jurisdiction over small hydroelectric projects(a) Discontinuance of regulation by the CommissionNotwithstanding sections 797(e) and 817 of this title, the Commission shall discontinue exercising licensing and regulatory authority under this subchapter over qualifying project works in the State of Alaska, effective on the date on which the Commission certifies that the State of Alaska has in place a regulatory program for water-power development that—(1) protects the public interest, the purposes listed in paragraph (2), and the environment to the same extent provided by licensing and regulation by the Commission under this subchapter and other applicable Federal laws, including the Endangered Species Act (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.) and the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (16 U.S.C. 661 et seq.);

(2) gives equal consideration to the purposes of—(A) energy conservation;

(B) the protection, mitigation of damage to, and enhancement of, fish and wildlife (including related spawning grounds and habitat);

(C) the protection of recreational opportunities;

(D) the preservation of other aspects of environmental quality;

(E) the interests of Alaska Natives; and

(F) other beneficial public uses, including irrigation, flood control, water supply, and navigation; and


(3) requires, as a condition of a license for any project works—(A) the construction, maintenance, and operation by a licensee at its own expense of such lights and signals as may be directed by the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, and such fishways as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Commerce, as appropriate;

(B) the operation of any navigation facilities which may be constructed as part of any project to be controlled at all times by such reasonable rules and regulations as may be made by the Secretary of the Army; and

(C) except as provided in subsection (j), conditions for the protection, mitigation, and enhance</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discontinuance of regulation by the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Discontinuance of regulation by the Commission Notwithstanding sections 797(e) and 817 of this title, the Commission shall discontinue exercising licensing and regulatory authority under this subchapter over qualifying project works in the State of Alaska, effective on the date on which the Commission certifies that the State of Alaska has in place a regulatory program for water-power development that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of “qualifying project works”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of “qualifying project works” For purposes of this section, the term “qualifying project works” means project works—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of State licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election of State licensing In the case of nonqualifying project works that would be a qualifying project works but for the fact that the project has been licensed (or exempted from licensing) by the Commission prior to November 9, 2000, the licensee of such project may in its discretion elect to make the project subject to licensing and regulation by the State of Alaska under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project works on Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project works on Federal lands With respect to projects located in whole or in part on a reservation, a conservation system unit, or the public lands, a State license or exemption from licensing shall be subject to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with affected agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with affected agencies The Commission shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Commerce before certifying the State of Alaska’s regulatory program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Federal laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application of Federal laws Nothing in this section shall preempt the application of Federal environmental, natural resources, or cultural resources protection laws according to their terms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight by the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Oversight by the Commission The State of Alaska shall notify the Commission not later than 30 days after making any significant modification to its regulatory program. The Commission shall periodically review the State’s program to ensure compliance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resumption of Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Resumption of Commission authority Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Commission shall reassert its licensing and regulatory authority under this subchapter if the Commission finds that the State of Alaska has not complied with one or more of the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Determination by the Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fish and wildlife If the State of Alaska determines that a recommendation under subsection (a)(3)(C) is inconsistent with paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), the State of Alaska may decline to adopt all or part of the recommendations in accordance with the procedures established under section 803(j)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>