<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/823f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_823f"><akn:num>823f</akn:num><akn:heading>Closed-loop pumped storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 823f. Closed-loop pumped storage projects(a) Expedited licensing process for closed-loop pumped storage projects(1) In generalAs provided in this section, the Commission may issue and amend licenses, as appropriate, for closed-loop pumped storage projects.


(2) RuleNot later than 180 days after October 23, 2018, the Commission shall issue a rule establishing an expedited process for issuing and amending licenses for closed-loop pumped storage projects under this section.


(3) Interagency task forceIn establishing the expedited process under this section, the Commission shall convene an interagency task force, with appropriate Federal and State agencies and Indian tribes represented, to coordinate the regulatory processes associated with the authorizations required to construct and operate closed-loop pumped storage projects.


(4) Length of processThe Commission shall seek to ensure that the expedited process under this section will result in final decision on an application for a license by not later than 2 years after receipt of a completed application for such license.



(b) Dam safetyBefore issuing any license for a closed-loop pumped storage project, the Commission shall assess the safety of existing dams and other structures related to the project (including possible consequences associated with failure of such structures).


(c) Exceptions from other requirements(1) In generalIn issuing or amending a license for a closed-loop pumped storage project pursuant to the expedited process established under this section, the Commission may grant an exception from any other requirement of this subchapter with respect to any part of the closed-loop pumped storage project (not including any dam or other impoundment).


(2) ConsultationIn granting an exception under paragraph (1), the Commission shall consult with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the National Marine Fisheries Service, and the State agency exercising administration over the fish and wildl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited licensing process for closed-loop pumped storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expedited licensing process for closed-loop pumped storage projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dam safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Dam safety Before issuing any license for a closed-loop pumped storage project, the Commission shall assess the safety of existing dams and other structures related to the project (including possible consequences associated with failure of such structures).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions from other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions from other requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfers Notwithstanding section 798 of this title, and regardless of whether the holder of a preliminary permit for a closed-loop pumped storage project claimed municipal preference under section 800(a) of this title when obtaining the permit, on request by a municipality, the Commission may, to facilitate development of a closed-loop pumped storage project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency communications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interagency communications Interagency cooperation in the preparation of environmental documents under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) with respect to an application for a license for a closed-loop pumped storage project submitted pursuant to this section, and interagency communications relating to licensing process coordination pursuant to this section, shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developing abandoned mines for pumped storage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Developing abandoned mines for pumped storage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying criteria for closed-loop pumped storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Qualifying criteria for closed-loop pumped storage projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_823f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Savings clause Nothing in this section affects any authority of the Commission to license a closed-loop pumped storage project under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>