<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824a–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824a–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824a–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824a_3"><akn:num>824a–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Cogeneration and small power production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824a–3. Cogeneration and small power production(a) Cogeneration and small power production rulesNot later than 1 year after November 9, 1978, the Commission shall prescribe, and from time to time thereafter revise, such rules as it determines necessary to encourage cogeneration and small power production, and to encourage geothermal small power production facilities of not more than 80 megawatts capacity, which rules require electric utilities to offer to—(1) sell electric energy to qualifying cogeneration facilities and qualifying small power production facilities 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. and

(2) purchase electric energy from such facilities.


Such rules shall be prescribed, after consultation with representatives of Federal and State regulatory agencies having ratemaking authority for electric utilities, and after public notice and a reasonable opportunity for interested persons (including State and Federal agencies) to submit oral as well as written data, views, and arguments. Such rules shall include provisions respecting minimum reliability of qualifying cogeneration facilities and qualifying small power production facilities (including reliability of such facilities during emergencies) and rules respecting reliability of electric energy service to be available to such facilities from electric utilities during emergencies. Such rules may not authorize a qualifying cogeneration facility or qualifying small power production facility to make any sale for purposes other than resale.

(b) Rates for purchases by electric utilitiesThe rules prescribed under subsection (a) shall insure that, in requiring any electric utility to offer to purchase electric energy from any qualifying cogeneration facility or qualifying small power production facility, the rates for such purchase—(1) shall be just and reasonable to the electric consumers of the electric utility and in the public interest, and

(2) shall not discriminate against qualify</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cogeneration and small power production rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cogeneration and small power production rules Not later than 1 year after November 9, 1978, the Commission shall prescribe, and from time to time thereafter revise, such rules as it determines necessary to encourage cogeneration and small power production, and to encourage geothermal small power production facilities of not more than 80 megawatts capacity, which rules require electric utilities to offer to— Such rules shall be prescribed, after consultation with representatives of Federal and State regulatory agencies having ratemaking authority for electric utilities, and after public notice and a reasonable opportunity for interested persons (including State and Federal agencies) to submit oral as well as written data, views, and arguments. Such rules shall include provisions respecting minimum reliability of qualifying cogeneration facilities and qualifying small power production facilities (including reliability of such facilities during emergencies) and rules respecting reliab</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates for purchases by electric utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rates for purchases by electric utilities The rules prescribed under subsection (a) shall insure that, in requiring any electric utility to offer to purchase electric energy from any qualifying cogeneration facility or qualifying small power production facility, the rates for such purchase— No such rule prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide for a rate which exceeds the incremental cost to the electric utility of alternative electric energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates for sales by utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rates for sales by utilities The rules prescribed under subsection (a) shall insure that, in requiring any electric utility to offer to sell electric energy to any qualifying cogeneration facility or qualifying small power production facility, the rates for such sale—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Incremental cost of alternative electric energy” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Incremental cost of alternative electric energy” defined For purposes of this section, the term “incremental cost of alternative electric energy” means, with respect to electric energy purchased from a qualifying cogenerator or qualifying small power producer, the cost to the electric utility of the electric energy which, but for the purchase from such cogenerator or small power producer, such utility would generate or purchase from another source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of rules for qualifying cogeneration and qualifying small power production facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation of rules for qualifying cogeneration and qualifying small power production facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Judicial review and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Commission enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Federal contracts No contract between a Federal agency and any electric utility for the sale of electric energy by such Federal agency for resale which is entered into after November 9, 1978, may contain any provision which will have the effect of preventing the implementation of any rule under this section with respect to such utility. Any provision in any such contract which has such effect shall be null and void.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824a_3_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>New dams and diversions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) New dams and diversions Except for a hydroelectric project located at a Government dam (as defined in section 3(10) of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 796(10)]) at which non-Federal hydroelectric development is permissible, this section shall not apply to any hydroelectric project which impounds or diverts the water of a natural watercourse by means of a new dam or diversion unless the project meets each of the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>