<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824d"><akn:num>824d</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates and charges; schedules; suspension of new rates; automatic adjustment clauses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824d. Rates and charges; schedules; suspension of new rates; automatic adjustment clauses(a) Just and reasonable ratesAll rates and charges made, demanded, or received by any public utility for or in connection with the transmission or sale of electric energy subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, and all rules and regulations affecting or pertaining to such rates or charges shall be just and reasonable, and any such rate or charge that is not just and reasonable is hereby declared to be unlawful.


(b) Preference or advantage unlawfulNo public utility shall, with respect to any transmission or sale subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, (1) make or grant any undue preference or advantage to any person or subject any person to any undue prejudice or disadvantage, or (2) maintain any unreasonable difference in rates, charges, service, facilities, or in any other respect, either as between localities or as between classes of service.


(c) SchedulesUnder such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe, every public utility shall file with the Commission, within such time and in such form as the Commission may designate, and shall keep open in convenient form and place for public inspection schedules showing all rates and charges for any transmission or sale subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, and the classifications, practices, and regulations affecting such rates and charges, together with all contracts which in any manner affect or relate to such rates, charges, classifications, and services.


(d) Notice required for rate changesUnless the Commission otherwise orders, no change shall be made by any public utility in any such rate, charge, classification, or service, or in any rule, regulation, or contract relating thereto, except after sixty days’ notice to the Commission and to the public. Such notice shall be given by filing with the Commission and keeping open for public inspection new schedules stating plainly the change </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Just and reasonable rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Just and reasonable rates All rates and charges made, demanded, or received by any public utility for or in connection with the transmission or sale of electric energy subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, and all rules and regulations affecting or pertaining to such rates or charges shall be just and reasonable, and any such rate or charge that is not just and reasonable is hereby declared to be unlawful.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference or advantage unlawful</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preference or advantage unlawful No public utility shall, with respect to any transmission or sale subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, (1) make or grant any undue preference or advantage to any person or subject any person to any undue prejudice or disadvantage, or (2) maintain any unreasonable difference in rates, charges, service, facilities, or in any other respect, either as between localities or as between classes of service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Schedules Under such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe, every public utility shall file with the Commission, within such time and in such form as the Commission may designate, and shall keep open in convenient form and place for public inspection schedules showing all rates and charges for any transmission or sale subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, and the classifications, practices, and regulations affecting such rates and charges, together with all contracts which in any manner affect or relate to such rates, charges, classifications, and services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice required for rate changes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice required for rate changes Unless the Commission otherwise orders, no change shall be made by any public utility in any such rate, charge, classification, or service, or in any rule, regulation, or contract relating thereto, except after sixty days’ notice to the Commission and to the public. Such notice shall be given by filing with the Commission and keeping open for public inspection new schedules stating plainly the change or changes to be made in the schedule or schedules then in force and the time when the change or changes will go into effect. The Commission, for good cause shown, may allow changes to take effect without requiring the sixty days’ notice herein provided for by an order specifying the changes so to be made and the time when they shall take effect and the manner in which they shall be filed and published.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of new rates; hearings; five-month period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension of new rates; hearings; five-month period Whenever any such new schedule is filed the Commission shall have authority, either upon complaint or upon its own initiative without complaint, at once, and, if it so orders, without answer or formal pleading by the public utility, but upon reasonable notice, to enter upon a hearing concerning the lawfulness of such rate, charge, classification, or service; and, pending such hearing and the decision thereon, the Commission, upon filing with such schedules and delivering to the public utility affected thereby a statement in writing of its reasons for such suspension, may suspend the operation of such schedule and defer the use of such rate, charge, classification, or service, but not for a longer period than five months beyond the time when it would otherwise go into effect; and after full hearings, either completed before or after the rate, charge, classification, or service goes into effect, the Commission may make such orders </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of automatic adjustment clauses and public utility practices; action by Commission; “automatic adjustment clause” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review of automatic adjustment clauses and public utility practices; action by Commission; “automatic adjustment clause” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inaction of Commissioners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inaction of Commissioners</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>