<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824i"><akn:num>824i</akn:num><akn:heading>Interconnection authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824i. Interconnection authority(a) Powers of Commission; application by State regulatory authority(1) Upon application of any electric utility, Federal power marketing agency, geothermal power producer (including a producer which is not an electric utility), qualifying cogenerator, or qualifying small power producer, the Commission may issue an order requiring—(A) the physical connection of any cogeneration facility, any small power production facility, or the transmission facilities of any electric utility, with the facilities of such applicant,

(B) such action as may be necessary to make effective any physical connection described in subparagraph (A), which physical connection is ineffective for any reason, such as inadequate size, poor maintenance, or physical unreliability,

(C) such sale or exchange of electric energy or other coordination, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of any order under subparagraph (A) or (B), or

(D) such increase in transmission capacity as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of any order under subparagraph (A) or (B).


(2) Any State regulatory authority may apply to the Commission for an order for any action referred to in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (1). No such order may be issued by the Commission with respect to a Federal power marketing agency upon application of a State regulatory authority.


(b) Notice, hearing and determination by CommissionUpon receipt of an application under subsection (a), the Commission shall—(1) issue notice to each affected State regulatory authority, each affected electric utility, each affected Federal power marketing agency, each affected owner or operator of a cogeneration facility or of a small power production facility, and to the public.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma.

(2) afford an opportunity for an evidentiary hearing, and

(3) make a determination with respect to the matters referred to in subsection (c).


(c) Necessary fin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Commission; application by State regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers of Commission; application by State regulatory authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, hearing and determination by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice, hearing and determination by Commission Upon receipt of an application under subsection (a), the Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Necessary findings No order may be issued by the Commission under subsection (a) unless the Commission determines that such order—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motion of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Motion of Commission The Commission may, on its own motion, after compliance with the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), issue an order requiring any action described in subsection (a)(1) if the Commission determines that such order meets the requirements of subsection (c). No such order may be issued upon the Commission’s own motion with respect to a Federal power marketing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>