<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824j"><akn:num>824j</akn:num><akn:heading>Wheeling authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824j. Wheeling authority(a) Transmission service by any electric utility; notice, hearing and findings by CommissionAny electric utility, Federal power marketing agency, or any other person generating electric energy for sale for resale, may apply to the Commission for an order under this subsection requiring a transmitting utility to provide transmission services (including any enlargement of transmission capacity necessary to provide such services) to the applicant. Upon receipt of such application, after public notice and notice to each affected State regulatory authority, each affected electric utility, and each affected Federal power marketing agency, and after affording an opportunity for an evidentiary hearing, the Commission may issue such order if it finds that such order meets the requirements of section 824k of this title, and would otherwise be in the public interest. No order may be issued under this subsection unless the applicant has made a request for transmission services to the transmitting utility that would be the subject of such order at least 60 days prior to its filing of an application for such order.


(b) Reliability of electric serviceNo order may be issued under this section or section 824i of this title if, after giving consideration to consistently applied regional or national reliability standards, guidelines, or criteria, the Commission finds that such order would unreasonably impair the continued reliability of electric systems affected by the order.


(c) Replacement of electric energyNo order may be issued under subsection (a) or (b) which requires the transmitting utility subject to the order to transmit, during any period, an amount of electric energy which replaces any amount of electric energy—(1) required to be provided to such applicant pursuant to a contract during such period, or

(2) currently provided to the applicant by the utility subject to the order pursuant to a rate schedule on file during such period with the Com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission service by any electric utility; notice, hearing and findings by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transmission service by any electric utility; notice, hearing and findings by Commission Any electric utility, Federal power marketing agency, or any other person generating electric energy for sale for resale, may apply to the Commission for an order under this subsection requiring a transmitting utility to provide transmission services (including any enlargement of transmission capacity necessary to provide such services) to the applicant. Upon receipt of such application, after public notice and notice to each affected State regulatory authority, each affected electric utility, and each affected Federal power marketing agency, and after affording an opportunity for an evidentiary hearing, the Commission may issue such order if it finds that such order meets the requirements of section 824k of this title, and would otherwise be in the public interest. No order may be issued under this subsection unless the applicant has made a request for transmission services to the transmitting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reliability of electric service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reliability of electric service No order may be issued under this section or section 824i of this title if, after giving consideration to consistently applied regional or national reliability standards, guidelines, or criteria, the Commission finds that such order would unreasonably impair the continued reliability of electric systems affected by the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Replacement of electric energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Replacement of electric energy No order may be issued under subsection (a) or (b) which requires the transmitting utility subject to the order to transmit, during any period, an amount of electric energy which replaces any amount of electric energy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or modification of order; notice, hearing and findings of Commission; contents of order; inclusion in order of terms and conditions agreed upon by parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination or modification of order; notice, hearing and findings of Commission; contents of order; inclusion in order of terms and conditions agreed upon by parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Facilities” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Facilities” defined As used in this section, the term “facilities” means only facilities used for the generation or transmission of electric energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>