<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824o"><akn:num>824o</akn:num><akn:heading>Electric reliability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824o. Electric reliability(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “bulk-power system” means—(A) facilities and control systems necessary for operating an interconnected electric energy transmission network (or any portion thereof); and

(B) electric energy from generation facilities needed to maintain transmission system reliability.


The term does not include facilities used in the local distribution of electric energy.

(2) The terms “Electric Reliability Organization” and “ERO” mean the organization certified by the Commission under subsection (c) the purpose of which is to establish and enforce reliability standards for the bulk-power system, subject to Commission review.

(3) The term “reliability standard” means a requirement, approved by the Commission under this section, to provide for reliable operation of the bulk-power system. The term includes requirements for the operation of existing bulk-power system facilities, including cybersecurity protection, and the design of planned additions or modifications to such facilities to the extent necessary to provide for reliable operation of the bulk-power system, but the term does not include any requirement to enlarge such facilities or to construct new transmission capacity or generation capacity.

(4) The term “reliable operation” means operating the elements of the bulk-power system within equipment and electric system thermal, voltage, and stability limits so that instability, uncontrolled separation, or cascading failures of such system will not occur as a result of a sudden disturbance, including a cybersecurity incident, or unanticipated failure of system elements.

(5) The term “Interconnection” means a geographic area in which the operation of bulk-power system components is synchronized such that the failure of one or more of such components may adversely affect the ability of the operators of other components within the system to maintain reliable operation of the facilities within </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction and applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Jurisdiction and applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification Following the issuance of a Commission rule under subsection (b)(2), any person may submit an application to the Commission for certification as the Electric Reliability Organization. The Commission may certify one such ERO if the Commission determines that such ERO—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reliability standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reliability standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in Electric Reliability Organization rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Changes in Electric Reliability Organization rules The Electric Reliability Organization shall file with the Commission for approval any proposed rule or proposed rule change, accompanied by an explanation of its basis and purpose. The Commission, upon its own motion or complaint, may propose a change to the rules of the ERO. A proposed rule or proposed rule change shall take effect upon a finding by the Commission, after notice and opportunity for comment, that the change is just, reasonable, not unduly discriminatory or preferential, is in the public interest, and satisfies the requirements of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reliability reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reliability reports The ERO shall conduct periodic assessments of the reliability and adequacy of the bulk-power system in North America.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with Canada and Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with Canada and Mexico The President is urged to negotiate international agreements with the governments of Canada and Mexico to provide for effective compliance with reliability standards and the effectiveness of the ERO in the United States and Canada or Mexico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Savings provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824o_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional advisory bodies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regional advisory bodies The Commission shall establish a regional advisory body on the petition of at least two-thirds of the States within a region that have more than one-half of their electric load served within the region. A regional advisory body shall be composed of one member from each participating State in the region, appointed by the Governor of each State, and may include representatives of agencies, States, and provinces outside the United States. A regional advisory body may provide advice to the Electric Reliability Organization, a regional entity, or the Commission regarding the governance of an existing or proposed regional entity within the same region, whether a standard proposed to apply within the region is just, reasonable, not unduly discriminatory or preferential, and in the public interest, whether fees proposed to be assessed within the region are just, reasonable, not unduly discriminatory or preferential, and in the public interest and any other responsi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>