<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/824t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_824t"><akn:num>824t</akn:num><akn:heading>Electricity market transparency rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 824t. Electricity market transparency rules(a) In general(1) The Commission is directed to facilitate price transparency in markets for the sale and transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce, having due regard for the public interest, the integrity of those markets, fair competition, and the protection of consumers.

(2) The Commission may prescribe such rules as the Commission determines necessary and appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. The rules shall provide for the dissemination, on a timely basis, of information about the availability and prices of wholesale electric energy and transmission service to the Commission, State commissions, buyers and sellers of wholesale electric energy, users of transmission services, and the public.

(3) The Commission may—(A) obtain the information described in paragraph (2) from any market participant; and

(B) rely on entities other than the Commission to receive and make public the information, subject to the disclosure rules in subsection (b).


(4) In carrying out this section, the Commission shall consider the degree of price transparency provided by existing price publishers and providers of trade processing services, and shall rely on such publishers and services to the maximum extent possible. The Commission may establish an electronic information system if it determines that existing price publications are not adequately providing price discovery or market transparency. Nothing in this section, however, shall affect any electronic information filing requirements in effect under this chapter as of August 8, 2005.


(b) Exemption of information from disclosure(1) Rules described in subsection (a)(2), if adopted, shall exempt from disclosure information the Commission determines would, if disclosed, be detrimental to the operation of an effective market or jeopardize system security.

(2) In determining the information to be made available under this section and time to make the informati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of information from disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemption of information from disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption from reporting requirements The Commission shall not require entities who have a de minimis market presence to comply with the reporting requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for violations occurring before notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Penalties for violations occurring before notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_824t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>ERCOT utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) ERCOT utilities This section shall not apply to a transaction for the purchase or sale of wholesale electric energy or transmission services within the area described in section 824k(k)(2)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>