<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/825d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/825d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/825d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_825d"><akn:num>825d</akn:num><akn:heading>Officials dealing in securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 825d. Officials dealing in securities(a) Benefits; making or declaring dividends out of capital accountIt shall be unlawful for any officer or director of any public utility to receive for his own benefit, directly or indirectly, any money or thing of value in respect of the negotiation, hypothecation, or sale by such public utility of any security issued or to be issued by such public utility, or to share in any of the proceeds thereof, or to participate in the making or paying of any dividends of such public utility from any funds properly included in capital account.


(b) Interlocking directorates(1) In generalAfter 6 months from August 26, 1935, it shall be unlawful for any person to hold the position of officer or director of more than one public utility or to hold the position of officer or director of a public utility and the position of officer or director of any bank, trust company, banking association, or firm that is authorized by law to underwrite or participate in the marketing of securities of a public utility, or officer or director of any company supplying electrical equipment to such public utility, unless the holding of such positions shall have been authorized by order of the Commission, upon due showing in form and manner prescribed by the Commission, that neither public nor private interests will be adversely affected thereby. The Commission shall not grant any such authorization in respect of such positions held on August 26, 1935, unless application for such authorization is filed with the Commission within sixty days after that date.


(2) Applicability(A) In generalIn the circumstances described in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall not apply to a person that holds or proposes to hold the positions of—(i) officer or director of a public utility; and

(ii) officer or director of a bank, trust company, banking association, or firm authorized by law to underwrite or participate in the marketing of securities of a public utility.


(B) Cir</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits; making or declaring dividends out of capital account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Benefits; making or declaring dividends out of capital account It shall be unlawful for any officer or director of any public utility to receive for his own benefit, directly or indirectly, any money or thing of value in respect of the negotiation, hypothecation, or sale by such public utility of any security issued or to be issued by such public utility, or to share in any of the proceeds thereof, or to participate in the making or paying of any dividends of such public utility from any funds properly included in capital account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interlocking directorates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interlocking directorates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of prior positions; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statement of prior positions; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>