<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8302"><akn:num>8302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8302. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Coastal ecosystemThe term “coastal ecosystem” means a biological community of organisms interacting with each other and their habitats in a coastal landscape.


(2) Coastal habitat assessmentThe term “coastal habitat assessment” means the process of evaluating the physical, chemical, and biological function of a coastal site to determine the value of the site to fish and wildlife.


(3) Coastal habitat enhancementThe term “coastal habitat enhancement” means the manipulation of the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a coastal ecosystem to increase or decrease specific biological functions that make the ecosystem valuable to fish and wildlife.


(4) Coastal habitat planningThe term “coastal habitat planning” means the process of developing a comprehensive plan that—(A) characterizes a coastal ecosystem;

(B) sets protection, restoration, or enhancement goals and identifies the priorities of those goals;

(C) describes conservation strategies and methodologies;

(D) establishes a timetable for implementation of the plan; and

(E) identifies roles of participants and stakeholders.


(5) Coastal habitat protection(A) In generalThe term “coastal habitat protection” means a long-term action to safeguard habitat of value to fish and wildlife in a coastal ecosystem.


(B) InclusionThe term “coastal habitat protection” includes activities to support establishment of a conservation easement or fee title acquisition by Federal and non-Federal partners.



(6) Coastal habitat restorationThe term “coastal habitat restoration” means the manipulation of the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a coastal ecosystem with the goal of returning, to the maximum extent practicable, the full natural biological functions to lost or degraded native habitat.


(7) Coastal landscapeThe term “coastal landscape” means a portion of a coastal ecosystem within or adjacent to a coastal State that contains various habitat types</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal ecosystem</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Coastal ecosystem The term “coastal ecosystem” means a biological community of organisms interacting with each other and their habitats in a coastal landscape.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal habitat assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Coastal habitat assessment The term “coastal habitat assessment” means the process of evaluating the physical, chemical, and biological function of a coastal site to determine the value of the site to fish and wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal habitat enhancement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Coastal habitat enhancement The term “coastal habitat enhancement” means the manipulation of the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a coastal ecosystem to increase or decrease specific biological functions that make the ecosystem valuable to fish and wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal habitat planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Coastal habitat planning The term “coastal habitat planning” means the process of developing a comprehensive plan that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal habitat protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Coastal habitat protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal habitat restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Coastal habitat restoration The term “coastal habitat restoration” means the manipulation of the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of a coastal ecosystem with the goal of returning, to the maximum extent practicable, the full natural biological functions to lost or degraded native habitat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal landscape</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Coastal landscape The term “coastal landscape” means a portion of a coastal ecosystem within or adjacent to a coastal State that contains various habitat types, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Coastal State The term “coastal State” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal trust species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Federal trust species The term “Federal trust species” means migratory birds, threatened species or endangered species listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.), interjurisdictional fish, and marine mammals for which the Secretary has management authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8302_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Financial assistance The term “financial assistance” means Federal funding provided to Federal, State, local, or Tribal governments, nongovernmental institutions, nonprofit organizations, and private individuals and entities through a grant or cooperative agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>