<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831a"><akn:num>831a</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership, operation, and duties of the Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831a. Membership, operation, and duties of the Board of Directors(a) Membership(1) AppointmentThe Board of Directors of the Corporation (referred to in this chapter as the “Board”) shall be composed of 9 members appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, at least 7 of whom shall be a legal resident of the service area of the Corporation.


(2) ChairmanThe members of the Board shall select 1 of the members to act as chairman of the Board.



(b) QualificationsTo be eligible to be appointed as a member of the Board, an individual—(1) shall be a citizen of the United States;

(2) shall have management expertise relative to a large for-profit or nonprofit corporate, government, or academic structure;

(3) shall not be an employee of the Corporation;

(4) shall make full disclosure to Congress of any investment or other financial interest that the individual holds in the energy industry; and

(5) shall affirm support for the objectives and missions of the Corporation, including being a national leader in technological innovation, low-cost power, and environmental stewardship.


(c) RecommendationsIn appointing members of the Board, the President shall—(1) consider recommendations from such public officials as—(A) the Governors of States in the service area;

(B) individual citizens;

(C) business, industrial, labor, electric power distribution, environmental, civic, and service organizations; and

(D) the congressional delegations of the States in the service area; and


(2) seek qualified members from among persons who reflect the diversity, including the geographical diversity, and needs of the service area of the Corporation.


(d) Terms(1) In generalA member of the Board shall serve a term of 5 years. A member of the Board whose term has expired may continue to serve after the member’s term has expired until the date on which a successor takes office, except that the member shall not serve beyond the end of the session of Congress </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications To be eligible to be appointed as a member of the Board, an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendations In appointing members of the Board, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Quorum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief executive officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Chief executive officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Compensation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>