<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831b"><akn:num>831b</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees; wages of laborers and mechanics; application of employees’ compensation prov</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831b. Officers and employees; wages of laborers and mechanics; application of employees’ compensation provisions(a) Appointment by the chief executive officerThe chief executive officer shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Board, and without regard to the provisions of the civil service laws applicable to officers and employees of the United States, such managers, assistant managers, officers, employees, attorneys, and agents as are necessary for the transaction of the business of the Corporation.


(b) Wage ratesAll contracts to which the Corporation is a party and which require the employment of laborers and mechanics in the construction, alteration, maintenance, or repair of buildings, dams, locks, or other projects shall contain a provision that not less than the prevailing rate of wages for work of a similar nature prevailing in the vicinity shall be paid to such laborers or mechanics.
In the event any dispute arises as to what are the prevailing rates of wages, the question shall be referred to the Secretary of Labor for determination, and his decision shall be final. In the determination of such prevailing rate or rates, due regard shall be given to those rates which have been secured through collective agreement by representatives of employers and employees.
Where such work as is described in the two preceding paragraphs is done directly by the Corporation the prevailing rate of wages shall be paid in the same manner as though such work had been let by contract.
Insofar as applicable, the benefits of subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5 shall extend to persons given employment under the provisions of this chapter.


(May 18, 1933, ch. 32, § 3, 48 Stat. 59; Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 225(a), June 6, 1972, 86 Stat. 206; Pub. L. 108–447, div. C, title VI, § 602, Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 2966.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
In the last par. of subsec. (b), “subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5” substituted for “the Act entitled ‘An Act to provid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment by the chief executive officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment by the chief executive officer The chief executive officer shall appoint, with the advice and consent of the Board, and without regard to the provisions of the civil service laws applicable to officers and employees of the United States, such managers, assistant managers, officers, employees, attorneys, and agents as are necessary for the transaction of the business of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wage rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wage rates All contracts to which the Corporation is a party and which require the employment of laborers and mechanics in the construction, alteration, maintenance, or repair of buildings, dams, locks, or other projects shall contain a provision that not less than the prevailing rate of wages for work of a similar nature prevailing in the vicinity shall be paid to such laborers or mechanics.
In the event any dispute arises as to what are the prevailing rates of wages, the question shall be referred to the Secretary of Labor for determination, and his decision shall be final. In the determination of such prevailing rate or rates, due regard shall be given to those rates which have been secured through collective agreement by representatives of employers and employees.
Where such work as is described in the two preceding paragraphs is done directly by the Corporation the prevailing rate of wages shall be paid in the same manner as though such work had been let by contract.
Insofar a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>