<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831c–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831c–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831c–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831c_3"><akn:num>831c–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831c–3. Law enforcement(a) Designation of law enforcement agentsThe Board may designate employees of the corporation to act as law enforcement agents in the area of jurisdiction described in subsection (c).


(b) Duties and powers(1) DutiesA law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) shall maintain law and order and protect persons and property in the area of jurisdiction described in subsection (c) and protect property and officials and employees of the corporation outside that area.


(2) PowersIn the performance of duties described in paragraph (1), a law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) may—(A) make arrests without warrant for any offense against the United States committed in the agent’s presence, or for any felony cognizable under the laws of the United States if the agent has probable cause to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such a felony;

(B) execute any warrant or other process issued by a court or officer of competent jurisdiction for the enforcement of any Federal law or regulation issued pursuant to law in connection with the investigation of an offense described in subparagraph (A);

(C) conduct an investigation of an offense described in subparagraph (A) in the absence of investigation of the offense by any Federal law enforcement agency having investigative jurisdiction over the offense or with the concurrence of that agency; and

(D) carry firearms in carrying out any activity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).



(c) Area of jurisdictionA law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) shall be authorized to exercise the law enforcement duties and powers described in subsection (b)—(1) on any lands or facilities owned or leased by the corporation or within such adjoining areas in the vicinities of such lands or facilities as may be determined by the Board under subsection (e); and

(2) on other lands or facilities—(A) when the person to be arrested is in the process </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of law enforcement agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of law enforcement agents The Board may designate employees of the corporation to act as law enforcement agents in the area of jurisdiction described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties and powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area of jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Area of jurisdiction A law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) shall be authorized to exercise the law enforcement duties and powers described in subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal investigative jurisdiction and State civil and criminal jurisdiction not preempted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal investigative jurisdiction and State civil and criminal jurisdiction not preempted Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of adjoining areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination of adjoining areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Qualifications and training The Board, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall adopt qualification and training standards for law enforcement agents designated under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relation to other law A law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) shall not be considered to be a law enforcement officer of the United States for the purposes of any other law, and no law enforcement agent designated under subsection (a) or other employee of the corporation shall receive an increase in compensation solely on account of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831c_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship with Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relationship with Attorney General The duties and powers of law enforcement agents designated under subsection (a) that are described in subsection (b) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>