<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831d"><akn:num>831d</akn:num><akn:heading>Directors; maintenance and operation of plant for production, sale, and distribution of fertilizer a</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831d. Directors; maintenance and operation of plant for production, sale, and distribution of fertilizer and power
The Board is authorized—(a) To contract with commercial producers for the production of such fertilizers or fertilizer materials as may be needed in the Government’s program of development and introduction in excess of that produced by Government plants. Such contracts may provide either for outright purchase of materials by the Board or only for the payment of carrying charges on special materials manufactured at the board’s 11 So in original. Probably should be “Board’s”. request for its program.

(b) To arrange with farmers and farm organizations for large-scale practical use of the new forms of fertilizers under conditions permitting an accurate measure of the economic return they produce.

(c) To cooperate with National, State, district, or county experimental stations or demonstration farms, with farmers, landowners, and associations of farmers or landowners, for the use of new forms of fertilizer or fertilizer practices during the initial or experimental period of their introduction, and for promoting the prevention of soil erosion by the use of fertilizers and otherwise.

(d) The Board, in order to improve and cheapen the production of fertilizer, is authorized to manufacture and sell fixed nitrogen, fertilizer, and fertilizer ingredients at Muscle Shoals by the employment of existing facilities, by modernizing existing plants, or by any other process or processes that in its judgment shall appear wise and profitable for the fixation of atmospheric nitrogen or the cheapening of the production of fertilizer.

(e) Under the authority of this chapter the Board may make donations or sales of the product of the plant or plants operated by it to be fairly and equitably distributed through the agency of county demonstration agents, agricultural colleges, or otherwise as the Board may direct, for experimentation, education, and introduction of the use</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To contract with commercial producers for the production of such fertilizers or fertilizer materials as may be needed in the Government’s program of development and introduction in excess of that produced by Government plants. Such contracts may provide either for outright purchase of materials by the Board or only for the payment of carrying charges on special materials manufactured at the board’s 11 So in original. Probably should be “Board’s”. request for its program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To arrange with farmers and farm organizations for large-scale practical use of the new forms of fertilizers under conditions permitting an accurate measure of the economic return they produce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To cooperate with National, State, district, or county experimental stations or demonstration farms, with farmers, landowners, and associations of farmers or landowners, for the use of new forms of fertilizer or fertilizer practices during the initial or experimental period of their introduction, and for promoting the prevention of soil erosion by the use of fertilizers and otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Board, in order to improve and cheapen the production of fertilizer, is authorized to manufacture and sell fixed nitrogen, fertilizer, and fertilizer ingredients at Muscle Shoals by the employment of existing facilities, by modernizing existing plants, or by any other process or processes that in its judgment shall appear wise and profitable for the fixation of atmospheric nitrogen or the cheapening of the production of fertilizer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Under the authority of this chapter the Board may make donations or sales of the product of the plant or plants operated by it to be fairly and equitably distributed through the agency of county demonstration agents, agricultural colleges, or otherwise as the Board may direct, for experimentation, education, and introduction of the use of such products in cooperation with practical farmers so as to obtain information as to the value, effect, and best methods of their use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Board is authorized to make alterations, modifications, or improvements in existing plants and facilities, and to construct new plants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In the event it is not used for the fixation of nitrogen for agricultural purposes or leased, then the Board shall maintain in stand-by condition nitrate plant numbered 2, or its equivalent, for the fixation of atmospheric nitrogen, for the production of explosives in the event of war or a national emergency, until the Congress shall by joint resolution release the Board from this obligation, and if any part thereof be used by the Board for the manufacture of phosphoric acid or potash, the balance of nitrate plant numbered 2 shall be kept in stand-by condition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) To establish, maintain, and operate laboratories and experimental plants, and to undertake experiments for the purpose of enabling the Corporation to furnish nitrogen products for military purposes, and nitrogen and other fertilizer products for agricultural purposes in the most economical manner and at the highest standard of efficiency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) To request the assistance and advice of any officer, agent, or employee of any executive department or of any independent office of the United States, to enable the Corporation the better to carry out its powers successfully, and as far as practicable shall utilize the services of such officers, agents, and employees, and the President shall, if in his opinion the public interest, service, or economy so require, direct that such assistance, advice, and service be rendered to the Corporation, and any individual that may be by the President directed to render such assistance, advice, and service shall be thereafter subject to the orders, rules, and regulations of the Board: Provided, That any invention or discovery made by virtue of and incidental to such service by an employee of the Government of the United States serving under this section, or by any employee of the Corporation, together with any patents which may be granted thereon, shall be the sole and exclusive property of the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Upon the requisition of the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Navy to manufacture for and sell at cost to the United States explosives or their nitrogenous content.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>