<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/831g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831g"><akn:num>831g</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal office of Corporation; books; directors’ oath</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831g. Principal office of Corporation; books; directors’ oath(a) LocationThe Corporation shall maintain its principal office in the immediate vicinity of Muscle Shoals, Alabama. The Corporation shall be held to be an inhabitant and resident of the northern judicial district of Alabama within the meaning of the laws of the United States relating to the venue of civil suits.


(b) Account booksThe Corporation shall at all times maintain complete and accurate books of accounts.


(c) Oath of officeEach member of the Board, before entering upon the duties of his office, shall subscribe to an oath (or affirmation) to support the Constitution of the United States and to faithfully and impartially perform the duties imposed upon him by this chapter.


(May 18, 1933, ch. 32, § 8, 48 Stat. 63; Pub. L. 108–447, div. C, title VI, § 603(a)(2), Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 2966.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 108–447 substituted “Board” for “board”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2004 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 108–447 effective on the later of the date on which at least three persons nominated under section 604(a) of Pub. L. 108–447 take office or May 18, 2005, see section 604(b) of Pub. L. 108–447, set out in an Appointments; Effective Date; Transition note under section 831a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Location The Corporation shall maintain its principal office in the immediate vicinity of Muscle Shoals, Alabama. The Corporation shall be held to be an inhabitant and resident of the northern judicial district of Alabama within the meaning of the laws of the United States relating to the venue of civil suits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Account books</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Account books The Corporation shall at all times maintain complete and accurate books of accounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oath of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Oath of office Each member of the Board, before entering upon the duties of his office, shall subscribe to an oath (or affirmation) to support the Constitution of the United States and to faithfully and impartially perform the duties imposed upon him by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>