<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_832e"><akn:num>832e</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 832e. Rate schedules
Schedules of rates and charges for electric energy produced at the Bonneville project and sold to purchasers as in this chapter provided shall be prepared by the administrator and become effective upon confirmation and approval thereof by the Secretary of Energy; and such rates and charges shall also be applicable to dispositions of electric energy to Federal agencies. Subject to confirmation and approval by the Secretary of Energy, such rate schedules may be modified from time to time by the administrator, and shall be fixed and established with a view to encouraging the widest possible diversified use of electric energy. The said rate schedules may provide for uniform rates or rates uniform throughout prescribed transmission areas in order to extend the benefits of an integrated transmission system and encourage the equitable distribution of the electric energy developed at the Bonneville project.
(Aug. 20, 1937, ch. 720, § 6, 50 Stat. 735; Oct. 23, 1945, ch. 433, § 3, 59 Stat. 546; Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(b), Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 578.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1945—Act Oct. 23, 1945, inserted “and such rates and charges shall also be applicable to dispositions of electric energy to Federal agencies” in first sentence.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
“Secretary of Energy” substituted in text for “Federal Power Commission” pursuant to Pub. L. 95–91, § 301(b), which is classified to section 7151(b) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.
Functions of Secretary of the Interior with respect to Bonneville Power Administration transferred to Secretary of Energy by section 7152(a)(1)(D), (2) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, with Bonneville Power Administration to be preserved as a distinct organizational entity within Department of Energy and headed by an Administrator.
The Federal Power Commission was terminated, and its functions, personnel, property, funds, etc., were transferred to the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>