<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/832h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_832h"><akn:num>832h</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 832h. Miscellaneous administrative provisions(a) Accounts; audit; procedures, etc., prescribedThe administrator, subject to the requirements of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], shall keep complete and accurate accounts of operations, including all funds expended and received in connection with transmission and sale of electric energy generated at the Bonneville project, and in the maintenance of such accounts, appropriate obligations shall be established for annual and sick leave of absence as earned. The Administrator shall, after the close of each fiscal year, obtain an independent commercial-type audit of such accounts. The forms, systems, and procedures prescribed by the Comptroller General for the Administrator’s appropriation and fund accounting shall be in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Power Act with respect to accounts of electric operations of public utilities and the regulations of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission pursuant thereto.


(b) Current expensesThe administrator may make such expenditures for offices, vehicles, furnishings, equipment, supplies, and books; for attendance at meetings; and for such other facilities and services as he may find necessary for the proper administration of this chapter.


(Aug. 20, 1937, ch. 720, § 9, 50 Stat. 736; Oct. 23, 1945, ch. 433, § 4, 59 Stat. 547; Pub. L. 89–448, § 2(a), formerly § 2, June 14, 1966, 80 Stat. 200, as renumbered Pub. L. 89–561, § 6(1), Sept. 7, 1966, 80 Stat. 714; Pub. L. 95–91, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(B), Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 583.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFederal Power Act, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original the “Federal Water Power Act”, and was redesignated the Federal Power Act by section 791a of this title. The Federal Power Act is act June 10, 1920, ch. 285, 41 Stat. 1063, and is classified generally to chapter 12 (§ 791a et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 791a of this ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounts; audit; procedures, etc., prescribed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Accounts; audit; procedures, etc., prescribed The administrator, subject to the requirements of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], shall keep complete and accurate accounts of operations, including all funds expended and received in connection with transmission and sale of electric energy generated at the Bonneville project, and in the maintenance of such accounts, appropriate obligations shall be established for annual and sick leave of absence as earned. The Administrator shall, after the close of each fiscal year, obtain an independent commercial-type audit of such accounts. The forms, systems, and procedures prescribed by the Comptroller General for the Administrator’s appropriation and fund accounting shall be in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Power Act with respect to accounts of electric operations of public utilities and the regulations of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission pursuant thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Current expenses The administrator may make such expenditures for offices, vehicles, furnishings, equipment, supplies, and books; for attendance at meetings; and for such other facilities and services as he may find necessary for the proper administration of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>