<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/833h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/833h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/833h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_833h"><akn:num>833h</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel; appointment and compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 833h. Personnel; appointment and compensation
The Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Army, and the Secretary of Energy, respectively, shall appoint such attorneys, engineers, and other experts as may be necessary for carrying out the functions entrusted to them under this chapter, and shall fix the compensation of each of such attorneys, engineers, and other experts; and they may, subject to the civil-service laws, appoint such other officers and employees as may be necessary to carry out such functions and fix their salaries in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. In the administration of this chapter the services of regular employees in the Bureau may be utilized and an equitable part of the salaries of such employees whose services are thus utilized may be charged by the Bureau to the operating costs of the power features of the Fort Peck project. The Bureau similarly may utilize and charge for facilities of the Bureau which economically can be used in connection with the administration of this chapter.
(May 18, 1938, ch. 250, § 9, 52 Stat. 406; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501; Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 782, title XI, § 1106(a), 63 Stat. 972; Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(b), Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 578.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Provisions which authorized the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Army, and the Secretary of Energy to appoint such attorneys, engineers, and other experts as may be necessary for carrying out the functions entrusted to them under this chapter “without regard to the provisions of the civil-service laws”, and to fix their compensation “at not to exceed $7,500 per annum”, have been omitted as obsolete and superseded.
Such appointments are subject to the civil service laws unless specifically excepted by those laws or by laws enacted subsequent to Executive Order No. 8743, Apr. 23, 1941, issued by the President pursuant to the Act of Nov. 26, 1940, ch. 9</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>