<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_835"><akn:num>835</akn:num><akn:heading>Project authorized; laws applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 835. Project authorized; laws applicable
In addition to the primary purposes for which the Grand Coulee Dam project (hereafter to be known as the Columbia Basin project and herein called the “project”) was authorized under the provisions of the Act of August 30, 1935 (49 Stat. 1028), the project is authorized and reauthorized as a project subject to the Reclamation Project Act of 1939; and the provisions of each of those two Acts together with the provisions of this Act shall govern the repayment of expenditures and the construction, operation, and maintenance of the works constructed as a part of the project.
(May 27, 1937, ch. 269, § 1, 50 Stat. 208; Mar. 10, 1943, ch. 14, 57 Stat. 14.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAct of August 30, 1935 (49 Stat. 1028), referred to in text, is act Aug. 30, 1935, ch. 831, 49 Stat. 1028, which act, by section 2, authorized the construction of the Grand Coulee Dam.
The Reclamation Project Act of 1939, referred to in text, is act Aug. 4, 1939, ch. 418, 53 Stat. 1187, which is classified generally to sections 375a, 387 to 389, 485 to 485h, and 485i to 485k of Title 43, Public Lands. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 485k of Title 43 and Tables.
Those two Acts, referred to in text, refer to the act of Aug. 30, 1935, and to the Reclamation Project Act of 1939. See notes above.
This Act, referred to in text, is act May 27, 1937, ch. 269, as amended generally by act Mar. 10, 1943, ch. 14, 57 Stat. 14, known as The Columbia Basin Project Act, which enacted this section, sections 835a to 835c–5 of this title, and provisions set out as a note under this section. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under this section and Tables.

Amendments1943—Act Mar. 10, 1943, amended section generally.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitleAct May 27, 1937, ch. 269, § 11, as added by Mar. 10, 1943, ch. 14, 57 Stat. 20, provided that: “This Act [enacting th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>