<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/835j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_835j"><akn:num>835j</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects marketing commercial power and energy; consolidated financial statement to President and Co</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 835j. Projects marketing commercial power and energy; consolidated financial statement to President and Congress; adjustment of rates to assure return of reimbursable construction costs within prescribed period
The Secretary of the Interior shall prepare, maintain, and present annually to the President and the Congress a consolidated financial statement for all projects heretofore or hereafter authorized, including the third powerplant at Grand Coulee Dam, from or by means of which commercial power and energy is marketed through the facilities of the Federal Columbia River power system and for all other projects associated therewith to the extent that the costs of these projects are required by law to be charged to and returned from net revenues derived from the power and energy, or any power and energy, so marketed, and he shall, if said consolidated statement indicates that the reimbursable construction costs of the projects, or any of the projects, covered thereby which are chargeable to and returnable from the commercial power and energy so marketed are likely not to be returned within the period prescribed by law, take prompt action to adjust the rates charged for such power and energy to the extent necessary to assure such return.
(Pub. L. 89–448, § 2(a), formerly § 2, June 14, 1966, 80 Stat. 200, renumbered Pub. L. 89–561, § 6(1), Sept. 7, 1966, 80 Stat. 714.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is comprised of first sentence of first par. of section 2(a) of Pub. L. 89–448, as so designated by Pub. L. 89–561. Second sentence of the first par. repealed section 832h(c) of this title; second par. of such section 2(a) is classified to section 835k of this title; subsecs. (b) and (c) of section 2 are classified to sections 835l and 835m of this title, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Reporting RequirementsFor termination, effective May 15, 2000, of provisions of this section requiring annual presentation to Congress of a c</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>