<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_839a"><akn:num>839a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 839a. Definitions
As used in this chapter, the term—(1) “Acquire” and “acquisition” shall not be construed as authorizing the Administrator to construct, or have ownership of, under this chapter or any other law, any electric generating facility.

(2) “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration.

(3) “Conservation” means any reduction in electric power consumption as a result of increases in the efficiency of energy use, production, or distribution.

(4)(A) “Cost-effective”, when applied to any measure or resource referred to in this chapter, means that such measure or resource must be forecast—(i) to be reliable and available within the time it is needed, and

(ii) to meet or reduce the electric power demand, as determined by the Council or the Administrator, as appropriate, of the consumers of the customers at an estimated incremental system cost no greater than that of the least-cost similarly reliable and available alternative measure or resource, or any combination thereof.


(B) For purposes of this paragraph, the term “system cost” means an estimate of all direct costs of a measure or resource over its effective life, including, if applicable, the cost of distribution and transmission to the consumer and, among other factors, waste disposal costs, end-of-cycle costs, and fuel costs (including projected increases), and such quantifiable environmental costs and benefits as the Administrator determines, on the basis of a methodology developed by the Council as part of the plan, or in the absence of the plan by the Administrator, are directly attributable to such measure or resource.

(C) In determining the amount of power that a conservation measure or other resource may be expected to save or to produce, the Council or the Administrator, as the case may be, shall take into account projected realization factors and plant factors, including appropriate historical experience with similar measures or resources.

(D) For purposes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “Acquire” and “acquisition” shall not be construed as authorizing the Administrator to construct, or have ownership of, under this chapter or any other law, any electric generating facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “Conservation” means any reduction in electric power consumption as a result of increases in the efficiency of energy use, production, or distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “Consumer” means any end user of electric power.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “Council” means, unless otherwise specifically provided, the members appointed to the Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council established pursuant to section 839b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “Customer” means anyone who contracts for the purchase of power from the Administrator pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “Direct service industrial customer” means an industrial customer that contracts for the purchase of power from the Administrator for direct consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) “Electric power” means electric peaking capacity, or electric energy, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839a_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “Federal base system resources” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>