<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_839b"><akn:num>839b</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional planning and participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 839b. Regional planning and participation(a) Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council; establishment and operation as regional agency(1) The purposes of this section are to provide for the prompt establishment and effective operation of the Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council, to further the purposes of this chapter by the Council promptly preparing and adopting (A) a regional conservation and electric power plan and (B) a program to protect, mitigate, and enhance fish and wildlife, and to otherwise expeditiously and effectively carry out the Council’s responsibilities and functions under this chapter.

(2) To achieve such purposes and facilitate cooperation among the States of Idaho, Montana, Oregon, and Washington, and with the Bonneville Power Administration, the consent of Congress is given for an agreement described in this paragraph and not in conflict with this chapter, pursuant to which—(A) there shall be established a regional agency known as the “Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council” which (i) shall have its offices in the Pacific Northwest, (ii) shall carry out its functions and responsibilities in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, (iii) shall continue in force and effect in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, and (iv) except as otherwise provided in this chapter, shall not be considered an agency or instrumentality of the United States for the purpose of any Federal law; and

(B) two persons from each State may be appointed, subject to the applicable laws of each such State, to undertake the functions and duties of members of the Council.


The State may fill any vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term of any member. The appointment of six initial members, subject to applicable State law, by June 30, 1981, by at least three of such States shall constitute an agreement by the States establishing the Council and such agreement is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council; establishment and operation as regional agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pacific Northwest Electric Power and Conservation Planning Council; establishment and operation as regional agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative establishment of Council as Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternative establishment of Council as Federal agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization and operation of Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Organization and operation of Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional conservation and electric power plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regional conservation and electric power plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan priorities and requisite features; studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan priorities and requisite features; studies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model conservation standards; surcharges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Model conservation standards; surcharges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public information; consultation; contracts and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public information; consultation; contracts and technical assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish and wildlife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fish and wildlife</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Review The Council may from time to time review the actions of the Administrator pursuant to this section and section 839d of this title to determine whether such actions are consistent with the plan and programs, the extent to which the plan and programs is being implemented, and to assist the Council in preparing amendments to the plan and programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests by Council for action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Requests by Council for action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>