<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_839d"><akn:num>839d</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation and resource acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 839d. Conservation and resource acquisition(a) Conservation measures; resources(1) The Administrator shall acquire such resources through conservation, implement all such conservation measures, and acquire such renewable resources which are installed by a residential or small commercial consumer to reduce load, as the Administrator determines are consistent with the plan, or if no plan is in effect with the criteria of section 839b(e)(1) of this title and the considerations of section 839b(e)(2) of this title and, in the case of major resources, in accordance with subsection (c) of this section. Such conservation measures and such resources may include, but are not limited to—(A) loans and grants to consumers for insulation or weatherization, increased system efficiency, and waste energy recovery by direct application,

(B) technical and financial assistance to, and other cooperation with, the Administrator’s customers and governmental authorities to encourage maximum cost-effective voluntary conservation and the attainment of any cost-effective conservation objectives adopted by individual States or subdivisions thereof,

(C) aiding the Administrator’s customers and governmental authorities in implementing model conservation standards adopted pursuant to section 839b(f) of this title, and

(D) conducting demonstration projects to determine the cost effectiveness of conservation measures and direct application of renewable energy resources.


(2) In addition to acquiring electric power pursuant to section 839c(c) of this title, or on a short-term basis pursuant to section 11(b)(6)(i) of the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act [16 U.S.C. 838i(b)(6)(i)], the Administrator shall acquire, in accordance with this section, sufficient resources—(A) to meet his contractual obligations that remain after taking into account planned savings from measures provided for in paragraph (1) of this subsection, and

(B) to assist in meeting the requirements of section 839</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation measures; resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conservation measures; resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for acquiring major resources, implementing conservation measures, paying or reimbursing investigation and preconstruction expenses, or granting billing credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure for acquiring major resources, implementing conservation measures, paying or reimbursing investigation and preconstruction expenses, or granting billing credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of resources other than major resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acquisition of resources other than major resources The Administrator is authorized to acquire a resource, other than a major resource, whether or not such resource meets the criteria of section 839b(e)(1) of this title and the considerations of section 839b(e)(2) of this title but which he determines is an experimental, developmental, demonstration, or pilot project of a type with a potential for providing cost-effective service to the region. The Administrator shall make no obligation for the acquisition of such resource until it is included in the annual budgets submitted to the Congress pursuant to the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act [16 U.S.C. 838 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectuation of priorities; use of customers and local entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effectuation of priorities; use of customers and local entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements; investigation and initial development of renewable resources other than major resources; reimbursement of investigation and preconstruction expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agreements; investigation and initial development of renewable resources other than major resources; reimbursement of investigation and preconstruction expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental impact statements At the request of the appropriate State, any environmental impact statement which may be required with respect to a resource, to the extent determined possible by the Administrator in accordance with applicable law and regulations, may be prepared jointly and in coordination with any required environmental impact statement of the State or any other statement which serves the purpose of an environmental impact statement which is required by State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Billing credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Billing credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Contracts Contracts for the acquisition of resources and for billing credits for major resources, including conservation activities, entered into pursuant to this section shall contain such terms and conditions, applicable after the contract is entered into, as will— Such contracts shall contain provisions assuring that the Administrator has the authority to approve all costs of, and proposals for, major modifications in construction, scheduling or operations and to assure that the Administrator is provided with such current information as he deems necessary to evaluate such construction and operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations not to be considered general obligations of United States or secured by full faith and credit of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Obligations not to be considered general obligations of United States or secured by full faith and credit of United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>