<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/839e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_839e"><akn:num>839e</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 839e. Rates(a) Establishment; periodic review and revision; confirmation and approval by Federal Energy Regulatory Commission(1) The Administrator shall establish, and periodically review and revise, rates for the sale and disposition of electric energy and capacity and for the transmission of non-Federal power. Such rates shall be established and, as appropriate, revised to recover, in accordance with sound business principles, the costs associated with the acquisition, conservation, and transmission of electric power, including the amortization of the Federal investment in the Federal Columbia River Power System (including irrigation costs required to be repaid out of power revenues) over a reasonable period of years and the other costs and expenses incurred by the Administrator pursuant to this chapter and other provisions of law. Such rates shall be established in accordance with sections 9 and 10 of the Federal Columbia River Transmission System Act (16 U.S.C. 838) [16 U.S.C. 838g and 838h], section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 [16 U.S.C. 825s], and the provisions of this chapter.

(2) Rates established under this section shall become effective only, except in the case of interim rules as provided in subsection (i)(6), upon confirmation and approval by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission upon a finding by the Commission, that such rates—(A) are sufficient to assure repayment of the Federal investment in the Federal Columbia River Power System over a reasonable number of years after first meeting the Administrator’s other costs,

(B) are based upon the Administrator’s total system costs, and

(C) insofar as transmission rates are concerned, equitably allocate the costs of the Federal transmission system between Federal and non-Federal power utilizing such system.



(b) General application of rates to meet general requirements(1) The Administrator shall establish a rate or rates of general application for electric power sold to meet the general requ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; periodic review and revision; confirmation and approval by Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; periodic review and revision; confirmation and approval by Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General application of rates to meet general requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General application of rates to meet general requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates applicable to direct service industrial customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rates applicable to direct service industrial customers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discount rates; special rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Discount rates; special rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform rates; rates for sale of peaking capacity; time-of-day, seasonal, and other rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Uniform rates; rates for sale of peaking capacity; time-of-day, seasonal, and other rates Nothing in this chapter prohibits the Administrator from establishing, in rate schedules of general application, a uniform rate or rates for sale of peaking capacity or from establishing time-of-day, seasonal rates, or other rate forms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis for rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Basis for rates Rates for all other firm power sold by the Administrator for use in the Pacific Northwest shall be based upon the cost of the portions of Federal base system resources, purchases of power under section 839c(c) of this title and additional resources which, in the determination of the Administrator, are applicable to such sales.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of costs and benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Allocation of costs and benefits Except to the extent that the allocation of costs and benefits is governed by provisions of law in effect on December 5, 1980, or by other provisions of this section, the Administrator shall equitably allocate to power rates, in accordance with generally accepted ratemaking principles and the provisions of this chapter, all costs and benefits not otherwise allocated under this section, including, but not limited to, conservation, fish and wildlife measures, uncontrollable events, reserves, the excess costs of experimental resources acquired under section 839d of this title, the cost of credits granted pursuant to section 839d of this title, operating services, and the sale of or inability to sell excess electric power.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surcharges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Surcharges Notwithstanding any other provision of this section (except the provisions of subsection (a) of this section), the Administrator shall adjust power rates to include any surcharges arising under section 839b(f) of this title, and shall allocate any revenues from such charges in such manner as the Administrator determines will help achieve the purposes of section 839b(f) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Procedures In establishing rates under this section, the Administrator shall use the following procedures:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_839e_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost figures to be indicated on rate schedules and power billings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cost figures to be indicated on rate schedules and power billings All rate schedules adopted, and all power billings rendered, by the Administrator pursuant to this section shall indicate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>