<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8421"><akn:num>8421</akn:num><akn:heading>Biking on long-distance trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8421. Biking on long-distance trails(a) Identification of long-distance trailsNot later than 18 months after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries shall identify—(1) not fewer than 10 long-distance bike trails that make use of trails and roads in existence on January 4, 2025; and

(2) not fewer than 10 areas in which there is an opportunity to develop or complete a trail that would qualify as a long-distance bike trail.


(b) Public commentThe Secretaries shall—(1) develop a process to allow members of the public to comment regarding the identification of trails and areas under subsection (a); and

(2) consider the identification, development, and completion of long-distance bike trails in a geographically equitable manner.


(c) Maps, signage, and promotional materialsFor any long-distance bike trail identified under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may—(1) publish and distribute maps, install signage, and issue promotional materials; and

(2) coordinate with stakeholders to leverage any non-Federal resources necessary for the stewardship, development, or completion of trails.


(d) ReportNot later than 2 years after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries, in partnership with interested organizations, shall prepare and publish a report that lists the trails identified under subsection (a), including a summary of public comments received in accordance with the process developed under subsection (b).


(e) Conflict avoidance with other usesBefore identifying a long-distance bike trail under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall ensure the long-distance bike trail—(1) minimizes conflict with—(A) the uses, before January 4, 2025, of any trail or road that is part of that long-distance bike trail;

(B) multiple-use areas where biking, hiking, horseback riding, or use by pack and saddle stock are existing uses on January 4, 2025;

(C) the purposes for which any trail was or is established under the National Trails System Act (16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.); and

(D) any a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of long-distance trails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Identification of long-distance trails Not later than 18 months after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries shall identify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public comment The Secretaries shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps, signage, and promotional materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maps, signage, and promotional materials For any long-distance bike trail identified under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 2 years after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries, in partnership with interested organizations, shall prepare and publish a report that lists the trails identified under subsection (a), including a summary of public comments received in accordance with the process developed under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict avoidance with other uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conflict avoidance with other uses Before identifying a long-distance bike trail under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall ensure the long-distance bike trail—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eminent domain or condemnation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eminent domain or condemnation In carrying out this section, the Secretaries may not use eminent domain or condemnation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>