<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8426"><akn:num>8426</akn:num><akn:heading>Aquatic resource activities assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8426. Aquatic resource activities assistance(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Aquatic Nuisance Species Task ForceThe term “Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force” means the Aquatic Nuisance Species Task Force established by section 4721(a) of this title.


(2) DecontaminationThe term “decontamination” means actions to remove aquatic nuisance species to prevent introduction or spread into new aquatic ecosystems.


(3) Federal land and waterThe term “Federal land and water” means Federal land and water operated and maintained by the Bureau of Land Management, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Reclamation, the Forest Service, or the National Park Service, as applicable.


(4) Indian TribeThe term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 5304 of title 25.


(5) InspectionThe term “inspection” means actions to find aquatic nuisance species to prevent introduction or spread into new aquatic ecosystems.


(6) PartnerThe term “partner” means—(A) a Reclamation State;

(B) an Indian Tribe in a Reclamation State;

(C) an applicable nonprofit organization in a Reclamation State;

(D) a unit of local government in a Reclamation State; or

(E) a private entity.


(7) Reclamation StateThe term “Reclamation State” includes any of the following States:(A) Alaska.

(B) Arizona.

(C) California.

(D) Colorado.

(E) Idaho.

(F) Kansas.

(G) Montana.

(H) Nebraska.

(I) Nevada.

(J) New Mexico.

(K) North Dakota.

(L) Oklahoma.

(M) Oregon.

(N) South Dakota.

(O) Texas.

(P) Utah.

(Q) Washington.

(R) Wyoming.


(8) Reclamation projectThe term “reclamation 11 So in original. “Reclamation” is capitalized in this term in section 460l–32(3) of this title and in this section. project” has the meaning given such term in section 460l–32(3) of this title.


(9) SecretariesThe term “Secretaries” means each of the following:(A) The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, the Commissioner of Reclamation, and the Director of the N</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Bureau of Land Management, Bureau of Reclamation, National Park Service, and Forest Service with respect to certain aquatic resource activities on Federal land and waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Bureau of Land Management, Bureau of Reclamation, National Park Service, and Forest Service with respect to certain aquatic resource activities on Federal land and waters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program for Reclamation States for vessel inspection and decontamination stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant program for Reclamation States for vessel inspection and decontamination stations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>