<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8464" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8464/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8464/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8464"><akn:num>8464</akn:num><akn:heading>Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8464. Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means an entity or combination of entities that represents or otherwise serves a qualifying area.


(2) Eligible nonprofit organizationThe term “eligible nonprofit organization” means an organization that is described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title.


(3) EntityThe term “entity” means—(A) a State;

(B) a political subdivision of a State, including—(i) a city;

(ii) a county; or

(iii) a special purpose district that manages open space, including a park district; and


(C) an Indian Tribe, urban Indian organization, or Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization.


(4) Low-income communityThe term “low-income community” has the same meaning given that term in 26 U.S.C. 45D(e)(1).11 See References in Text note below.


(5) Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership ProgramThe term “Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Program” means the program codified under subsection (b)(1).


(6) Qualifying areaThe term “qualifying area” means—(A) an urbanized area or urban cluster that has a population of 25,000 or more in the most recent census;

(B) 2 or more adjacent urban clusters with a combined population of 25,000 or more in the most recent census; or

(C) an area administered by an Indian Tribe or an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community organization.



(b) Grants authorized(1) Codification of program(A) In generalThere is established an existing program, to be known as the “Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Program”, under which the Secretary may award grants to eligible entities for projects—(i) to acquire land and water for parks and other outdoor recreation purposes in qualifying areas; and

(ii) to develop new or renovate existing outdoor recreation facilities that provide outdoor recreation opportunities to the public in qualifying areas.


(B) PriorityI</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8464_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8464_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8464_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and evaluation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review and evaluation requirements In carrying out the Outdoor Recreation Legacy Partnership Program, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8464_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>