<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8503"><akn:num>8503</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships to promote military and veteran recreation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8503. Partnerships to promote military and veteran recreation(a) In generalThe Secretary concerned shall seek to enter into partnerships or agreements with State, Tribal, local, or private entities with expertise in outdoor recreation, volunteer, accessibility, and health and wellness programs for members of the Armed Forces or veterans.


(b) PartnershipsAs part of a partnership or agreement entered into under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may host events on Federal recreational lands and waters designed to promote outdoor recreation among members of the Armed Forces and veterans.


(c) Financial and technical assistanceUnder a partnership or agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may provide financial or technical assistance to the entity with which the respective Secretary concerned has entered into the partnership or agreement to assist with—(1) the planning, development, and execution of events, activities, or programs designed to promote outdoor recreation for members of the Armed Forces or veterans; or

(2) the acquisition of assistive technology to facilitate improved outdoor recreation opportunities for members of the Armed Forces or veterans.


(Pub. L. 118–234, title II, § 223, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2887.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary concerned shall seek to enter into partnerships or agreements with State, Tribal, local, or private entities with expertise in outdoor recreation, volunteer, accessibility, and health and wellness programs for members of the Armed Forces or veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Partnerships As part of a partnership or agreement entered into under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may host events on Federal recreational lands and waters designed to promote outdoor recreation among members of the Armed Forces and veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial and technical assistance Under a partnership or agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary concerned may provide financial or technical assistance to the entity with which the respective Secretary concerned has entered into the partnership or agreement to assist with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>