<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8542"><akn:num>8542</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8542. Permit flexibility(a) In generalThe Secretary concerned shall establish guidelines to allow a holder of a special recreation permit under subsection (h) of section 6802 of this title (as amended by this title), to engage in another recreational activity under the special recreation permit that is substantially similar to the specific activity authorized under the special recreation permit.


(b) CriteriaFor the purposes of this section, a recreational activity shall be considered to be a substantially similar recreational activity if the recreational activity—(1) is comparable in type, nature, scope, and ecological setting to the specific activity authorized under the special recreation permit;

(2) does not result in a greater impact on natural and cultural resources than the impact of the authorized activity;

(3) does not adversely affect—(A) any other holder of a special recreation permit or other permit; or

(B) any other authorized use of the Federal recreational lands and waters; and


(4) is consistent with—(A) any applicable laws (including regulations); and

(B) the land management plan, resource management plan, or equivalent plan applicable to the Federal recreational lands and waters.



(c) Surrender of unused visitor-use days(1) In generalA recreation service provider holding a special recreation permit described in paragraph (13)(A)(iv) of section 6801 of this title (as amended by this title) may—(A) notify the Secretary concerned of an inability to use visitor-use days annually allocated to the recreation service provider under the special recreation permit; and

(B) surrender to the Secretary concerned the unused visitor-use days for the applicable year for temporary reassignment under section 8547(b) of this title.


(2) DeterminationTo ensure a recreation service provider described in paragraph (1) is able to make an informed decision before surrendering any unused visitor-use day under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary concerned shall, on </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8542_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary concerned shall establish guidelines to allow a holder of a special recreation permit under subsection (h) of section 6802 of this title (as amended by this title), to engage in another recreational activity under the special recreation permit that is substantially similar to the specific activity authorized under the special recreation permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8542_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria For the purposes of this section, a recreational activity shall be considered to be a substantially similar recreational activity if the recreational activity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8542_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surrender of unused visitor-use days</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Surrender of unused visitor-use days</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8542_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect Nothing in this section affects any authority of, regulation issued by, or decision of the Secretary concerned relating to the use of electric bicycles on Federal recreational lands and waters under any other Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>