<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8550" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8550/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8550/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8550"><akn:num>8550</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8550. Savings provision
Nothing in this part, or in any amendment made by this part, shall be construed as affecting the authority or responsibility of the Secretary of the Interior to award concessions contracts for the provision of accommodations, facilities, and services, or commercial use authorizations to provide services, to visitors to U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service refuges or units of the National Park System pursuant to subchapter II of chapter 1019 of title 54 (formerly known as the “National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998”), except that sections 8543(a), 8544, 8548(a), 8548(b), and 8548(c) of this title shall also apply to commercial use authorizations under that Act.
(Pub. L. 118–234, title III, § 323, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2911.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis part, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle” meaning subtitle A (§§ 311–323) of title III of Pub. L. 118–234, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2891, which enacted sections 6804a and 8541 to 8550 of this title, amended sections 6801 to 6804, 6807, and 6809 of this title, and repealed section 1703 of Title 43, Public Lands.
The National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998, referred to in text, is title IV of Pub. L. 105–391, Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3503. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1998 Act note set out under section 100101 of Title 54, National Park Service and Related Programs, and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>