<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8572"><akn:num>8572</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit relief for picnic areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8572. Permit relief for picnic areas(a) In generalIf the Secretary concerned does not require the public to obtain a permit or reservation to access a picnic area on Federal recreational lands and waters administered by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management, the Secretary concerned shall not require a covered person to obtain a permit solely to access the picnic area.


(b) Covered person definedIn this section, the term “covered person” means a person (including an educational group) that provides outfitting and guiding services to fewer than 40 customers per year at a picnic area described in subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 118–234, title III, § 352, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2916.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Secretary concerned does not require the public to obtain a permit or reservation to access a picnic area on Federal recreational lands and waters administered by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management, the Secretary concerned shall not require a covered person to obtain a permit solely to access the picnic area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered person defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered person defined In this section, the term “covered person” means a person (including an educational group) that provides outfitting and guiding services to fewer than 40 customers per year at a picnic area described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>