<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8573" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8573/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/8573/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8573"><akn:num>8573</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency report on special recreation permits for underserved communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8573. Interagency report on special recreation permits for underserved communities(a) Covered community definedIn this section, the term “covered community” means a rural or urban community, including an Indian Tribe, that is—(1) low-income or underserved; and

(2) has been underrepresented in outdoor recreation opportunities on Federal recreational lands and waters.


(b) ReportNot later than 3 years after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries, acting jointly, shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—(1) the estimated use of special recreation permits serving covered communities;

(2) examples of special recreation permits, partnerships, cooperative agreements, or other arrangements providing access to Federal recreational lands and waters for covered communities;

(3) other ways covered communities are engaging on Federal recreational lands and waters, including through stewardship and conservation projects or activities;

(4) any barriers for existing or prospective recreation service providers and holders of commercial use authorizations operating within or serving a covered community; and

(5) any recommendations to facilitate and increase permitted access to Federal recreational lands and waters for covered communities.


(Pub. L. 118–234, title III, § 353, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2917.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8573_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered community defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Covered community defined In this section, the term “covered community” means a rural or urban community, including an Indian Tribe, that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8573_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Not later than 3 years after January 4, 2025, the Secretaries, acting jointly, shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>