<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/90e–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/90e–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/90e–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_90e_1"><akn:num>90e–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Glacier Peak Wilderness, Wenatchee and Mount Baker National Forests; extension of boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 90e–1. Glacier Peak Wilderness, Wenatchee and Mount Baker National Forests; extension of boundaries
The boundaries of the Glacier Peak Wilderness, an area classified as such more than thirty days before the effective date of the Wilderness Act [16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.] and being within and a part of the Wenatchee National Forest and the Mount Baker National Forest, subject to valid existing rights, are hereby extended to include portions of the Suiattle River corridor and the White Chuck River corridor on the western side thereof, comprising areas totaling about ten thousand acres, as depicted in the area designated as “Additions to Glacier Peak Wilderness” on the map referred to in section 90 of this title.
(Pub. L. 90–544, title VI, § 602, Oct. 2, 1968, 82 Stat. 930.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Wilderness Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 88–577, Sept. 3, 1964, 78 Stat. 890, which is classified generally to chapter 23 (§ 1131 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1131 of this title and Tables.
Effective date of the Wilderness Act, referred to in text, means the date of enactment, Sept. 3, 1964, of such act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>