<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/933" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/933/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/933/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_933"><akn:num>933</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 933. Advisory Committee(a) Appointment and number of members; factors in selectionThe United States Section shall appoint an advisory committee for each of the Great Lakes, upon which committee each State bordering on the lake may be represented by not more than four members. In making such appointments, the United States Section shall make its selection for each State from a list proposed by the Governor of that State; and shall give due consideration to the interests of—(1) State agencies having jurisdiction over fisheries;

(2) the commercial fishing industry of the lake;

(3) the sports fishing of the lake; and

(4) the public at large.


(b) Membership on other committeesA member of the advisory committee for one lake may also be a member of the advisory committee for one or more other lakes.


(c) CompensationThe members of the advisory committee shall receive no compensation from the Government of the United States for their services as such members. Not more than ten members of all the committees, designated by the committees and approved by the United States Section, may be paid by the Government of the United States for transportation expenses and per diem incident to attendance at the annual meeting of the Commission or of the United States Section.


(d) MeetingsThe members of the advisory committee for each lake shall be invited to attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States Section relating to that lake and at such meetings shall be granted opportunity to examine and be heard on all proposed recommendations, programs, and activities relating to that lake.


(June 4, 1956, ch. 358, § 4, 70 Stat. 242; Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title II, § 208, Sept. 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 1364.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2002—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 107–228, which directed the substitution of “ten” for “five” and “the annual” for “each” in subsec. (c) of section 4 of the Great Lakes Fisheries Act of 1956, was executed by making the substitutions in subsec. (c) of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_933_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and number of members; factors in selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment and number of members; factors in selection The United States Section shall appoint an advisory committee for each of the Great Lakes, upon which committee each State bordering on the lake may be represented by not more than four members. In making such appointments, the United States Section shall make its selection for each State from a list proposed by the Governor of that State; and shall give due consideration to the interests of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_933_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership on other committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership on other committees A member of the advisory committee for one lake may also be a member of the advisory committee for one or more other lakes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_933_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation The members of the advisory committee shall receive no compensation from the Government of the United States for their services as such members. Not more than ten members of all the committees, designated by the committees and approved by the United States Section, may be paid by the Government of the United States for transportation expenses and per diem incident to attendance at the annual meeting of the Commission or of the United States Section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_933_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings The members of the advisory committee for each lake shall be invited to attend all nonexecutive meetings of the United States Section relating to that lake and at such meetings shall be granted opportunity to examine and be heard on all proposed recommendations, programs, and activities relating to that lake.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>