<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/941c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/941c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/941c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_941c"><akn:num>941c</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification, review, and implementation of proposals and regional projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 941c. Identification, review, and implementation of proposals and regional projects(a) In generalSubject to subsection (b)(2), the Director—(1) shall encourage the development and, subject to the availability of appropriations, the implementation of fish and wildlife restoration proposals and regional projects based on the results of the Report; and

(2) in cooperation with the State Directors and Indian Tribes, shall identify, develop, and, subject to the availability of appropriations, implement regional projects in the Great Lakes Basin to be administered by Director in accordance with this section.


(b) Identification of proposals and regional projects(1) Request by the DirectorThe Director shall annually request that State Directors and Indian Tribes, in cooperation or partnership with other interested entities and in accordance with subsection (a), submit proposals or regional projects for the restoration of fish and wildlife resources.


(2) Requirements for proposals and regional projectsA proposal or regional project under paragraph (1) shall be—(A) submitted in the manner and form prescribed by the Director; and

(B) consistent with—(i) the goals of the Great Lakes Water Quality Agreement, as amended;

(ii) the 1954 Great Lakes Fisheries Convention;

(iii) the 1980 Joint Strategic Plan for Management of Great Lakes Fisheries, as revised in 1997, and Fish Community Objectives for each Great Lake and connecting water as established under the Joint Strategic Plan;

(iv) the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 (16 U.S.C. 4701 et seq.);

(v) the North American Waterfowl Management Plan and joint ventures established under the plan;

(vi) the strategies outlined through the Great Lakes Regional Collaboration authorized under Executive Order 13340 (69 Fed. Reg. 29043; relating to the Great Lakes Interagency Task Force);

(vii) the strategic action plan of the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative; and

(viii) each applicable State wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_941c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsection (b)(2), the Director—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_941c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of proposals and regional projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of proposals and regional projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_941c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_941c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of proposals and regional projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation of proposals and regional projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_941c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>