<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/953" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/953/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/953/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_953"><akn:num>953</akn:num><akn:heading>General Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 953. General Advisory Committee and Scientific Advisory Subcommittee(a) General Advisory Committee(1) Appointments; public participation; compensation(A) The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall appoint a General Advisory Committee which shall consist of not more than 25 individuals who shall be representative of the various groups concerned with the fisheries covered by the Convention, including nongovernmental conservation organizations, providing to the maximum extent practicable an equitable balance among such groups. Members of the General Advisory Committee will be eligible to participate as members of the United States delegation to the Commission and its working groups to the extent the Commission rules and space for delegations allow.

(B) The chair of the Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Subpanel for Highly Migratory Fisheries and the chair of the Western Pacific Fishery Management Council’s Advisory Committee shall be ex-officio members of the General Advisory Committee by virtue of their positions in those Councils.

(C) Each member of the General Advisory Committee appointed under subparagraph (A) shall serve for a term of 3 years and is eligible for reappointment.

(D) The General Advisory Committee shall be invited to attend all non-executive meetings of the United States delegation and at such meetings shall be given opportunity to examine and to be heard on all proposed programs of investigation, reports, recommendations, and regulations of the Commission.

(E) The General Advisory Committee shall determine its organization, and prescribe its practices and procedures for carrying out its functions under this chapter, the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.), and the Convention. The General Advisory Committee shall publish and make available to the public a statement of its organization, practices, and procedures. Meetings of the General Advisory Committee, except wh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_953_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_953_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scientific Advisory Subcommittee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>