<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/971f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/971f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/971f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_971f"><akn:num>971f</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 971f. Enforcement(a) For additional prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see section 1826g of this title.

(b) To the extent authorized under the convention or by agreements between the United States and any contracting party concluded pursuant to section 971c(b) of this title for international enforcement, the duly authorized officials of such party shall have the authority to carry out enforcement activities with respect to this chapter that are otherwise authorized by law with respect to persons or vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and the officials of the United States authorized pursuant to this section shall have the authority to carry out enforcement activities with respect to this chapter that are otherwise authorized by law with respect to persons or vessels subject to the jurisdiction of such party, except that where any agreement provides for arrest or seizure of persons or vessels under United States jurisdiction it shall also provide that the person or vessel arrested or seized shall be promptly handed over to a United States enforcement officer or another authorized United States official.

(Pub. L. 94–70, § 8, Aug. 5, 1975, 89 Stat. 391; Pub. L. 114–81, title I, § 107(3), (4), Nov. 5, 2015, 129 Stat. 658.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 114–81, § 107(3), added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which related to particular powers of persons authorized to enforce the provisions of this chapter and the regulations issued thereunder.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 114–81, § 107(4), substituted “enforcement activities with respect to this chapter that are otherwise authorized by law” for “the enforcement activities specified in subsection (a) of this section” in two places.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 114–81, § 107(3)(A), struck out subsec. (c) which related to bonds or stipulations.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For additional prohibitions relating to this chapter and enforcement of this chapter, see section 1826g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To the extent authorized under the convention or by agreements between the United States and any contracting party concluded pursuant to section 971c(b) of this title for international enforcement, the duly authorized officials of such party shall have the authority to carry out enforcement activities with respect to this chapter that are otherwise authorized by law with respect to persons or vessels subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, and the officials of the United States authorized pursuant to this section shall have the authority to carry out enforcement activities with respect to this chapter that are otherwise authorized by law with respect to persons or vessels subject to the jurisdiction of such party, except that where any agreement provides for arrest or seizure of persons or vessels under United States jurisdiction it shall also provide that the person or vessel arrested or seized shall be promptly handed over to a United States enforcement officer or anoth</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>