<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_973g"><akn:num>973g</akn:num><akn:heading>Licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 973g. Licenses(a) Issuance; establishment of procedures; designation of agent for service of legal process in license application; reception and response to processLicenses to fish in the Licensing Area, to be issued by the Administrator in accordance with the Treaty, may be requested from the Secretary by operators of vessels, under procedures established by the Secretary. The license application shall designate an agent for the service of legal process to be located in Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea. The applicant shall ensure that the designated agent for service of process, acting on behalf of the license holder, will receive and respond to any legal process issued in accordance with the Treaty and will, within 21 days after notification, travel if necessary for this purpose to any Pacific Island Party at no expense to that Party.


(b) Forwarding and transmittal of vessel license applicationExcept as provided in subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, the Secretary shall forward a vessel license application to the Secretary of State for transmittal to the Administrator whenever such application is in accordance with application procedures established by the Secretary, includes a complete application form as required by Annex II of the Treaty, and is accompanied by the required license fee.


(c) Fees and fee schedules(1) In the initial year of implementation, fees for the first 40 vessel licenses shall be at least $50,000 each, for any 10 vessel licenses in addition to the first 40 shall be $60,000 each, and for vessel licenses in addition to the first 50 shall be in accordance with Annex II of the Treaty.

(2) After such initial year, fees for vessel licenses shall be paid in accordance with fee schedules established under Annex II of the Treaty and published by the Secretary.


(d) Period of validityLicenses shall be valid for the licensing period specified by the Administrator.


(e) Allocation systemThe Secretary may establish a system of allocatin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance; establishment of procedures; designation of agent for service of legal process in license application; reception and response to process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance; establishment of procedures; designation of agent for service of legal process in license application; reception and response to process Licenses to fish in the Licensing Area, to be issued by the Administrator in accordance with the Treaty, may be requested from the Secretary by operators of vessels, under procedures established by the Secretary. The license application shall designate an agent for the service of legal process to be located in Port Moresby, Papua New Guinea. The applicant shall ensure that the designated agent for service of process, acting on behalf of the license holder, will receive and respond to any legal process issued in accordance with the Treaty and will, within 21 days after notification, travel if necessary for this purpose to any Pacific Island Party at no expense to that Party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forwarding and transmittal of vessel license application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Forwarding and transmittal of vessel license application Except as provided in subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, the Secretary shall forward a vessel license application to the Secretary of State for transmittal to the Administrator whenever such application is in accordance with application procedures established by the Secretary, includes a complete application form as required by Annex II of the Treaty, and is accompanied by the required license fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and fee schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fees and fee schedules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of validity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of validity Licenses shall be valid for the licensing period specified by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocation system The Secretary may establish a system of allocating licenses in the event more applications are received than there are licenses available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum fees required to be received in initial year of implementation for forwarding and transmittal of license applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minimum fees required to be received in initial year of implementation for forwarding and transmittal of license applications For the initial year of implementation, license fees totaling at least $1,750,000 must be received by the Secretary before any license applications will be forwarded to the Secretary of State for transmittal to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grounds for denial of forwarding of license application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grounds for denial of forwarding of license application The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may determine that a license application should not be forwarded to the Administrator for one of the following reasons:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grandfathering of vessels documented before November 3, 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Grandfathering of vessels documented before Notwithstanding the requirements of— any vessel documented under the laws of the United States as of November 3, 1995, for which a license has been issued under subsection (a) may fish for tuna in the Treaty Area, including those waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States in accordance with international law, subject to the provisions of the treaty 33 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. and this chapter, provided that no such vessel fishing in the Treaty Area intentionally deploys a purse seine net to encircle any dolphin or other marine mammal in the course of fishing under the provisions of the Treaty or this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>