<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/16/973l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_973l"><akn:num>973l</akn:num><akn:heading>Observers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 973l. Observers(a) Required access and assistance; scope of authoritiesThe operator and each member of the crew of a vessel shall allow and assist any individual identified as an observer under the Treaty by the Pacific Island Parties—(1) to board the vessel for scientific, compliance, monitoring and other functions at the point and time notified by the Pacific Island Parties to the Secretary;

(2) without interfering unduly with the lawful operation of the vessel, to have full access to and use of facilities and equipment on board the vessel which the observer may determine are necessary to carry out observer duties; have full access to the bridge, fish on board, and areas which may be used to hold, process, weigh, and store fish; remove samples; have full access to the vessel’s records, including its log and documentation for the purpose of inspection and copying; and gather any other information relating to fisheries in the Licensing Area;

(3) to disembark at the point and time notified by the Pacific Island Parties to the Secretary; and

(4) to carry out observer duties safely.


(b) Free provision of food, etc., while on vesselThe operator shall provide any such observer, while on board the vessel, at no expense to the Pacific Island Parties, with food, accommodation, and medical facilities of such reasonable standard as may be acceptable to the Pacific Island Party whose representative is serving as the observer.


(c) Removal of fish samples and gathering of other information relating to fisheriesThe operator of any vessel from which any fish taken in the Licensing Area is unloaded shall allow, or arrange for, and assist any individual so authorized by the Pacific Island Parties to have full access to any place where such fish is unloaded, to remove samples, and to gather any other information relating to fisheries in the Licensing Area.


(Pub. L. 100–330, § 14, June 7, 1988, 102 Stat. 599.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required access and assistance; scope of authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required access and assistance; scope of authorities The operator and each member of the crew of a vessel shall allow and assist any individual identified as an observer under the Treaty by the Pacific Island Parties—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free provision of food, etc., while on vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Free provision of food, etc., while on vessel The operator shall provide any such observer, while on board the vessel, at no expense to the Pacific Island Parties, with food, accommodation, and medical facilities of such reasonable standard as may be acceptable to the Pacific Island Party whose representative is serving as the observer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_973l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal of fish samples and gathering of other information relating to fisheries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removal of fish samples and gathering of other information relating to fisheries The operator of any vessel from which any fish taken in the Licensing Area is unloaded shall allow, or arrange for, and assist any individual so authorized by the Pacific Island Parties to have full access to any place where such fish is unloaded, to remove samples, and to gather any other information relating to fisheries in the Licensing Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>