<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1103"><akn:num>1103</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Secretary, the Under Secretary, and the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1103. Powers and duties of the Secretary, the Under Secretary, and the Attorney General(a) Secretary of Homeland Security(1) The Secretary of Homeland Security shall be charged with the administration and enforcement of this chapter and all other laws relating to the immigration and naturalization of aliens, except insofar as this chapter or such laws relate to the powers, functions, and duties conferred upon the President, Attorney General, the Secretary of State, the officers of the Department of State, or diplomatic or consular officers: Provided, however, That determination and ruling by the Attorney General with respect to all questions of law shall be controlling.

(2) He shall have control, direction, and supervision of all employees and of all the files and records of the Service.

(3) He shall establish such regulations; prescribe such forms of bond, reports, entries, and other papers; issue such instructions; and perform such other acts as he deems necessary for carrying out his authority under the provisions of this chapter.

(4) He may require or authorize any employee of the Service or the Department of Justice to perform or exercise any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon any other employee of the Service.

(5) He shall have the power and duty to control and guard the boundaries and borders of the United States against the illegal entry of aliens and shall, in his discretion, appoint for that purpose such number of employees of the Service as to him shall appear necessary and proper.

(6) He is authorized to confer or impose upon any employee of the United States, with the consent of the head of the Department or other independent establishment under whose jurisdiction the employee is serving, any of the powers, privileges, or duties conferred or imposed by this chapter or regulations issued thereunder upon officers or employees of the Service.

(7) He may, with the concurren</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Homeland Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Secretary of Homeland Security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land acquisition authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioner; appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Commissioner; appointment The Commissioner shall be a citizen of the United States and shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. He shall be charged with any and all responsibilities and authority in the administration of the Service and of this chapter which are conferred upon the Attorney General as may be delegated to him by the Attorney General or which may be prescribed by the Attorney General. The Commissioner may enter into cooperative agreements with State and local law enforcement agencies for the purpose of assisting in the enforcement of the immigration laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statistical information system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statistical information system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum number of agents in States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minimum number of agents in States The Attorney General shall allocate to each State not fewer than 10 full-time active duty agents of the Immigration and Naturalization Service to carry out the functions of the Service, in order to ensure the effective enforcement of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Attorney General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>