<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1152"><akn:num>1152</akn:num><akn:heading>Numerical limitations on individual foreign states</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1152. Numerical limitations on individual foreign states(a) Per country level(1) Nondiscrimination(A) Except as specifically provided in paragraph (2) and in sections 1101(a)(27), 1151(b)(2)(A)(i), and 1153 of this title, no person shall receive any preference or priority or be discriminated against in the issuance of an immigrant visa because of the person’s race, sex, nationality, place of birth, or place of residence.

(B) Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of State to determine the procedures for the processing of immigrant visa applications or the locations where such applications will be processed.


(2) Per country levels for family-sponsored and employment-based immigrantsSubject to paragraphs (3), (4), and (5), the total number of immigrant visas made available to natives of any single foreign state or dependent area under subsections (a) and (b) of section 1153 of this title in any fiscal year may not exceed 7 percent (in the case of a single foreign state) or 2 percent (in the case of a dependent area) of the total number of such visas made available under such subsections in that fiscal year.


(3) Exception if additional visas availableIf because of the application of paragraph (2) with respect to one or more foreign states or dependent areas, the total number of visas available under both subsections (a) and (b) of section 1153 of this title for a calendar quarter exceeds the number of qualified immigrants who otherwise may be issued such a visa, paragraph (2) shall not apply to visas made available to such states or areas during the remainder of such calendar quarter.


(4) Special rules for spouses and children of lawful permanent resident aliens(A) 75 percent of 2nd preference set-aside for spouses and children not subject to per country limitation(i) In generalOf the visa numbers made available under section 1153(a) of this title to immigrants described in section 1153(a)(2)(A) of this title in an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1152_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per country level</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Per country level</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1152_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for chargeability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules for chargeability Each independent country, self-governing dominion, mandated territory, and territory under the international trusteeship system of the United Nations, other than the United States and its outlying possessions, shall be treated as a separate foreign state for the purposes of a numerical level established under subsection (a)(2) when approved by the Secretary of State. All other inhabited lands shall be attributed to a foreign state specified by the Secretary of State. For the purposes of this chapter the foreign state to which an immigrant is chargeable shall be determined by birth within such foreign state except that (1) an alien child, when accompanied by or following to join his alien parent or parents, may be charged to the foreign state of either parent if such parent has received or would be qualified for an immigrant visa, if necessary to prevent the separation of the child from the parent or parents, and if immigration charged to the foreign state to</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1152_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chargeability for dependent areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chargeability for dependent areas Any immigrant born in a colony or other component or dependent area of a foreign state overseas from the foreign state, other than an alien described in section 1151(b) of this title, shall be chargeable for the purpose of the limitation set forth in subsection (a), to the foreign state.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1152_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in territory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Changes in territory In the case of any change in the territorial limits of foreign states, the Secretary of State shall, upon recognition of such change issue appropriate instructions to all diplomatic and consular offices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1152_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for countries at ceiling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for countries at ceiling If it is determined that the total number of immigrant visas made available under subsections (a) and (b) of section 1153 of this title to natives of any single foreign state or dependent area will exceed the numerical limitation specified in subsection (a)(2) in any fiscal year, in determining the allotment of immigrant visa numbers to natives under subsections (a) and (b) of section 1153 of this title, visa numbers with respect to natives of that state or area shall be allocated (to the extent practicable and otherwise consistent with this section and section 1153 of this title) in a manner so that— Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the number of visas that may be issued to natives of a foreign state or dependent area under section 1153(a) or 1153(b) of this title if there is insufficient demand for visas for such natives under section 1153(b) or 1153(a) of this title, respectively, or as limiting the number of visas </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>