<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1153a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1153a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1153a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1153a"><akn:num>1153a</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1153a. Transparency(a) In generalEmployees of the Department of Homeland Security, including the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary’s counselors, the Assistant Secretary for the Private Sector, the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, counselors to such Director, and the Chief of the Immigrant Investor Programs Office (or any successor to such Office) at U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, shall act impartially and may not give preferential treatment to any entity, organization, or individual in connection with any aspect of the immigrant visa program described in section 1153(b)(5) of this title.


(b) Improper activitiesActivities that constitute preferential treatment under subsection (a) shall include—(1) working on, or in any way attempting to influence, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits under the immigrant visa program referred to in subsection (a), the standard processing of an application, petition, or benefit for—(A) a regional center;

(B) a new commercial enterprise;

(C) a job-creating entity; or

(D) any person or entity associated with such regional center, new commercial enterprise, or job-creating entity; and


(2) meeting or communicating with persons associated with the entities listed in paragraph (1), at the request of such persons, in a manner not available to or accorded to all other petitioners, applicants, and seekers of benefits under such immigrant visa program.


(c) Reporting of communications(1) Written communicationEmployees of the Department of Homeland Security, including the officials listed in subsection (a), shall include, in the record of proceeding for a case under section 1153(b)(5) of this title, actual or electronic copies of all case-specific written communication, including emails from government and private accounts, with non-Department persons or entities advocating for regional center applications or individual petit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Employees of the Department of Homeland Security, including the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary’s counselors, the Assistant Secretary for the Private Sector, the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, counselors to such Director, and the Chief of the Immigrant Investor Programs Office (or any successor to such Office) at U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, shall act impartially and may not give preferential treatment to any entity, organization, or individual in connection with any aspect of the immigrant visa program described in section 1153(b)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improper activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Improper activities Activities that constitute preferential treatment under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of communications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting of communications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consideration of evidence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Channels of communication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Channels of communication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding classified information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction regarding classified information Nothing in this section may be construed to modify any law, regulation, or policy regarding the handling or disclosure of classified information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding private right of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction regarding private right of action Nothing in this section may be construed to create or authorize a private right of action to challenge a decision of an employee of the Department of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effective date This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall take effect on March 15, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>