<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1154" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1154/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1154/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1154"><akn:num>1154</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for granting immigrant status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1154. Procedure for granting immigrant status(a) Petitioning procedure(1)(A)(i) Except as provided in clause (viii), any citizen of the United States claiming that an alien is entitled to classification by reason of a relationship described in paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of section 1153(a) of this title or to an immediate relative status under section 1151(b)(2)(A)(i) of this title may file a petition with the Attorney General for such classification.

(ii) An alien spouse described in the second sentence of section 1151(b)(2)(A)(i) of this title also may file a petition with the Attorney General under this subparagraph for classification of the alien (and the alien’s children) under such section.

(iii)(I) An alien who is described in subclause (II) may file a petition with the Attorney General under this clause for classification of the alien (and any child of the alien) if the alien demonstrates to the Attorney General that—(aa) the marriage or the intent to marry the United States citizen was entered into in good faith by the alien; and

(bb) during the marriage or relationship intended by the alien to be legally a marriage, the alien or a child of the alien has been battered or has been the subject of extreme cruelty perpetrated by the alien’s spouse or intended spouse.


(II) For purposes of subclause (I), an alien described in this subclause is an alien—(aa)(AA) who is the spouse of a citizen of the United States;

(BB) who believed that he or she had married a citizen of the United States and with whom a marriage ceremony was actually performed and who otherwise meets any applicable requirements under this chapter to establish the existence of and bona fides of a marriage, but whose marriage is not legitimate solely because of the bigamy of such citizen of the United States; or

(CC) who was a bona fide spouse of a United States citizen within the past 2 years and—(aaa) whose spouse died within the past 2 years;

(bbb) whose spouse lost or renounced citizen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitioning procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petitioning procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation; consultation; approval; authorization to grant preference status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigation; consultation; approval; authorization to grant preference status After an investigation of the facts in each case, and after consultation with the Secretary of Labor with respect to petitions to accord a status under section 1153(b)(2) or 1153(b)(3) of this title, the Attorney General shall, if he determines that the facts stated in the petition are true and that the alien in behalf of whom the petition is made is an immediate relative specified in section 1151(b) of this title or is eligible for preference under subsection (a) or (b) of section 1153 of this title, approve the petition and forward one copy thereof to the Department of State. The Secretary of State shall then authorize the consular officer concerned to grant the preference status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on orphan petitions approved for a single petitioner; prohibition against approval in cases of marriages entered into in order to evade immigration laws; restriction on future entry of aliens involved with marriage fraud</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on orphan petitions approved for a single petitioner; prohibition against approval in cases of marriages entered into in order to evade immigration laws; restriction on future entry of aliens involved with marriage fraud Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (b) no petition shall be approved if (1) the alien has previously been accorded, or has sought to be accorded, an immediate relative or preference status as the spouse of a citizen of the United States or the spouse of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, by reason of a marriage determined by the Attorney General to have been entered into for the purpose of evading the immigration laws, or (2) the Attorney General has determined that the alien has attempted or conspired to enter into a marriage for the purpose of evading the immigration laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendation of valid home-study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recommendation of valid home-study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent finding of non-entitlement to preference classification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsequent finding of non-entitlement to preference classification Nothing in this section shall be construed to entitle an immigrant, in behalf of whom a petition under this section is approved, to be admitted 33 So in original. Probably should be followed by “to”. the United States as an immigrant under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 1153 of this title or as an immediate relative under section 1151(b) of this title if upon his arrival at a port of entry in the United States he is found not to be entitled to such classification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential treatment for children fathered by United States citizens and born in Korea, Vietnam, Laos, Kampuchea, or Thailand after 1950 and before October 22, 1982</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preferential treatment for children fathered by United States citizens and born in Korea, Vietnam, Laos, Kampuchea, or Thailand after 1950 and before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on petitions based on marriages entered while in exclusion or deportation proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Restriction on petitions based on marriages entered while in exclusion or deportation proceedings Notwithstanding subsection (a), except as provided in section 1255(e)(3) of this title, a petition may not be approved to grant an alien immediate relative status or preference status by reason of a marriage which was entered into during the period described in section 1255(e)(2) of this title, until the alien has resided outside the United States for a 2-year period beginning after the date of the marriage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survival of rights to petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Survival of rights to petition The legal termination of a marriage may not be the sole basis for revocation under section 1155 of this title of a petition filed under subsection (a)(1)(A)(iii) or a petition filed under subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) pursuant to conditions described in subsection (a)(1)(A)(iii)(I). Remarriage of an alien whose petition was approved under subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) or (a)(1)(A)(iii) or marriage of an alien described in clause (iv) or (vi) of subsection (a)(1)(A) or in subsection (a)(1)(B)(iii) shall not be the basis for revocation of a petition approval under section 1155 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional athletes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Professional athletes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1154_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Job flexibility for long delayed applicants for adjustment of status to permanent residence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Job flexibility for long delayed applicants for adjustment of status to permanent residence A petition under subsection (a)(1)(D) 4 for an individual whose application for adjustment of status pursuant to section 1255 of this title has been filed and remained unadjudicated for 180 days or more shall remain valid with respect to a new job if the individual changes jobs or employers if the new job is in the same or a similar occupational classification as the job for which the petition was filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>