<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1182" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1182/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1182/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1182"><akn:num>1182</akn:num><akn:heading>Inadmissible aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1182. Inadmissible aliens(a) Classes of aliens ineligible for visas or admissionExcept as otherwise provided in this chapter, aliens who are inadmissible under the following paragraphs are ineligible to receive visas and ineligible to be admitted to the United States:(1) Health-related grounds(A) In generalAny alien—(i) who is determined (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services) to have a communicable disease of public health significance; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a comma.

(ii) except as provided in subparagraph (C), who seeks admission as an immigrant, or who seeks adjustment of status to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and who has failed to present documentation of having received vaccination against vaccine-preventable diseases, which shall include at least the following diseases: mumps, measles, rubella, polio, tetanus and diphtheria toxoids, pertussis, influenza type B and hepatitis B, and any other vaccinations against vaccine-preventable diseases recommended by the Advisory Committee for Immunization Practices,

(iii) who is determined (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in consultation with the Attorney General)—(I) to have a physical or mental disorder and behavior associated with the disorder that may pose, or has posed, a threat to the property, safety, or welfare of the alien or others, or

(II) to have had a physical or mental disorder and a history of behavior associated with the disorder, which behavior has posed a threat to the property, safety, or welfare of the alien or others and which behavior is likely to recur or to lead to other harmful behavior, or


(iv) who is determined (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services) to be a drug abuser or addict,


is inadmissible.

(B) Waiver authorizedFor provision authorizing waiver of certain claus</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classes of aliens ineligible for visas or admission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Classes of aliens ineligible for visas or admission Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, aliens who are inadmissible under the following paragraphs are ineligible to receive visas and ineligible to be admitted to the United States:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notices of denials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notices of denials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–208, div. C, title III, § 304(b), Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–597</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary admission of nonimmigrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Temporary admission of nonimmigrants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational visitor status; foreign residence requirement; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Educational visitor status; foreign residence requirement; waiver No person admitted under section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title or acquiring such status after admission (i) whose participation in the program for which he came to the United States was financed in whole or in part, directly or indirectly, by an agency of the Government of the United States or by the government of the country of his nationality or his last residence, (ii) who at the time of admission or acquisition of status under section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title was a national or resident of a country which the Director of the United States Information Agency, pursuant to regulations prescribed by him, had designated as clearly requiring the services of persons engaged in the field of specialized knowledge or skill in which the alien was engaged, or (iii) who came to the United States or acquired such status in order to receive graduate medical education or training, shall be eligible to apply for an immigrant vi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of entry or imposition of restrictions by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Suspension of entry or imposition of restrictions by President Whenever the President finds that the entry of any aliens or of any class of aliens into the United States would be detrimental to the interests of the United States, he may by proclamation, and for such period as he shall deem necessary, suspend the entry of all aliens or any class of aliens as immigrants or nonimmigrants, or impose on the entry of aliens any restrictions he may deem to be appropriate. Whenever the Attorney General finds that a commercial airline has failed to comply with regulations of the Attorney General relating to requirements of airlines for the detection of fraudulent documents used by passengers traveling to the United States (including the training of personnel in such detection), the Attorney General may suspend the entry of some or all aliens transported to the United States by such airline.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond and conditions for admission of alien inadmissible on health-related grounds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bond and conditions for admission of alien inadmissible on health-related grounds The Attorney General may waive the application of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of subsection (a)(2)(A)(i)(I), (II), (B), (D), and (E)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Waiver of subsection (a)(2)(A)(i)(I), (II), (B), (D), and (E) The Attorney General may, in his discretion, waive the application of subparagraphs (A)(i)(I), (B), (D), and (E) of subsection (a)(2) and subparagraph (A)(i)(II) of such subsection insofar as it relates to a single offense of simple possession of 30 grams or less of marijuana if— No waiver shall be provided under this subsection in the case of an alien who has been convicted of (or who has admitted committing acts that constitute) murder or criminal acts involving torture, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit murder or a criminal act involving torture. No waiver shall be granted under this subsection in the case of an alien who has previously been admitted to the United States as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if either since the date of such admission the alien has been convicted of an aggravated felony or the alien has not lawfully resided continuously in the United States for a period of not less </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission of immigrant inadmissible for fraud or willful misrepresentation of material fact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Admission of immigrant inadmissible for fraud or willful misrepresentation of material fact</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on immigration of foreign medical graduates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on immigration of foreign medical graduates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>