<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1183a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1183a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1183a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1183a"><akn:num>1183a</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for sponsor’s affidavit of support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1183a. Requirements for sponsor’s affidavit of support(a) Enforceability(1) Terms of affidavitNo affidavit of support may be accepted by the Attorney General or by any consular officer to establish that an alien is not excludable as a public charge under section 1182(a)(4) of this title unless such affidavit is executed by a sponsor of the alien as a contract—(A) in which the sponsor agrees to provide support to maintain the sponsored alien at an annual income that is not less than 125 percent of the Federal poverty line during the period in which the affidavit is enforceable;

(B) that is legally enforceable against the sponsor by the sponsored alien, the Federal Government, any State (or any political subdivision of such State), or by any other entity that provides any means-tested public benefit (as defined in subsection (e) 11 See References in Text note below.), consistent with the provisions of this section; and

(C) in which the sponsor agrees to submit to the jurisdiction of any Federal or State court for the purpose of actions brought under subsection (b)(2).


(2) Period of enforceabilityAn affidavit of support shall be enforceable with respect to benefits provided for an alien before the date the alien is naturalized as a citizen of the United States, or, if earlier, the termination date provided under paragraph (3).


(3) Termination of period of enforceability upon completion of required period of employment, etc.(A) In generalAn affidavit of support is not enforceable after such time as the alien (i) has worked 40 qualifying quarters of coverage as defined under title II of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.] or can be credited with such qualifying quarters as provided under subparagraph (B), and (ii) in the case of any such qualifying quarter creditable for any period beginning after December 31, 1996, did not receive any Federal means-tested public benefit (as provided under section 1613 of this title) during any such period.


(B) Qual</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforceability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforceability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of government expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reimbursement of government expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Remedies Remedies available to enforce an affidavit of support under this section include any or all of the remedies described in section 3201, 3203, 3204, or 3205 of title 28, as well as an order for specific performance and payment of legal fees and other costs of collection, and include corresponding remedies available under State law. A Federal agency may seek to collect amounts owed under this section in accordance with the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 37 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of change of address</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of change of address</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Jurisdiction An action to enforce an affidavit of support executed under subsection (a) may be brought against the sponsor in any appropriate court—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Sponsor” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Sponsor” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Section enacted without a subsec. (g). “Federal poverty line” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) For purposes of this section, the term “Federal poverty line” means the level of income equal to the official poverty line (as defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, as revised annually by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in accordance with section 9902(2) of title 42) that is applicable to a family of the size involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1183a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sponsor’s social security account number required to be provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Sponsor’s social security account number required to be provided</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>