<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1184" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1184/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1184/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1184"><akn:num>1184</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission of nonimmigrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1184. Admission of nonimmigrants(a) Regulations(1) The admission to the United States of any alien as a nonimmigrant shall be for such time and under such conditions as the Attorney General may by regulations prescribe, including when he deems necessary the giving of a bond with sufficient surety in such sum and containing such conditions as the Attorney General shall prescribe, to insure that at the expiration of such time or upon failure to maintain the status under which he was admitted, or to maintain any status subsequently acquired under section 1258 of this title, such alien will depart from the United States. No alien admitted to Guam or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands without a visa pursuant to section 1182(l) of this title may be authorized to enter or stay in the United States other than in Guam or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands or to remain in Guam or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands for a period exceeding 45 days from date of admission to Guam or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. No alien admitted to the United States without a visa pursuant to section 1187 of this title may be authorized to remain in the United States as a nonimmigrant visitor for a period exceeding 90 days from the date of admission.

(2)(A) The period of authorized status as a nonimmigrant described in section 1101(a)(15)(O) of this title shall be for such period as the Attorney General may specify in order to provide for the event (or events) for which the nonimmigrant is admitted.

(B) The period of authorized status as a nonimmigrant described in section 1101(a)(15)(P) of this title shall be for such period as the Attorney General may specify in order to provide for the competition, event, or performance for which the nonimmigrant is admitted. In the case of nonimmigrants admitted as individual athletes under section 1101(a)(15)(P) of this title, the period of authorized status may be for an initial period (not t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption of status; written waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presumption of status; written waiver Every alien (other than a nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (L) or (V) of section 1101(a)(15) of this title, and other than a nonimmigrant described in any provision of section 1101(a)(15)(H)(i) of this title except subclause (b1) of such section) shall be presumed to be an immigrant until he establishes to the satisfaction of the consular officer, at the time of application for a visa, and the immigration officers, at the time of application for admission, that he is entitled to a nonimmigrant status under section 1101(a)(15) of this title. An alien who is an officer or employee of any foreign government or of any international organization entitled to enjoy privileges, exemptions, and immunities under the International Organizations Immunities Act [22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.], or an alien who is the attendant, servant, employee, or member of the immediate family of any such alien shall not be entitled to apply for or receive an immigrant visa</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition of importing employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Petition of importing employer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of visa to fiancée or fiancé of citizen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuance of visa to fiancée or fiancé of citizen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonimmigrant professionals and annual numerical limit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonimmigrant professionals and annual numerical limit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of crewmember status in case of certain labor disputes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Denial of crewmember status in case of certain labor disputes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary workers and trainees; limitation on numbers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Temporary workers and trainees; limitation on numbers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intention to abandon foreign residence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Intention to abandon foreign residence The fact that an alien is the beneficiary of an application for a preference status filed under section 1154 of this title or has otherwise sought permanent residence in the United States shall not constitute evidence of an intention to abandon a foreign residence for purposes of obtaining a visa as a nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (H)(i)(b) or (c), (L), or (V) of section 1101(a)(15) of this title or otherwise obtaining or maintaining the status of a nonimmigrant described in such subparagraph, if the alien had obtained a change of status under section 1258 of this title to a classification as such a nonimmigrant before the alien’s most recent departure from the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Specialty occupation” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) “Specialty occupation” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1184_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor disputes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Labor disputes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>