<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1186b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1186b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1186b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1186b"><akn:num>1186b</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional permanent resident status for certain alien entrepreneurs, spouses, and children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1186b. Conditional permanent resident status for certain alien entrepreneurs, spouses, and children(a) In general(1) Conditional basis for statusAn alien investor, alien spouse, and alien child shall be considered, at the time of obtaining status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, to have obtained such status on a conditional basis subject to the provisions of this section.


(2) Notice of requirements(A) At time of obtaining permanent residenceAt the time an alien investor, alien spouse, or alien child obtains permanent resident status on a conditional basis under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide for notice to such an investor, spouse, or child respecting the provisions of this section and the requirements of subsection (c)(1) to have the conditional basis of such status removed.


(B) At time of required petitionIn addition, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall attempt to provide notice to such an investor, spouse, or child, at or about the beginning of the 90-day period described in subsection (d)(2)(A), of the requirements of subsection (c)(1).


(C) Effect of failure to provide noticeThe failure of the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide a notice under this paragraph shall not affect the enforcement of the provisions of this section with respect to such an investor, spouse, or child.




(b) Termination of status if finding that qualifying investment improper(1) In generalIn the case of an alien investor with permanent resident status on a conditional basis under subsection (a), if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines, before the second anniversary of the alien’s obtaining the status of lawful admission for permanent residence, that—(A) the investment in the commercial enterprise was intended solely as a means of evading the immigration laws of the United States,

(B) the alien did not invest the requisite capital; or

(C) the alien was otherwise not conforming to the requirements of sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of status if finding that qualifying investment improper</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of status if finding that qualifying investment improper</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for removal of condition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for removal of condition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Details of petition and interview</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Details of petition and interview</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of period for purposes of naturalization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of period for purposes of naturalization For purposes of subchapter III, in the case of an alien who is in the United States as a lawful permanent resident on a conditional basis under this section, the alien shall be considered to have been admitted as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence and to be in the United States as an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1186b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>