<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1201"><akn:num>1201</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of visas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1201. Issuance of visas(a) Immigrants; nonimmigrants(1) Under the conditions hereinafter prescribed and subject to the limitations prescribed in this chapter or regulations issued thereunder, a consular officer may issue(A) to an immigrant who has made proper application therefor, an immigrant visa which shall consist of the application provided for in section 1202 of this title, visaed by such consular officer, and shall specify the foreign state, if any, to which the immigrant is charged, the immigrant’s particular status under such foreign state, the preference, immediate relative, or special immigrant classification to which the alien is charged, the date on which the validity of the visa shall expire, and such additional information as may be required; and

(B) to a nonimmigrant who has made proper application therefor, a nonimmigrant visa, which shall specify the classification under section 1101(a)(15) of this title of the nonimmigrant, the period during which the nonimmigrant visa shall be valid, and such additional information as may be required.


(2) The Secretary of State shall provide to the Service an electronic version of the visa file of each alien who has been issued a visa to ensure that the data in that visa file is available to immigration inspectors at the United States ports of entry before the arrival of the alien at such a port of entry.


(b) Registration; photographs; waiver of requirementEach alien who applies for a visa shall be registered in connection with his application, and shall furnish copies of his photograph signed by him for such use as may be by regulations required. The requirements of this subsection may be waived in the discretion of the Secretary of State in the case of any alien who is within that class of nonimmigrants enumerated in sections 1101(a)(15)(A), and 1101(a)(15)(G) of this title, or in the case of any alien who is granted a diplomatic visa on a diplomatic passport or on the equivalent thereof.


(c) Period of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immigrants; nonimmigrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Immigrants; nonimmigrants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration; photographs; waiver of requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration; photographs; waiver of requirement Each alien who applies for a visa shall be registered in connection with his application, and shall furnish copies of his photograph signed by him for such use as may be by regulations required. The requirements of this subsection may be waived in the discretion of the Secretary of State in the case of any alien who is within that class of nonimmigrants enumerated in sections 1101(a)(15)(A), and 1101(a)(15)(G) of this title, or in the case of any alien who is granted a diplomatic visa on a diplomatic passport or on the equivalent thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of validity; renewal or replacement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period of validity; renewal or replacement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Physical examination Prior to the issuance of an immigrant visa to any alien, the consular officer shall require such alien to submit to a physical and mental examination in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed. Prior to the issuance of a nonimmigrant visa to any alien, the consular officer may require such alien to submit to a physical or mental examination, or both, if in his opinion such examination is necessary to ascertain whether such alien is eligible to receive a visa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surrender of visa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Surrender of visa Each immigrant shall surrender his immigrant visa to the immigration officer at the port of entry, who shall endorse on the visa the date and the port of arrival, the identity of the vessel or other means of transportation by which the immigrant arrived, and such other endorsements as may be by regulations required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surrender of documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Surrender of documents Each nonimmigrant shall present or surrender to the immigration officer at the port of entry such documents as may be by regulation required. In the case of an alien crewman not in possession of any individual documents other than a passport and until such time as it becomes practicable to issue individual documents, such alien crewman may be admitted, subject to the provisions of this part, if his name appears in the crew list of the vessel or aircraft on which he arrives and the crew list is visaed by a consular officer, but the consular officer shall have the right to deny admission to any alien crewman from the crew list visa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonissuance of visas or other documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonissuance of visas or other documents No visa or other documentation shall be issued to an alien if (1) it appears to the consular officer, from statements in the application, or in the papers submitted therewith, that such alien is ineligible to receive a visa or such other documentation under section 1182 of this title, or any other provision of law, (2) the application fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter, or the regulations issued thereunder, or (3) the consular officer knows or has reason to believe that such alien is ineligible to receive a visa or such other documentation under section 1182 of this title, or any other provision of law: Provided, That a visa or other documentation may be issued to an alien who is within the purview of section 1182(a)(4) of this title, if such alien is otherwise entitled to receive a visa or other documentation, upon receipt of notice by the consular officer from the Attorney General of the giving of a bond or undertaking prov</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonadmission upon arrival</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonadmission upon arrival Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to entitle any alien, to whom a visa or other documentation has been issued, to be admitted 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “to”. the United States, if, upon arrival at a port of entry in the United States, he is found to be inadmissible under this chapter, or any other provision of law. The substance of this subsection shall appear upon every visa application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1201_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of visas or documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Revocation of visas or documents After the issuance of a visa or other documentation to any alien, the consular officer or the Secretary of State may at any time, in his discretion, revoke such visa or other documentation. Notice of such revocation shall be communicated to the Attorney General, and such revocation shall invalidate the visa or other documentation from the date of issuance: Provided, That carriers or transportation companies, and masters, commanding officers, agents, owners, charterers, or consignees, shall not be penalized under section 1323(b) of this title for action taken in reliance on such visas or other documentation, unless they received due notice of such revocation prior to the alien’s embarkation. There shall be no means of judicial review (including review pursuant to section 2241 of title 28 or any other habeas corpus provision, and sections 1361 and 1651 of such title) of a revocation under this subsection, except in the context of a removal proceeding </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>