<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1227" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1227/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1227/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1227"><akn:num>1227</akn:num><akn:heading>Deportable aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1227. Deportable aliens(a) Classes of deportable aliensAny alien (including an alien crewman) in and admitted to the United States shall, upon the order of the Attorney General, be removed if the alien is within one or more of the following classes of deportable aliens:(1) Inadmissible at time of entry or of adjustment of status or violates status(A) Inadmissible aliensAny alien who at the time of entry or adjustment of status was within one or more of the classes of aliens inadmissible by the law existing at such time is deportable.


(B) Present in violation of lawAny alien who is present in the United States in violation of this chapter or any other law of the United States, or whose nonimmigrant visa (or other documentation authorizing admission into the United States as a nonimmigrant) has been revoked under section 1201(i) of this title, is deportable.


(C) Violated nonimmigrant status or condition of entry(i) Nonimmigrant status violatorsAny alien who was admitted as a nonimmigrant and who has failed to maintain the nonimmigrant status in which the alien was admitted or to which it was changed under section 1258 of this title, or to comply with the conditions of any such status, is deportable.


(ii) Violators of conditions of entryAny alien whom the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies has failed to comply with terms, conditions, and controls that were imposed under section 1182(g) of this title is deportable.



(D) Termination of conditional permanent residence(i) In generalAny alien with permanent resident status on a conditional basis under section 1186a of this title (relating to conditional permanent resident status for certain alien spouses and sons and daughters) or under section 1186b of this title (relating to conditional permanent resident status for certain alien entrepreneurs, spouses, and children) who has had such status terminated under such respective section is deportable.


(ii) ExceptionClause (i) shall not apply in the cas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1227_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classes of deportable aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Classes of deportable aliens Any alien (including an alien crewman) in and admitted to the United States shall, upon the order of the Attorney General, be removed if the alien is within one or more of the following classes of deportable aliens:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1227_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deportation of certain nonimmigrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deportation of certain nonimmigrants An alien, admitted as a nonimmigrant under the provisions of either section 1101(a)(15)(A)(i) or 1101(a)(15)(G)(i) of this title, and who fails to maintain a status under either of those provisions, shall not be required to depart from the United States without the approval of the Secretary of State, unless such alien is subject to deportation under paragraph (4) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1227_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of grounds for deportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of grounds for deportation Paragraphs (1)(A), (1)(B), (1)(C), (1)(D), and (3)(A) of subsection (a) (other than so much of paragraph (1) as relates to a ground of inadmissibility described in paragraph (2) or (3) of section 1182(a) of this title) shall not apply to a special immigrant described in section 1101(a)(27)(J) of this title based upon circumstances that existed before the date the alien was provided such special immigrant status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1227_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative stay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative stay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>