<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1229"><akn:num>1229</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of removal proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1229. Initiation of removal proceedings(a) Notice to appear(1) In generalIn removal proceedings under section 1229a of this title, written notice (in this section referred to as a “notice to appear”) shall be given in person to the alien (or, if personal service is not practicable, through service by mail to the alien or to the alien’s counsel of record, if any) specifying the following:(A) The nature of the proceedings against the alien.

(B) The legal authority under which the proceedings are conducted.

(C) The acts or conduct alleged to be in violation of law.

(D) The charges against the alien and the statutory provisions alleged to have been violated.

(E) The alien may be represented by counsel and the alien will be provided (i) a period of time to secure counsel under subsection (b)(1) and (ii) a current list of counsel prepared under subsection (b)(2).

(F)(i) The requirement that the alien must immediately provide (or have provided) the Attorney General with a written record of an address and telephone number (if any) at which the alien may be contacted respecting proceedings under section 1229a of this title.

(ii) The requirement that the alien must provide the Attorney General immediately with a written record of any change of the alien’s address or telephone number.

(iii) The consequences under section 1229a(b)(5) of this title of failure to provide address and telephone information pursuant to this subparagraph.


(G)(i) The time and place at which the proceedings will be held.

(ii) The consequences under section 1229a(b)(5) of this title of the failure, except under exceptional circumstances, to appear at such proceedings.



(2) Notice of change in time or place of proceedings(A) In generalIn removal proceedings under section 1229a of this title, in the case of any change or postponement in the time and place of such proceedings, subject to subparagraph (B) a written notice shall be given in person to the alien (or, if personal service is not pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to appear</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to appear</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Securing of counsel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Securing of counsel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service by mail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Service by mail Service by mail under this section shall be sufficient if there is proof of attempted delivery to the last address provided by the alien in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(F).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt initiation of removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prompt initiation of removal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of compliance with restrictions on disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification of compliance with restrictions on disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>