<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1229a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1229a"><akn:num>1229a</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1229a. Removal proceedings(a) Proceeding(1) In generalAn immigration judge shall conduct proceedings for deciding the inadmissibility or deportability of an alien.


(2) ChargesAn alien placed in proceedings under this section may be charged with any applicable ground of inadmissibility under section 1182(a) of this title or any applicable ground of deportability under section 1227(a) of this title.


(3) Exclusive proceduresUnless otherwise specified in this chapter, a proceeding under this section shall be the sole and exclusive procedure for determining whether an alien may be admitted to the United States or, if the alien has been so admitted, removed from the United States. Nothing in this section shall affect proceedings conducted pursuant to section 1228 of this title.



(b) Conduct of proceeding(1) Authority of immigration judgeThe immigration judge shall administer oaths, receive evidence, and interrogate, examine, and cross-examine the alien and any witnesses. The immigration judge may issue subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and presentation of evidence. The immigration judge shall have authority (under regulations prescribed by the Attorney General) to sanction by civil money penalty any action (or inaction) in contempt of the judge’s proper exercise of authority under this chapter.


(2) Form of proceeding(A) In generalThe proceeding may take place—(i) in person,

(ii) where agreed to by the parties, in the absence of the alien,

(iii) through video conference, or

(iv) subject to subparagraph (B), through telephone conference.


(B) Consent required in certain casesAn evidentiary hearing on the merits may only be conducted through a telephone conference with the consent of the alien involved after the alien has been advised of the right to proceed in person or through video conference.



(3) Presence of alienIf it is impracticable by reason of an alien’s mental incompetency for the alien to be present at the proceeding, the Attorney General </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proceeding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conduct of proceeding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision and burden of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Decision and burden of proof</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stipulated removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Stipulated removal The Attorney General shall provide by regulation for the entry by an immigration judge of an order of removal stipulated to by the alien (or the alien’s representative) and the Service. A stipulated order shall constitute a conclusive determination of the alien’s removability from the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1229a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section and section 1229b of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>