<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1255a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1255a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1255a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1255a"><akn:num>1255a</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of status of certain entrants before January 1, 1982, to that of person admitted for lawf</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1255a. Adjustment of status of certain entrants before January 1, 1982, to that of person admitted for lawful residence(a) Temporary resident statusThe Attorney General shall adjust the status of an alien to that of an alien lawfully admitted for temporary residence if the alien meets the following requirements:(1) Timely application(A) During application periodExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the alien must apply for such adjustment during the 12-month period beginning on a date (not later than 180 days after November 6, 1986) designated by the Attorney General.


(B) Application within 30 days of show-cause orderAn alien who, at any time during the first 11 months of the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A), is the subject of an order to show cause issued under section 1252 of this title (as in effect before October 1, 1996), must make application under this section not later than the end of the 30-day period beginning either on the first day of such 12-month period or on the date of the issuance of such order, whichever day is later.


(C) Information included in applicationEach application under this subsection shall contain such information as the Attorney General may require, including information on living relatives of the applicant with respect to whom a petition for preference or other status may be filed by the applicant at any later date under section 1154(a) of this title.



(2) Continuous unlawful residence since 1982(A) In generalThe alien must establish that he entered the United States before January 1, 1982, and that he has resided continuously in the United States in an unlawful status since such date and through the date the application is filed under this subsection.


(B) NonimmigrantsIn the case of an alien who entered the United States as a nonimmigrant before January 1, 1982, the alien must establish that the alien’s period of authorized stay as a nonimmigrant expired before such date through the passage of time or the alie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary resident status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Temporary resident status The Attorney General shall adjust the status of an alien to that of an alien lawfully admitted for temporary residence if the alien meets the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent adjustment to permanent residence and nature of temporary resident status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subsequent adjustment to permanent residence and nature of temporary resident status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for adjustment of status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications for adjustment of status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of numerical limitations and certain grounds for exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of numerical limitations and certain grounds for exclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary stay of deportation and work authorization for certain applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary stay of deportation and work authorization for certain applicants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative and judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Implementation of section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary disqualification of newly legalized aliens from receiving certain public welfare assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Temporary disqualification of newly legalized aliens from receiving certain public welfare assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1255a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information on legalization program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Dissemination of information on legalization program Beginning not later than the date designated by the Attorney General under subsection (a)(1)(A), the Attorney General, in cooperation with qualified designated entities, shall broadly disseminate information respecting the benefits which aliens may receive under this section and the requirements to obtain such benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>