<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1288"><akn:num>1288</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on performance of longshore work by alien crewmen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1288. Limitations on performance of longshore work by alien crewmen(a) In generalFor purposes of section 1101(a)(15)(D)(i) of this title, the term “normal operation and service on board a vessel” does not include any activity that is longshore work (as defined in subsection (b)), except as provided under subsection (c), (d), or (e).


(b) “Longshore work” defined(1) In generalIn this section, except as provided in paragraph (2), the term “longshore work” means any activity relating to the loading or unloading of cargo, the operation of cargo-related equipment (whether or not integral to the vessel), and the handling of mooring lines on the dock when the vessel is made fast or let go, in the United States or the coastal waters thereof.


(2) Exception for safety and environmental protectionThe term “longshore work” does not include the loading or unloading of any cargo for which the Secretary of Transportation has, under the authority contained in chapter 37 of title 46 (relating to Carriage of Liquid Bulk Dangerous Cargoes), section 1321 of title 33, section 4106 of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990, or section 5103(b), 5104, 5106, 5107, or 5110 of title 49 prescribed regulations which govern—(A) the handling or stowage of such cargo,

(B) the manning of vessels and the duties, qualifications, and training of the officers and crew of vessels carrying such cargo, and

(C) the reduction or elimination of discharge during ballasting, tank cleaning, handling of such cargo.


(3) ConstructionNothing in this section shall be construed as broadening, limiting, or otherwise modifying the meaning or scope of longshore work for purposes of any other law, collective bargaining agreement, or international agreement.



(c) Prevailing practice exception(1) Subsection (a) shall not apply to a particular activity of longshore work in and about a local port if—(A)(i) there is in effect in the local port one or more collective bargaining agreements each covering at least 30 percent of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of section 1101(a)(15)(D)(i) of this title, the term “normal operation and service on board a vessel” does not include any activity that is longshore work (as defined in subsection (b)), except as provided under subsection (c), (d), or (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Longshore work” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Longshore work” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevailing practice exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prevailing practice exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State of Alaska exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State of Alaska exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocity exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reciprocity exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>