<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1367" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1367/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1367/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1367"><akn:num>1367</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for disclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1367. Penalties for disclosure of information(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b), in no case may the Attorney General, or any other official or employee of the Department of Justice, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or any other official or employee of the Department of Homeland Security or Department of State (including any bureau or agency of either of such Departments)—(1) make an adverse determination of admissibility or deportability of an alien under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.] using information furnished solely by—(A) a spouse or parent who has battered the alien or subjected the alien to extreme cruelty,

(B) a member of the spouse’s or parent’s family residing in the same household as the alien who has battered the alien or subjected the alien to extreme cruelty when the spouse or parent consented to or acquiesced in such battery or cruelty,

(C) a spouse or parent who has battered the alien’s child or subjected the alien’s child to extreme cruelty (without the active participation of the alien in the battery or extreme cruelty),

(D) a member of the spouse’s or parent’s family residing in the same household as the alien who has battered the alien’s child or subjected the alien’s child to extreme cruelty when the spouse or parent consented to or acquiesced in such battery or cruelty and the alien did not actively participate in such battery or cruelty,

(E) in the case of an alien applying for status under section 101(a)(15)(U) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(U)], the perpetrator of the substantial physical or mental abuse and the criminal activity,11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “or”.

(F) in the case of an alien applying for status under section 101(a)(15)(T) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(T)), under section 7105(b)(1)(E)(i)(II)(bb) of title 22, under section 244(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1367_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (b), in no case may the Attorney General, or any other official or employee of the Department of Justice, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or any other official or employee of the Department of Homeland Security or Department of State (including any bureau or agency of either of such Departments)— The limitation under paragraph (2) ends when the application for relief is denied and all opportunities for appeal of the denial have been exhausted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1367_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1367_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalties for violations Anyone who willfully uses, publishes, or permits information to be disclosed in violation of this section or who knowingly makes a false certification under section 239(e) of the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1229(e)] shall be subject to appropriate disciplinary action and subject to a civil money penalty of not more than $5,000 for each such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1367_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidance The Attorney General, Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide guidance to officers and employees of the Department of Justice, Department of State, or the Department of Homeland Security who have access to information covered by this section regarding the provisions of this section, including the provisions to protect victims of domestic violence and severe forms of trafficking in persons or criminal activity listed in section 101(a)(15)(U) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(u)) from harm that could result from the inappropriate disclosure of covered information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>