<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1375a"><akn:num>1375a</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic violence information and resources for immigrants and regulation of international marriage </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1375a. Domestic violence information and resources for immigrants and regulation of international marriage brokers(a) Information for K nonimmigrants on legal rights and resources for immigrant victims of domestic violence(1) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of State, shall develop an information pamphlet, as described in paragraph (2), on legal rights and resources for immigrant victims of domestic violence and distribute and make such pamphlet available as described in paragraph (5). In preparing such materials, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consult with nongovernmental organizations with expertise on the legal rights of immigrant victims of battery, extreme cruelty, sexual assault, and other crimes.


(2) Information pamphletThe information pamphlet developed under paragraph (1) shall include information on the following:(A) The K nonimmigrant visa application process and the marriage-based immigration process, including conditional residence and adjustment of status.

(B) The illegality of domestic violence, sexual assault, and child abuse in the United States and the dynamics of domestic violence.

(C) Domestic violence and sexual assault services in the United States, including the National Domestic Violence Hotline and the National Sexual Assault Hotline.

(D) The legal rights of immigrant victims of abuse and other crimes in immigration, criminal justice, family law, and other matters, including access to protection orders.

(E) The obligations of parents to provide child support for children.

(F) Marriage fraud under United States immigration laws and the penalties for committing such fraud.

(G) A warning concerning the potential use of K nonimmigrant visas by United States citizens who have a history of committing domestic violence, sexual assault, child abuse, or other crimes and an explanation that such acts may not have resulted in a criminal record for such a citize</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information for K nonimmigrants on legal rights and resources for immigrant victims of domestic violence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information for K nonimmigrants on legal rights and resources for immigrant victims of domestic violence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visa and adjustment interviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Visa and adjustment interviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidentiality In fulfilling the requirements of this section, no official of the Department of State or the Department of Homeland Security shall disclose to a nonimmigrant visa applicant the name or contact information of any person who was granted a protection order or restraining order against the petitioner or who was a victim of a crime of violence perpetrated by the petitioner, but shall disclose the relationship of the person to the petitioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of international marriage brokers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulation of international marriage brokers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO studies and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) GAO studies and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>