<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1375c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1375c"><akn:num>1375c</akn:num><akn:heading>Protections, remedies, and limitations on issuance for A–3 and G–5 visas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1375c. Protections, remedies, and limitations on issuance for A–3 and G–5 visas(a) Limitations on issuance of A–3 and G–5 visas(1) Contract requirementNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of State may not issue—(A) an A–3 visa unless the applicant is employed, or has signed a contract to be employed containing the requirements set forth in subsection (d)(2),11 So in original. Probably should be “(b)(2),”. by an officer of a diplomatic mission or consular post; or

(B) a G–5 visa unless the applicant is employed, or has signed a contract to be employed by an employee in an international organization.


(2) Suspension requirementNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall suspend, for a period of at least 1 year, except if the Secretary determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees, in advance, the reasons a shorter period is in the national interest,,22 So in original. the issuance of A–3 visas or G–5 visas to applicants seeking to work for officials of a diplomatic mission or an international organization, if there is an unpaid default or final civil judgement directly or indirectly related to human trafficking against the employer or a family member assigned to the embassy, or the diplomatic mission or international organization hosting the employer or family member has not responded affirmatively to a request to waive immunity within 6 weeks of the request in a case brought by the United States Government and the country that accredited the employer or family member or, in the case of international organizations, the country of citizenship, has not initiated prosecution against the employer or family member.


(3) Action by diplomatic missions or international organizationsThe Secretary may suspend the application of the limitation under paragraph (2) if the Secretary determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that, as applicable, the unpaid default judgment or final civil judg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on issuance of A–3 and G–5 visas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitations on issuance of A–3 and G–5 visas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protections and remedies for A–3 and G–5 nonimmigrants employed by diplomats and staff of international organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Protections and remedies for A–3 and G–5 nonimmigrants employed by diplomats and staff of international organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection from removal during legal actions against former employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection from removal during legal actions against former employers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Study and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to law enforcement investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance to law enforcement investigations The Secretary shall cooperate, to the fullest extent possible consistent with the United States obligations under the Vienna Convention on Diplomatic Relations, done at Vienna, April 18, 1961, (23 U.S.T. 3229),33 So in original. Probably should be “April 18, 1961 (23 U.S.T. 3227),”. with any investigation by United States law enforcement authorities of crimes related to abuse or exploitation of a nonimmigrant holding an A–3 visa or a G–5 visa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>