<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1426"><akn:num>1426</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizenship denied alien relieved of service in Armed Forces because of alienage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1426. Citizenship denied alien relieved of service in Armed Forces because of alienage(a) Permanent ineligibilityNotwithstanding the provisions of section 405(b) 11 See References in Text note below. but subject to subsection (c), any alien who applies or has applied for exemption or discharge from training or service in the Armed Forces or in the National Security Training Corps of the United States on the ground that he is an alien, and is or was relieved or discharged from such training or service on such ground, shall be permanently ineligible to become a citizen of the United States.


(b) Conclusiveness of recordsThe records of the Selective Service System or of the Department of Defense shall be conclusive as to whether an alien was relieved or discharged from such liability for training or service because he was an alien.


(c) Service in armed forces of foreign countryAn alien shall not be ineligible for citizenship under this section or otherwise because of an exemption from training or service in the Armed Forces of the United States pursuant to the exercise of rights under a treaty, if before the time of the exercise of such rights the alien served in the Armed Forces of a foreign country of which the alien was a national.


(June 27, 1952, ch. 477, title III, ch. 2, § 315, 66 Stat. 242; Pub. L. 100–525, § 9(v), Oct. 24, 1988, 102 Stat. 2621; Pub. L. 101–649, title IV, § 404, Nov. 29, 1990, 104 Stat. 5039.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 405(b), referred to in subsec. (a), is section 405(b) of act June 27, 1952, ch. 477, title IV, 66 Stat. 280, which is set out as a Savings Clause note under section 1101 of this title.

Amendments1990—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 101–649, § 404(1), inserted “but subject to subsection (c)” after “section 405(b)”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 101–649, § 404(2), added subsec. (c).
1988—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 100–525 substituted “Department of Defense” for “National Military Establishment”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent ineligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permanent ineligibility Notwithstanding the provisions of section 405(b) 11 See References in Text note below. but subject to subsection (c), any alien who applies or has applied for exemption or discharge from training or service in the Armed Forces or in the National Security Training Corps of the United States on the ground that he is an alien, and is or was relieved or discharged from such training or service on such ground, shall be permanently ineligible to become a citizen of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conclusiveness of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conclusiveness of records The records of the Selective Service System or of the Department of Defense shall be conclusive as to whether an alien was relieved or discharged from such liability for training or service because he was an alien.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service in armed forces of foreign country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Service in armed forces of foreign country An alien shall not be ineligible for citizenship under this section or otherwise because of an exemption from training or service in the Armed Forces of the United States pursuant to the exercise of rights under a treaty, if before the time of the exercise of such rights the alien served in the Armed Forces of a foreign country of which the alien was a national.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>