<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1440g"><akn:num>1440g</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information on military naturalization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1440g. Provision of information on military naturalization(a) In generalNot later than 30 days after the effective date of any modification to a regulation related to naturalization under section 1439 or 1440 of this title, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make appropriate updates to the Internet sites maintained by the Secretary to reflect such modification.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Homeland Security, not later than 180 days after each effective date described in subsection (a), should make necessary updates to the appropriate application forms of the Department of Homeland Security.


(Pub. L. 110–251, § 3, June 26, 2008, 122 Stat. 2320.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Kendell Frederick Citizenship Assistance Act, and not as part of the Immigration and Nationality Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 30 days after the effective date of any modification to a regulation related to naturalization under section 1439 or 1440 of this title, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make appropriate updates to the Internet sites maintained by the Secretary to reflect such modification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Homeland Security, not later than 180 days after each effective date described in subsection (a), should make necessary updates to the appropriate application forms of the Department of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>