<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1440–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1440_1"><akn:num>1440–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Posthumous citizenship through death while on active-duty service in armed forces during World War I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1440–1. Posthumous citizenship through death while on active-duty service in armed forces during World War I, World War II, the Korean hostilities, the Vietnam hostilities, or in other periods of military hostilities(a) Permitting granting of posthumous citizenshipNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide, in accordance with this section, for the granting of posthumous citizenship at the time of death to a person described in subsection (b) if the Secretary of Homeland Security approves an application for that posthumous citizenship under subsection (c).


(b) Noncitizens eligible for posthumous citizenshipA person referred to in subsection (a) is a person who, while an alien or a noncitizen national of the United States—(1) served honorably in an active-duty status in the military, air, or naval forces of the United States during any period described in the first sentence of section 1440(a) of this title,

(2) died as a result of injury or disease incurred in or aggravated by that service, and

(3) satisfied the requirements of clause (1) or (2) of the first sentence of section 1440(a) of this title.


The executive department under which the person so served shall determine whether the person satisfied the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2).

(c) Requests for posthumous citizenship(1) In generalA request for the granting of posthumous citizenship to a person described in subsection (b) may be filed on behalf of that person—(A) upon locating the next-of-kin, and if so requested by the next-of-kin, by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary’s designee with the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services in the Department of Homeland Security immediately upon the death of that person; or

(B) by the next-of-kin.


(2) ApprovalThe Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services shall approve a request for posthumous citizenship filed by the next-of-kin in accordance with paragraph</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitting granting of posthumous citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permitting granting of posthumous citizenship Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide, in accordance with this section, for the granting of posthumous citizenship at the time of death to a person described in subsection (b) if the Secretary of Homeland Security approves an application for that posthumous citizenship under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncitizens eligible for posthumous citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Noncitizens eligible for posthumous citizenship A person referred to in subsection (a) is a person who, while an alien or a noncitizen national of the United States— The executive department under which the person so served shall determine whether the person satisfied the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for posthumous citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requests for posthumous citizenship</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation of posthumous citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Documentation of posthumous citizenship If the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services approves the request referred to in subsection (c), the Director shall send to the next-of-kin of the person who is granted citizenship, a suitable document which states that the United States considers the person to have been a citizen of the United States at the time of the person’s death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>