<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1447" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1447/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1447/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1447"><akn:num>1447</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings on denials of applications for naturalization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1447. Hearings on denials of applications for naturalization(a) Request for hearing before immigration officerIf, after an examination under section 1446 of this title, an application for naturalization is denied, the applicant may request a hearing before an immigration officer.


(b) Request for hearing before district courtIf there is a failure to make a determination under section 1446 of this title before the end of the 120-day period after the date on which the examination is conducted under such section, the applicant may apply to the United States district court for the district in which the applicant resides for a hearing on the matter. Such court has jurisdiction over the matter and may either determine the matter or remand the matter, with appropriate instructions, to the Service to determine the matter.


(c) Appearance of Attorney GeneralThe Attorney General shall have the right to appear before any immigration officer in any naturalization proceedings for the purpose of cross-examining the applicant and the witnesses produced in support of the application concerning any matter touching or in any way affecting the applicant’s right to admission to citizenship, and shall have the right to call witnesses, including the applicant, produce evidence, and be heard in opposition to, or in favor of the granting of any application in naturalization proceedings.


(d) Subpena of witnessesThe immigration officer shall, if the applicant requests it at the time of filing the request for the hearing, issue a subpena for the witnesses named by such applicant to appear upon the day set for the hearing, but in case such witnesses cannot be produced upon the hearing other witnesses may be summoned upon notice to the Attorney General, in such manner and at such time as the Attorney General may by regulation prescribe. Such subpenas may be enforced in the same manner as subpenas under section 1446(b) of this title may be enforced.


(e) Change of nameIt shall be lawful a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1447_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for hearing before immigration officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Request for hearing before immigration officer If, after an examination under section 1446 of this title, an application for naturalization is denied, the applicant may request a hearing before an immigration officer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1447_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for hearing before district court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Request for hearing before district court If there is a failure to make a determination under section 1446 of this title before the end of the 120-day period after the date on which the examination is conducted under such section, the applicant may apply to the United States district court for the district in which the applicant resides for a hearing on the matter. Such court has jurisdiction over the matter and may either determine the matter or remand the matter, with appropriate instructions, to the Service to determine the matter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1447_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appearance of Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appearance of Attorney General The Attorney General shall have the right to appear before any immigration officer in any naturalization proceedings for the purpose of cross-examining the applicant and the witnesses produced in support of the application concerning any matter touching or in any way affecting the applicant’s right to admission to citizenship, and shall have the right to call witnesses, including the applicant, produce evidence, and be heard in opposition to, or in favor of the granting of any application in naturalization proceedings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1447_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpena of witnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subpena of witnesses The immigration officer shall, if the applicant requests it at the time of filing the request for the hearing, issue a subpena for the witnesses named by such applicant to appear upon the day set for the hearing, but in case such witnesses cannot be produced upon the hearing other witnesses may be summoned upon notice to the Attorney General, in such manner and at such time as the Attorney General may by regulation prescribe. Such subpenas may be enforced in the same manner as subpenas under section 1446(b) of this title may be enforced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1447_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change of name</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Change of name It shall be lawful at the time and as a part of the administration by a court of the oath of allegiance under section 1448(a) of this title for the court, in its discretion, upon the bona fide prayer of the applicant included in an appropriate petition to the court, to make a decree changing the name of said person, and the certificate of naturalization shall be issued in accordance therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>