<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1532" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1532/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1532/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1532"><akn:num>1532</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of removal court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1532. Establishment of removal court(a) Designation of judgesThe Chief Justice of the United States shall publicly designate 5 district court judges from 5 of the United States judicial circuits who shall constitute a court that shall have jurisdiction to conduct all removal proceedings. The Chief Justice may, in the Chief Justice’s discretion, designate the same judges under this section as are designated pursuant to section 103(a) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1803(a)).


(b) TermsEach judge designated under subsection (a) shall serve for a term of 5 years and shall be eligible for redesignation, except that of the members first designated—(1) 1 member shall serve for a term of 1 year;

(2) 1 member shall serve for a term of 2 years;

(3) 1 member shall serve for a term of 3 years; and

(4) 1 member shall serve for a term of 4 years.


(c) Chief judge(1) DesignationThe Chief Justice shall publicly designate one of the judges of the removal court to be the chief judge of the removal court.


(2) ResponsibilitiesThe chief judge shall—(A) promulgate rules to facilitate the functioning of the removal court; and

(B) assign the consideration of cases to the various judges on the removal court.



(d) Expeditious and confidential nature of proceedingsThe provisions of section 103(c) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1803(c)) shall apply to removal proceedings in the same manner as they apply to proceedings under that Act [50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.].


(e) Establishment of panel of special attorneysThe removal court shall provide for the designation of a panel of attorneys each of whom—(1) has a security clearance which affords the attorney access to classified information, and

(2) has agreed to represent permanent resident aliens with respect to classified information under section 1534(e)(3) of this title in accordance with (and subject to the penalties under) this subchapter.


(June 27, 1952, ch. 477, ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1532_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of judges The Chief Justice of the United States shall publicly designate 5 district court judges from 5 of the United States judicial circuits who shall constitute a court that shall have jurisdiction to conduct all removal proceedings. The Chief Justice may, in the Chief Justice’s discretion, designate the same judges under this section as are designated pursuant to section 103(a) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1803(a)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1532_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms Each judge designated under subsection (a) shall serve for a term of 5 years and shall be eligible for redesignation, except that of the members first designated—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1532_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief judge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chief judge</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1532_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expeditious and confidential nature of proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expeditious and confidential nature of proceedings The provisions of section 103(c) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1803(c)) shall apply to removal proceedings in the same manner as they apply to proceedings under that Act [50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1532_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of panel of special attorneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of panel of special attorneys The removal court shall provide for the designation of a panel of attorneys each of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>