<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1534"><akn:num>1534</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1534. Removal hearing(a) In general(1) Expeditious hearingIn any case in which an application for an order is approved under section 1533(c)(2) of this title, a removal hearing shall be conducted under this section as expeditiously as practicable for the purpose of determining whether the alien to whom the order pertains should be removed from the United States on the grounds that the alien is an alien terrorist.


(2) Public hearingThe removal hearing shall be open to the public.



(b) NoticeAn alien who is the subject of a removal hearing under this subchapter shall be given reasonable notice of—(1) the nature of the charges against the alien, including a general account of the basis for the charges; and

(2) the time and place at which the hearing will be held.


(c) Rights in hearing(1) Right of counselThe alien shall have a right to be present at such hearing and to be represented by counsel. Any alien financially unable to obtain counsel shall be entitled to have counsel assigned to represent the alien. Such counsel shall be appointed by the judge pursuant to the plan for furnishing representation for any person financially unable to obtain adequate representation for the district in which the hearing is conducted, as provided for in section 3006A of title 18. All provisions of that section shall apply and, for purposes of determining the maximum amount of compensation, the matter shall be treated as if a felony was charged.


(2) Introduction of evidenceSubject to the limitations in subsection (e), the alien shall have a reasonable opportunity to introduce evidence on the alien’s own behalf.


(3) Examination of witnessesSubject to the limitations in subsection (e), the alien shall have a reasonable opportunity to examine the evidence against the alien and to cross-examine any witness.


(4) RecordA verbatim record of the proceedings and of all testimony and evidence offered or produced at such a hearing shall be kept.


(5) Removal decision based on evide</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice An alien who is the subject of a removal hearing under this subchapter shall be given reasonable notice of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights in hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rights in hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoenas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subpoenas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discovery</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arguments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Arguments Following the receipt of evidence, the Government and the alien shall be given fair opportunity to present argument as to whether the evidence is sufficient to justify the removal of the alien. The Government shall open the argument. The alien shall be permitted to reply. The Government shall then be permitted to reply in rebuttal. The judge may allow any part of the argument that refers to evidence received in camera and ex parte to be heard in camera and ex parte.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Burden of proof In the hearing, it is the Government’s burden to prove, by the preponderance of the evidence, that the alien is subject to removal because the alien is an alien terrorist.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules of evidence The Federal Rules of Evidence shall not apply in a removal hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of deportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Determination of deportation If the judge, after considering the evidence on the record as a whole, finds that the Government has met its burden, the judge shall order the alien removed and detained pending removal from the United States. If the alien was released pending the removal hearing, the judge shall order the Attorney General to take the alien into custody.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Written order At the time of issuing a decision as to whether the alien shall be removed, the judge shall prepare a written order containing a statement of facts found and conclusions of law. Any portion of the order that would reveal the substance or source of information received in camera and ex parte pursuant to subsection (e) shall not be made available to the alien or the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>