<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1537" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1537/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1537/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1537"><akn:num>1537</akn:num><akn:heading>Custody and release after removal hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1537. Custody and release after removal hearing(a) Release(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), if the judge decides that an alien should not be removed, the alien shall be released from custody.


(2) Custody pending appealIf the Attorney General takes an appeal from such decision, the alien shall remain in custody, subject to the provisions of section 3142 of title 18.



(b) Custody and removal(1) CustodyIf the judge decides that an alien shall be removed, the alien shall be detained pending the outcome of any appeal. After the conclusion of any judicial review thereof which affirms the removal order, the Attorney General shall retain the alien in custody and remove the alien to a country specified under paragraph (2).


(2) Removal(A) In generalThe removal of an alien shall be to any country which the alien shall designate if such designation does not, in the judgment of the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, impair the obligation of the United States under any treaty (including a treaty pertaining to extradition) or otherwise adversely affect the foreign policy of the United States.


(B) Alternate countriesIf the alien refuses to designate a country to which the alien wishes to be removed or if the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that removal of the alien to the country so designated would impair a treaty obligation or adversely affect United States foreign policy, the Attorney General shall cause the alien to be removed to any country willing to receive such alien.


(C) Continued detentionIf no country is willing to receive such an alien, the Attorney General may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, retain the alien in custody. The Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall make periodic efforts to reach agreement with other countries to accept such an alien and at least every 6 months shall provide to the attorney representing the alien at the removal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Release</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Custody and removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Custody and removal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued detention pending trial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continued detention pending trial</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of certain provisions relating to escape of prisoners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application of certain provisions relating to escape of prisoners For purposes of sections 751 and 752 of title 18, an alien in the custody of the Attorney General pursuant to this subchapter shall be subject to the penalties provided by those sections in relation to a person committed to the custody of the Attorney General by virtue of an arrest on a charge of a felony.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1537_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of aliens in custody</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rights of aliens in custody</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>