<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1551"><akn:num>1551</akn:num><akn:heading>Immigration and Naturalization Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1551. Immigration and Naturalization Service
There is created and established in the Department of Justice an Immigration and Naturalization Service.
(Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 4, 32 Stat. 826; June 29, 1906, ch. 3592, § 1, 34 Stat. 596; Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 3, 37 Stat. 737; Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 14, June 10, 1933; 1940 Reorg. Plan No. V, eff. June 14, 1940, 5 F.R. 2223, 54 Stat. 1238.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 342 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2000 AmendmentPub. L. 106–313, title II, § 201, Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1262, provided that: “This title [enacting subchapter II of this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000’.”



Abolition of Immigration and Naturalization Service and Transfer of Functions
The Immigration and Naturalization Service was abolished by section 291(a) of Title 6, Domestic Security, upon completion of all transfers from the Immigration and Naturalization Service as provided for by chapter 1 of Title 6.
Functions of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization performed under the Border Patrol program, the detention and removal program, the intelligence program, the investigations program, and the inspections program, and all personnel, assets, and liabilities pertaining to such programs, were transferred to the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security of the Department of Homeland Security by section 251 of Title 6 and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of November 25, 2002, as modified, set out as a note under section 542 of Title 6.
Functions of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization relating to adjudications of immigrant visa petitions, adjudications of naturalization petitions, adjudications of asyl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>