<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1612"><akn:num>1612</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited eligibility of qualified aliens for certain Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1612. Limited eligibility of qualified aliens for certain Federal programs(a) Limited eligibility for specified Federal programs(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in paragraph (2), an alien who is a qualified alien (as defined in section 1641 of this title) is not eligible for any specified Federal program (as defined in paragraph (3)).


(2) Exceptions(A) Time-limited exception for refugees and asyleesWith respect to the specified Federal programs described in paragraph (3), paragraph (1) shall not apply to an alien until 7 years after the date—(i) an alien is admitted to the United States as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1157];

(ii) an alien is granted asylum under section 208 of such Act [8 U.S.C. 1158];

(iii) an alien’s deportation is withheld under section 243(h) of such Act [8 U.S.C. 1253] (as in effect immediately before the effective date of section 307 of division C of Public Law 104–208) or section 241(b)(3) of such Act [8 U.S.C. 1231(b)(3)] (as amended by section 305(a) of division C of Public Law 104–208);

(iv) an alien is granted status as a Cuban and Haitian entrant (as defined in section 501(e) of the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980); or

(v) an alien is admitted to the United States as an Amerasian immigrant pursuant to section 584 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1988 (as contained in section 101(e) of Public Law 100–202 and amended by the 9th proviso under migration and refugee assistance in title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1989, Public Law 100–461, as amended).


(B) Certain permanent resident aliensParagraph (1) shall not apply to an alien who—(i) is lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.]; and

(ii)(I) has worked 40 qualifying quarters of co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited eligibility for specified Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limited eligibility for specified Federal programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited eligibility for designated Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limited eligibility for designated Federal programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>