<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1621" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1621/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1621/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1621"><akn:num>1621</akn:num><akn:heading>Aliens who are not qualified aliens or nonimmigrants ineligible for State and local public benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1621. Aliens who are not qualified aliens or nonimmigrants ineligible for State and local public benefits(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subsections (b) and (d), an alien who is not—(1) a qualified alien (as defined in section 1641 of this title),

(2) a nonimmigrant under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.], or

(3) an alien who is paroled into the United States under section 212(d)(5) of such Act [8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)] for less than one year,


is not eligible for any State or local public benefit (as defined in subsection (c)).

(b) ExceptionsSubsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the following State or local public benefits:(1) Assistance for health care items and services that are necessary for the treatment of an emergency medical condition (as defined in section 1396b(v)(3) of title 42) of the alien involved and are not related to an organ transplant procedure.

(2) Short-term, non-cash, in-kind emergency disaster relief.

(3) Public health assistance for immunizations with respect to immunizable diseases and for testing and treatment of symptoms of communicable diseases whether or not such symptoms are caused by a communicable disease.

(4) Programs, services, or assistance (such as soup kitchens, crisis counseling and intervention, and short-term shelter) specified by the Attorney General, in the Attorney General’s sole and unreviewable discretion after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies and departments, which (A) deliver in-kind services at the community level, including through public or private nonprofit agencies; (B) do not condition the provision of assistance, the amount of assistance provided, or the cost of assistance provided on the individual recipient’s income or resources; and (C) are necessary for the protection of life or safety.


(c) “State or local public benefit” defined(1) Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), for purposes of this subch</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in subsections (b) and (d), an alien who is not— is not eligible for any State or local public benefit (as defined in subsection (c)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the following State or local public benefits:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State or local public benefit” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “State or local public benefit” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State authority to provide for eligibility of illegal aliens for State and local public benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State authority to provide for eligibility of illegal aliens for State and local public benefits A State may provide that an alien who is not lawfully present in the United States is eligible for any State or local public benefit for which such alien would otherwise be ineligible under subsection (a) only through the enactment of a State law after August 22, 1996, which affirmatively provides for such eligibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>