<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1631"><akn:num>1631</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal attribution of sponsor’s income and resources to alien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1631. Federal attribution of sponsor’s income and resources to alien(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, in determining the eligibility and the amount of benefits of an alien for any Federal means-tested public benefits program (as provided under section 1613 of this title), the income and resources of the alien shall be deemed to include the following:(1) The income and resources of any person who executed an affidavit of support pursuant to section 213A of the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1183a] (as added by section 423 and as amended by section 551(a) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996) on behalf of such alien.

(2) The income and resources of the spouse (if any) of the person.


(b) Duration of attribution periodSubsection (a) shall apply with respect to an alien until such time as the alien—(1) achieves United States citizenship through naturalization pursuant to chapter 2 of title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.]; or

(2)(A) has worked 40 qualifying quarters of coverage as defined under title II of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.] or can be credited with such qualifying quarters as provided under section 1645 of this title, and (B) in the case of any such qualifying quarter creditable for any period beginning after December 31, 1996, did not receive any Federal means-tested public benefit (as provided under section 1613 of this title) during any such period.



(c) Review of income and resources of alien upon reapplicationWhenever an alien is required to reapply for benefits under any Federal means-tested public benefits program, the applicable agency shall review the income and resources attributed to the alien under subsection (a).


(d) Application(1) If on August 22, 1996, a Federal means-tested public benefits program attributes a sponsor’s income and resources to an alien in determining the alien’s eligibility and the amount of ben</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in determining the eligibility and the amount of benefits of an alien for any Federal means-tested public benefits program (as provided under section 1613 of this title), the income and resources of the alien shall be deemed to include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of attribution period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duration of attribution period Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to an alien until such time as the alien—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of income and resources of alien upon reapplication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of income and resources of alien upon reapplication Whenever an alien is required to reapply for benefits under any Federal means-tested public benefits program, the applicable agency shall review the income and resources attributed to the alien under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indigence exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Indigence exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for battered spouse and child</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule for battered spouse and child</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>