<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1711"><akn:num>1711</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for hiring and training Government personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1711. Authorization of appropriations for hiring and training Government personnel(a) Additional personnel(1) INS inspectorsSubject to the availability of appropriations, during each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2006, the Attorney General shall increase the number of inspectors and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service by the equivalent of at least 200 full-time employees over the number of inspectors and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service authorized by the USA PATRIOT Act.


(2) INS investigative personnelSubject to the availability of appropriations, during each of the fiscal years 2003 through 2006, the Attorney General shall increase the number of investigative and associated support staff of the Immigration and Naturalization Service by the equivalent of at least 200 full-time employees over the number of investigators and associated support staff in the Immigration and Naturalization Service authorized by the USA PATRIOT Act.


(3) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection, including such sums as may be necessary to provide facilities, attorney personnel and support staff, and other resources needed to support the increased number of inspectors, investigative staff, and associated support staff.



(b) Authorization of appropriations for INS staffing(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Justice such sums as may be necessary to provide an increase in the annual rate of basic pay effective October 1, 2002—(A) for all journeyman Border Patrol agents and inspectors who have completed at least one year’s service and are receiving an annual rate of basic pay for positions at GS–9 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 from the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at GS–9 of the General Schedule u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Additional personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for INS staffing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations for INS staffing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations for training There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for consular functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations for consular functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>