<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1715" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1715/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1715/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715"><akn:num>1715</akn:num><akn:heading>Consular and Border Security Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715. Consular and Border Security Programs(a) Separate fundThere is established in the Treasury a separate fund to be known as the “Consular and Border Security Programs” account into which the following fees shall be deposited for the purposes of the consular and border security programs.


(b) to (g) Omitted

(h) Transfer of funds(1) The unobligated balances of amounts available from fees referenced under this section may be transferred to the Consular and Border Security Programs account.

(2) Funds deposited in or transferred to the Consular and Border Security Programs account may be transferred between funds appropriated under the heading “Administration of Foreign Affairs”.

(3) The transfer authorities in this section shall be in addition to any other transfer authority available to the Department of State.


(i) Effective dateThe amendments made by this section shall take effect no later than October 1, 2018, and shall be implemented in a manner that ensures the fees collected, transferred, and used in fiscal year 2019 can be readily tracked.


(Pub. L. 115–31, div. J, title VII, § 7081, May 5, 2017, 131 Stat. 716.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section appears under the heading “Consular and Border Security Programs” in title VII of div. J of Pub. L. 115–31. It was enacted as part of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2017, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2017, and not as part of the Enhanced Border Security and Visa Entry Reform Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.
Section is comprised of section 7081 of title VII of div. J of Pub. L. 115–31. Subsecs. (b) and (c) of section 7081 of Pub. L. 115–31 amended sections 1713 and 1714, respectively, of this title. Subsecs. (d) and (e) of section 7081 amended provisions set out as notes under sections 1153 and 1183a, respectively, of this title. Subsec. (f) of section 7081 amended section 214 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Inte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Separate fund There is established in the Treasury a separate fund to be known as the “Consular and Border Security Programs” account into which the following fees shall be deposited for the purposes of the consular and border security programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (g) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) to (g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transfer of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effective date The amendments made by this section shall take effect no later than October 1, 2018, and shall be implemented in a manner that ensures the fees collected, transferred, and used in fiscal year 2019 can be readily tracked.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>