<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1762" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1762/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1762/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1762"><akn:num>1762</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of institutions and other entities authorized to enroll or sponsor certain nonimmigrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1762. Review of institutions and other entities authorized to enroll or sponsor certain nonimmigrants(a) Periodic review of complianceNot later than two years after May 14, 2002, and every two years thereafter, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall conduct a review of the institutions certified to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title. Each review shall determine whether the institutions are in compliance with—(1) recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title; and

(2) recordkeeping and reporting requirements under section 1372 of this title.


(b) Periodic review of sponsors of exchange visitors(1) Requirement for reviewsNot later than two years after May 14, 2002, and every two years thereafter, the Secretary of State shall conduct a review of the entities designated to sponsor exchange visitor program participants under section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title.


(2) DeterminationsOn the basis of reviews of entities under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine whether the entities are in compliance with—(A) recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant exchange visitor program participants under section 1101(a)(15)(J) of this title; and

(B) recordkeeping and reporting requirements under section 1372 of this title.



(c) Effect of material failure to complyMaterial failure of an institution or other entity to comply with the recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant students or exchange visitor program participants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title, or section 1372 of this title, shall result in the suspension for at least one year or termination, at the election of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, of the institution’s approval to receive such students, or result in the suspension for at least o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Periodic review of compliance Not later than two years after May 14, 2002, and every two years thereafter, the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall conduct a review of the institutions certified to receive nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title. Each review shall determine whether the institutions are in compliance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of sponsors of exchange visitors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic review of sponsors of exchange visitors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of material failure to comply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of material failure to comply Material failure of an institution or other entity to comply with the recordkeeping and reporting requirements to receive nonimmigrant students or exchange visitor program participants under section 1101(a)(15)(F), (M), or (J) of this title, or section 1372 of this title, shall result in the suspension for at least one year or termination, at the election of the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization, of the institution’s approval to receive such students, or result in the suspension for at least one year or termination, at the election of the Secretary of State, of the other entity’s designation to sponsor exchange visitor program participants, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>