<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1805" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1805/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/8/1805/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1805"><akn:num>1805</akn:num><akn:heading>Special immigrant juvenile fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1805. Special immigrant juvenile fee(a) In generalIn addition to any other fee authorized by law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall require the payment of a fee, equal to the amount specified in this section, by any alien, parent, or legal guardian of an alien applying for special immigrant juvenile status under section 1101(a)(27)(J) of this title.


(b) Initial amountFor fiscal year 2025, the amount specified in this section shall be the greater of—(1) $250; or

(2) such amount as the Secretary of Homeland Security may establish, by rule.


(c) Annual adjustments for inflationDuring fiscal year 2026, and during each subsequent fiscal year, the amount specified in this section shall be equal to the sum of—(1) the amount of the fee required under this subsection for the most recently concluded fiscal year; and

(2) the product resulting from the multiplication of the amount referred to in paragraph (1) by the percentage (if any) by which the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers for the month of July preceding the date on which such adjustment takes effect exceeds the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers for the same month of the preceding calendar year, rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10.


(d) Disposition of special immigrant juvenile feesAll of the fees collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury.


(Pub. L. 119–21, title X, § 100005, July 4, 2025, 139 Stat. 368.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In addition to any other fee authorized by law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall require the payment of a fee, equal to the amount specified in this section, by any alien, parent, or legal guardian of an alien applying for special immigrant juvenile status under section 1101(a)(27)(J) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial amount For fiscal year 2025, the amount specified in this section shall be the greater of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual adjustments for inflation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual adjustments for inflation During fiscal year 2026, and during each subsequent fiscal year, the amount specified in this section shall be equal to the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of special immigrant juvenile fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disposition of special immigrant juvenile fees All of the fees collected pursuant to this section shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>