<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1102"><akn:num>1102</akn:num><akn:heading>National Domestic Preparedness Consortium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1102. National Domestic Preparedness Consortium(a) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to establish, operate, and maintain a National Domestic Preparedness Consortium within the Department.


(b) MembersMembers of the National Domestic Preparedness Consortium shall consist of—(1) the Center for Domestic Preparedness;

(2) the National Energetic Materials Research and Testing Center, New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology;

(3) the National Center for Biomedical Research and Training, Louisiana State University;

(4) the National Emergency Response and Rescue Training Center, Texas A&amp;M University;

(5) the National Exercise, Test, and Training Center, Nevada Test Site;

(6) the Transportation Technology Center, Incorporated, in Pueblo, Colorado; and

(7) the National Disaster Preparedness Training Center, University of Hawaii.


(c) DutiesThe National Domestic Preparedness Consortium shall identify, develop, test, and deliver training to State, local, and tribal emergency response providers, provide on-site and mobile training at the performance and management and planning levels, and facilitate the delivery of training by the training partners of the Department.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—(1) for the Center for Domestic Preparedness—(A) $57,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(B) $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;

(C) $63,000,000 for fiscal year 2010; and

(D) $66,000,000 for fiscal year 2011; and


(2) for the National Energetic Materials Research and Testing Center, the National Center for Biomedical Research and Training, the National Emergency Response and Rescue Training Center, the National Exercise, Test, and Training Center, the Transportation Technology Center, Incorporated, and the National Disaster Preparedness Training Center each—(A) $22,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(B) $23,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;

(C) $24,000,000 for fiscal year 2010; and

(D) $25,500,000 for fiscal year 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary is authorized to establish, operate, and maintain a National Domestic Preparedness Consortium within the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Members Members of the National Domestic Preparedness Consortium shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The National Domestic Preparedness Consortium shall identify, develop, test, and deliver training to State, local, and tribal emergency response providers, provide on-site and mobile training at the performance and management and planning levels, and facilitate the delivery of training by the training partners of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings provision From the amounts appropriated pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall ensure that future amounts provided to each of the following entities are not less than the amounts provided to each such entity for participation in the Consortium in fiscal year 2007—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>