<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1104"><akn:num>1104</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity for reports of suspected terrorist activity or suspicious behavior and response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1104. Immunity for reports of suspected terrorist activity or suspicious behavior and response(a) Immunity for reports of suspected terrorist activity or suspicious behavior(1) In generalAny person who, in good faith and based on objectively reasonable suspicion, makes, or causes to be made, a voluntary report of covered activity to an authorized official shall be immune from civil liability under Federal, State, and local law for such report.


(2) False reportsParagraph (1) shall not apply to any report that the person knew to be false or was made with reckless disregard for the truth at the time that person made that report.



(b) Immunity for response(1) In generalAny authorized official who observes, or receives a report of, covered activity and takes reasonable action in good faith to respond to such activity shall have qualified immunity from civil liability for such action, consistent with applicable law in the relevant jurisdiction. An authorized official as defined by subsection (d)(1)(A) not entitled to assert the defense of qualified immunity shall nevertheless be immune from civil liability under Federal, State, and local law if such authorized official takes reasonable action, in good faith, to respond to the reported activity.


(2) Savings clauseNothing in this subsection shall affect the ability of any authorized official to assert any defense, privilege, or immunity that would otherwise be available, and this subsection shall not be construed as affecting any such defense, privilege, or immunity.



(c) Attorney fees and costsAny person or authorized official found to be immune from civil liability under this section shall be entitled to recover from the plaintiff all reasonable costs and attorney fees.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Authorized officialThe term “authorized official” means—(A) any employee or agent of a passenger transportation system or other person with responsibilities relating to the security of such systems;

(B) any o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity for reports of suspected terrorist activity or suspicious behavior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Immunity for reports of suspected terrorist activity or suspicious behavior</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity for response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Immunity for response</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney fees and costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Attorney fees and costs Any person or authorized official found to be immune from civil liability under this section shall be entitled to recover from the plaintiff all reasonable costs and attorney fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section shall take effect on October 1, 2006, and shall apply to all activities and claims occurring on or after such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>