<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1118" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1118/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1118/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1118"><akn:num>1118</akn:num><akn:heading>Biometrics expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1118. Biometrics expansion(a) In generalThe Administrator and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall consult with each other on the deployment of biometric technologies.


(b) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to facilitate or expand the deployment of biometric technologies, or otherwise collect, use, or retain biometrics, not authorized by any provision of or amendment made by the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (Public Law 108–458; 118 Stat. 3638) or the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (Public Law 110–53; 121 Stat. 266).


(c) Report requiredNot later than 270 days after October 5, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, and to any Member of Congress upon the request of that Member, a report that includes specific assessments from the Administrator and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to the following:(1) The operational and security impact of using biometric technology to identify travelers.

(2) The potential effects on privacy of the expansion of the use of biometric technology under paragraph (1), including methods proposed or implemented to mitigate any risks to privacy identified by the Administrator or the Commissioner related to the active or passive collection of biometric data.

(3) Methods to analyze and address any matching performance errors related to race, gender, or age identified by the Administrator with respect to the use of biometric technology, including the deployment of facial recognition technology; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.

(4) With respect to the biometric entry-exit program, the following:(A) Assessments of—(i) the error rates, including the rates of false positives and false negatives, and accuracy of biometric technologies;

(ii) the effects of biometric tec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1118_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall consult with each other on the deployment of biometric technologies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1118_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to facilitate or expand the deployment of biometric technologies, or otherwise collect, use, or retain biometrics, not authorized by any provision of or amendment made by the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (Public Law 108–458; 118 Stat. 3638) or the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (Public Law 110–53; 121 Stat. 266).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1118_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report required Not later than 270 days after October 5, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, and to any Member of Congress upon the request of that Member, a report that includes specific assessments from the Administrator and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1118_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of assessments The Secretary, the Administrator, and the Commissioner shall, if practicable, publish a public version of the assessment required by subsection (c)(2) on the Internet website of the TSA and of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>