<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_113"><akn:num>113</akn:num><akn:heading>Other officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 113. Other officers(a) Deputy Secretary; Under Secretaries(1) In generalExcept as provided under paragraph (2), there are the following officers, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate:(A) A Deputy Secretary of Homeland Security, who shall be the Secretary’s first assistant for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 33 of title 5.

(B) An Under Secretary for Science and Technology.

(C) A Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.

(D) An Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.

(E) A Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services.

(F) An Under Secretary for Management, who shall be first assistant to the Deputy Secretary of Homeland Security for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 33 of title 5.

(G) A Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.

(H) A Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.

(I) Not more than 12 Assistant Secretaries.

(J) A General Counsel, who shall be the chief legal officer of the Department.

(K) An Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans.


(2) Assistant SecretariesIf any of the Assistant Secretaries referred to under paragraph (1)(I) is designated to be the Assistant Secretary for Health Affairs, the Assistant Secretary for Legislative Affairs, or the Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs, that Assistant Secretary shall be appointed by the President without the advice and consent of the Senate.



(b) Inspector GeneralThere shall be in the Department an Office of Inspector General and an Inspector General at the head of such office, as provided in chapter 4 of title 5.


(c) Commandant of the Coast GuardTo assist the Secretary in the performance of the Secretary’s functions, there is a Commandant of the Coast Guard, who shall be appointed as provided in section 44 11 See References in Text note below. of title 14 and who shall report directly to the Secretary. In addition to such duties as may be provided in this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Secretary; Under Secretaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deputy Secretary; Under Secretaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspector General There shall be in the Department an Office of Inspector General and an Inspector General at the head of such office, as provided in chapter 4 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commandant of the Coast Guard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Commandant of the Coast Guard To assist the Secretary in the performance of the Secretary’s functions, there is a Commandant of the Coast Guard, who shall be appointed as provided in section 44 11 See References in Text note below. of title 14 and who shall report directly to the Secretary. In addition to such duties as may be provided in this chapter and as assigned to the Commandant by the Secretary, the duties of the Commandant shall include those required by section 2 1 of title 14.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other officers To assist the Secretary in the performance of the Secretary’s functions, there are the following officers, appointed by the President:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Financial Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chief Financial Officer There shall be in the Department a Chief Financial Officer, as provided in chapter 9 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance of specific functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Performance of specific functions Subject to the provisions of this chapter, every officer of the Department shall perform the functions specified by law for the official’s office or prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>