<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1137" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1137/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1137/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1137"><akn:num>1137</akn:num><akn:heading>Public transportation security training program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1137. Public transportation security training program(a) In generalNot later than 90 days after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall develop and issue detailed interim final regulations, and not later than 1 year after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall develop and issue detailed final regulations, for a public transportation security training program to prepare public transportation employees, including frontline employees, for potential security threats and conditions.


(b) ConsultationThe Secretary shall develop the interim final and final regulations under subsection (a) in consultation with—(1) appropriate law enforcement, fire service, security, and terrorism experts;

(2) representatives of public transportation agencies; and

(3) nonprofit employee labor organizations representing public transportation employees or emergency response personnel.


(c) Program elementsThe interim final and final regulations developed under subsection (a) shall require security training programs to include, at a minimum, elements to address the following:(1) Determination of the seriousness of any occurrence or threat.

(2) Crew and passenger communication and coordination.

(3) Appropriate responses to defend oneself, including using nonlethal defense devices.

(4) Use of personal protective devices and other protective equipment.

(5) Evacuation procedures for passengers and employees, including individuals with disabilities and the elderly.

(6) Training related to behavioral and psychological understanding of, and responses to, terrorist incidents, including the ability to cope with hijacker behavior, and passenger responses.

(7) Live situational training exercises regarding various threat conditions, including tunnel evacuation procedures.

(8) Recognition and reporting of dangerous substances and suspicious packages, persons, and situations.

(9) Understanding security incident procedures, including procedures for communicating with governmental and nongovernmental em</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 90 days after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall develop and issue detailed interim final regulations, and not later than 1 year after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall develop and issue detailed final regulations, for a public transportation security training program to prepare public transportation employees, including frontline employees, for potential security threats and conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation The Secretary shall develop the interim final and final regulations under subsection (a) in consultation with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program elements The interim final and final regulations developed under subsection (a) shall require security training programs to include, at a minimum, elements to address the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Required programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability A public transportation agency that receives a grant award under this subchapter shall be required to develop and implement a security training program pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-term training requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Long-term training requirement Any public transportation agency required to develop a security training program pursuant to this section shall provide routine and ongoing training for employees covered under the program, regardless of whether the public transportation agency receives subsequent grant awards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Training Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) National Training Program The Secretary shall ensure that the training program developed under subsection (a) is a component of the National Training Program established under section 748 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ferry exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Ferry exemption This section shall not apply to any ferry system for which training is required to be conducted pursuant to section 70103 of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report Not later than 2 years after the date of issuance of the final regulation, the Comptroller General shall review implementation of the training program, including interviewing a representative sample of public transportation agencies and employees, and report to the appropriate congressional committees, on the number of reviews conducted and the results. The Comptroller General may submit the report in both classified and redacted formats as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>