<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_115"><akn:num>115</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade and customs revenue functions of the Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 115. Trade and customs revenue functions of the Department(a) Trade and customs revenue functions(1) Designation of appropriate officialThe Secretary shall designate an appropriate senior official in the office of the Secretary who shall—(A) ensure that the trade and customs revenue functions of the Department are coordinated within the Department and with other Federal departments and agencies, and that the impact on legitimate trade is taken into account in any action impacting the functions; and

(B) monitor and report to Congress on the Department’s mandate to ensure that the trade and customs revenue functions of the Department are not diminished, including how spending, operations, and personnel related to these functions have kept pace with the level of trade entering the United States.


(2) Director of Trade PolicyThere shall be a Director of Trade Policy (in this subsection referred to as the “Director”), who shall be subject to the direction and control of the official designated pursuant to paragraph (1). The Director shall—(A) advise the official designated pursuant to paragraph (1) regarding all aspects of Department policies relating to the trade and customs revenue functions of the Department;

(B) coordinate the development of Department-wide policies regarding trade and customs revenue functions and trade facilitation; and

(C) coordinate the trade and customs revenue-related policies of the Department with the policies of other Federal departments and agencies.



(b) Study; report(1) In generalThe Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study evaluating the extent to which the Department of Homeland Security is meeting its obligations under section 212(b) of this title with respect to the maintenance of customs revenue functions.


(2) AnalysisThe study shall include an analysis of—(A) the extent to which the customs revenue functions carried out by the former United States Customs Service have been consolidated with other func</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade and customs revenue functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Trade and customs revenue functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study; report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Study; report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation on trade and customs revenue functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation on trade and customs revenue functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of reorganization of customs revenue functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of reorganization of customs revenue functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>