<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1151" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1151/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1151/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1151"><akn:num>1151</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1151. Definitions
In this subchapter, the following definitions apply:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.


(2) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.


(3) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Homeland Security.


(4) Over-the-road busThe term “over-the-road bus” means a bus characterized by an elevated passenger deck located over a baggage compartment.


(5) Over-the-road bus frontline employeesIn this section,11 So in original. “In this section,” probably should not appear. the term “over-the-road bus frontline employees” means over-the-road bus drivers, security personnel, dispatchers, maintenance and maintenance support personnel, ticket agents, other terminal employees, and other employees of an over-the-road bus operator or terminal owner or operator that the Secretary determines should receive security training under this subchapter.


(6) Railroad frontline employeesIn this section,1 the term “railroad frontline employees” means security personnel, dispatchers, locomotive engineers, conductors, trainmen, other onboard employees, maintenance and maintenance support personnel, bridge tenders, and any other employees of railroad carriers that the Secretary determines should receive security training under this subchapter.


(7) RailroadThe term “railroad” has the meaning that term has in section 20102 of title 49.


(8) Railroad carrierThe term “railroad carrier” has the meaning that term has in section 20102 of title 49.


(9) StateThe term “State” means any one of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Over-the-road bus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Over-the-road bus The term “over-the-road bus” means a bus characterized by an elevated passenger deck located over a baggage compartment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Over-the-road bus frontline employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Over-the-road bus frontline employees In this section,11 So in original. “In this section,” probably should not appear. the term “over-the-road bus frontline employees” means over-the-road bus drivers, security personnel, dispatchers, maintenance and maintenance support personnel, ticket agents, other terminal employees, and other employees of an over-the-road bus operator or terminal owner or operator that the Secretary determines should receive security training under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad frontline employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Railroad frontline employees In this section,1 the term “railroad frontline employees” means security personnel, dispatchers, locomotive engineers, conductors, trainmen, other onboard employees, maintenance and maintenance support personnel, bridge tenders, and any other employees of railroad carriers that the Secretary determines should receive security training under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Railroad The term “railroad” has the meaning that term has in section 20102 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Railroad carrier The term “railroad carrier” has the meaning that term has in section 20102 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) State The term “State” means any one of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terrorism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Terrorism The term “terrorism” has the meaning that term has in section 101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>