<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1162" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1162/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1162/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1162"><akn:num>1162</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad carrier assessments and plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1162. Railroad carrier assessments and plans(a) In generalNot later than 12 months after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall issue regulations that—(1) require each railroad carrier assigned to a high-risk tier under this section to—(A) conduct a vulnerability assessment in accordance with subsections (c) and (d); and

(B) to 11 So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear. prepare, submit to the Secretary for approval, and implement a security plan in accordance with this section that addresses security performance requirements; and


(2) establish standards and guidelines, based on and consistent with the risk assessment and National Strategy for Railroad Transportation Security developed under section 1161 of this title, for developing and implementing the vulnerability assessments and security plans for railroad carriers assigned to high-risk tiers.


(b) Non high-risk programsThe Secretary may establish a security program for railroad carriers not assigned to a high-risk tier, including—(1) guidance for such carriers in conducting vulnerability assessments and preparing and implementing security plans, as determined appropriate by the Secretary; and

(2) a process to review and approve such assessments and plans, as appropriate.


(c) Deadline for submissionNot later than 9 months after the date of issuance of the regulations under subsection (a), the vulnerability assessments and security plans required by such regulations for railroad carriers assigned to a high-risk tier shall be completed and submitted to the Secretary for review and approval.


(d) Vulnerability assessments(1) RequirementsThe Secretary shall provide technical assistance and guidance to railroad carriers in conducting vulnerability assessments under this section and shall require that each vulnerability assessment of a railroad carrier assigned to a high-risk tier under this section, include, as applicable—(A) identification and evaluation of critical railroad carrier assets a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 12 months after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall issue regulations that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non high-risk programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non high-risk programs The Secretary may establish a security program for railroad carriers not assigned to a high-risk tier, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deadline for submission Not later than 9 months after the date of issuance of the regulations under subsection (a), the vulnerability assessments and security plans required by such regulations for railroad carriers assigned to a high-risk tier shall be completed and submitted to the Secretary for review and approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vulnerability assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Vulnerability assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Security plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for review process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deadline for review process Not later than 6 months after receiving the assessments and plans required under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim security measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interim security measures The Secretary may require railroad carriers, during the period before the deadline established under subsection (c), to submit a security plan under subsection (e) to implement any necessary interim security measures essential to providing adequate security of the railroad carrier’s system. An interim plan required under this subsection will be superseded by a plan required under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tier assignment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tier assignment Utilizing the risk assessment and National Strategy for Railroad Transportation Security required under section 1161 of this title, the Secretary shall assign each railroad carrier to a risk-based tier established by the Secretary:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondisclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nondisclosure of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing procedures, protocols and standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Existing procedures, protocols and standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>