<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1170" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1170/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1170/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1170"><akn:num>1170</akn:num><akn:heading>Security background checks of covered individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1170. Security background checks of covered individuals(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Security background checkThe term “security background check” means reviewing, for the purpose of identifying individuals who may pose a threat to transportation security or national security, or of terrorism—(A) relevant criminal history databases;

(B) in the case of an alien (as defined in the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(3)),11 So in original. Another closing parenthesis probably should precede the comma. the relevant databases to determine the status of the alien under the immigration laws of the United States; and

(C) other relevant information or databases, as determined by the Secretary.


(2) Covered individualThe term “covered individual” means an employee of a railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier.



(b) Guidance(1) Any guidance, recommendations, suggested action items, or any other widely disseminated voluntary action items issued by the Secretary to a railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier relating to performing a security background check of a covered individual shall contain recommendations on the appropriate scope and application of such a security background check, including the time period covered, the types of disqualifying offenses, and a redress process for adversely impacted covered individuals consistent with subsections (c) and (d) of this section.

(2) Within 60 days after August 3, 2007, any guidance, recommendations, suggested action items, or any other widely disseminated voluntary action item issued by the Secretary prior to August 3, 2007, to a railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier relating to performing a security background check of a covered individual shall be updated in compliance with paragraph (1).

(3) If a railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier perfor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements If the Secretary issues a rule, regulation, or directive requiring a railroad carrier or contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier to perform a security background check of a covered individual, then the Secretary shall prohibit the railroad carrier or contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier from making an adverse employment decision, including removal or suspension of the covered individual, due to such rule, regulation, or directive with respect to a covered individual unless the railroad carrier or contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier determines that the covered individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redress process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Redress process If the Secretary issues a rule, regulation, or directive requiring a railroad carrier or contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier to perform a security background check of a covered individual, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>False statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) False statements A railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier may not knowingly misrepresent to an employee or other relevant person, including an arbiter involved in a labor arbitration, the scope, application, or meaning of any rules, regulations, directives, or guidance issued by the Secretary related to security background check requirements for covered individuals when conducting a security background check. Not later than 1 year after August 3, 2007, the Secretary shall issue a regulation that prohibits a railroad carrier or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier from knowingly misrepresenting to an employee or other relevant person, including an arbiter involved in a labor arbitration, the scope, application, or meaning of any rules, regulations, directives, or guidance issued by the Secretary related to security background check requirements for covered individuals when conducting a security background check.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rights and responsibilities Nothing in this section shall be construed to abridge a railroad carrier’s or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier’s rights or responsibilities to make adverse employment decisions permitted by other Federal, State, or local laws. Nothing in the section shall be construed to abridge rights and responsibilities of covered individuals, a railroad carrier, or a contractor or subcontractor of a railroad carrier, under any other Federal, State, or local laws or under any collective bargaining agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No preemption of Federal or State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No preemption of Federal or State law Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt a Federal, State, or local law that requires criminal history background checks, immigration status checks, or other background checks, of covered individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1170_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Statutory construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the process for review established under section 70105(c) of title 46, including regulations issued pursuant to such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>