<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1182" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1182/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1182/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1182"><akn:num>1182</akn:num><akn:heading>Over-the-road bus security assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1182. Over-the-road bus security assistance(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program for making grants to eligible private operators providing transportation by an over-the-road bus for security improvements described in subsection (b).


(b) Uses of fundsA recipient of a grant received under subsection (a) shall use the grant funds for one or more of the following:(1) Constructing and modifying terminals, garages, and facilities, including terminals and other over-the-road bus facilities owned by State or local governments, to increase their security.

(2) Modifying over-the-road buses to increase their security.

(3) Protecting or isolating the driver of an over-the-road bus.

(4) Acquiring, upgrading, installing, or operating equipment, software, or accessorial services for collection, storage, or exchange of passenger and driver information through ticketing systems or other means and for information links with government agencies, for security purposes.

(5) Installing cameras and video surveillance equipment on over-the-road buses and at terminals, garages, and over-the-road bus facilities.

(6) Establishing and improving an emergency communications system linking drivers and over-the-road buses to the recipient’s operations center or linking the operations center to law enforcement and emergency personnel.

(7) Implementing and operating passenger screening programs for weapons and explosives.

(8) Public awareness campaigns for enhanced over-the-road bus security.

(9) Operating and capital costs associated with over-the-road bus security awareness, preparedness, and response training, including training under section 1184 of this title and training developed by institutions of higher education and by nonprofit employee labor organizations, for over-the-road bus employees, including frontline employees.

(10) Chemical, biological, radiological, or explosive detection, including canine patrols for such detection.

(11) Overtime reimbursement, in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a program for making grants to eligible private operators providing transportation by an over-the-road bus for security improvements described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses of funds A recipient of a grant received under subsection (a) shall use the grant funds for one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Due consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Due consideration In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize grant funding based on security risks to bus passengers and the ability of a project to reduce, or enhance response to, that risk, and shall not penalize private operators of over-the-road buses that have taken measures to enhance over-the-road bus transportation security prior to September 11, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Homeland Security responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Department of Homeland Security responsibilities In carrying out the responsibilities under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of grants Not later than 90 days after August 3, 2007, the Secretary and the Secretary of Transportation shall determine the most effective and efficient way to distribute grant funds to the recipients of grants determined by the Secretary under subsection (a). Subject to the determination made by the Secretaries, the Secretary may transfer funds to the Secretary of Transportation for the purposes of disbursing funds to the grant recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subject to certain terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subject to certain terms and conditions Except as otherwise specifically provided in this section, a grant made under this section shall be subject to the terms and conditions applicable to subrecipients who provide over-the-road bus transportation under section 5311(f) of title 49 and such other terms and conditions as are determined necessary by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on uses of funds A grant made under this section may not be used to make any State or local government cost-sharing contribution under any other Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual reports Each recipient of a grant under this section shall report annually to the Secretary and on the use of such grant funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1182_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Consultation In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with over-the-road bus operators and nonprofit employee labor organizations representing over-the-road bus employees, public safety and law enforcement officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>