<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_124a"><akn:num>124a</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeland security information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 124a. Homeland security information sharing(a) Information sharingConsistent with section 485 of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, shall integrate the information and standardize the format of the products of the intelligence components of the Department containing homeland security information, terrorism information, weapons of mass destruction information, or national intelligence (as defined in section 3003(5) of title 50) except for any internal security protocols or personnel information of such intelligence components, or other administrative processes that are administered by any chief security officer of the Department.


(b) Information sharing and knowledge management officersFor each intelligence component of the Department, the Secretary shall designate an information sharing and knowledge management officer who shall report to the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis regarding coordinating the different systems used in the Department to gather and disseminate homeland security information or national intelligence (as defined in section 3003(5) of title 50).


(c) State, local, and private-sector sources of information(1) Establishment of business processesThe Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis or the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, as appropriate, shall—(A) establish Department-wide procedures for the review and analysis of information provided by State, local, and tribal governments and the private sector;

(B) as appropriate, integrate such information into the information gathered by the Department and other departments and agencies of the Federal Government; and

(C) make available such information, as appropriate, within the Department and to other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.


(2) FeedbackThe Secretary shall develop mechanisms to provide feedback regarding the analysis and utility </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information sharing Consistent with section 485 of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis, shall integrate the information and standardize the format of the products of the intelligence components of the Department containing homeland security information, terrorism information, weapons of mass destruction information, or national intelligence (as defined in section 3003(5) of title 50) except for any internal security protocols or personnel information of such intelligence components, or other administrative processes that are administered by any chief security officer of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing and knowledge management officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information sharing and knowledge management officers For each intelligence component of the Department, the Secretary shall designate an information sharing and knowledge management officer who shall report to the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis regarding coordinating the different systems used in the Department to gather and disseminate homeland security information or national intelligence (as defined in section 3003(5) of title 50).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State, local, and private-sector sources of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State, local, and private-sector sources of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and evaluation of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Training and evaluation of employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>