<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_124j"><akn:num>124j</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Policing Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 124j. Rural Policing Institute(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a Rural Policing Institute, which shall be administered by the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, to target training to law enforcement agencies and other emergency response providers located in rural areas. The Secretary, through the Rural Policing Institute, shall—(1) evaluate the needs of law enforcement agencies and other emergency response providers in rural areas;

(2) develop expert training programs designed to address the needs of law enforcement agencies and other emergency response providers in rural areas as identified in the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1), including training programs about intelligence-led policing and protections for privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties;

(3) provide the training programs developed under paragraph (2) to law enforcement agencies and other emergency response providers in rural areas; and

(4) conduct outreach efforts to ensure that local and tribal governments in rural areas are aware of the training programs developed under paragraph (2) so they can avail themselves of such programs.


(b) CurriculaThe training at the Rural Policing Institute established under subsection (a) shall—(1) be configured in a manner so as not to duplicate or displace any law enforcement or emergency response program of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center or a local or tribal government entity in existence on August 3, 2007; and

(2) to the maximum extent practicable, be delivered in a cost-effective manner at facilities of the Department, on closed military installations with adequate training facilities, or at facilities operated by the participants.


(c) DefinitionIn this section, the term “rural” means an area that is not located in a metropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section (including for co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a Rural Policing Institute, which shall be administered by the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center, to target training to law enforcement agencies and other emergency response providers located in rural areas. The Secretary, through the Rural Policing Institute, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Curricula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Curricula The training at the Rural Policing Institute established under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definition In this section, the term “rural” means an area that is not located in a metropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section (including for contracts, staff, and equipment)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>