<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_124k"><akn:num>124k</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Threat Assessment and Coordination Group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 124k. Interagency Threat Assessment and Coordination Group(a) In generalTo improve the sharing of information within the scope of the information sharing environment established under section 485 of this title with State, local, tribal, and private sector officials, the Director of National Intelligence, through the program manager for the information sharing environment, in coordination with the Secretary, shall coordinate and oversee the creation of an Interagency Threat Assessment and Coordination Group (referred to in this section as the “ITACG”).


(b) Composition of ITACGThe ITACG shall consist of—(1) an ITACG Advisory Council to set policy and develop processes for the integration, analysis, and dissemination of federally-coordinated information within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, and weapons of mass destruction information; and

(2) an ITACG Detail comprised of State, local, and tribal homeland security and law enforcement officers and intelligence analysts detailed to work in the National Counterterrorism Center with Federal intelligence analysts for the purpose of integrating, analyzing, and assisting in the dissemination of federally-coordinated information within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, and weapons of mass destruction information, through appropriate channels identified by the ITACG Advisory Council.


(c) Responsibilities of SecretaryThe Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, in coordination with the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center and the ITACG Advisory Council, shall—(1) create policies and standards for the creation of information products derived from information within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, and weapons of mass destruction information, that are suitable for disseminat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To improve the sharing of information within the scope of the information sharing environment established under section 485 of this title with State, local, tribal, and private sector officials, the Director of National Intelligence, through the program manager for the information sharing environment, in coordination with the Secretary, shall coordinate and oversee the creation of an Interagency Threat Assessment and Coordination Group (referred to in this section as the “ITACG”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of ITACG</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition of ITACG The ITACG shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities of Secretary The Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, in coordination with the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center and the ITACG Advisory Council, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Membership The Secretary, or the Secretary’s designee, shall serve as the chair of the ITACG Advisory Council, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Criteria The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, the Attorney General, and the program manager of the information sharing environment established under section 485 of this title, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the ITACG or any subsidiary groups thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2012 to carry out this section, including to obtain security clearances for the State, local, and tribal participants in the ITACG.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>