<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/124n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_124n"><akn:num>124n</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of certain facilities and assets from unmanned aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 124n. Protection of certain facilities and assets from unmanned aircraft(a) AuthorityNotwithstanding section 46502 of title 49 or sections 32, 1030, 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, the Secretary and the Attorney General may, for their respective Departments, take, and may authorize personnel with assigned duties that include the security or protection of people, facilities, or assets, to take such actions as are described in subsection (b)(1) that are necessary to mitigate a credible threat (as defined by the Secretary or the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation) that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.


(b) Actions described(1) In generalThe actions authorized in subsection (a) are the following:(A) During the operation of the unmanned aircraft system, detect, identify, monitor, and track the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.

(B) Warn the operator of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, including by passive or active, and direct or indirect physical, electronic, radio, and electromagnetic means.

(C) Disrupt control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by disabling the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft by intercepting, interfering, or causing interference with wire, oral, electronic, or radio communications used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.

(D) Seize or exercise control of the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.

(E) Seize or otherwise confiscate the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.

(F) Use reasonable force, if necessary, to disable, damage, or destroy the unmanned aircraft system o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49 or sections 32, 1030, 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, the Secretary and the Attorney General may, for their respective Departments, take, and may authorize personnel with assigned duties that include the security or protection of people, facilities, or assets, to take such actions as are described in subsection (b)(1) that are necessary to mitigate a credible threat (as defined by the Secretary or the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation) that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Actions described</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Forfeiture Any unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft described in subsection (a) that is seized by the Secretary or the Attorney General is subject to forfeiture to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations and guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Privacy protection The regulations or guidance issued to carry out actions authorized under subsection (b) by each Secretary or the Attorney General, as the case may be, shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Budget The Secretary and the Attorney General shall submit to Congress, as a part of the homeland security or justice budget materials for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2019, a consolidated funding display that identifies the funding source for the actions described in subsection (b)(1) within the Department of Homeland Security or the Department of Justice. The funding display shall be in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual briefings and notifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Semiannual briefings and notifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination The authority to carry out this section with respect to a covered facility or asset specified in subsection (k)(3) shall terminate on September 30, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124n_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Scope of authority Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide the Secretary or the Attorney General with additional authorities beyond those described in subsections (a) and (k)(3)(C)(iii).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>