<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/126" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/126/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/126/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_126"><akn:num>126</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Homeland Security data framework</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 126. Department of Homeland Security data framework(a) In general(1) DevelopmentThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop a data framework to integrate existing Department of Homeland Security datasets and systems, as appropriate, for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties policies and protections.


(2) RequirementsIn developing the framework required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure, in accordance with all applicable statutory and regulatory requirements, the following information is included:(A) All information acquired, held, or obtained by an office or component of the Department of Homeland Security that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, including homeland security information, terrorism information, weapons of mass destruction information, and national intelligence.

(B) Any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.



(b) Data framework access(1) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the data framework required under this section is accessible to employees of the Department of Homeland Security who the Secretary determines—(A) have an appropriate security clearance;

(B) are assigned to perform a function that requires access to information in such framework; and

(C) are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.


(2) GuidanceThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall—(A) issue guidance for Department of Homeland Security employees authorized to access and contribute to the data framework pursuant to paragraph (1); and

(B) ensure that such guidance enforces a duty to share between offices and components of the Department when accessing or contributing to such framework for mission needs.


(3) EfficiencyThe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data framework access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data framework access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of information The Secretary of Homeland Security may exclude information from the data framework required under this section if the Secretary determines inclusion of such information may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Safeguards The Secretary of Homeland Security shall incorporate into the data framework required under this section systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information included in such framework. Such capabilities shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deadline for implementation Not later than 2 years after December 19, 2018, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure the data framework required under this section has the ability to include appropriate information in existence within the Department of Homeland Security to meet the critical mission operations of the Department of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_126_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>