<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/146" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/146/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/146/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_146"><akn:num>146</akn:num><akn:heading>Cybersecurity workforce assessment and strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 146. Cybersecurity workforce assessment and strategy(a) Workforce assessment(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 18, 2014, and annually thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary shall assess the cybersecurity workforce of the Department.


(2) ContentsThe assessment required under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum—(A) an assessment of the readiness and capacity of the workforce of the Department to meet its cybersecurity mission;

(B) information on where cybersecurity workforce positions are located within the Department;

(C) information on which cybersecurity workforce positions are—(i) performed by—(I) permanent full-time equivalent employees of the Department, including, to the greatest extent practicable, demographic information about such employees;

(II) independent contractors; and

(III) individuals employed by other Federal agencies, including the National Security Agency; or


(ii) vacant; and


(D) information on—(i) the percentage of individuals within each Cybersecurity Category and Specialty Area who received essential training to perform their jobs; and

(ii) in cases in which such essential training was not received, what challenges, if any, were encountered with respect to the provision of such essential training.




(b) Workforce strategy(1) In generalThe Secretary shall—(A) not later than 1 year after December 18, 2014, develop a comprehensive workforce strategy to enhance the readiness, capacity, training, recruitment, and retention of the cybersecurity workforce of the Department; and

(B) maintain and, as necessary, update the comprehensive workforce strategy developed under subparagraph (A).


(2) ContentsThe comprehensive workforce strategy developed under paragraph (1) shall include a description of—(A) a multi-phased recruitment plan, including with respect to experienced professionals, members of disadvantaged or underserved communities, the unemployed, and veterans;

(B) a 5-year implementation plan;

(C) a 10-yea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Workforce assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Workforce assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Workforce strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Workforce strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Updates The Secretary submit 11 So in original. to the appropriate congressional committees annual updates on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>