<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1506"><akn:num>1506</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight of government activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1506. Oversight of government activities(a) Report on implementation(1) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 18, 2015, the heads of the appropriate Federal entities shall jointly submit to Congress a detailed report concerning the implementation of this subchapter.


(2) ContentsThe report required by paragraph (1) may include such recommendations as the heads of the appropriate Federal entities may have for improvements or modifications to the authorities, policies, procedures, and guidelines under this subchapter and shall include the following:(A) An evaluation of the effectiveness of real-time information sharing through the capability and process developed under section 1504(c) of this title, including any impediments to such real-time sharing.

(B) An assessment of whether cyber threat indicators or defensive measures have been properly classified and an accounting of the number of security clearances authorized by the Federal Government for the purpose of sharing cyber threat indicators or defensive measures with the private sector.

(C) The number of cyber threat indicators or defensive measures received through the capability and process developed under section 1504(c) of this title.

(D) A list of Federal entities that have received cyber threat indicators or defensive measures under this subchapter.



(b) Biennial report on compliance(1) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 18, 2015 and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the inspectors general of the appropriate Federal entities, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community and the Council of Inspectors General on Financial Oversight, shall jointly submit to Congress an interagency report on the actions of the executive branch of the Federal Government to carry out this subchapter during the most recent 2-year period.


(2) ContentsEach report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the foll</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report on implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report on compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Biennial report on compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent report on removal of personal information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Independent report on removal of personal information Not later than 3 years after December 18, 2015, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the actions taken by the Federal Government to remove personal information from cyber threat indicators or defensive measures pursuant to this subchapter. Such report shall include an assessment of the sufficiency of the policies, procedures, and guidelines established under this subchapter in addressing concerns relating to privacy and civil liberties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Form of reports Each report required under this section shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public availability of reports The unclassified portions of the reports required under this section shall be made available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>