<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1507"><akn:num>1507</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1507. Construction and preemption(a) Otherwise lawful disclosuresNothing in this subchapter shall be construed—(1) to limit or prohibit otherwise lawful disclosures of communications, records, or other information, including reporting of known or suspected criminal activity, by a non-Federal entity to any other non-Federal entity or the Federal Government under this subchapter; or

(2) to limit or prohibit otherwise lawful use of such disclosures by any Federal entity, even when such otherwise lawful disclosures duplicate or replicate disclosures made under this subchapter.


(b) Whistle blower protectionsNothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prohibit or limit the disclosure of information protected under section 2302(b)(8) of title 5 (governing disclosures of illegality, waste, fraud, abuse, or public health or safety threats), section 7211 of title 5 (governing disclosures to Congress), section 1034 of title 10 (governing disclosure to Congress by members of the military), section 3234 of title 50 (governing disclosure by employees of elements of the intelligence community), or any similar provision of Federal or State law.


(c) Protection of sources and methodsNothing in this subchapter shall be construed—(1) as creating any immunity against, or otherwise affecting, any action brought by the Federal Government, or any agency or department thereof, to enforce any law, executive order, or procedure governing the appropriate handling, disclosure, or use of classified information;

(2) to affect the conduct of authorized law enforcement or intelligence activities; or

(3) to modify the authority of a department or agency of the Federal Government to protect classified information and sources and methods and the national security of the United States.


(d) Relationship to other lawsNothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect any requirement under any other provision of law for a non-Federal entity to provide information to the Federal Govern</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Otherwise lawful disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Otherwise lawful disclosures Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Whistle blower protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Whistle blower protections Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prohibit or limit the disclosure of information protected under section 2302(b)(8) of title 5 (governing disclosures of illegality, waste, fraud, abuse, or public health or safety threats), section 7211 of title 5 (governing disclosures to Congress), section 1034 of title 10 (governing disclosure to Congress by members of the military), section 3234 of title 50 (governing disclosure by employees of elements of the intelligence community), or any similar provision of Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of sources and methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection of sources and methods Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to other laws Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect any requirement under any other provision of law for a non-Federal entity to provide information to the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited conduct Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to permit price-fixing, allocating a market between competitors, monopolizing or attempting to monopolize a market, boycotting, or exchanges of price or cost information, customer lists, or information regarding future competitive planning.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing relationships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information sharing relationships Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of contractual obligations and rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preservation of contractual obligations and rights Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Anti-tasking restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Anti-tasking restriction Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to permit a Federal entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>No liability for non-participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No liability for non-participation Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to subject any entity to liability for choosing not to engage in the voluntary activities authorized in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use and retention of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Use and retention of information Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize, or to modify any existing authority of, a department or agency of the Federal Government to retain or use any information shared under this subchapter for any use other than permitted in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>