<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1521" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1521/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/1521/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1521"><akn:num>1521</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1521. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) AgencyThe term “agency” has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44.


(2) Agency information systemThe term “agency information system” has the meaning given the term in section 660 of this title.


(3) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.


(4) Cybersecurity risk; information systemThe terms “cybersecurity risk” and “information system” have the meanings given those terms in section 650 of this title.


(5) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.


(6) Intelligence communityThe term “intelligence community” has the meaning given the term in section 3003(4) of title 50.


(7) National security systemThe term “national security system” has the meaning given the term in section 11103 of title 40.


(8) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.


(Pub. L. 114–113, div. N, title II, § 222, Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 2963; Pub. L. 115–278, § 2(h)(1)(D), Nov. 16, 2018, 132 Stat. 4182; Pub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7143(d)(1)(A), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3663.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle B (§§ 221–229) of title II of div. N of Pub. L. 114–113, which is classified principally to this subchapter. For complete classification of subtitle B to the Code, see Tables.

Amendments2022—Par. (4). Pub. L. 117–263 substituted “section 650 of this title” for “section 659 of this title”.
2018—Par. (2). Pub. L. 115–278, § 2(h)(1)(D)(i), substituted “section 660 of this title” for “section 149 of this title, as added by section 223(a)(4) of this division”.
Par. (4). Pub. L. 115–278, § 2(h)(1)(D)(ii), substituted “section 659 of this title” for “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agency The term “agency” has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency information system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agency information system The term “agency information system” has the meaning given the term in section 660 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cybersecurity risk; information system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Cybersecurity risk; information system The terms “cybersecurity risk” and “information system” have the meanings given those terms in section 650 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Intelligence community The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given the term in section 3003(4) of title 50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>National security system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) National security system The term “national security system” has the meaning given the term in section 11103 of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>