<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_164"><akn:num>164</akn:num><akn:heading>Abolishment of Office of Science and Technology of National Institute of Justice; transfer of functi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 164. Abolishment of Office of Science and Technology of National Institute of Justice; transfer of functions(a) Authority to transfer functionsThe Attorney General may transfer to the Office any other program or activity of the Department of Justice that the Attorney General, in consultation with the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, determines to be consistent with the mission of the Office.


(b) Transfer of personnel and assetsWith respect to any function, power, or duty, or any program or activity, that is established in the Office, those employees and assets of the element of the Department of Justice from which the transfer is made that the Attorney General determines are needed to perform that function, power, or duty, or for that program or activity, as the case may be, shall be transferred to the Office: Provided, That any such transfer shall be carried out in accordance with section 605 of Public Law 107–77.


(c) Report on implementationNot later than 1 year after November 25, 2002, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of this subchapter. The report shall—(1) provide an accounting of the amounts and sources of funding available to the Office to carry out its mission under existing authorizations and appropriations, and set forth the future funding needs of the Office; and

(2) include such other information and recommendations as the Attorney General considers appropriate.


(Pub. L. 107–296, title II, § 234, Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2161; Pub. L. 108–7, div. L, § 103(2), Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 529.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 605 of Public Law 107–77, referred to in subsec. (b), is section 605 of Pub. L. 107–77, title VI, Nov. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 798, which is not classified to the Code.
This subchapter, referred to in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to transfer functions The Attorney General may transfer to the Office any other program or activity of the Department of Justice that the Attorney General, in consultation with the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, determines to be consistent with the mission of the Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of personnel and assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of personnel and assets With respect to any function, power, or duty, or any program or activity, that is established in the Office, those employees and assets of the element of the Department of Justice from which the transfer is made that the Attorney General determines are needed to perform that function, power, or duty, or for that program or activity, as the case may be, shall be transferred to the Office: Provided, That any such transfer shall be carried out in accordance with section 605 of Public Law 107–77.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on implementation Not later than 1 year after November 25, 2002, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of this subchapter. The report shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>