<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/186" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/186/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/186/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_186"><akn:num>186</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 186. Miscellaneous provisions(a) ClassificationTo the greatest extent practicable, research conducted or supported by the Department shall be unclassified.


(b) ConstructionNothing in this subchapter shall be construed to preclude any Under Secretary of the Department from carrying out research, development, demonstration, or deployment activities, as long as such activities are coordinated through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology.


(c) RegulationsThe Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, may issue necessary regulations with respect to research, development, demonstration, testing, and evaluation activities of the Department, including the conducting, funding, and reviewing of such activities.


(d) Notification of Presidential life sciences designationsNot later than 60 days before effecting any transfer of Department of Energy life sciences activities pursuant to section 183(1)(D) of this title, the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed transfer and shall include the reasons for the transfer and a description of the effect of the transfer on the activities of the Department of Energy.


(Pub. L. 107–296, title III, § 306, Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2168.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_186_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Classification To the greatest extent practicable, research conducted or supported by the Department shall be unclassified.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_186_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to preclude any Under Secretary of the Department from carrying out research, development, demonstration, or deployment activities, as long as such activities are coordinated through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_186_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, may issue necessary regulations with respect to research, development, demonstration, testing, and evaluation activities of the Department, including the conducting, funding, and reviewing of such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_186_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Presidential life sciences designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of Presidential life sciences designations Not later than 60 days before effecting any transfer of Department of Energy life sciences activities pursuant to section 183(1)(D) of this title, the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed transfer and shall include the reasons for the transfer and a description of the effect of the transfer on the activities of the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>