<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_195c"><akn:num>195c</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting antiterrorism through international cooperation program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 195c. Promoting antiterrorism through international cooperation program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director selected under subsection (b)(2).


(2) International cooperative activityThe term “international cooperative activity” includes—(A) coordinated research projects, joint research projects, or joint ventures;

(B) joint studies or technical demonstrations;

(C) coordinated field exercises, scientific seminars, conferences, symposia, and workshops;

(D) training of scientists and engineers;

(E) visits and exchanges of scientists, engineers, or other appropriate personnel;

(F) exchanges or sharing of scientific and technological information; and

(G) joint use of laboratory facilities and equipment.



(b) Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office(1) EstablishmentThe Under Secretary shall establish the Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office.


(2) DirectorThe Office shall be headed by a Director, who—(A) shall be selected, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for International Affairs, by and shall report to the Under Secretary; and

(B) may be an officer of the Department serving in another position.


(3) Responsibilities(A) Development of mechanismsThe Director shall be responsible for developing, in coordination with the Department of State and, as appropriate, the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, and other Federal agencies, understandings and agreements to allow and to support international cooperative activity in support of homeland security.


(B) PrioritiesThe Director shall be responsible for developing, in coordination with the Office of International Affairs and other Federal agencies, strategic priorities for international cooperative activity for the Department in support of homeland security.


(C) ActivitiesThe Director shall facilitate the planning, development, and implementation of internat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matching funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign reimbursements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Foreign reimbursements If the Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office participates in an international cooperative activity with a foreign partner on a cost-sharing basis, any reimbursements or contributions received from that foreign partner to meet its share of the project may be credited to appropriate current appropriations accounts of the Directorate of Science and Technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress on international cooperative activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report to Congress on international cooperative activities Not later than one year after August 3, 2007, and every 5 years thereafter, the Under Secretary, acting through the Director, shall submit to Congress a report containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal and zoonotic diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Animal and zoonotic diseases As part of the international cooperative activities authorized in this section, the Under Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office, the Department of State, and appropriate officials of the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Defense, and the Department of Health and Human Services, may enter into cooperative activities with foreign countries, including African nations, to strengthen American preparedness against foreign animal and zoonotic diseases overseas that could harm the Nation’s agricultural and public health sectors if they were to reach the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cybersecurity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cybersecurity As part of the international cooperative activities authorized in this section, the Under Secretary, in coordination with the Department of State and appropriate Federal officials, may enter into cooperative research activities with Israel to strengthen preparedness against cyber threats and enhance capabilities in cybersecurity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction; authorities of the Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Construction; authorities of the Secretary of State Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or affect the following provisions of law:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>