<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_195e"><akn:num>195e</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency in research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 195e. Transparency in research and development(a) Requirement to list research and development programs(1) In generalThe Secretary shall maintain a detailed list of the following:(A) Each classified and unclassified research and development project, and all appropriate details for each such project, including the component of the Department responsible for each such project.

(B) Each task order for a Federally Funded Research and Development Center not associated with a research and development project.

(C) Each task order for a University-based center of excellence not associated with a research and development project.

(D) The indicators developed and tracked by the Under Secretary for Science and Technology with respect to transitioned projects pursuant to subsection (c).


(2) Exception for certain completed projectsParagraph (1) shall not apply to a project completed or otherwise terminated before December 23, 2016.


(3) UpdatesThe list required under paragraph (1) shall be updated as frequently as possible, but not less frequently than once per quarter.


(4) Research and development definedFor purposes of the list required under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide a definition for the term “research and development”.



(b) Requirement to report to Congress on all projectsNot later than January 1, 2017, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a classified and unclassified report, as applicable, that lists each ongoing classified and unclassified project at the Department, including all appropriate details of each such project.


(c) Indicators of success of transitioned projects(1) In generalFor each project that has been transitioned to practice from research and development, the Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall develop and track indicators to demonstrate the uptake of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to list research and development programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement to list research and development programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to report to Congress on all projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement to report to Congress on all projects Not later than January 1, 2017, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a classified and unclassified report, as applicable, that lists each ongoing classified and unclassified project at the Department, including all appropriate details of each such project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indicators of success of transitioned projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indicators of success of transitioned projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation Nothing in this section overrides or otherwise affects the requirements specified in section 468 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>