<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/195f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_195f"><akn:num>195f</akn:num><akn:heading>EMP and GMD mitigation research and development and threat assessment, response, and recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 195f. EMP and GMD mitigation research and development and threat assessment, response, and recovery(a) In generalIn furtherance of domestic preparedness and response, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in consultation with other relevant executive agencies, relevant State, local, and tribal governments, and relevant owners and operators of critical infrastructure, shall, to the extent practicable, conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of threats of EMP and GMD.


(b) ScopeThe scope of the research and development under subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) An objective scientific analysis—(A) evaluating the risks to critical infrastructure from a range of threats of EMP and GMD; and

(B) which shall—(i) be conducted in conjunction with the Office of Intelligence and Analysis; and

(ii) include a review and comparison of the range of threats and hazards facing critical infrastructure of the electrical grid.



(2) Determination of the critical utilities and national security assets and infrastructure that are at risk from threats of EMP and GMD.

(3) An evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attack, which shall include a review of the feasibility of rapidly isolating one or more portions of the electrical grid from the main electrical grid.

(4) An analysis of technology options that are available to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to threats of EMP and GMD, including an analysis of neutral current blocking devices that may protect high-voltage transmission lines.

(5) The restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption from various threats of EMP and GMD, as informed by the objective scientific analysis conducted under p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In furtherance of domestic preparedness and response, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in consultation with other relevant executive agencies, relevant State, local, and tribal governments, and relevant owners and operators of critical infrastructure, shall, to the extent practicable, conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of threats of EMP and GMD.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope The scope of the research and development under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption from disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Threat assessment, response, and recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Threat assessment, response, and recovery</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construe— 11 So in original. Probably should be “construed—”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>