<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_218"><akn:num>218</akn:num><akn:heading>Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 218. Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Cards(a) In generalThe Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection is authorized to issue an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Card (referred to in this section as an “ABT Card”) to any individual described in subsection (b).


(b) Card issuanceAn individual described in this subsection is an individual who—(1) is a citizen of the United States;

(2) has been approved and is in good standing in an existing international trusted traveler program of the Department; and

(3) is—(A) engaged in business in the Asia-Pacific region, as determined by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection; or

(B) a United States Government official actively engaged in Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation business, as determined by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.



(c) Integration with existing travel programsThe Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall integrate application procedures for, and issuance, renewal, and revocation of, ABT Cards with existing international trusted traveler programs of the Department.


(d) Cooperation with private entities and nongovernmental organizationsIn carrying out this section, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may consult with appropriate private sector entities and nongovernmental organizations, including academic institutions.


(e) Fee(1) In generalThe Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall—(A) prescribe and collect a fee for the issuance and renewal of ABT Cards; and

(B) adjust such fee to the extent the Commissioner determines necessary to comply with paragraph (2).


(2) LimitationThe Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall ensure that the total amount of the fees collected under paragraph (1) during any fiscal year is sufficient to offset the direct and indirect costs associated with carrying out this section during such fiscal year, including the costs assoc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection is authorized to issue an Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Business Travel Card (referred to in this section as an “ABT Card”) to any individual described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Card issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Card issuance An individual described in this subsection is an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration with existing travel programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Integration with existing travel programs The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall integrate application procedures for, and issuance, renewal, and revocation of, ABT Cards with existing international trusted traveler programs of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with private entities and nongovernmental organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperation with private entities and nongovernmental organizations In carrying out this section, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may consult with appropriate private sector entities and nongovernmental organizations, including academic institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate not later than 60 days after the expenditures of funds to operate and provide ABT Card services beyond the amounts collected under subsection (e)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trusted traveler program defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Trusted traveler program defined In this section, the term “trusted traveler program” means a voluntary program of the Department that allows U.S. Customs and Border Protection to expedite clearance of pre-approved, low-risk travelers arriving in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>