<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231"><akn:num>231</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain agricultural inspection functions of the Department of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231. Transfer of certain agricultural inspection functions of the Department of Agriculture(a) Transfer of agricultural import and entry inspection functionsThere shall be transferred to the Secretary the functions of the Secretary of Agriculture relating to agricultural import and entry inspection activities under the laws specified in subsection (b).


(b) Covered animal and plant protection lawsThe laws referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) The Act commonly known as the Virus-Serum-Toxin Act (the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry” in the Act of March 4, 1913; 21 U.S.C. 151 et seq.).

(2) Section 1 of the Act of August 31, 1922 (commonly known as the Honeybee Act; 7 U.S.C. 281).

(3) Title III of the Federal Seed Act (7 U.S.C. 1581 et seq.).

(4) The Plant Protection Act (7 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.).

(5) The Animal Health Protection Act (subtitle E of title X of Public Law 107–171; 7 U.S.C. 8301 et seq.).

(6) The Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (16 U.S.C. 3371 et seq.).

(7) Section 11 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1540).


(c) Exclusion of quarantine activitiesFor purposes of this section, the term “functions” does not include any quarantine activities carried out under the laws specified in subsection (b).


(d) Effect of transfer(1) Compliance with Department of Agriculture regulationsThe authority transferred pursuant to subsection (a) shall be exercised by the Secretary in accordance with the regulations, policies, and procedures issued by the Secretary of Agriculture regarding the administration of the laws specified in subsection (b).


(2) Rulemaking coordinationThe Secretary of Agriculture shall coordinate with the Secretary whenever the Secretary of Agriculture prescribes regulations, policies, or procedures for administering the functions transferred under subsection (a) under a law specified in subsection (b).


(3) Effective administrationThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of agricultural import and entry inspection functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of agricultural import and entry inspection functions There shall be transferred to the Secretary the functions of the Secretary of Agriculture relating to agricultural import and entry inspection activities under the laws specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered animal and plant protection laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered animal and plant protection laws The laws referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of quarantine activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of quarantine activities For purposes of this section, the term “functions” does not include any quarantine activities carried out under the laws specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of transfer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic transfer of funds to Department of Homeland Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic transfer of funds to Department of Homeland Security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Department of Agriculture employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer of Department of Agriculture employees Not later than the completion of the transition period defined under section 541 of this title, the Secretary of Agriculture shall transfer to the Secretary not more than 3,200 full-time equivalent positions of the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>