<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/236" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/236/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/236/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_236"><akn:num>236</akn:num><akn:heading>Visa issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 236. Visa issuance(a) DefinitionIn this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. the term “consular office” 22 So in original. Probably should be “ ‘consular officer’ ”. has the meaning given that term under section 101(a)(9) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(9)).


(b) In generalNotwithstanding section 104(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1104(a)) or any other provision of law, and except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary—(1) shall be vested exclusively with all authorities to issue regulations with respect to, administer, and enforce the provisions of such Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.], and of all other immigration and nationality laws, relating to the functions of consular officers of the United States in connection with the granting or refusal of visas, and shall have the authority to refuse visas in accordance with law and to develop programs of homeland security training for consular officers (in addition to consular training provided by the Secretary of State), which authorities shall be exercised through the Secretary of State, except that the Secretary shall not have authority to alter or reverse the decision of a consular officer to refuse a visa to an alien; and

(2) shall have authority to confer or impose upon any officer or employee of the United States, with the consent of the head of the executive agency under whose jurisdiction such officer or employee is serving, any of the functions specified in paragraph (1).


(c) Authority of the Secretary of State(1) In generalNotwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary of State may direct a consular officer to refuse a visa to an alien if the Secretary of State deems such refusal necessary or advisable in the foreign policy or security interests of the United States.


(2) Construction regarding authorityNothing in this section, consistent with the Secretary of Homeland Security’s authority to refuse visas in accordance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. the term “consular office” 22 So in original. Probably should be “ ‘consular officer’ ”. has the meaning given that term under section 101(a)(9) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(9)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general Notwithstanding section 104(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1104(a)) or any other provision of law, and except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority of the Secretary of State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consular officers and chiefs of missions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consular officers and chiefs of missions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of Homeland Security employees to diplomatic and consular posts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assignment of Homeland Security employees to diplomatic and consular posts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No creation of private right of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No creation of private right of action Nothing in this section shall be construed to create or authorize a private right of action to challenge a decision of a consular officer or other United States official or employee to grant or deny a visa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study regarding use of foreign nationals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study regarding use of foreign nationals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report Not later than 120 days after November 25, 2002, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit to Congress a report on how the provisions of this section will affect procedures for the issuance of student visas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_236_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visa issuance program for Saudi Arabia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Visa issuance program for Saudi Arabia Notwithstanding any other provision of law, after November 25, 2002, all third party screening programs in Saudi Arabia shall be terminated. On-site personnel of the Department of Homeland Security shall review all visa applications prior to adjudication.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>