<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/252" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/252/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/252/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_252"><akn:num>252</akn:num><akn:heading>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 252. U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere shall be in the Department of Homeland Security a bureau to be known as the “Bureau of Border Security”.


(2) Assistant SecretaryThe head of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall be the Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, who—(A) shall report directly to the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security; and

(B) shall have a minimum of 5 years professional experience in law enforcement, and a minimum of 5 years of management experience.


(3) FunctionsThe Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—(A) shall establish the policies for performing such functions as are—(i) transferred to the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security by section 251 of this title and delegated to the Assistant Secretary by the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security; or

(ii) otherwise vested in the Assistant Secretary by law;


(B) shall oversee the administration of such policies; and

(C) shall advise the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security with respect to any policy or operation of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement affecting U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services established under part E of this subchapter, including potentially conflicting policies or operations.


(4) Program to collect information relating to foreign studentsThe Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall be responsible for administering the program to collect information relating to nonimmigrant foreign students and other exchange program participants described in section 1372 of title 8, including the Student and Exchange Visitor Information System established under that section, and shall use such information to carry out the enforcement functions of the agency.


(5) Managerial rotation program(A) In generalNot later than 1 year after the date on which the transfer of functions</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_252_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_252_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief of Policy and Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chief of Policy and Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_252_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal advisor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Legal advisor There shall be a principal legal advisor to the Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement. The legal advisor shall provide specialized legal advice to the Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and shall represent the agency in all exclusion, deportation, and removal proceedings before the Executive Office for Immigration Review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>