<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/257" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/257/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/257/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_257"><akn:num>257</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 257. Report(a) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit an annual report to the congressional committees set forth in subsection (b) that includes a description of—(1) the cross-border tunnels along the border between Mexico and the United States discovered during the preceding fiscal year; and

(2) the needs of the Department of Homeland Security to effectively prevent, investigate and prosecute border tunnel construction along the border between Mexico and the United States.


(b) Congressional committeesThe congressional committees set forth in this subsection are—(1) the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;

(2) the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;

(3) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(4) the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;

(5) the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and

(6) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(Pub. L. 112–127, § 8, June 5, 2012, 126 Stat. 371.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Border Tunnel Prevention Act of 2012, and not as part of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
DHS Illicit Cross-Border Tunnel DefensePub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXI, § 7134, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3649, provided that:
“(a) Counter Illicit Cross-border Tunnel Operations Strategic Plan.—“(1) In general.—Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 23, 2022], the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and, as appropriate, other officials of the Department of Homeland Security, shall develop a counter illicit cross-border tunnel operations strategic plan (in this section referred to as the ‘strategic plan’) to address the following:“(A) Risk-based criteria to be used to prioritize the identificatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_257_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit an annual report to the congressional committees set forth in subsection (b) that includes a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_257_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional committees The congressional committees set forth in this subsection are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>