<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/271" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/271/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/271/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_271"><akn:num>271</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 271. Establishment of Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services(a) Establishment of Bureau(1) In generalThere shall be in the Department a bureau to be known as the “Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services”.


(2) DirectorThe head of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services shall be the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services, who—(A) shall report directly to the Deputy Secretary;

(B) shall have a minimum of 5 years of management experience; and

(C) shall be paid at the same level as the Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Border Security.


(3) FunctionsThe Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services—(A) shall establish the policies for performing such functions as are transferred to the Director by this section or this chapter or otherwise vested in the Director by law;

(B) shall oversee the administration of such policies;

(C) shall advise the Deputy Secretary with respect to any policy or operation of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services that may affect the Bureau of Border Security of the Department, including potentially conflicting policies or operations;

(D) shall establish national immigration services policies and priorities;

(E) shall meet regularly with the Ombudsman described in section 272 of this title to correct serious service problems identified by the Ombudsman; and

(F) shall establish procedures requiring a formal response to any recommendations submitted in the Ombudsman’s annual report to Congress within 3 months after its submission to Congress.


(4) Managerial rotation program(A) In generalNot later than 1 year after the effective date specified in section 455,11 See References in Text note below. the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services shall design and implement a managerial rotation program under which employees of such bureau holding positions involving supervisory or managerial responsibility and classified, in accordance wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Bureau</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of functions from Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of functions from Commissioner In accordance with subchapter XII (relating to transition provisions), there are transferred from the Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization to the Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services the following functions, and all personnel, infrastructure, and funding provided to the Commissioner in support of such functions immediately before the effective date specified in section 455: 1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief of Policy and Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chief of Policy and Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal advisor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Legal advisor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Budget Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief of Office of Citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chief of Office of Citizenship</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>