<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/292" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/292/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/292/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_292"><akn:num>292</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary separation incentive payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 292. Voluntary separation incentive payments(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “employee” means an employee (as defined by section 2105 of title 5) who—(A) has completed at least 3 years of current continuous service with 1 or more covered entities; and

(B) is serving under an appointment without time limitation,


but does not include any person under subparagraphs (A)–(G) of section 663(a)(2) of Public Law 104–208 (5 U.S.C. 5597 note);

(2) the term “covered entity” means—(A) the Immigration and Naturalization Service;

(B) the Bureau of Border Security of the Department of Homeland Security; and

(C) the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of Homeland Security; and


(3) the term “transfer date” means the date on which the transfer of functions specified under section 251 of this title takes effect.


(b) Strategic restructuring planBefore the Attorney General or the Secretary obligates any resources for voluntary separation incentive payments under this section, such official shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a strategic restructuring plan, which shall include—(1) an organizational chart depicting the covered entities after their restructuring pursuant to this chapter;

(2) a summary description of how the authority under this section will be used to help carry out that restructuring; and

(3) the information specified in section 663(b)(2) of Public Law 104–208 (5 U.S.C. 5597 note).


As used in the preceding sentence, the “appropriate committees of Congress” are the Committees on Appropriations, Government Reform, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations, Governmental Affairs, and the Judiciary of the Senate.

(c) AuthorityThe Attorney General and the Secretary may, to the extent necessary to help carry out their respective strategic restructuring plan described in subsection (b), make voluntary separation incentive payments to employees. An</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic restructuring plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Strategic restructuring plan Before the Attorney General or the Secretary obligates any resources for voluntary separation incentive payments under this section, such official shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a strategic restructuring plan, which shall include— As used in the preceding sentence, the “appropriate committees of Congress” are the Committees on Appropriations, Government Reform, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations, Governmental Affairs, and the Judiciary of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority The Attorney General and the Secretary may, to the extent necessary to help carry out their respective strategic restructuring plan described in subsection (b), make voluntary separation incentive payments to employees. Any such payment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional agency contributions to the retirement fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional agency contributions to the retirement fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of subsequent employment with the Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of subsequent employment with the Government An individual who receives a voluntary separation incentive payment under this section and who, within 5 years after the date of the separation on which the payment is based, accepts any compensated employment with the Government or works for any agency of the Government through a personal services contract, shall be required to pay, prior to the individual’s first day of employment, the entire amount of the incentive payment. Such payment shall be made to the covered entity from which the individual separated or, if made on or after the transfer date, to the Deputy Secretary or the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security (for transfer to the appropriate component of the Department of Homeland Security, if necessary).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on employment levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on employment levels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>