<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/321j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/321j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/321j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_321j"><akn:num>321j</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of security countermeasures for Strategic National Stockpile</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 321j. Procurement of security countermeasures for Strategic National Stockpile(a) Authorization of appropriationsFor the procurement of security countermeasures under section 247d–6b(c) of title 42 (referred to in this section as the “security countermeasures program”), there is authorized to be appropriated up to $5,593,000,000 for the fiscal years 2004 through 2013. Of the amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence, not to exceed $3,418,000,000 may be obligated during the fiscal years 2004 through 2008, of which not to exceed $890,000,000 may be obligated during fiscal year 2004. None of the funds made available under this subsection shall be used to procure countermeasures to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm resulting from any naturally occurring infectious disease or other public health threat that are not security countermeasures under section 247d–6b(c)(1)(B) of title 42.11 See References in Text note below.


(b) Special reserve fundFor purposes of the security countermeasures program, the term “special reserve fund” means the “Biodefense Countermeasures” appropriations account or any other appropriation made under subsection (a).


(c) AvailabilityAmounts appropriated under subsection (a) become available for a procurement under the security countermeasures program only upon the approval by the President of such availability for the procurement in accordance with paragraph (6)(B) of such program.


(d) Related authorizations of appropriations(1) Threat assessment capabilitiesFor the purpose of carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary for terror threat assessment under the security countermeasures program, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2004 through 2006, for the hiring of professional personnel within the Office of Intelligence and Analysis, who shall be analysts responsible for chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear threat assessment (including but not </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations For the procurement of security countermeasures under section 247d–6b(c) of title 42 (referred to in this section as the “security countermeasures program”), there is authorized to be appropriated up to $5,593,000,000 for the fiscal years 2004 through 2013. Of the amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence, not to exceed $3,418,000,000 may be obligated during the fiscal years 2004 through 2008, of which not to exceed $890,000,000 may be obligated during fiscal year 2004. None of the funds made available under this subsection shall be used to procure countermeasures to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, or treat harm resulting from any naturally occurring infectious disease or other public health threat that are not security countermeasures under section 247d–6b(c)(1)(B) of title 42.11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special reserve fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special reserve fund For purposes of the security countermeasures program, the term “special reserve fund” means the “Biodefense Countermeasures” appropriations account or any other appropriation made under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability Amounts appropriated under subsection (a) become available for a procurement under the security countermeasures program only upon the approval by the President of such availability for the procurement in accordance with paragraph (6)(B) of such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related authorizations of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Related authorizations of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>