<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_323"><akn:num>323</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance on how to prevent exposure to and release of PFAS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 323. Guidance on how to prevent exposure to and release of PFAS(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 20, 2022, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the heads of any other relevant agencies, shall—(1) develop and publish guidance for firefighters and other emergency response personnel on training, education programs, and best practices;

(2) make available a curriculum designed to—(A) reduce and eliminate exposure to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances (commonly referred to as “PFAS”) from firefighting foam and personal protective equipment;

(B) prevent the release of PFAS from firefighting foam into the environment; and

(C) educate firefighters and other emergency response personnel on foams and non-foam alternatives, personal protective equipment, and other firefighting tools and equipment that do not contain PFAS; and


(3) create an online public repository, which shall be updated on a regular basis, on tools and best practices for firefighters and other emergency response personnel to reduce, limit, and prevent the release of and exposure to PFAS.


(b) Curriculum(1) In generalFor the purpose of developing the curriculum required under subsection (a)(2), the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration shall make recommendations to the Secretary of Homeland Security as to the content of the curriculum.


(2) ConsultationFor the purpose of making recommendations under paragraph (1), the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration shall consult with interested entities, as appropriate, including—(A) firefighters and other emergency response personnel, including national fire service and emergency response organizations;

(B) impacted communities dealing with PFAS contamination;

(C) scientists, including public an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after December 20, 2022, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, and the heads of any other relevant agencies, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Curriculum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Curriculum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review Not later than 3 years after the date on which the guidance and curriculum required under subsection (a) is issued, and not less frequently than once every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, shall review the guidance and curriculum and, as appropriate, issue updates to the guidance and curriculum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of FACA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of FACA The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) 11 See References in Text note below. shall not apply to this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to promulgate or enforce regulations under subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>