<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_331"><akn:num>331</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of charitable trusts for members of the Armed Forces of the United States and other govern</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 331. Treatment of charitable trusts for members of the Armed Forces of the United States and other governmental organizations(a) FindingsCongress finds the following:(1) Members of the Armed Forces of the United States defend the freedom and security of our Nation.

(2) Members of the Armed Forces of the United States have lost their lives while battling the evils of terrorism around the world.

(3) Personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) charged with the responsibility of covert observation of terrorists around the world are often put in harm’s way during their service to the United States.

(4) Personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency have also lost their lives while battling the evils of terrorism around the world.

(5) Employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and other Federal agencies charged with domestic protection of the United States put their lives at risk on a daily basis for the freedom and security of our Nation.

(6) United States military personnel, CIA personnel, FBI personnel, and other Federal agents in the service of the United States are patriots of the highest order.

(7) CIA officer Johnny Micheal Spann became the first American to give his life for his country in the War on Terrorism declared by President George W. Bush following the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001.

(8) Johnny Micheal Spann left behind a wife and children who are very proud of the heroic actions of their patriot father.

(9) Surviving dependents of members of the Armed Forces of the United States who lose their lives as a result of terrorist attacks or military operations abroad receive a $6,000 death benefit, plus a small monthly benefit.

(10) The current system of compensating spouses and children of American patriots is inequitable and needs improvement.


(b) Designation of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot TrustsAny charitable corporation, fund, foundation, or trust (or separate fund or account thereof) which otherwise meets all applica</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts Any charitable corporation, fund, foundation, or trust (or separate fund or account thereof) which otherwise meets all applicable requirements under law with respect to charitable entities and meets the requirements described in subsection (c) shall be eligible to characterize itself as a “Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trust”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for the designation of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for the designation of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts The requirements described in this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trusts Each Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trust shall refrain from conducting the activities described in clauses (i) and (ii) of section 30101(20)(A) of title 52 so that a general solicitation of funds by an individual described in paragraph (1) of section 30125(e) of title 52 will be permissible if such solicitation meets the requirements of paragraph (4)(A) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Trust beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notification of Trust beneficiaries Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in a manner consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods and sensitive law enforcement information, and other sensitive national security information, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the Director of Central Intelligence, or their designees, as applicable, may forward information received from an executor, administrator, or other legal representative of the estate of a decedent described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D) of subsection (c)(1), to a Johnny Micheal Spann Patriot Trust on how to contact individuals eligible for a distribution under subsection (c)(1) for the purpose of providing assistance from such Trust: Provided, That, neither forwarding nor failing to forward any information under this subsection shall create any cause of action against any Federal department, agency, officer, agent, or employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations Not later than 90 days after November 25, 2002, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of Central Intelligence, shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>