<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_342"><akn:num>342</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Financial Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 342. Chief Financial Officer(a) In generalThe Chief Financial Officer shall perform functions as specified in chapter 9 of title 31 and, with respect to all such functions and other responsibilities that may be assigned to the Chief Financial Officer from time to time, shall also report to the Under Secretary for Management.


(b) Program analysis and evaluation function(1) Establishment of Office of Program Analysis and EvaluationNot later than 90 days after October 16, 2004, the Secretary shall establish an Office of Program Analysis and Evaluation within the Department (in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(2) ResponsibilitiesThe Office shall perform the following functions:(A) Analyze and evaluate plans, programs, and budgets of the Department in relation to United States homeland security objectives, projected threats, vulnerability assessments, estimated costs, resource constraints, and the most recent homeland security strategy developed pursuant to section 454(b)(2) of this title.

(B) Develop and perform analyses and evaluations of alternative plans, programs, personnel levels, and budget submissions for the Department in relation to United States homeland security objectives, projected threats, vulnerability assessments, estimated costs, resource constraints, and the most recent homeland security strategy developed pursuant to section 454(b)(2) of this title.

(C) Establish policies for, and oversee the integration of, the planning, programming, and budgeting system of the Department.

(D) Review and ensure that the Department meets performance-based budget requirements established by the Office of Management and Budget.

(E) Provide guidance for, and oversee the development of, the Future Years Homeland Security Program of the Department, as specified under section 454 of this title.

(F) Ensure that the costs of Department programs, including classified programs, are presented accurately and completely.

(G) Oversee the preparation of the an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Chief Financial Officer shall perform functions as specified in chapter 9 of title 31 and, with respect to all such functions and other responsibilities that may be assigned to the Chief Financial Officer from time to time, shall also report to the Under Secretary for Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program analysis and evaluation function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program analysis and evaluation function</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification regarding transfer or reprogramming of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification regarding transfer or reprogramming of funds In any case in which appropriations available to the Department or any officer of the Department are transferred or reprogrammed and notice of such transfer or reprogramming is submitted to the Congress (including any officer, office, or Committee of the Congress), the Chief Financial Officer of the Department shall simultaneously submit such notice to the Select Committee on Homeland Security (or any successor to the jurisdiction of that committee) and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>