<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/349" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/349/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/349/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_349"><akn:num>349</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 349. Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans(a) In generalThere is established in the Department an Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans.


(b) Head of OfficeThe Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall be headed by an Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans, who shall serve as the principal policy advisor to the Secretary. The Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(c) FunctionsThe Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall—(1) lead, conduct, and coordinate Department-wide policy development and implementation and strategic planning;

(2) develop and coordinate policies to promote and ensure quality, consistency, and integration for the programs, components, offices, and activities across the Department;

(3) develop and coordinate strategic plans and long-term goals of the Department with risk-based analysis and planning to improve operational mission effectiveness, including consultation with the Secretary regarding the quadrennial homeland security review under section 347 of this title;

(4) manage Department leadership councils and provide analytics and support to such councils;

(5) manage international coordination and engagement for the Department;

(6) review and incorporate, as appropriate, external stakeholder feedback into Department policy; and

(7) carry out such other responsibilities as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(d) Deputy Under Secretary(1) In generalThe Secretary may—(A) establish within the Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans a position of Deputy Under Secretary to support the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans in carrying out the Under Secretary’s responsibilities; and

(B) appoint a career employee to such position.


(2) Limitation on establishment of Deputy Under Secretary positionsA Deputy Under Secretary position (or any substantially similar position) within the Office of Strategy, Policy, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established in the Department an Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Head of Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Head of Office The Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall be headed by an Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans, who shall serve as the principal policy advisor to the Secretary. The Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions The Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Under Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deputy Under Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination by Department components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination by Department components To ensure consistency with the policy priorities of the Department, the head of each component of the Department shall coordinate with the Office of Strategy, Policy, and Plans in establishing or modifying policies or strategic planning guidance with respect to each such component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeland Security statistics and joint analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Homeland Security statistics and joint analysis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistant Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_349_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation Nothing in this section overrides or otherwise affects the requirements specified in section 468 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>