<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/353" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/353/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/353/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_353"><akn:num>353</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition professional career program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 353. Acquisition professional career program(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department an acquisition professional career program to develop a cadre of acquisition professionals within the Department.


(b) AdministrationThe Under Secretary for Management shall administer the acquisition professional career program established pursuant to subsection (a).


(c) Program requirementsThe Under Secretary for Management shall carry out the following with respect to the acquisition professional career program.11 So in original. Probably should be a colon.(1) Designate the occupational series, grades, and number of acquisition positions throughout the Department to be included in the program and manage centrally such positions.

(2) Establish and publish on the Department’s website eligibility criteria for candidates to participate in the program.

(3) Carry out recruitment efforts to attract candidates—(A) from institutions of higher education, including such institutions with established acquisition specialties and courses of study, historically Black colleges and universities, and Hispanic-serving institutions;

(B) with diverse work experience outside of the Federal Government; or

(C) with military service.


(4) Hire eligible candidates for designated positions under the program.

(5) Develop a structured program comprised of acquisition training, on-the-job experience, Department-wide rotations, mentorship, shadowing, and other career development opportunities for program participants.

(6) Provide, beyond required training established for program participants, additional specialized acquisition training, including small business contracting and innovative acquisition techniques training.


(d) ReportsNot later than one year after December 27, 2021, and annually thereafter through 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Department an acquisition professional career program to develop a cadre of acquisition professionals within the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration The Under Secretary for Management shall administer the acquisition professional career program established pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program requirements The Under Secretary for Management shall carry out the following with respect to the acquisition professional career program.11 So in original. Probably should be a colon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports Not later than one year after December 27, 2021, and annually thereafter through 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the acquisition professional career program. Each such report shall include the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>