<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/444" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/444/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/444/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_444"><akn:num>444</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 444. Definitions
For purposes of this part, the following definitions apply:(1) Qualified anti-terrorism technologyFor purposes of this part, the term “qualified anti-terrorism technology” means any product, equipment, service (including support services), device, or technology (including information technology) designed, developed, modified, or procured for the specific purpose of preventing, detecting, identifying, or deterring acts of terrorism or limiting the harm such acts might otherwise cause, that is designated as such by the Secretary.


(2) Act of terrorism(A) The term “act of terrorism” means any act that the Secretary determines meets the requirements under subparagraph (B), as such requirements are further defined and specified by the Secretary.

(B) Requirements.—An act meets the requirements of this subparagraph if the act—(i) is unlawful;

(ii) causes harm to a person, property, or entity, in the United States, or in the case of a domestic United States air carrier or a United States-flag vessel (or a vessel based principally in the United States on which United States income tax is paid and whose insurance coverage is subject to regulation in the United States), in or outside the United States; and

(iii) uses or attempts to use instrumentalities, weapons or other methods designed or intended to cause mass destruction, injury or other loss to citizens or institutions of the United States.



(3) Insurance carrierThe term “insurance carrier” means any corporation, association, society, order, firm, company, mutual,11 So in original. partnership, individual aggregation of individuals, or any other legal entity that provides commercial property and casualty insurance. Such term includes any affiliates of a commercial insurance carrier.


(4) Liability insurance(A) 22 So in original. No subpar. (B) has been enacted. In generalThe term “liability insurance” means insurance for legal liabilities incurred by the insured resulting from—(i) loss of or dama</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified anti-terrorism technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Qualified anti-terrorism technology For purposes of this part, the term “qualified anti-terrorism technology” means any product, equipment, service (including support services), device, or technology (including information technology) designed, developed, modified, or procured for the specific purpose of preventing, detecting, identifying, or deterring acts of terrorism or limiting the harm such acts might otherwise cause, that is designated as such by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Act of terrorism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Act of terrorism</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Insurance carrier The term “insurance carrier” means any corporation, association, society, order, firm, company, mutual,11 So in original. partnership, individual aggregation of individuals, or any other legal entity that provides commercial property and casualty insurance. Such term includes any affiliates of a commercial insurance carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Liability insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Loss The term “loss” means death, bodily injury, or loss of or damage to property, including business interruption loss.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal Government customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Non-Federal Government customers The term “non-Federal Government customers” means any customer of a Seller that is not an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government with authority under Public Law 85–804 [50 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.] to provide for indemnification under certain circumstances for third-party claims against its contractors, including but not limited to State and local authorities and commercial entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>