<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/464" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/464/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/464/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_464"><akn:num>464</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 464. Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall maintain in the Department the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers (FLETC), headed by a Director, who shall report to the Secretary.


(b) PositionThe Director shall occupy a career-reserved position within the Senior Executive Service.


(c) Functions of the DirectorThe Director shall—(1) develop training goals and establish strategic and tactical organizational program plan and priorities;

(2) provide direction and management for FLETC’s training facilities, programs, and support activities while ensuring that organizational program goals and priorities are executed in an effective and efficient manner;

(3) develop homeland security and law enforcement training curricula, including curricula related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism, for Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, and international law enforcement and security agencies and private sector security agencies;

(4) monitor progress toward strategic and tactical FLETC plans regarding training curricula, including curricula related to domestic preparedness and response to threats or acts of terrorism, and facilities;

(5) ensure the timely dissemination of homeland security information as necessary to Federal, State, local, tribal, territorial, and international law enforcement and security agencies and the private sector to achieve the training goals for such entities, in accordance with paragraph (1);

(6) carry out delegated acquisition responsibilities in a manner that—(A) fully complies with—(i) Federal law;

(ii) the Federal Acquisition Regulation, including requirements regarding agency obligations to contract only with responsible prospective contractors; and

(iii) Department acquisition management directives; and


(B) maximizes opportunities for small business participation;


(7) coordinate and share information with the heads of relevant components and offices on di</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall maintain in the Department the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers (FLETC), headed by a Director, who shall report to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Position The Director shall occupy a career-reserved position within the Senior Executive Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of the Director The Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Training responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>On-FLETC housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) On-FLETC housing Notwithstanding any other provision of law, individuals attending training at any FLETC facility shall, to the extent practicable and in accordance with FLETC policy, reside in on-FLETC or FLETC-provided housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional fiscal authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional fiscal authorities In order to further the goals and objectives of FLETC, the Director is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_464_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on new funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition on new funding No funds are authorized to carry out this section. This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise appropriated or made available for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>