<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/475a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/475a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/475a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_475a"><akn:num>475a</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor-protégé program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 475a. Mentor-protégé program(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department a mentor-protégé program (in this section referred to as the “Program”) under which a mentor firm enters into an agreement with a protégé firm for the purpose of assisting the protégé firm to compete for prime contracts and subcontracts of the Department.


(b) EligibilityThe Secretary shall establish criteria for mentor firms and protégé firms to be eligible to participate in the Program, including a requirement that a firm is not included on any list maintained by the Federal Government of contractors that have been suspended or debarred.


(c) Program application and approval(1) ApplicationThe Secretary, acting through the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department, shall establish a process for submission of an application jointly by a mentor firm and the protégé firm selected by the mentor firm. The application shall include each of the following:(A) A description of the assistance to be provided by the mentor firm, including, to the extent available, the number and a brief description of each anticipated subcontract to be awarded to the protégé firm.

(B) A schedule with milestones for achieving the assistance to be provided over the period of participation in the Program.

(C) An estimate of the costs to be incurred by the mentor firm for providing assistance under the Program.

(D) Attestations that Program participants will submit to the Secretary reports at times specified by the Secretary to assist the Secretary in evaluating the protégé firm’s developmental progress.

(E) Attestations that Program participants will inform the Secretary in the event of a change in eligibility or voluntary withdrawal from the Program.


(2) ApprovalNot later than 60 days after receipt of an application pursuant to paragraph (1), the head of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization shall notify applicants of approval or, in th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Department a mentor-protégé program (in this section referred to as the “Program”) under which a mentor firm enters into an agreement with a protégé firm for the purpose of assisting the protégé firm to compete for prime contracts and subcontracts of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility The Secretary shall establish criteria for mentor firms and protégé firms to be eligible to participate in the Program, including a requirement that a firm is not included on any list maintained by the Federal Government of contractors that have been suspended or debarred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program application and approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program application and approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Program duration A mentor firm and protégé firm approved under subsection (c) shall enter into an agreement to participate in the Program for a period of not less than 36 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program benefits A mentor firm and protégé firm that enter into an agreement under subsection (d) may receive the following Program benefits:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting Not later than one year after December 23, 2022, and annually thereafter, the head of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to limit, diminish, impair, or otherwise affect the authority of the Department to participate in any program carried out by or requiring approval of the Small Business Administration or adopt or follow any regulation or policy that the Administrator of the Small Business Administration may promulgate, except that, to the extent that any provision of this section (including subsection (h)) conflicts with any other provision of law, regulation, or policy, this section shall control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>