<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/485" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/485/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/485/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_485"><akn:num>485</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 485. Information sharing(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Homeland security informationThe term “homeland security information” has the meaning given that term in section 482(f) of this title.


(2) Information Sharing CouncilThe term “Information Sharing Council” means the Information Systems Council established by Executive Order 13356, or any successor body designated by the President, and referred to under subsection (g).


(3) Information sharing environmentThe terms “information sharing environment” and “ISE” mean an approach that facilitates the sharing of terrorism and homeland security information, which may include any method determined necessary and appropriate for carrying out this section.


(4) Program managerThe term “program manager” means the program manager designated under subsection (f).


(5) Terrorism informationThe term “terrorism information”—(A) means all information, whether collected, produced, or distributed by intelligence, law enforcement, military, homeland security, or other activities relating to—(i) the existence, organization, capabilities, plans, intentions, vulnerabilities, means of finance or material support, or activities of foreign or international terrorist groups or individuals, or of domestic groups or individuals involved in transnational terrorism;

(ii) threats posed by such groups or individuals to the United States, United States persons, or United States interests, or to those of other nations;

(iii) communications of or by such groups or individuals; or

(iv) groups or individuals reasonably believed to be assisting or associated with such groups or individuals; and


(B) includes weapons of mass destruction information.


(6) Weapons of mass destruction informationThe term “weapons of mass destruction information” means information that could reasonably be expected to assist in the development, proliferation, or use of a weapon of mass destruction (including a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear weap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information sharing environment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preliminary report Not later than 180 days after December 17, 2004, the program manager shall, in consultation with the Information Sharing Council—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidelines and requirements As soon as possible, but in no event later than 270 days after December 17, 2004, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation plan report Not later than one year after December 17, 2004, the President shall, with the assistance of the program manager, submit to Congress a report containing an implementation plan for the ISE. The report shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program manager</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Program manager</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Sharing Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information Sharing Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Agency responsibilities The head of each department or agency that possesses or uses intelligence or terrorism information, operates a system in the ISE, or otherwise participates (or expects to participate) in the ISE shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on the information sharing environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report on the information sharing environment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_485_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Additional positions The program manager is authorized to hire not more than 40 full-time employees to assist the program manager in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>