<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/488a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/488a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/488a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_488a"><akn:num>488a</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of the sale and transfer of ammonium nitrate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 488a. Regulation of the sale and transfer of ammonium nitrate(a) In generalThe Secretary shall regulate the sale and transfer of ammonium nitrate by an ammonium nitrate facility in accordance with this part to prevent the misappropriation or use of ammonium nitrate in an act of terrorism. Such regulations shall be carried out by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.


(b) Ammonium nitrate mixturesNot later than 90 days after December 26, 2007, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of appropriate Federal departments and agencies (including the Secretary of Agriculture), shall, after notice and an opportunity for comment, establish a threshold percentage for ammonium nitrate in a substance.


(c) Registration of owners of ammonium nitrate facilities(1) RegistrationThe Secretary shall establish a process by which any person that—(A) owns an ammonium nitrate facility is required to register with the Department; and

(B) registers under subparagraph (A) is issued a registration number for purposes of this part.


(2) Registration informationAny person applying to register under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary—(A) the name, address, and telephone number of each ammonium nitrate facility owned by that person;

(B) the name of the person designated by that person as the point of contact for each such facility, for purposes of this part; and

(C) such other information as the Secretary may determine is appropriate.



(d) Registration of ammonium nitrate purchasers(1) RegistrationThe Secretary shall establish a process by which any person that—(A) intends to be an ammonium nitrate purchaser is required to register with the Department; and

(B) registers under subparagraph (A) is issued a registration number for purposes of this part.


(2) Registration informationAny person applying to register under paragraph (1) as an ammonium nitrate purchaser shall submit to the Secretary—(A) the name, address, and telephone number of the applicant; </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall regulate the sale and transfer of ammonium nitrate by an ammonium nitrate facility in accordance with this part to prevent the misappropriation or use of ammonium nitrate in an act of terrorism. Such regulations shall be carried out by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ammonium nitrate mixtures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ammonium nitrate mixtures Not later than 90 days after December 26, 2007, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of appropriate Federal departments and agencies (including the Secretary of Agriculture), shall, after notice and an opportunity for comment, establish a threshold percentage for ammonium nitrate in a substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of owners of ammonium nitrate facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration of owners of ammonium nitrate facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of ammonium nitrate purchasers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Registration of ammonium nitrate purchasers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for explosive purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption for explosive purposes The Secretary may exempt from this part a person producing, selling, or purchasing ammonium nitrate exclusively for use in the production of an explosive under a license or permit issued under chapter 40 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Consultation In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture, States, and appropriate private sector entities, to ensure that the access of agricultural producers to ammonium nitrate is not unduly burdened.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Data confidentiality</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_488a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration procedures and check of terrorist screening database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Registration procedures and check of terrorist screening database</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>