<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/579" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/579/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/579/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_579"><akn:num>579</akn:num><akn:heading>Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 579. Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish the Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program to make grants to States to carry out initiatives to improve local, tribal, statewide, regional, national and, where appropriate, international interoperable emergency communications, including communications in collective response to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.


(b) PolicyThe Assistant Director for Emergency Communications shall ensure that a grant awarded to a State under this section is consistent with the policies established pursuant to the responsibilities and authorities of the Emergency Communications Division under this subchapter, including ensuring that activities funded by the grant—(1) comply with the statewide plan for that State required by section 194(f) of this title; and

(2) comply with the National Emergency Communications Plan under section 572 of this title, when completed.


(c) Administration(1) In generalThe Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall administer the Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program pursuant to the responsibilities and authorities of the Administrator under subchapter V.


(2) GuidanceIn administering the grant program, the Administrator shall ensure that the use of grants is consistent with guidance established by the Assistant Director for Emergency Communications pursuant to section 194(a)(1)(H) of this title.



(d) Use of fundsA State that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to implement that State’s Statewide Interoperability Plan required under section 194(f) of this title and approved under subsection (e), and to assist with activities determined by the Secretary to be integral to interoperable emergency communications.


(e) Approval of plans(1) Approval as condition of grantBefore a State may receive a grant under this section, the Assistant Director for Eme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish the Interoperable Emergency Communications Grant Program to make grants to States to carry out initiatives to improve local, tribal, statewide, regional, national and, where appropriate, international interoperable emergency communications, including communications in collective response to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Policy The Assistant Director for Emergency Communications shall ensure that a grant awarded to a State under this section is consistent with the policies established pursuant to the responsibilities and authorities of the Emergency Communications Division under this subchapter, including ensuring that activities funded by the grant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds A State that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to implement that State’s Statewide Interoperability Plan required under section 194(f) of this title and approved under subsection (e), and to assist with activities determined by the Secretary to be integral to interoperable emergency communications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Approval of plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations on uses of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations on award of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Award of grants In approving applications and awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity to amend applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Opportunity to amend applications In considering applications for grants under this section, the Administrator shall provide applicants with a reasonable opportunity to correct defects in the application, if any, before making final awards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Minimum grant amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>