<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/596b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/596b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/596b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_596b"><akn:num>596b</akn:num><akn:heading>Securing the Cities program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 596b. Securing the Cities program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary, through the Assistant Secretary, shall establish a program, to be known as the “Securing the Cities” or “STC” program, to enhance the ability of the United States to detect and prevent terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials that pose a high risk to homeland security in high-risk urban areas.


(b) ElementsThrough the STC program the Secretary shall—(1) assist State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments in designing and implementing, or enhancing existing, architectures for coordinated and integrated detection and interdiction of nuclear or other radiological materials that are out of regulatory control;

(2) support the development of an operating capability to detect and report on nuclear and other radiological materials out of regulatory control;

(3) provide resources to enhance detection, analysis, communication, and coordination to better integrate State, local, Tribal, and territorial assets into Federal operations;

(4) facilitate alarm adjudication and provide subject matter expertise and technical assistance on concepts of operations, training, exercises, and alarm response protocols;

(5) communicate with, and promote sharing of information about the presence or detection of nuclear or other radiological materials among appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial government agencies, in a manner that ensures transparency with the jurisdictions designated under subsection (c);

(6) provide augmenting resources, as appropriate, to enable State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to sustain and refresh their capabilities developed under the STC program;

(7) monitor expenditures under the STC program and track performance in meeting the goals of the STC program; and

(8) provide any other assistance the Secretary determines appropriate.


(c) Designation of jurisdictions(1) In generalIn carrying out the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_596b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary, through the Assistant Secretary, shall establish a program, to be known as the “Securing the Cities” or “STC” program, to enhance the ability of the United States to detect and prevent terrorist attacks and other high-consequence events utilizing nuclear or other radiological materials that pose a high risk to homeland security in high-risk urban areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_596b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements Through the STC program the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_596b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of jurisdictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of jurisdictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_596b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>