<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_601"><akn:num>601</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 601. Definitions
In this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.


(2) Appropriate committees of CongressThe term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and

(B) those committees of the House of Representatives that the Speaker of the House of Representatives determines appropriate.


(3) Critical infrastructure sectorsThe term “critical infrastructure sectors” means the following sectors, in both urban and rural areas:(A) Agriculture and food.

(B) Banking and finance.

(C) Chemical industries.

(D) Commercial facilities.

(E) Commercial nuclear reactors, materials, and waste.

(F) Dams.

(G) The defense industrial base.

(H) Emergency services.

(I) Energy.

(J) Government facilities.

(K) Information technology.

(L) National monuments and icons.

(M) Postal and shipping.

(N) Public health and health care.

(O) Telecommunications.

(P) Transportation systems.

(Q) Water.


(4) Directly eligible tribeThe term “directly eligible tribe” means—(A) any Indian tribe—(i) that is located in the continental United States;

(ii) that operates a law enforcement or emergency response agency with the capacity to respond to calls for law enforcement or emergency services;

(iii)(I) that is located on or near an international border or a coastline bordering an ocean (including the Gulf of Mexico) or international waters;

(II) that is located within 10 miles of a system or asset included on the prioritized critical infrastructure list established under section 664(a)(2) of this title or has such a system or asset within its territory;

(III) that is located within or contiguous to 1 of the 50 most populous metropolitan statistical areas in the United States; or

(IV) the jurisdiction of which includes not less than 1,000 square miles of Indian country, as that term is defined</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate committees of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate committees of Congress The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical infrastructure sectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Critical infrastructure sectors The term “critical infrastructure sectors” means the following sectors, in both urban and rural areas:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directly eligible tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Directly eligible tribe The term “directly eligible tribe” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible metropolitan area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Eligible metropolitan area The term “eligible metropolitan area” means any of the 100 most populous metropolitan statistical areas in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-risk urban area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) High-risk urban area The term “high-risk urban area” means a high-risk urban area designated under section 604(b)(3)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304(e) of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Metropolitan statistical area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Metropolitan statistical area The term “metropolitan statistical area” means a metropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Special Security Event</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) National Special Security Event The term “National Special Security Event” means a designated event that, by virtue of its political, economic, social, or religious significance, may be the target of terrorism or other criminal activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_601_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Population The term “population” means population according to the most recent United States census population estimates available at the start of the relevant fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>