<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_606"><akn:num>606</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to directly eligible tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 606. Grants to directly eligible tribes(a) In generalNotwithstanding section 605(b) of this title, the Administrator may award grants to directly eligible tribes under section 605 of this title.


(b) Tribal applicationsA directly eligible tribe may apply for a grant under section 605 of this title by submitting an application to the Administrator that includes, as appropriate, the information required for an application by a State under section 605(b) of this title.


(c) Consistency with State plans(1) In generalTo ensure consistency with any applicable State homeland security plan, a directly eligible tribe applying for a grant under section 605 of this title shall provide a copy of its application to each State within which any part of the tribe is located for review before the tribe submits such application to the Department.


(2) Opportunity for commentIf the Governor of a State determines that the application of a directly eligible tribe is inconsistent with the State homeland security plan of that State, or otherwise does not support the application, not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of that application the Governor shall—(A) notify the Administrator, in writing, of that fact; and

(B) provide an explanation of the reason for not supporting the application.



(d) Final authorityThe Administrator shall have final authority to approve any application of a directly eligible tribe. The Administrator shall notify each State within the boundaries of which any part of a directly eligible tribe is located of the approval of an application by the tribe.


(e) PrioritizationThe Administrator shall allocate funds to directly eligible tribes in accordance with the factors applicable to allocating funds among States under section 608 of this title.


(f) Distribution of awards to directly eligible tribesIf the Administrator awards funds to a directly eligible tribe under this section, the Administrator shall distribute the grant funds directly to the t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding section 605(b) of this title, the Administrator may award grants to directly eligible tribes under section 605 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tribal applications A directly eligible tribe may apply for a grant under section 605 of this title by submitting an application to the Administrator that includes, as appropriate, the information required for an application by a State under section 605(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency with State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consistency with State plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Final authority The Administrator shall have final authority to approve any application of a directly eligible tribe. The Administrator shall notify each State within the boundaries of which any part of a directly eligible tribe is located of the approval of an application by the tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prioritization The Administrator shall allocate funds to directly eligible tribes in accordance with the factors applicable to allocating funds among States under section 608 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of awards to directly eligible tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Distribution of awards to directly eligible tribes If the Administrator awards funds to a directly eligible tribe under this section, the Administrator shall distribute the grant funds directly to the tribe and not through any State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Minimum allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal liaison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tribal liaison A directly eligible tribe applying for a grant under section 605 of this title shall designate an individual to serve as a tribal liaison with the Department and other Federal, State, local, and regional government officials concerning preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to acts of terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for other funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Eligibility for other funds A directly eligible tribe that receives a grant under section 605 of this title may receive funds for other purposes under a grant from the State or States within the boundaries of which any part of such tribe is located and from any high-risk urban area of which it is a part, consistent with the homeland security plan of the State or high-risk urban area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_606_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>