<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/609a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/609a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/609a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_609a"><akn:num>609a</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit Security Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 609a. Nonprofit Security Grant Program(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department a program to be known as the “Nonprofit Security Grant Program” (in this section referred to as the “Program”). Under the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall make grants to eligible nonprofit organizations described in subsection (b), through the State in which such organizations are located, for target hardening and other security enhancements to protect against terrorist attacks or other threats.


(b) Eligible recipientsEligible nonprofit organizations described in this subsection are organizations that are—(1) described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title; and

(2) determined by the Secretary to be at risk of terrorist attacks or other threats.


(c) Permitted uses(1) In generalThe recipient of a grant under this section may use such grant for any of the following uses:(A) Target hardening activities, including physical security enhancement equipment, inspection and screening systems, and alteration or remodeling of existing buildings or physical facilities.

(B) Fees for security training relating to physical security and cybersecurity, target hardening, terrorism awareness, and employee awareness.

(C) Facility security personnel costs.

(D) Expenses directly related to the administration of the grant, except that those expenses may not exceed 5 percent of the amount of the grant.

(E) Any other appropriate activity, including cybersecurity resilience activities, as determined by the Administrator.


(2) RetentionEach State through which a recipient receives a grant under this section may retain not more than 5 percent of each grant for expenses directly related to the administration of the grant.


(3) Outreach and technical assistance(A) In generalIf the Administrator establishes target allocations in determining award amounts under the Program, a State may request a project to use a p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Department a program to be known as the “Nonprofit Security Grant Program” (in this section referred to as the “Program”). Under the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall make grants to eligible nonprofit organizations described in subsection (b), through the State in which such organizations are located, for target hardening and other security enhancements to protect against terrorist attacks or other threats.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible recipients Eligible nonprofit organizations described in this subsection are organizations that are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitted uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Permitted uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of performance The Administrator shall make funds provided under this section available for use by a recipient of a grant for a period of not less than 36 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report The Administrator shall annually for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2028 submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing information on the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration Not later than 120 days after December 23, 2022, the Administrator shall ensure that within the Federal Emergency Management Agency a program office for the Program (in this subsection referred to as the “program office”) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grant guidelines For each fiscal year, before awarding grants under this section, the Administrator—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Paperwork Reduction Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Paperwork Reduction Act Chapter 35 of title 44 (commonly known as the “Paperwork Reduction Act”) shall not apply to any changes to the application materials, Program forms, or other core Program documentation intended to enhance participation by eligible nonprofit organizations in the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_609a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>