<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_611"><akn:num>611</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 611. Administration and coordination(a) Regional coordinationThe Administrator shall ensure that—(1) all recipients of grants administered by the Department to prevent, prepare for, protect against, or respond to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters (excluding assistance provided under section 203, title IV, or title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5133, 5170 et seq., and 5191 et seq.)) coordinate, as appropriate, their prevention, preparedness, and protection efforts with neighboring State, local, and tribal governments; and

(2) all high-risk urban areas and other recipients of grants administered by the Department to prevent, prepare for, protect against, or respond to natural disasters, acts of terrorism, or other man-made disasters (excluding assistance provided under section 203, title IV, or title V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5133, 5170 et seq., and 5191 et seq.)) that include or substantially affect parts or all of more than 1 State coordinate, as appropriate, across State boundaries, including, where appropriate, through the use of regional working groups and requirements for regional plans.


(b) Planning committees(1) In generalAny State or high-risk urban area receiving a grant under section 604 or 605 of this title shall establish a State planning committee or urban area working group to assist in preparation and revision of the State, regional, or local homeland security plan or the threat and hazard identification and risk assessment, as the case may be, and to assist in determining effective funding priorities for grants under such sections.


(2) Composition(A) In generalThe State planning committees and urban area working groups referred to in paragraph (1) shall include at least one representative from each of the following significant stakeholders:(i) Local or tribal government officials.

(ii) Emergency respon</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regional coordination The Administrator shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that, in order to ensure that the Nation is most effectively able to prevent, prepare for, protect against, and respond to all hazards, including natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other man-made disasters—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>