<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/653" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/653/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/653/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_653"><akn:num>653</akn:num><akn:heading>Cybersecurity Division</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 653. Cybersecurity Division(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere is established in the Agency a Cybersecurity Division.


(2) Executive Assistant DirectorThe Cybersecurity Division shall be headed by an Executive Assistant Director for Cybersecurity (in this section referred to as “the Executive Assistant Director”), who shall—(A) be at the level of Assistant Secretary within the Department;

(B) be appointed by the President without the advice and consent of the Senate; and

(C) report to the Director.


(3) ReferenceAny reference to the Assistant Secretary for Cybersecurity and Communications or Assistant Director for Cybersecurity in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the Executive Assistant Director for Cybersecurity.



(b) FunctionsThe Executive Assistant Director shall—(1) direct the cybersecurity efforts of the Agency;

(2) carry out activities, at the direction of the Director, related to the security of Federal information and Federal information systems consistent with law, including subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 44 and the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (contained in division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (Public Law 114–113));

(3) fully participate in the mechanisms required under section 652(c)(7) of this title; and

(4) carry out such other duties and powers as prescribed by the Director.


(Pub. L. 107–296, title XXII, § 2203, as added Pub. L. 115–278, § 2(a), Nov. 16, 2018, 132 Stat. 4174; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. H, title XC, § 9001(c)(1), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4766.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Cybersecurity Act of 2015, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is div. N of Pub. L. 114–113, Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 2835. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1501 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2021—Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 116–283, § 9001(c)(1)(A)(i), in heading, substituted </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_653_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_653_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Executive Assistant Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>