<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/659" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/659/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/659/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_659"><akn:num>659</akn:num><akn:heading>National cybersecurity and communications integration center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 659. National cybersecurity and communications integration center(a) DefinitionThe term “cybersecurity vulnerability” has the meaning given the term “security vulnerability” in section 650 of this title.


(b) CenterThere is in the Department a national cybersecurity and communications integration center (referred to in this section as the “Center”) to carry out certain responsibilities of the Director. The Center shall be located in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. The head of the Center shall report to the Executive Assistant Director for Cybersecurity.


(c) FunctionsThe cybersecurity functions of the Center shall include—(1) being a Federal civilian interface for the multi-directional and cross-sector sharing of information related to cyber threat indicators, defensive measures, cybersecurity risks, incidents, analysis, and warnings for Federal and non-Federal entities, including the implementation of title I of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 [6 U.S.C. 1501 et seq.];

(2) providing shared situational awareness to enable real-time, integrated, and operational actions across the Federal Government and non-Federal entities to address cybersecurity risks and incidents to Federal and non-Federal entities;

(3) coordinating the sharing of information related to cyber threat indicators, defensive measures, cybersecurity risks, and incidents across the Federal Government;

(4) facilitating cross-sector coordination to address cybersecurity risks and incidents, including cybersecurity risks and incidents that may be related or could have consequential impacts across multiple sectors;

(5)(A) conducting integration and analysis, including cross-sector integration and analysis, of cyber threat indicators, defensive measures, cybersecurity risks, and incidents;

(B) sharing mitigation protocols to counter cybersecurity vulnerabilities pursuant to subsection (n), as appropriate; and

(C) sharing the analysis conducted under subparagraph (A) and mitigati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition The term “cybersecurity vulnerability” has the meaning given the term “security vulnerability” in section 650 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Center There is in the Department a national cybersecurity and communications integration center (referred to in this section as the “Center”) to carry out certain responsibilities of the Director. The Center shall be located in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency. The head of the Center shall report to the Executive Assistant Director for Cybersecurity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions The cybersecurity functions of the Center shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Composition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Principles In carrying out the functions under subsection (c), the Center shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cyber hunt and incident response teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cyber hunt and incident response teams</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No right or benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No right or benefit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Automated information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Automated information sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary information sharing procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Voluntary information sharing procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_659_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Direct reporting The Secretary shall develop policies and procedures for direct reporting to the Secretary by the Director of the Center regarding significant cybersecurity risks and incidents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>