<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/663" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/663/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/663/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_663"><akn:num>663</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal intrusion detection and prevention system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 663. Federal intrusion detection and prevention system(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “agency” has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44;

(2) the term “agency information” means information collected or maintained by or on behalf of an agency; 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “and”.

(3) the term “agency information system” has the meaning given the term in section 660 of this title; and 22 So in original. The “; and” probably should be a period.


(b) Requirement(1) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 18, 2015, the Secretary shall deploy, operate, and maintain, to make available for use by any agency, with or without reimbursement—(A) a capability to detect cybersecurity risks in network traffic transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system; and

(B) a capability to prevent network traffic associated with such cybersecurity risks from transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system or modify such network traffic to remove the cybersecurity risk.


(2) Regular improvementThe Secretary shall regularly deploy new technologies and modify existing technologies to the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities described in paragraph (1) as appropriate to improve the intrusion detection and prevention capabilities.



(c) ActivitiesIn carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary—(1) may access, and the head of an agency may disclose to the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under paragraph (2), information transiting or traveling to or from an agency information system, regardless of the location from which the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under paragraph (2) accesses such information, notwithstanding any other provision of law that would otherwise restrict or prevent the head of an agency from disclosing such information to the Secretary or a private entity providing assistance to the Secretary under para</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Principles In carrying out subsection (b), the Secretary shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Private entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_663_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy Officer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Privacy Officer review Not later than 1 year after December 18, 2015, the Privacy Officer appointed under section 142 of this title, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall review the policies and guidelines for the program carried out under this section to ensure that the policies and guidelines are consistent with applicable privacy laws, including those governing the acquisition, interception, retention, use, and disclosure of communications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>