<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/664" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/664/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/664/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_664"><akn:num>664</akn:num><akn:heading>National asset database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 664. National asset database(a) Establishment(1) National asset databaseThe Secretary shall establish and maintain a national database of each system or asset that—(A) the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate homeland security officials of the States, determines to be vital and the loss, interruption, incapacity, or destruction of which would have a negative or debilitating effect on the economic security, public health, or safety of the United States, any State, or any local government; or

(B) the Secretary determines is appropriate for inclusion in the database.


(2) Prioritized critical infrastructure listIn accordance with Homeland Security Presidential Directive–7, as in effect on January 1, 2007, the Secretary shall establish and maintain a single classified prioritized list of systems and assets included in the database under paragraph (1) that the Secretary determines would, if destroyed or disrupted, cause national or regional catastrophic effects.



(b) Use of databaseThe Secretary shall use the database established under subsection (a)(1) in the development and implementation of Department plans and programs as appropriate.


(c) Maintenance of database(1) In generalThe Secretary shall maintain and annually update the database established under subsection (a)(1) and the list established under subsection (a)(2), including—(A) establishing data collection guidelines and providing such guidelines to the appropriate homeland security official of each State;

(B) regularly reviewing the guidelines established under subparagraph (A), including by consulting with the appropriate homeland security officials of States, to solicit feedback about the guidelines, as appropriate;

(C) after providing the homeland security official of a State with the guidelines under subparagraph (A), allowing the official a reasonable amount of time to submit to the Secretary any data submissions recommended by the official for inclusion in the database established under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of database The Secretary shall use the database established under subsection (a)(1) in the development and implementation of Department plans and programs as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maintenance of database</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Infrastructure Protection Consortium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Infrastructure Protection Consortium The Secretary may establish a consortium to be known as the “National Infrastructure Protection Consortium”. The Consortium may advise the Secretary on the best way to identify, generate, organize, and maintain any database or list of systems and assets established by the Secretary, including the database established under subsection (a)(1) and the list established under subsection (a)(2). If the Secretary establishes the National Infrastructure Protection Consortium, the Consortium may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>