<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/665m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/665m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/665m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_665m"><akn:num>665m</akn:num><akn:heading>President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 665m. President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition(a) In generalThe Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (in this section referred to as the “Director”) of the Department of Homeland Security is authorized to hold an annual cybersecurity competition to be known as the “Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency’s President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition” (in this section referred to as the “competition”) for the purpose of identifying, challenging, and competitively awarding prizes, including cash prizes, to the United States Government’s best cybersecurity practitioners and teams across offensive and defensive cybersecurity disciplines.


(b) EligibilityTo be eligible to participate in the competition, an individual shall be a Federal civilian employee or member of the uniformed services (as such term is defined in section 2101(3) of title 5) and shall comply with any rules promulgated by the Director regarding the competition.


(c) Competition administrationThe Director may enter into a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with a private sector for-profit or nonprofit entity or State or local government agency to administer the competition.


(d) Competition parametersEach competition shall incorporate the following elements:(1) Cybersecurity skills outlined in the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education Framework, or any successor framework.

(2) Individual and team events.

(3) Categories demonstrating offensive and defensive cyber operations, such as software reverse engineering and exploitation, network operations, forensics, big data analysis, cyber analysis, cyber defense, cyber exploitation, secure programming, obfuscated coding, or cyber-physical systems.

(4) Any other elements related to paragraphs (1), (2), or (3), as determined necessary by the Director.


(e) Use of funds(1) In generalIn order to further the goals and objectives of the competition, the Dir</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (in this section referred to as the “Director”) of the Department of Homeland Security is authorized to hold an annual cybersecurity competition to be known as the “Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency’s President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition” (in this section referred to as the “competition”) for the purpose of identifying, challenging, and competitively awarding prizes, including cash prizes, to the United States Government’s best cybersecurity practitioners and teams across offensive and defensive cybersecurity disciplines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility To be eligible to participate in the competition, an individual shall be a Federal civilian employee or member of the uniformed services (as such term is defined in section 2101(3) of title 5) and shall comply with any rules promulgated by the Director regarding the competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Competition administration The Director may enter into a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with a private sector for-profit or nonprofit entity or State or local government agency to administer the competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition parameters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Competition parameters Each competition shall incorporate the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prize limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prize limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_665m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting requirements The Director shall annually provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that includes the following with respect to each competition conducted in the preceding year:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>