<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/681" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/681/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/681/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_681"><akn:num>681</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 681. Definitions
In this part:(1) CenterThe term “Center” means the center established under section 659 of this title.


(2) CouncilThe term “Council” means the Cyber Incident Reporting Council described in section 681f of this title.


(3) Covered cyber incidentThe term “covered cyber incident” means a substantial cyber incident experienced by a covered entity that satisfies the definition and criteria established by the Director in the final rule issued pursuant to section 681b(b) of this title.


(4) Covered entityThe term “covered entity” means an entity in a critical infrastructure sector, as defined in Presidential Policy Directive 21, that satisfies the definition established by the Director in the final rule issued pursuant to section 681b(b) of this title.


(5) Cyber incidentThe term “cyber incident”—(A) has the meaning given the term “incident” in section 659 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and

(B) does not include an occurrence that imminently, but not actually, jeopardizes—(i) information on information systems; or

(ii) information systems.



(6) Cyber threatThe term “cyber threat” has the meaning given the term “cybersecurity threat” in section 650 of this title.


(7) Federal entityThe term “Federal entity” has the meaning given the term in section 1501 of this title.


(8) Ransom paymentThe term “ransom payment” means the transmission of any money or other property or asset, including virtual currency, or any portion thereof, which has at any time been delivered as ransom in connection with a ransomware attack.


(9) Significant cyber incidentThe term “significant cyber incident” means a cyber incident, or a group of related cyber incidents, that the Secretary determines is likely to result in demonstrable harm to the national security interests, foreign relations, or economy of the United States or to the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the people of the United States.


(10) Virtual curr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Center The term “Center” means the center established under section 659 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Council The term “Council” means the Cyber Incident Reporting Council described in section 681f of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered cyber incident</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Covered cyber incident The term “covered cyber incident” means a substantial cyber incident experienced by a covered entity that satisfies the definition and criteria established by the Director in the final rule issued pursuant to section 681b(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Covered entity The term “covered entity” means an entity in a critical infrastructure sector, as defined in Presidential Policy Directive 21, that satisfies the definition established by the Director in the final rule issued pursuant to section 681b(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cyber incident</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Cyber incident The term “cyber incident”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cyber threat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Cyber threat The term “cyber threat” has the meaning given the term “cybersecurity threat” in section 650 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Federal entity The term “Federal entity” has the meaning given the term in section 1501 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ransom payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Ransom payment The term “ransom payment” means the transmission of any money or other property or asset, including virtual currency, or any portion thereof, which has at any time been delivered as ransom in connection with a ransomware attack.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Significant cyber incident</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Significant cyber incident The term “significant cyber incident” means a cyber incident, or a group of related cyber incidents, that the Secretary determines is likely to result in demonstrable harm to the national security interests, foreign relations, or economy of the United States or to the public confidence, civil liberties, or public health and safety of the people of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Virtual currency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Virtual currency The term “virtual currency” means the digital representation of value that functions as a medium of exchange, a unit of account, or a store of value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>