<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/741" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/741/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/741/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_741"><akn:num>741</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 741. Definitions
In this part:(1) CapabilityThe term “capability” means the ability to provide the means to accomplish one or more tasks under specific conditions and to specific performance standards. A capability may be achieved with any combination of properly planned, organized, equipped, trained, and exercised personnel that achieves the intended outcome.


(2) Credentialed; credentialingThe terms “credentialed” and “credentialing” have the meanings given those terms in section 311 of this title.


(3) HazardThe term “hazard” has the meaning given that term under section 5195a(a)(1) of title 42.


(4) Mission assignmentThe term “mission assignment” means a work order issued to a Federal agency by the Agency, directing completion by that agency of a specified task and setting forth funding, other managerial controls, and guidance.


(5) National preparedness goalThe term “national preparedness goal” means the national preparedness goal established under section 743 of this title.


(6) National preparedness systemThe term “national preparedness system” means the national preparedness system established under section 744 of this title.


(7) National training programThe term “national training program” means the national training program established under section 748(a) of this title.


(8) Operational readinessThe term “operational readiness” means the capability of an organization, an asset, a system, or equipment to perform the missions or functions for which it is organized or designed.


(9) Performance measureThe term “performance measure” means a quantitative or qualitative characteristic used to gauge the results of an outcome compared to its intended purpose.


(10) Performance metricThe term “performance metric” means a particular value or characteristic used to measure the outcome that is generally expressed in terms of a baseline and a target.


(11) PreventionThe term “prevention” means any activity undertaken to avoid, prevent, or stop a threatene</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Capability The term “capability” means the ability to provide the means to accomplish one or more tasks under specific conditions and to specific performance standards. A capability may be achieved with any combination of properly planned, organized, equipped, trained, and exercised personnel that achieves the intended outcome.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credentialed; credentialing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Credentialed; credentialing The terms “credentialed” and “credentialing” have the meanings given those terms in section 311 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Hazard The term “hazard” has the meaning given that term under section 5195a(a)(1) of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission assignment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Mission assignment The term “mission assignment” means a work order issued to a Federal agency by the Agency, directing completion by that agency of a specified task and setting forth funding, other managerial controls, and guidance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>National preparedness goal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) National preparedness goal The term “national preparedness goal” means the national preparedness goal established under section 743 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>National preparedness system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) National preparedness system The term “national preparedness system” means the national preparedness system established under section 744 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>National training program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) National training program The term “national training program” means the national training program established under section 748(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational readiness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Operational readiness The term “operational readiness” means the capability of an organization, an asset, a system, or equipment to perform the missions or functions for which it is organized or designed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance measure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Performance measure The term “performance measure” means a quantitative or qualitative characteristic used to gauge the results of an outcome compared to its intended purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_741_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance metric</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Performance metric The term “performance metric” means a particular value or characteristic used to measure the outcome that is generally expressed in terms of a baseline and a target.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>