<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/749" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/749/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/749/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_749"><akn:num>749</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive assessment system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 749. Comprehensive assessment system(a) EstablishmentThe Administrator, in coordination with the National Council on Disability and the National Advisory Council, shall establish a comprehensive system to assess, on an ongoing basis, the Nation’s prevention capabilities and overall preparedness, including operational readiness.


(b) Performance metrics and measuresThe Administrator shall ensure that each component of the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies, and the reports required under section 752 of this title is developed, revised, and updated with clear and quantifiable performance metrics, measures, and outcomes.


(c) ContentsThe assessment system established under subsection (a) shall assess—(1) compliance with the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies;

(2) capability levels at the time of assessment against target capability levels defined pursuant to the guidelines established under section 746(a) of this title;

(3) resource needs to meet the desired target capability levels defined pursuant to the guidelines established under section 746(a) of this title; and

(4) performance of training, exercises, and operations.


(Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 649, Oct. 4, 2006, 120 Stat. 1428.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_749_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Administrator, in coordination with the National Council on Disability and the National Advisory Council, shall establish a comprehensive system to assess, on an ongoing basis, the Nation’s prevention capabilities and overall preparedness, including operational readiness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_749_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance metrics and measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Performance metrics and measures The Administrator shall ensure that each component of the national preparedness system, National Incident Management System, National Response Plan, and other related plans and strategies, and the reports required under section 752 of this title is developed, revised, and updated with clear and quantifiable performance metrics, measures, and outcomes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_749_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents The assessment system established under subsection (a) shall assess—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>