<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/774" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/774/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/774/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_774"><akn:num>774</akn:num><akn:heading>Reunification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 774. Reunification(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Child Locator CenterThe term “Child Locator Center” means the National Emergency Child Locator Center established under subsection (b).


(2) Declared eventThe term “declared event” means a major disaster or emergency.


(3) Displaced adultThe term “displaced adult” means an individual 21 years of age or older who is displaced from the habitual residence of that individual as a result of a declared event.


(4) Displaced childThe term “displaced child” means an individual under 21 years of age who is displaced from the habitual residence of that individual as a result of a declared event.



(b) National Emergency Child Locator Center(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator, in coordination with the Attorney General of the United States, shall establish within the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children the National Emergency Child Locator Center. In establishing the National Emergency Child Locator Center, the Administrator shall establish procedures to make all relevant information available to the National Emergency Child Locator Center in a timely manner to facilitate the expeditious identification and reunification of children with their families.


(2) PurposesThe purposes of the Child Locator Center are to—(A) enable individuals to provide to the Child Locator Center the name of and other identifying information about a displaced child or a displaced adult who may have information about the location of a displaced child;

(B) enable individuals to receive information about other sources of information about displaced children and displaced adults; and

(C) assist law enforcement in locating displaced children.


(3) Responsibilities and dutiesThe responsibilities and duties of the Child Locator Center are to—(A) establish a toll-free telephone number to receive reports of displaced children and information about displaced adults that may assist in locating </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Emergency Child Locator Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Emergency Child Locator Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 270 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report describing in detail the status of the Child Locator Center, including funding issues and any difficulties or issues in establishing the Center or completing the cooperative agreements described in subsection (b)(3)(K).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>