<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/775" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/775/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/775/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_775"><akn:num>775</akn:num><akn:heading>National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 775. National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “displaced individual” means an individual displaced by an emergency or major disaster; and

(2) the term “National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System” means the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System established under subsection (b).


(b) EstablishmentNot later than 180 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall establish a National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System to help reunify families separated after an emergency or major disaster.


(c) Operation of SystemThe National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System shall—(1) allow a displaced adult (including medical patients) to voluntarily register (and allow an adult that is the parent or guardian of a displaced child to register such child), by submitting personal information to be entered into a database (such as the name, current location of residence, and any other relevant information that could be used by others seeking to locate that individual);

(2) ensure that information submitted under paragraph (1) is accessible to those individuals named by a displaced individual and to those law enforcement officials;

(3) be accessible through the Internet and through a toll-free number, to receive reports of displaced individuals; and

(4) include a means of referring displaced children to the National Emergency Child Locator Center established under section 774 of this title.


(d) Publication of informationNot later than 210 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall establish a mechanism to inform the public about the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System and its potential usefulness for assisting to reunite displaced individuals with their families.


(e) CoordinationNot later than 90 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall enter a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Justice, the National Center for Missin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment Not later than 180 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall establish a National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System to help reunify families separated after an emergency or major disaster.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation of System The National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of information Not later than 210 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall establish a mechanism to inform the public about the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System and its potential usefulness for assisting to reunite displaced individuals with their families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination Not later than 90 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall enter a memorandum of understanding with the Department of Justice, the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the American Red Cross and other relevant private organizations that will enhance the sharing of information to facilitate reuniting displaced individuals (including medical patients) with their families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_775_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 270 days after October 4, 2006, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing in detail the status of the National Emergency Family Registry and Locator System, including any difficulties or issues in establishing the System, including funding issues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>