<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/793" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/793/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/793/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_793"><akn:num>793</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight and accountability of Federal disaster expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 793. Oversight and accountability of Federal disaster expenditures(a) Authority of Administrator to designate funds for oversight activitiesThe Administrator may designate up to 1 percent of the total amount provided to a Federal agency for a mission assignment as oversight funds to be used by the recipient agency for performing oversight of activities carried out under the Agency reimbursable mission assignment process. Such funds shall remain available until expended.


(b) Use of funds(1) Types of oversight activitiesOversight funds may be used for the following types of oversight activities related to Agency mission assignments:(A) Monitoring, tracking, and auditing expenditures of funds.

(B) Ensuring that sufficient management and internal control mechanisms are available so that Agency funds are spent appropriately and in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations.

(C) Reviewing selected contracts and other activities.

(D) Investigating allegations of fraud involving Agency funds.

(E) Conducting and participating in fraud prevention activities with other Federal, State, and local government personnel and contractors.


(2) Plans and reportsOversight funds may be used to issue the plans required under subsection (e) and the reports required under subsection (f).



(c) Restriction on use of fundsOversight funds may not be used to finance existing agency oversight responsibilities related to direct agency appropriations used for disaster response, relief, and recovery activities.


(d) Methods of oversight activities(1) In generalOversight activities may be carried out by an agency under this section either directly or by contract. Such activities may include evaluations and financial and performance audits.


(2) Coordination of oversight activitiesTo the extent practicable, evaluations and audits under this section shall be performed by the inspector general of the agency.



(e) Development of oversight plans(1) In generalIf an agency receives </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Administrator to designate funds for oversight activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Administrator to designate funds for oversight activities The Administrator may designate up to 1 percent of the total amount provided to a Federal agency for a mission assignment as oversight funds to be used by the recipient agency for performing oversight of activities carried out under the Agency reimbursable mission assignment process. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on use of funds Oversight funds may not be used to finance existing agency oversight responsibilities related to direct agency appropriations used for disaster response, relief, and recovery activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods of oversight activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Methods of oversight activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of oversight plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Development of oversight plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal disaster assistance accountability reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal disaster assistance accountability reports A Federal agency receiving oversight funds under this section shall submit annually to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress a consolidated report regarding the use of such funds, including information summarizing oversight activities and the results achieved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_793_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition In this section, the term “oversight funds” means funds referred to in subsection (a) that are designated for use in performing oversight activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>