<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/794" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/794/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/794/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_794"><akn:num>794</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on length of certain noncompetitive contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 794. Limitation on length of certain noncompetitive contracts(a) RegulationsThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations applicable to contracts described in subsection (c) to restrict the contract period of any such contract entered into using procedures other than competitive procedures pursuant to the exception provided in paragraph (2) of section 3304(a) of title 41 to the minimum contract period necessary—(1) to meet the urgent and compelling requirements of the work to be performed under the contract; and

(2) to enter into another contract for the required goods or services through the use of competitive procedures.


(b) Specific contract periodThe regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall require the contract period to not to exceed 11 So in original. Probably should be “period not to exceed”. 150 days, unless the Secretary determines that exceptional circumstances apply.


(c) Covered contractsThis section applies to any contract in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined by section 134 of title 41) entered into by the Department to facilitate response to or recovery from a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster.


(Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 695, Oct. 4, 2006, 120 Stat. 1460.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
In subsec. (a), “paragraph (2) of section 3304(a) of title 41” substituted for “paragraph (2) of section 303(c) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (41 U.S.C. 253(c))” on authority of Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3854, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.
In subsec. (c), “section 134 of title 41” substituted for “section 4 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act (41 U.S.C. 403)” on authority of Pub. L. 111–350, § 6(c), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3854, which Act enacted Title 41, Public Contracts.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations applicable to contracts described in subsection (c) to restrict the contract period of any such contract entered into using procedures other than competitive procedures pursuant to the exception provided in paragraph (2) of section 3304(a) of title 41 to the minimum contract period necessary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific contract period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specific contract period The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall require the contract period to not to exceed 11 So in original. Probably should be “period not to exceed”. 150 days, unless the Secretary determines that exceptional circumstances apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Covered contracts This section applies to any contract in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (as defined by section 134 of title 41) entered into by the Department to facilitate response to or recovery from a natural disaster, act of terrorism, or other man-made disaster.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>