<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/796" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/796/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/796/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796"><akn:num>796</akn:num><akn:heading>Registry of disaster response contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796. Registry of disaster response contractors(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “registry” means the registry created under subsection (b); and

(2) the terms “small business concern”, “small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals”, “small business concern owned and controlled by women”, and “small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans” have the meanings given those terms under the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.).


(b) Registry(1) In generalThe Administrator shall establish and maintain a registry of contractors who are willing to perform debris removal, distribution of supplies, reconstruction, and other disaster or emergency relief activities.


(2) ContentsThe registry shall include, for each business concern—(A) the name of the business concern;

(B) the location of the business concern;

(C) the area served by the business concern;

(D) the type of good or service provided by the business concern;

(E) the bonding level of the business concern; and

(F) whether the business concern is—(i) a small business concern;

(ii) a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;

(iii) a small business concern owned and controlled by women; or

(iv) a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans.



(3) Source of information(A) SubmissionInformation maintained in the registry shall be submitted on a voluntary basis and be kept current by the submitting business concerns.


(B) AttestationEach business concern submitting information to the registry shall submit—(i) an attestation that the information is true; and

(ii) documentation supporting such attestation.


(C) VerificationThe Administrator shall verify that the documentation submitted by each business concern supports the information submitted by that business concern.



(4) Availability of registryThe registry shall be made gener</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>