<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/921" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/921/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/921/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_921"><akn:num>921</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic radiation detection and imaging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 921. Domestic radiation detection and imaging(a) Scanning containersSubject to section 1318 of title 19, not later than December 31, 2007, all containers entering the United States through the 22 ports through which the greatest volume of containers enter the United States by vessel shall be scanned for radiation. To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall deploy next generation radiation detection technology.


(b) StrategyThe Secretary shall develop a strategy for the deployment of radiation detection capabilities that includes—(1) a risk-based prioritization of ports of entry at which radiation detection equipment will be deployed;

(2) a proposed timeline of when radiation detection equipment will be deployed at each port of entry identified under paragraph (1);

(3) the type of equipment to be used at each port of entry identified under paragraph (1), including the joint deployment and utilization of radiation detection equipment and nonintrusive imaging equipment;

(4) standard operating procedures for examining containers with such equipment, including sensor alarming, networking, and communications and response protocols;

(5) operator training plans;

(6) an evaluation of the environmental health and safety impacts of nonintrusive imaging technology and a radiation risk reduction plan, in consultation with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, and the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, that seeks to minimize radiation exposure of workers and the public to levels as low as reasonably achievable;

(7) the policy of the Department for using nonintrusive imaging equipment in tandem with radiation detection equipment; and

(8) a classified annex that—(A) details plans for covert testing; and

(B) outlines the risk-based prioritization of ports of entry identified under paragraph (1).



(c) StandardsThe Secretary, acting through the Director for Domestic Nuclear Detection 11 See Change of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scanning containers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scanning containers Subject to section 1318 of title 19, not later than December 31, 2007, all containers entering the United States through the 22 ports through which the greatest volume of containers enter the United States by vessel shall be scanned for radiation. To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall deploy next generation radiation detection technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Strategy The Secretary shall develop a strategy for the deployment of radiation detection capabilities that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Standards The Secretary, acting through the Director for Domestic Nuclear Detection 11 See Change of Name note below. and in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall publish technical capability standards and recommended standard operating procedures for the use of nonintrusive imaging and radiation detection equipment in the United States. Such standards and procedures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation Not later than 3 years after October 13, 2006, the Secretary shall fully implement the strategy developed under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion to other United States ports of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expansion to other United States ports of entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_921_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermodal Rail Radiation Detection Test Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Intermodal Rail Radiation Detection Test Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>