<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/942" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/942/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/942/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_942"><akn:num>942</akn:num><akn:heading>Post-incident resumption of trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 942. Post-incident resumption of trade(a) In generalThe Secretary shall develop and update, as necessary, protocols for the resumption of trade in accordance with section 941(b)(10) of this title in the event of a transportation disruption or a transportation security incident. The protocols shall include—(1) the identification of the appropriate initial incident commander, if the Commandant of the Coast Guard is not the appropriate person, and lead departments, agencies, or offices to execute such protocols;

(2) a plan to redeploy resources and personnel, as necessary, to reestablish the flow of trade;

(3) a plan to provide training for the periodic instruction of personnel of the United States Customs and Border Protection, the Coast Guard, and the Transportation Security Administration in trade resumption functions and responsibilities; and

(4) appropriate factors for establishing prioritization of vessels and cargo determined by the President to be critical for response and recovery, including factors relating to public health, national security, and economic need.


(b) VesselsIn determining the prioritization of vessels accessing facilities (as defined under section 70101 of title 46), the Commandant of the Coast Guard may, to the extent practicable and consistent with the protocols and plans required under this section to ensure the safe and secure transit of vessels to ports in the United States after a transportation security incident, give priority to a vessel—(1) that has an approved security plan under section 70103(c) of title 46 or a valid international ship security certificate, as provided under part 104 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations;

(2) that is manned by individuals who are described in section 70105(b)(2)(B) of title 46; and

(3) that is operated by validated participants in the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program.


(c) CargoIn determining the prioritization of the resumption of the flow of cargo and consistent wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall develop and update, as necessary, protocols for the resumption of trade in accordance with section 941(b)(10) of this title in the event of a transportation disruption or a transportation security incident. The protocols shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Vessels In determining the prioritization of vessels accessing facilities (as defined under section 70101 of title 46), the Commandant of the Coast Guard may, to the extent practicable and consistent with the protocols and plans required under this section to ensure the safe and secure transit of vessels to ports in the United States after a transportation security incident, give priority to a vessel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cargo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cargo In determining the prioritization of the resumption of the flow of cargo and consistent with the protocols established under this section, the Commissioner may give preference to cargo—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination The Secretary shall ensure that there is appropriate coordination among the Commandant of the Coast Guard, the Commissioner, and other Federal officials following a maritime disruption or maritime transportation security incident in order to provide for the resumption of trade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Communication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Communication Consistent with section 941 of this title, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, Commissioner, and other appropriate Federal officials, shall promptly communicate any revised procedures or instructions intended for the private sector following a maritime disruption or maritime transportation security incident.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>