<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/966" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/966/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/6/966/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_966"><akn:num>966</akn:num><akn:heading>Tier 3 participants in C–TPAT</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 966. Tier 3 participants in C–TPAT(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall establish a third tier of C–TPAT participation that offers additional benefits to participants who demonstrate a sustained commitment to maintaining security measures and supply chain security practices that exceed the guidelines established for validation as a Tier 2 participant in C–TPAT under section 965 of this title.


(b) CriteriaThe Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall designate criteria for validating a C–TPAT participant as a Tier 3 participant under this section. Such criteria may include—(1) compliance with any additional guidelines established by the Secretary that exceed the guidelines established pursuant to section 965 of this title for validating a C–TPAT participant as a Tier 2 participant, particularly with respect to controls over access to cargo throughout the supply chain;

(2) submission of additional information regarding cargo prior to loading, as determined by the Secretary;

(3) utilization of container security devices, technologies, policies, or practices that meet standards and criteria established by the Secretary; and

(4) compliance with any other cargo requirements established by the Secretary.


(c) BenefitsThe Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, in consultation with the Commercial Operations Advisory Committee and the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee, shall extend benefits to each C–TPAT participant that has been validated as a Tier 3 participant under this section, which may include—(1) the expedited release of a Tier 3 participant’s cargo in destination ports within the United States during all threat levels designated by the Secretary;

(2) further reduction in examinations of cargo;

(3) priority for examinations of cargo; and

(4) further reduction in the risk score assigned pursuant to the Automated Targeting System; and

(5) inclusion in joint incident management exercises, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_966_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall establish a third tier of C–TPAT participation that offers additional benefits to participants who demonstrate a sustained commitment to maintaining security measures and supply chain security practices that exceed the guidelines established for validation as a Tier 2 participant in C–TPAT under section 965 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_966_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall designate criteria for validating a C–TPAT participant as a Tier 3 participant under this section. Such criteria may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_966_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Benefits The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, in consultation with the Commercial Operations Advisory Committee and the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee, shall extend benefits to each C–TPAT participant that has been validated as a Tier 3 participant under this section, which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_966_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deadline Not later than 2 years after October 13, 2006, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall designate appropriate criteria pursuant to subsection (b) and provide benefits to validated Tier 3 participants pursuant to subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>