<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1021"><akn:num>1021</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declarations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1021. Congressional declarations(a) GenerallyThe Congress declares that it is the continuing policy and responsibility of the Federal Government to use all practicable means, consistent with its needs and obligations and other essential national policies, and with the assistance and cooperation of both small and larger businesses, agriculture, labor, and State and local governments, to coordinate and utilize all its plans, functions, and resources for the purpose of creating and maintaining, in a manner calculated to foster and promote free competitive enterprise and the general welfare, conditions which promote useful employment opportunities, including self-employment, for those able, willing, and seeking to work, and promote full employment and production, increased real income, balanced growth, a balanced Federal budget, adequate productivity growth, proper attention to national priorities, achievement of an improved trade balance through increased exports and improvement in the international competitiveness of agriculture, business, and industry, and reasonable price stability as provided in section 1022b(b) of this title.


(b) Full opportunities for employmentThe Congress further declares and establishes as a national goal the fulfillment of the right to full opportunities for useful paid employment at fair rates of compensation of all individuals able, willing, and seeking to work.


(c) InflationThe Congress further declares that inflation is a major national problem requiring improved government policies relating to food, energy, improved and coordinated fiscal and monetary management, the reform of outmoded rules and regulations of the Federal Government, the correction of structural defects in the economy that prevent or seriously impede competition in private markets, and other measures to reduce the rate of inflation.


(d) Coordination of Federal policies and programsThe Congress further declares that it is the purpose of the Full Employment and Bal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Generally The Congress declares that it is the continuing policy and responsibility of the Federal Government to use all practicable means, consistent with its needs and obligations and other essential national policies, and with the assistance and cooperation of both small and larger businesses, agriculture, labor, and State and local governments, to coordinate and utilize all its plans, functions, and resources for the purpose of creating and maintaining, in a manner calculated to foster and promote free competitive enterprise and the general welfare, conditions which promote useful employment opportunities, including self-employment, for those able, willing, and seeking to work, and promote full employment and production, increased real income, balanced growth, a balanced Federal budget, adequate productivity growth, proper attention to national priorities, achievement of an improved trade balance through increased exports and improvement in the international competitiveness of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full opportunities for employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Full opportunities for employment The Congress further declares and establishes as a national goal the fulfillment of the right to full opportunities for useful paid employment at fair rates of compensation of all individuals able, willing, and seeking to work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inflation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inflation The Congress further declares that inflation is a major national problem requiring improved government policies relating to food, energy, improved and coordinated fiscal and monetary management, the reform of outmoded rules and regulations of the Federal Government, the correction of structural defects in the economy that prevent or seriously impede competition in private markets, and other measures to reduce the rate of inflation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Federal policies and programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination of Federal policies and programs The Congress further declares that it is the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] to improve the coordination and integration of the policies and programs of the Federal Government toward achievement of the objectives of such Act through better management, increased efficiency, and attention to long-range as well as short-range problems and to balancing the Federal budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal controls The Congress further declares that, although it is the purpose under the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] to seek diligently and to encourage the voluntary cooperation of the private sector in helping to achieve the objectives of such Act, no provisions of such Act or this chapter shall be used, with respect to any portion of the private sector of the economy, to provide for Federal Government control of production, employment, allocation of resources, or wages and prices, except to the extent authorized under other Federal laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of private employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expansion of private employment The Congress further declares that it is the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] to maximize and place primary emphasis upon the expansion of private employment, and all programs and policies under such Act shall be in accord with such purpose. Toward this end, the effort to expand jobs to the full employment level shall be in this order of priority to the extent consistent with balanced growth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade deficits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Trade deficits The Congress further declares that trade deficits are a major national problem requiring a strong national export policy including improved Government policies relating to the promotion, facilitation, and financing of commercial and agricultural exports, Government policies designed to reduce foreign barriers to exports through international negotiation and agreement, Federal support for research, development, and diffusion of new technologies to promote innovation in agriculture, business, and industry, the elimination or modification of Government rules or regulations that burden or disadvantage exports and the national and international competitiveness of agriculture, business, and industry, the reexamination of antitrust laws and policies when necessary to enable agriculture, business, and industry to meet foreign competition in the United States and abroad, and the achievement of a free and fair international trading system and a sound and stable international m</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Balanced Federal budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Balanced Federal budget The Congress further declares that it is the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] to achieve a balanced Federal budget consistent with the achievement of the medium-term goals specified in section 1022a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment needs of private enterprise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Investment needs of private enterprise The Congress further declares that it is the continuing policy and responsibility of the Federal Government, in cooperation with State and local governments, to use all practical means consistent with other essential considerations of national policy to provide sufficient incentives to assure meeting the investment needs of private enterprise, including the needs of small and medium sized businesses, in order to increase the production of goods, the provision of services, employment, the opportunity for profit, the payment of taxes, and to reduce and control inflation. To the extent it is reasonably possible to do so, private enterprise investments in depressed urban and rural areas should be promoted to reduce the high levels of unemployment that exist there.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reliance on private sector</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reliance on private sector The Congress further declares that it is the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] to rely principally on the private sector for expansion of economic activity and creation of new jobs for a growing labor force. Toward this end, it is the purpose of this chapter to encourage the adoption of fiscal policies that would establish the share of the gross national product accounted for by Federal outlays at the lowest level consistent with national needs and priorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>