<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1022" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1022/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1022/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1022"><akn:num>1022</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic Report of President; coverage; supplementary reports; reference to Congressional joint comm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1022. Economic Report of President; coverage; supplementary reports; reference to Congressional joint committee; percentage rate of unemployment; definitions(a) Time of submission; contentsThe President shall annually transmit to the Congress not later than 10 days after the submission of the budget under section 1105(a) of title 31, with copies transmitted to the Governor of each State and to other appropriate State and local officials, an economic report (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Economic Report”) together with the annual report of the Council of Economic Advisers submitted in accord with section 1023(c) of this title, setting forth—(1) the current and foreseeable trends in the levels of employment, unemployment, production, capital formation, real income, Federal budget outlays and receipts, productivity, international trade and payments, and prices, and a review and analysis of recent domestic and international developments affecting economic trends in the Nation;

(2)(A) annual numerical goals for employment and unemployment, production, real income, productivity, Federal outlays as a proportion of gross national product, and prices for the calendar year in which the Economic Report is transmitted and for the following calendar year, designated as short-term goals, which shall be consistent with achieving as rapidly as feasible the goals of full employment and production, increased real income, balanced growth, fiscal policies that would establish the share of an expanding gross national product accounted for by Federal outlays at the lowest level consistent with national needs and priorities, a balanced Federal budget, adequate productivity growth, price stability, achievement of an improved trade balance, and proper attention to national priorities; and

(B) annual numerical goals as specified in subparagraph (A) for the three successive calendar years, designated as medium term goals;


(3) employment objectives for certain significa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1022_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of submission; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Time of submission; contents The President shall annually transmit to the Congress not later than 10 days after the submission of the budget under section 1105(a) of title 31, with copies transmitted to the Governor of each State and to other appropriate State and local officials, an economic report (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Economic Report”) together with the annual report of the Council of Economic Advisers submitted in accord with section 1023(c) of this title, setting forth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1022_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supplementary reports The President may transmit from time to time to the Congress reports supplementary to the Economic Report, each of which shall include such supplementary or revised recommendations as he may deem necessary or desirable to achieve the policy declared in section 1021 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1022_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral to joint committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Referral to joint committee The Economic Report, and all supplementary reports transmitted under subsection (b), shall, when transmitted to Congress, be referred to the joint committee created by section 1024 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1022_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of unemployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rate of unemployment For the purposes of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.] the percentage rate of unemployment as 11 So in original. Probably should be “is”. a percentage of the civilian labor force as set forth by the Bureau of Labor Statistics in the Department of Labor as computed under the procedures in effect as of October 27, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1022_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Inflation”; “prices”; “reasonable price stability” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Inflation”; “prices”; “reasonable price stability” defined For the purpose of the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.], the terms “inflation”, “prices”, and “reasonable price stability” refer to the rate of change or level of the consumer price index as set forth by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>