<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1023" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1023/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1023/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1023"><akn:num>1023</akn:num><akn:heading>Council of Economic Advisers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1023. Council of Economic Advisers(a) Creation; composition; qualifications; chairman and vice chairman(1) CreationThere is created in the Executive Office of the President a Council of Economic Advisers (hereinafter called the “Council”).


(2) CompositionThe Council shall be composed of three members, of whom—(A) 1 shall be the chairman who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and

(B) 2 shall be appointed by the President.


(3) QualificationsEach member shall be a person who, as a result of training, experience, and attainments, is exceptionally qualified to analyze and interpret economic developments, to appraise programs and activities of the Government in the light of the policy declared in section 1021 of this title, and to formulate and recommend national economic policy to promote full employment, production, and purchasing power under free competitive enterprise.


(4) Vice chairmanThe President shall designate 1 of the members of the Council as vice chairman, who shall act as chairman in the absence of the chairman.



(b) Employment of specialists, experts, and other personnelThe Council is authorized to employ, and fix the compensation of, such specialists and other experts as may be necessary for the carrying out of its functions under this chapter, without regard to the civil-service laws, and is authorized, subject to the civil-service laws, to employ such other officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out its functions under this chapter, and fix their compensation in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.


(c) DutiesIt shall be the duty and function of the Council—(1) to assist and advise the President in the preparation of the Economic Report;

(2) to gather timely and authoritative information concerning economic developments and economic trends, both current and prospective, to analyze and interpret such information in the light of the policy dec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation; composition; qualifications; chairman and vice chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation; composition; qualifications; chairman and vice chairman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of specialists, experts, and other personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment of specialists, experts, and other personnel The Council is authorized to employ, and fix the compensation of, such specialists and other experts as may be necessary for the carrying out of its functions under this chapter, without regard to the civil-service laws, and is authorized, subject to the civil-service laws, to employ such other officers and employees as may be necessary for carrying out its functions under this chapter, and fix their compensation in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties It shall be the duty and function of the Council—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual report The Council shall make an annual report to the President in December of each year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with other groups and agencies; utilization of Government services and private research agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with other groups and agencies; utilization of Government services and private research agencies In exercising its powers, functions and duties under this chapter— In its work under this chapter and the Full Employment and Balanced Growth Act of 1978 [15 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.], the Council is authorized and directed to seek and obtain the cooperation of the various executive and independent agencies in the development of specialized studies essential to its responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1023_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appropriations To enable the Council to exercise its powers, functions, and duties under this chapter, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>