<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1025/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1025/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1025"><akn:num>1025</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing of monthly publication by Joint Economic Committee entitled “Economic Indicators”; distribu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1025. Printing of monthly publication by Joint Economic Committee entitled “Economic Indicators”; distribution
The Joint Economic Committee is authorized to issue a monthly publication entitled “Economic Indicators”, and a sufficient quantity shall be printed to furnish one copy to each Member of Congress; the Secretary and the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate; the Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, and Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives; two copies to the libraries of the Senate and House, and the Congressional Library; seven hundred copies to the Joint Economic Committee; and the required number of copies to the Superintendent of Documents for distribution to depository libraries; and the Superintendent of Documents is authorized to have copies printed for sale to the public.
(June 23, 1949, ch. 237, 63 Stat. 264; Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 217, Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1747.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as a part of the Employment Act of 1946 which comprises this chapter.
“Joint Economic Committee” substituted in text for “Joint Committee on the Economic Report” to conform to act June 18, 1956, ch. 399, § 2, 70 Stat. 290. See section 1024(a) of this title.

Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–186 substituted “Chief Administrative Officer” for “Doorkeeper”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>