<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1066a"><akn:num>1066a</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte expungement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1066a. Ex parte expungement(a) PetitionNotwithstanding sections 1057(b) and 1072 of this title, and subsections (a) and (b) of section 1115 of this title, any person may file a petition to expunge a registration of a mark on the basis that the mark has never been used in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services recited in the registration.


(b) Contents of petitionA petition filed under subsection (a), together with any supporting documents, shall—(1) identify the registration that is the subject of the petition;

(2) identify each good or service recited in the registration for which it is alleged that the mark has never been used in commerce;

(3) include a verified statement that sets forth—(A) the elements of the reasonable investigation the petitioner conducted to determine that the mark has never been used in commerce on or in connection with the goods and services identified in the petition; and

(B) any additional facts that support the allegation that the mark has never been used in commerce on or in connection with the identified goods and services;


(4) include any supporting evidence on which the petitioner relies; and

(5) be accompanied by the fee prescribed by the Director.


(c) Initial determination; institution(1) Prima facie case determination, institution, and notificationThe Director shall, for each good or service identified under subsection (b)(2), determine whether the petition sets forth a prima facie case of the mark having never been used in commerce on or in connection with each such good or service, institute an ex parte expungement proceeding for each good or service for which the Director determines that a prima facie case has been set forth, and provide a notice to the registrant and petitioner of the determination of whether or not the proceeding was instituted. Such notice shall include a copy of the petition and any supporting documents and evidence that were included with the petition.


(2) Reaso</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petition Notwithstanding sections 1057(b) and 1072 of this title, and subsections (a) and (b) of section 1115 of this title, any person may file a petition to expunge a registration of a mark on the basis that the mark has never been used in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services recited in the registration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of petition A petition filed under subsection (a), together with any supporting documents, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial determination; institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initial determination; institution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte expungement procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ex parte expungement procedures The procedures for ex parte expungement shall be the same as the procedures for examination under section 1062(b) of this title, except that the Director shall promulgate regulations establishing and governing a proceeding under this section, which may include regulations that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registrant’s evidence of use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Registrant’s evidence of use A registrant’s documentary evidence of use shall be consistent with when a mark shall be deemed to be in use in commerce under the definition of “use in commerce” in section 1127 of this title, but shall not be limited in form to that of specimens as provided in section 1051(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excusable nonuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Excusable nonuse During an ex parte expungement proceeding, for a mark registered under section 1126(e) of this title or an extension of protection under section 1141f of this title, the registrant may offer evidence showing that any nonuse is due to special circumstances that excuse such nonuse. In such a case, the examiner shall determine whether the facts and evidence demonstrate excusable nonuse and shall not find that the registration should be cancelled under subsection (g) for any good or service for which excusable nonuse is demonstrated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examiner’s decision; order to cancel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Examiner’s decision; order to cancel For each good or service for which it is determined that a mark has never been used in commerce, and for which the provisions of subsection (f) do not apply, the examiner shall find that the registration should be cancelled for each such good or service. A mark shall not be found to have never been used in commerce if there is evidence of use in commerce by the registrant that temporally would have supported registration at the time the application was filed or the relevant allegation of use was made, or after registration, but before the petition to expunge was filed under subsection (a), or an ex parte expungement proceeding was instituted by the Director under subsection (h). Unless overturned on review of the examiner’s decision, the Director shall issue an order cancelling the registration, in whole or in part, after the time for appeal has expired or any appeal proceeding has terminated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte expungement by the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Ex parte expungement by the Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Time for institution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on later ex parte expungement proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on later ex parte expungement proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>