<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1066b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1066b"><akn:num>1066b</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte reexamination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1066b. Ex parte reexamination(a) Petition for reexaminationAny person may file a petition to reexamine a registration of a mark on the basis that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services recited in the registration on or before the relevant date.


(b) Relevant dateIn this section, the term “relevant date” means, with respect to an application for the registration of a mark with an initial filing basis of—(1) section 1051(a) of this title and not amended at any point to be filed pursuant to section 1051(b) of this title, the date on which the application was initially filed; or

(2) section 1051(b) of this title or amended at any point to be filed pursuant to section 1051(b) of this title, the date on which—(A) an amendment to allege use under section 1051(c) of this title was filed; or

(B) the period for filing a statement of use under section 1051(d) of this title expired, including all approved extensions thereof.



(c) Requirements for the petitionA petition filed under subsection (a), together with any supporting documents, shall—(1) identify the registration that is the subject of the petition;

(2) identify each good and service recited in the registration for which it is alleged that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with on or before the relevant date;

(3) include a verified statement that sets forth—(A) the elements of the reasonable investigation the petitioner conducted to determine that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with the goods and services identified in the petition on or before the relevant date; and

(B) any additional facts that support the allegation that the mark was not in use in commerce on or before the relevant date on or in connection with the identified goods and services;


(4) include supporting evidence on which the petitioner relies; and

(5) be accompanied by the fee prescribed by the Director.


(d) Initial determination; in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for reexamination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petition for reexamination Any person may file a petition to reexamine a registration of a mark on the basis that the mark was not in use in commerce on or in connection with some or all of the goods or services recited in the registration on or before the relevant date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relevant date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relevant date In this section, the term “relevant date” means, with respect to an application for the registration of a mark with an initial filing basis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for the petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for the petition A petition filed under subsection (a), together with any supporting documents, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial determination; institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initial determination; institution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reexamination procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reexamination procedures The procedures for reexamination shall be the same as the procedures established under section 1062(b) of this title except that the Director shall promulgate regulations establishing and governing a proceeding under this section, which may include regulations that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registrant’s evidence of use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Registrant’s evidence of use A registrant’s documentary evidence of use shall be consistent with when a mark shall be deemed to be in use in commerce under the definition of “use in commerce” in section 1127 of this title, but shall not be limited in form to that of specimens as provided in section 1051(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examiner’s decision; order to cancel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Examiner’s decision; order to cancel For each good or service for which it is determined that the registration should not have issued because the mark was not in use in commerce on or before the relevant date, the examiner shall find that the registration should be cancelled for each such good or service. Unless overturned on review of the examiner’s decision, the Director shall issue an order cancelling the registration, in whole or in part, after the time for appeal has expired or any appeal proceeding has terminated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reexamination by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reexamination by Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Time for institution A petition for ex parte reexamination may be filed, or the Director may institute on the Director’s own initiative an ex parte reexamination proceeding, at any time not later than 5 years after the date of registration of a mark registered based on use in commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on later ex parte reexamination proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on later ex parte reexamination proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>