<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1112"><akn:num>1112</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of goods and services; registration in plurality of classes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1112. Classification of goods and services; registration in plurality of classes
The Director may establish a classification of goods and services, for convenience of Patent and Trademark Office administration, but not to limit or extend the applicant’s or registrant’s rights. The applicant may apply to register a mark for any or all of the goods or services on or in connection with which he or she is using or has a bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce: Provided, That if the Director by regulation permits the filing of an application for the registration of a mark for goods or services which fall within a plurality of classes, a fee equaling the sum of the fees for filing an application in each class shall be paid, and the Director may issue a single certificate of registration for such mark.
(July 5, 1946, ch. 540, title IV, § 30, 60 Stat. 436; Pub. L. 87–772, § 16, Oct. 9, 1962, 76 Stat. 773; Pub. L. 93–596, § 1, Jan. 2, 1975, 88 Stat. 1949; Pub. L. 100–667, title I, § 126, Nov. 16, 1988, 102 Stat. 3943; Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(9) [title IV, § 4732(b)(1)(B)], Nov. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 1536, 1501A–583.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsAct May 4, 1906, ch. 2081, § 2, 34 Stat. 169.

Amendments1999—Pub. L. 106–113 substituted “Director” for “Commissioner” wherever appearing.
1988—Pub. L. 100–667 inserted “or registrant’s” after “applicant’s” and substituted “may apply” for “may file an application”, “goods or services on or in connection with which he or she is using or has a bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce:” for “goods and services upon or in connection with which he is actually using the mark:”, and “Provided, That if the Commissioner by regulation permits the filing of an application for the registration of a mark for goods or services which fall” for “Provided, That when such goods or services fall”.
1975—Pub. L. 93–596 substituted “Patent and Trademark Office” for “Patent Office”.
1962—Pub. L. 87–772, among other changes, s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>