<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1141"><akn:num>1141</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1141. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Basic applicationThe term “basic application” means the application for the registration of a mark that has been filed with an Office of a Contracting Party and that constitutes the basis for an application for the international registration of that mark.


(2) Basic registrationThe term “basic registration” means the registration of a mark that has been granted by an Office of a Contracting Party and that constitutes the basis for an application for the international registration of that mark.


(3) Contracting PartyThe term “Contracting Party” means any country or inter-governmental organization that is a party to the Madrid Protocol.


(4) Date of recordalThe term “date of recordal” means the date on which a request for extension of protection, filed after an international registration is granted, is recorded on the International Register.


(5) Declaration of bona fide intention to use the mark in commerceThe term “declaration of bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce” means a declaration that is signed by the applicant for, or holder of, an international registration who is seeking extension of protection of a mark to the United States and that contains a statement that—(A) the applicant or holder has a bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce;

(B) the person making the declaration believes himself or herself, or the firm, corporation, or association in whose behalf he or she makes the declaration, to be entitled to use the mark in commerce; and

(C) no other person, firm, corporation, or association, to the best of his or her knowledge and belief, has the right to use such mark in commerce either in the identical form of the mark or in such near resemblance to the mark as to be likely, when used on or in connection with the goods of such other person, firm, corporation, or association, to cause confusion, mistake, or deception.


(6) Extension of protectionThe term “extension of protection” means the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Basic application The term “basic application” means the application for the registration of a mark that has been filed with an Office of a Contracting Party and that constitutes the basis for an application for the international registration of that mark.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Basic registration The term “basic registration” means the registration of a mark that has been granted by an Office of a Contracting Party and that constitutes the basis for an application for the international registration of that mark.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting Party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Contracting Party The term “Contracting Party” means any country or inter-governmental organization that is a party to the Madrid Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date of recordal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Date of recordal The term “date of recordal” means the date on which a request for extension of protection, filed after an international registration is granted, is recorded on the International Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Declaration of bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce The term “declaration of bona fide intention to use the mark in commerce” means a declaration that is signed by the applicant for, or holder of, an international registration who is seeking extension of protection of a mark to the United States and that contains a statement that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Extension of protection The term “extension of protection” means the protection resulting from an international registration that extends to the United States at the request of the holder of the international registration, in accordance with the Madrid Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Holder of an international registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Holder of an international registration A “holder” of an international registration is the natural or juristic person in whose name the international registration is recorded on the International Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>International application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) International application The term “international application” means an application for international registration that is filed under the Madrid Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) International Bureau The term “International Bureau” means the International Bureau of the World Intellectual Property Organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1141_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) International Register The term “International Register” means the official collection of data concerning international registrations maintained by the International Bureau that the Madrid Protocol or its implementing regulations require or permit to be recorded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>