<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1193" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1193/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1193/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1193"><akn:num>1193</akn:num><akn:heading>Flammability standards or regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1193. Flammability standards or regulations(a) Proceedings by Commission for determinationWhenever the Commission finds on the basis of the investigations or research conducted pursuant to section 1201 of this title that a new or amended flammability standard or other regulation, including labeling, for a fabric, related material, or product may be needed to protect the public against unreasonable risk of the occurrence of fire leading to death or personal injury, or significant property damage, it shall institute proceedings for the determination of an appropriate flammability standard (including conditions and manner of testing) or other regulation or amendment thereto for such fabric, related material, or product.


(b) Necessary findings; effective date; exemptionsEach standard, regulation, or amendment thereto promulgated pursuant to this section shall be based on findings that such standard, regulation, or amendment thereto is needed to adequately protect the public against unreasonable risk of the occurrence of fire leading to death, injury, or significant property damage, is reasonable, technologically practicable, and appropriate, is limited to such fabrics, related materials, or products which have been determined to present such unreasonable risks, and shall be stated in objective terms. Each such standard, regulation, or amendment thereto, shall become effective twelve months from the date on which such standard, regulation, or amendment is promulgated, unless the Commission finds for good cause shown that an earlier or later effective date is in the public interest and publishes the reason for such finding. Each such standard or regulation or amendment thereto shall exempt fabrics related materials, or products in inventory or with the trade as of the date on which the standard, regulation, or amendment thereto, becomes effective except that, if the Commission finds that any such fabric, related material, or product is so highly flammable as to be dan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings by Commission for determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proceedings by Commission for determination Whenever the Commission finds on the basis of the investigations or research conducted pursuant to section 1201 of this title that a new or amended flammability standard or other regulation, including labeling, for a fabric, related material, or product may be needed to protect the public against unreasonable risk of the occurrence of fire leading to death or personal injury, or significant property damage, it shall institute proceedings for the determination of an appropriate flammability standard (including conditions and manner of testing) or other regulation or amendment thereto for such fabric, related material, or product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary findings; effective date; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Necessary findings; effective date; exemptions Each standard, regulation, or amendment thereto promulgated pursuant to this section shall be based on findings that such standard, regulation, or amendment thereto is needed to adequately protect the public against unreasonable risk of the occurrence of fire leading to death, injury, or significant property damage, is reasonable, technologically practicable, and appropriate, is limited to such fabrics, related materials, or products which have been determined to present such unreasonable risks, and shall be stated in objective terms. Each such standard, regulation, or amendment thereto, shall become effective twelve months from the date on which such standard, regulation, or amendment is promulgated, unless the Commission finds for good cause shown that an earlier or later effective date is in the public interest and publishes the reason for such finding. Each such standard or regulation or amendment thereto shall exempt fabrics relat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of information by Commission; confidential status of trade secrets and related information; disclosure of confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Collection of information by Commission; confidential status of trade secrets and related information; disclosure of confidential information The Commission may obtain from any person by regulation or subpena issued pursuant thereto such information in the form of testimony, books, records, or other writings as is pertinent to the findings or determinations which it is required or authorized to make pursuant to this chapter. All information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Commission or its representative pursuant to this subsection which information contains or relates to a trade secret or other matter referred to in section 1905 of title 18, shall be considered confidential for the purpose of that section, except that such information may be disclosed to other officers or employees concerned with carrying out this chapter or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter. Nothing in this section shall authorize the withholding of information by the Commission or any o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of section 553 of title 5; oral presentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of Standards, regulations, and amendments to standards and regulations under this section shall be made in accordance with section 553 of title 5, except that interested persons shall be given an opportunity for the oral presentation of data, views, or arguments in addition to an opportunity to make written submissions. A transcript shall be kept of any oral presentation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review; additional information before Commission; applicability of sections 701 to 706 of title 5; finality of judgment; survival of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial review; additional information before Commission; applicability of sections 701 to 706 of title 5; finality of judgment; survival of action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transcript of proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transcript of proceedings A certified copy of the transcript of the record and proceedings under subsection (e) shall be furnished by the Commission to any interested party at his request, and payment of the costs thereof, and shall be admissible in any criminal, exclusion of imports, or other proceeding arising under or in respect of this chapter, irrespective of whether proceedings with respect to the standard or regulation or amendment thereto have previously been initiated or become final under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of regulation; commencement of proceeding; publication of prescribed notice of proposed rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Promulgation of regulation; commencement of proceeding; publication of prescribed notice of proposed rulemaking A proceeding for the promulgation of a regulation under this section for a fabric, related material, or product may be commenced by a notice of proposed rulemaking or by the publication in the Federal Register of an advance notice of proposed rulemaking which shall— The Commission shall transmit such notice within 10 calendar days to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary standard; publication as proposed regulation; prerequisites for reliance by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Voluntary standard; publication as proposed regulation; prerequisites for reliance by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of proposed rule by Commission; preliminary regulatory analysis; contents; transmission of notice by Commission to Committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Publication of proposed rule by Commission; preliminary regulatory analysis; contents; transmission of notice by Commission to Committees No regulation may be proposed by the Commission under this section unless the Commission publishes in the Federal Register the text of the proposed rule, including any alternatives, which the Commission proposes to promulgate, together with a preliminary regulatory analysis containing— The Commission shall transmit such notice within 10 calendar days to the appropriate Congressional committees. Nothing in this subsection shall preclude any person from submitting an existing standard or portion of a standard as a proposed regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1193_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final regulatory analysis; contents; publication; judicial review of regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Final regulatory analysis; contents; publication; judicial review of regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>