<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1194" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1194/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1194/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1194"><akn:num>1194</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1194. Administration and enforcement(a) Enforcement under Federal Trade Commission Act provisions; civil action to enforce standard or regulationExcept as otherwise specifically provided herein, sections 1192, 1194, 1195, and 1197(b) of this title shall be enforced by the Commission under rules, regulations and procedures provided for in the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.]. In the case of an attorney general of a State alleging a violation of a standard or regulation under section 1193 of this title that affects or may affect such State or its residents, such attorney general may bring a civil action for an injunction to enforce the requirement of such standard or regulation. The procedural requirements of section 2073 of this title shall apply to any such action.


(b) Application of Federal Trade Commission Act provisionsThe Commission is authorized and directed to prevent any person from violating the provisions of section 1192 of this title in the same manner, by the same means and with the same jurisdiction, powers and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.] were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter; and any such person violating any provision of section 1192 of this title shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in said Federal Trade Commission Act as though the applicable terms and provisions of the said Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.


(c) Rules and regulationsThe Commission is authorized and directed to prescribe such rules and regulations, including provisions for maintenance of records relating to fabrics, related materials, and products, as may be necessary and proper for administration and enforcement of this chapter. The violation of such rules and regulations shall be unlawful and shall be an unfair method of competition and an unfair and decepti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1194_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement under Federal Trade Commission Act provisions; civil action to enforce standard or regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforcement under Federal Trade Commission Act provisions; civil action to enforce standard or regulation Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, sections 1192, 1194, 1195, and 1197(b) of this title shall be enforced by the Commission under rules, regulations and procedures provided for in the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.]. In the case of an attorney general of a State alleging a violation of a standard or regulation under section 1193 of this title that affects or may affect such State or its residents, such attorney general may bring a civil action for an injunction to enforce the requirement of such standard or regulation. The procedural requirements of section 2073 of this title shall apply to any such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1194_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Federal Trade Commission Act provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of Federal Trade Commission Act provisions The Commission is authorized and directed to prevent any person from violating the provisions of section 1192 of this title in the same manner, by the same means and with the same jurisdiction, powers and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.] were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter; and any such person violating any provision of section 1192 of this title shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in said Federal Trade Commission Act as though the applicable terms and provisions of the said Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1194_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules and regulations The Commission is authorized and directed to prescribe such rules and regulations, including provisions for maintenance of records relating to fabrics, related materials, and products, as may be necessary and proper for administration and enforcement of this chapter. The violation of such rules and regulations shall be unlawful and shall be an unfair method of competition and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, in commerce, under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1194_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection and analysis of products; cooperation with other governmental entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inspection and analysis of products; cooperation with other governmental entities The Commission is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1194_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>