<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1274"><akn:num>1274</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies respecting banned hazardous substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1274. Remedies respecting banned hazardous substances(a) Notice to protect public; form and contentsIf any article or substance sold in commerce is defined as a banned hazardous substance (whether or not it was such at the time of its sale) and the Commission determines (after affording interested persons, including consumers and consumer organizations, an opportunity for a hearing) that notification is required to adequately protect the public from such article or substance, the Commission may order the manufacturer or any distributor or dealer of the article or substance to take any one or more of the following actions:(1) To give public notice that the article or substance is a banned hazardous substance.

(2) To mail such notice to each person who is a manufacturer, distributor, or dealer of such article or substance.

(3) To mail such notice to every person to whom the person giving the notice knows such article or substance was delivered or sold.


An order under this subsection shall specify the form and content of any notice required to be given under the order.

(b) Order of Commission; repair, replacement, or refundIf any article or substance sold in commerce is defined as a banned hazardous substance (whether or not it was such at the time of its sale) and the Commission determines (after affording interested persons, including consumers and consumer organizations, an opportunity for a hearing) that action under this subsection is in the public interest, the Commission may order the manufacturer, distributor, or dealer to take whichever of the following actions the person to whom the order is directed elects:(1) If repairs to or changes in the article or substance may be made so that it will not be a banned hazardous substance, to make such repairs or changes.

(2) To replace such article or substance with a like or equivalent article or substance which is not a banned hazardous substance.

(3) To refund the purchase price of the article or substance (l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to protect public; form and contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to protect public; form and contents If any article or substance sold in commerce is defined as a banned hazardous substance (whether or not it was such at the time of its sale) and the Commission determines (after affording interested persons, including consumers and consumer organizations, an opportunity for a hearing) that notification is required to adequately protect the public from such article or substance, the Commission may order the manufacturer or any distributor or dealer of the article or substance to take any one or more of the following actions: An order under this subsection shall specify the form and content of any notice required to be given under the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of Commission; repair, replacement, or refund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Order of Commission; repair, replacement, or refund If any article or substance sold in commerce is defined as a banned hazardous substance (whether or not it was such at the time of its sale) and the Commission determines (after affording interested persons, including consumers and consumer organizations, an opportunity for a hearing) that action under this subsection is in the public interest, the Commission may order the manufacturer, distributor, or dealer to take whichever of the following actions the person to whom the order is directed elects: An order under this subsection may also require the person to whom it applies to submit a plan, satisfactory to the Commission, for taking the action which such person has elected to take. The Commission shall specify in the order the persons to whom refunds must be made if the person to whom the order is directed elects to take the action described in paragraph (3). If an order under this subsection is directed to more than one person</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary remedial activities available to Commission; orders; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discretionary remedial activities available to Commission; orders; contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge for remedy; reimbursement for expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Charge for remedy; reimbursement for expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing; representative of class</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hearing; representative of class An order under subsection (a), (b), or (c) may be issued only after an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with section 554 of title 5, except that, if the Commission determines that any person who wishes to participate in such hearing is a part of a class of participants who share an identity of interest, the Commission may limit such person’s participation in such hearing to participation through a single representative designated by such class (or by the Commission if such class fails to designate such a representative).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Manufacturer” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Manufacturer” defined For purposes of this section (1) the term “manufacturer” includes an importer for resale, and (2) a dealer who sells at wholesale an article or substance shall with respect to that sale be considered the distributor of that article or substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-benefit analysis of notification or other action not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cost-benefit analysis of notification or other action not required Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the Commission, in determining that an article or substance distributed in commerce presents a substantial product hazard and that notification or other action under this section should be taken, to prepare a comparison of the costs that would be incurred in providing notification or taking other action under this section with the benefits from such notification or action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>