<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1278"><akn:num>1278</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for labeling certain toys and games</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1278. Requirements for labeling certain toys and games(a) Toys or games for children who are at least 3(1) RequirementThe packaging of any toy or game intended for use by children who are at least 3 years old but not older than 6 years (or such other upper age limit as the Commission may determine, which may not be less than 5 years old), any descriptive material which accompanies such toy or game, and, in the case of bulk sales of such toy or game when unpackaged, any bin, container for retail display, or vending machine from which the unpackaged toy or game is dispensed shall bear or contain the cautionary statement described in paragraph (2) if the toy or game—(A) is manufactured for sale, offered for sale, or distributed in commerce in the United States, and

(B) includes a small part, as defined by the Commission.


(2) LabelThe cautionary statement required by paragraph (1) for a toy or game shall be as follows:




(b) Balloons, small balls, and marbles(1) RequirementIn the case of any latex balloon, any ball with a diameter of 1.75 inches or less intended for children 3 years of age or older, any marble intended for children 3 years of age or older, or any toy or game which contains such a balloon, ball, or marble, which is manufactured for sale, offered for sale, or distributed in commerce in the United States—(A) the packaging of such balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game,

(B) any descriptive material which accompanies such balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game, and

(C) in the case of bulk sales of any such product when unpackaged, any bin, container for retail display, or vending machine from which such unpackaged balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game is dispensed,


shall bear or contain the cautionary statement described in paragraph (2).

(2) LabelThe cautionary statement required under paragraph (1) for a balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game shall be as follows:(A) BalloonsIn the case of balloons, or toys or games that contain latex balloons, the followi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Toys or games for children who are at least 3</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Toys or games for children who are at least 3</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Balloons, small balls, and marbles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Balloons, small balls, and marbles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advertising</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General labeling requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General labeling requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as misbranded hazardous substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment as misbranded hazardous substance A balloon, ball, marble, toy, or game, that is not in compliance with the requirements of this subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “this section”. shall be considered a misbranded hazardous substance under section 1261(p) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>