<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1278a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1278a"><akn:num>1278a</akn:num><akn:heading>Children’s products containing lead; lead paint rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1278a. Children’s products containing lead; lead paint rule(a) General lead ban(1) Treatment as a banned hazardous substanceExcept as expressly provided in subsection (b) beginning on the dates provided in paragraph (2), any children’s product (as defined in section 3(a) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2052(a))) that contains more lead than the limit established by paragraph (2) shall be treated as a banned hazardous substance under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (15 U.S.C. 1261 et seq.).


(2) Lead limit(A) 600 parts per millionExcept as provided in subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E), beginning 180 days after August 14, 2008, the lead limit referred to in paragraph (1) is 600 parts per million total lead content by weight for any part of the product.


(B) 300 parts per millionExcept as provided by subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E), beginning on the date that is 1 year after August 14, 2008, the lead limit referred to in paragraph (1) is 300 parts per million total lead content by weight for any part of the product.


(C) 100 parts per millionExcept as provided in subparagraphs (D) and (E), beginning on the date that is 3 years after August 14, 2008, subparagraph (B) shall be applied by substituting “100 parts per million” for “300 parts per million” unless the Commission determines that a limit of 100 parts per million is not technologically feasible for a product or product category. The Commission may make such a determination only after notice and a hearing and after analyzing the public health protections associated with substantially reducing lead in children’s products.


(D) Alternate reduction of limitIf the Commission determines under subparagraph (C) that the 100 parts per million limit is not technologically feasible for a product or product category, the Commission shall, by regulation, establish an amount that is the lowest amount of lead, lower than 300 parts per million, the Commission determines to be technologically feasible </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General lead ban</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General lead ban</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain materials or products and inaccessible component parts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exclusion of certain materials or products and inaccessible component parts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application with ASTM F963</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application with ASTM F963 To the extent that any regulation promulgated by the Commission under this section (or any section of the Consumer Product Safety Act [15 U.S.C. 2051 et seq.] or any other Act enforced by the Commission, as such Acts are affected by this section) is inconsistent with the ASTM F963 standard, such promulgated regulation shall supersede the ASTM F963 standard to the extent of the inconsistency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technological feasibility defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technological feasibility defined For purposes of this section, a limit shall be deemed technologically feasible with regard to a product or product category if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending rulemaking proceedings to have no effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pending rulemaking proceedings to have no effect The pendency of a rulemaking proceeding to consider— shall not delay the effect of any provision or limit under this section nor shall it stay general enforcement of the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>More stringent lead paint ban</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) More stringent lead paint ban</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1278a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as a regulation under the FHSA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment as a regulation under the FHSA Any ban imposed by subsection (a) or rule promulgated under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, and section 1303.1 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations (as modified pursuant to subsection (f)(1) or (2)), or any successor regulation, shall be considered a regulation of the Commission promulgated under or for the enforcement of section 2(q) of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (15 U.S.C. 1261(q)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>