<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1333" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1333/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1333/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1333"><akn:num>1333</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1333. Labeling(a) Label requirements(1) In generalIt shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture, package, sell, offer to sell, distribute, or import for sale or distribution within the United States any cigarettes the package of which fails to bear, in accordance with the requirements of this section, one of the following labels:
WARNING: Cigarettes are addictive.
WARNING: Tobacco smoke can harm your children.
WARNING: Cigarettes cause fatal lung disease.
WARNING: Cigarettes cause cancer.
WARNING: Cigarettes cause strokes and heart disease.
WARNING: Smoking during pregnancy can harm your baby.
WARNING: Smoking can kill you.
WARNING: Tobacco smoke causes fatal lung disease in nonsmokers.
WARNING: Quitting smoking now greatly reduces serious risks to your health.


(2) Placement; typography; etc.Each label statement required by paragraph (1) shall be located in the upper portion of the front and rear panels of the package, directly on the package underneath the cellophane or other clear wrapping. Each label statement shall comprise the top 50 percent of the front and rear panels of the package. The word “WARNING” shall appear in capital letters and all text shall be in conspicuous and legible 17-point type, unless the text of the label statement would occupy more than 70 percent of such area, in which case the text may be in a smaller conspicuous and legible type size, provided that at least 60 percent of such area is occupied by required text. The text shall be black on a white background, or white on a black background, in a manner that contrasts, by typography, layout, or color, with all other printed material on the package, in an alternating fashion under the plan submitted under subsection (c).


(3) Does not apply to foreign distributionThe provisions of this subsection do not apply to a tobacco product manufacturer or distributor of cigarettes which does not manufacture, package, or import cigarettes for sale or distribution within the United States.


</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Label requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Label requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advertising requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Marketing requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. There are two subsecs. designated (d). Graphic label statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than 24 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall issue regulations that require color graphics depicting the negative health consequences of smoking to accompany the label statements specified in subsection (a)(1). The Secretary may adjust the type size, text and format of the label statements specified in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2) as the Secretary determines appropriate so that both the graphics and the accompanying label statements are clear, conspicuous, legible and appear within the specified area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 Change in required statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary through a rulemaking conducted under section 553 of title 5 may adjust the format, type size, color graphics, and text of any of the label requirements, or establish the format, type size, and text of any other disclosures required under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], if the Secretary finds that such a change would promote greater public understanding of the risks associated with the use of tobacco products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1333_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tar, nicotine, and other smoke constituent disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tar, nicotine, and other smoke constituent disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>