<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/146a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/146a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/146a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_146a"><akn:num>146a</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of suits by or against China Trade Act corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 146a. Jurisdiction of suits by or against China Trade Act corporation
The Federal district courts shall have exclusive original jurisdiction of all suits to which a China Trade Act corporation, or a stockholder, director, or officer thereof in his capacity as such, is a party. Suit against the corporation may be brought in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the Federal district court for any district in which the corporation has an agent and is engaged in doing business.
(Sept. 19, 1922, ch. 346, § 20(a), formerly § 20, 42 Stat. 855; renumbered § 20(a), Feb. 26, 1925, ch. 345, § 10, 43 Stat. 996; June 25, 1936, ch. 804, 49 Stat. 1921; Treaty of Jan. 11, 1943, 57 Stat. 767; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a), 62 Stat. 991; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127, 63 Stat. 107.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section comprises subsec. (a) of section 20 of act Sept. 19, 1922, as amended by act Feb. 26, 1925. Subsec. (b) of section 20 is classified to section 160 of this title.
In the first sentence, the words “(except as provided by the Act entitled ‘An Act creating a United States Court for China and prescribing the jurisdiction thereof,’ approved June 30, 1906, as amended)” have been omitted because that Act (formerly classified to sections 191 to 197, 199, 200, and 202 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse) was repealed by act June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 39, 62 Stat. 992, eff. Sept. 1, 1948.
The provision in the second sentence that suits against the China Trade Act corporation might also be brought in the United States Court for China was omitted as that court is no longer in operation. By the treaty of Jan. 11, 1943, between the United States and China, the United States relinquished extraterritorial rights in China. See Codification note set out under section 142 of this title.
Section was formerly classified to section 53 of Title 28 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, by act June </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>