<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1472a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1472a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1472a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1472a"><akn:num>1472a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special packaging for liquid nicotine containers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1472a. Special packaging for liquid nicotine containers(a) RequirementNotwithstanding section 1261(f)(2) of this title and section 2052(a)(5) of this title, any nicotine provided in a liquid nicotine container sold, offered for sale, manufactured for sale, distributed in commerce, or imported into the United States shall be packaged in accordance with the standards provided in section 1700.15 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, as determined through testing in accordance with the method described in section 1700.20 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, and any subsequent changes to such sections adopted by the Commission.


(b) Savings clause(1) In generalNothing in this section shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to regulate, issue guidance, or take action regarding the manufacture, marketing, sale, distribution, importation, or packaging, including child-resistant packaging, of nicotine, liquid nicotine, liquid nicotine containers, electronic cigarettes, electronic nicotine delivery systems or other similar products that contain or dispense liquid nicotine, or any other nicotine-related products, including—(A) authority under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.) and the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (Public Law 111–31) and the amendments made by such Act; and

(B) authority for the rulemaking entitled “Deeming Tobacco Products to Be Subject to the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as Amended by the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act; regulations on the Sale and Distribution of Tobacco Products and the Required Warning Statements for Tobacco Products” (April 2014) (FDA–2014–N–0189), the rulemaking entitled “Nicotine Exposure Warnings and Child-Resistant Packaging for Liquid Nicotine, Nicotine-Containing E-Liquid(s), and Other Tobacco Products” (June 2015) (FDA–2015–N–1514), and subsequent actions by the Secretary reg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1472a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement Notwithstanding section 1261(f)(2) of this title and section 2052(a)(5) of this title, any nicotine provided in a liquid nicotine container sold, offered for sale, manufactured for sale, distributed in commerce, or imported into the United States shall be packaged in accordance with the standards provided in section 1700.15 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, as determined through testing in accordance with the method described in section 1700.20 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, and any subsequent changes to such sections adopted by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1472a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Savings clause</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1472a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability Notwithstanding section 2052(a)(5) of this title and section 1261(f)(2) of this title, the requirement of subsection (a) shall be treated as a standard for the special packaging of a household substance established under section 3(a) of the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 1472(a)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1472a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>