<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1511d"><akn:num>1511d</akn:num><akn:heading>Chesapeake Bay Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1511d. Chesapeake Bay Office(a) Establishment(1) The Secretary of Commerce shall establish, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, an office to be known as the Chesapeake Bay Office (in this section referred to as the “Office”).

(2) The Office shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council. Any individual appointed as Director shall have knowledge and experience in research or resource management efforts in the Chesapeake Bay.

(3) The Director may appoint such additional personnel for the Office as the Director determines necessary to carry out this section.


(b) FunctionsThe Office, in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council, shall—(1) provide technical assistance to the Administrator, to other Federal departments and agencies, and to State and local government agencies in—(A) assessing the processes that shape the Chesapeake Bay system and affect its living resources;

(B) identifying technical and management alternatives for the restoration and protection of living resources and the habitats they depend upon; and

(C) monitoring the implementation and effectiveness of management plans;


(2) develop and implement a strategy for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that integrates the science, research, monitoring, data collection, regulatory, and management responsibilities of the Secretary of Commerce in such a manner as to assist the cooperative, intergovernmental Chesapeake Bay Program to meet the commitments of the Chesapeake Bay Agreement;

(3) coordinate the programs and activities of the various organizations within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Chesapeake Bay Regional Sea Grant Programs, and the Chesapeake Bay units of the National Estuarine Research Reserve System, including—(A) programs and activities in—(i) coastal and estuarine research, monitoring, and assessment;

(ii) fisheries rese</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Office, in consultation with the Chesapeake Executive Council, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chesapeake Bay fishery and habitat restoration small watershed grants program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chesapeake Bay fishery and habitat restoration small watershed grants program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chesapeake Executive Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chesapeake Executive Council For purposes of this section, “Chesapeake Executive Council” means the representatives from the Commonwealth of Virginia, the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania, the Environmental Protection Agency, the District of Columbia, and the Chesapeake Bay Commission, who are signatories to the Chesapeake Bay Agreement, and any future signatories to that Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce for the Chesapeake Bay Office $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>