<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1511b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1511b"><akn:num>1511b</akn:num><akn:heading>United States fishery trade officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1511b. United States fishery trade officers(a) AppointmentFor purposes of carrying out export promotion and other fishery development responsibilities, the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall appoint not fewer than six officers who shall serve abroad to promote United States fishing interests. These officers shall be knowledgeable about the United States fishing industry, preferably with experience derived from the harvesting, processing, or marketing sectors of the industry or from the administration of fisheries programs. Such officers, who shall be employees of the Department of Commerce, shall have the designation of fishery trade officers.


(b) AssignmentUpon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of State shall officially assign fishery trade officers to such diplomatic missions of the United States as the Secretary designates (three of which shall be those in Brussels, Belgium; Rome, Italy; and Tokyo, Japan) and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by foreign service personnel of comparable rank and salary.


(c) Functions of fishery trade officersThe functions of fishery trade officers appointed under subsection (a) shall be—(1) to increase the effectiveness of United States fishery export promotion efforts through such activities as the coordination of market development efforts and the provision of services and facilities for exporters of United States fishery products;

(2) to develop, maintain, and make available to interested persons listings of (A) trade, government, and other organizations that are concerned with, or have an interest in, international trade in United States fishery products, and (B) United States fishery products available for such trade;

(3) to prepare quarterly reports regarding (A) the supply, demand, and prices of each United States fishery product exported, or for which there may be export potential, to the foreign nati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment For purposes of carrying out export promotion and other fishery development responsibilities, the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall appoint not fewer than six officers who shall serve abroad to promote United States fishing interests. These officers shall be knowledgeable about the United States fishing industry, preferably with experience derived from the harvesting, processing, or marketing sectors of the industry or from the administration of fisheries programs. Such officers, who shall be employees of the Department of Commerce, shall have the designation of fishery trade officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assignment Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of State shall officially assign fishery trade officers to such diplomatic missions of the United States as the Secretary designates (three of which shall be those in Brussels, Belgium; Rome, Italy; and Tokyo, Japan) and shall obtain for them diplomatic privileges and immunities equivalent to those enjoyed by foreign service personnel of comparable rank and salary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of fishery trade officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of fishery trade officers The functions of fishery trade officers appointed under subsection (a) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration The Secretary of State and the Secretary shall enter into cooperative arrangements concerning the provision of office space, equipment, facilities, clerical services, and such other administrative support as may be required for fishery trade officers and their families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>