<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1517"><akn:num>1517</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of statistical or scientific work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1517. Transfer of statistical or scientific work
The President is authorized, by order in writing, to transfer at any time the whole or any part of any office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service engaged in statistical or scientific work, from the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Defense, the Department of Justice, the United States Postal Service, or the Department of the Interior, to the Department of Commerce; and in every such case the duties and authority performed by and conferred by law upon such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof so transferred, shall be thereby transferred with such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof which is so transferred. All power and authority conferred by law, both supervisory and appellate, upon the department from which such transfer is made, or the Secretary thereof, in relation to the said office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service, or the part thereof so transferred, shall immediately, when such transfer is so ordered by the President, be fully conferred upon and vested in the Department of Commerce, or the Secretary thereof, as the case may be, as to the whole or part of such office, bureau, division, or other branch of the public service so transferred.
(Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 12, 32 Stat. 830; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 201(a), 61 Stat. 499; Aug. 10, 1949, ch. 412, § 4, 63 Stat. 579; Pub. L. 91–375, §§ 4(a), 6(o), Aug. 12, 1970, 84 Stat. 773, 783.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 602 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.
Section is based on section 12 of act Feb. 14, 1903, as originally enacted. Section 12 of the act was amended generally by Pub. L. 93–498, § 23, Oct. 29, 1974, </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>