<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1534"><akn:num>1534</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of fees for access to environmental data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1534. Assessment of fees for access to environmental data(a) Basis of assessmentExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary is authorized to assess fees, based on fair market value, for access to environmental data and information and products derived therefrom collected and/or archived by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.


(b) Eligible recipients; waiver of fees in cases of foreign governments and international organizations(1) The Secretary shall provide data, information, and products described in subsection (a) to Federal, State, and local government agencies, to universities, and to other nonprofit institutions at the cost of reproduction and transmission, if such data, information, and products are to be used for research and not for commercial purposes.

(2) The Secretary shall waive the assessment of fees under subsection (a) as necessary to continue to provide data, information, or products to foreign governments and international organizations on a basis of exchanging such data, information, and products or as otherwise provided by international agreement.

(3) The Secretary shall waive the assessment of fees authorized by subsection (a) as necessary to continue to provide weather warnings, watches, and similar products and services essential to the mission of the National Oceanic Atmospheric 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “and”. Administration.


(c) Publication of fee schedules in Federal Register; initial schedule effective for three-year periodThe initial schedule of any fees assessed under this section, and any subsequent amendment to such schedule, shall be published by the Secretary in the Federal Register at least 30 days before such fees will take effect. The initial schedule shall remain in effect without amendment for the three-year period beginning on the date that fees under the schedule take effect.


(d) Effective date of assessments; progressive incrementsAny assessment of fees under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis of assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basis of assessment Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary is authorized to assess fees, based on fair market value, for access to environmental data and information and products derived therefrom collected and/or archived by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible recipients; waiver of fees in cases of foreign governments and international organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible recipients; waiver of fees in cases of foreign governments and international organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of fee schedules in Federal Register; initial schedule effective for three-year period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication of fee schedules in Federal Register; initial schedule effective for three-year period The initial schedule of any fees assessed under this section, and any subsequent amendment to such schedule, shall be published by the Secretary in the Federal Register at least 30 days before such fees will take effect. The initial schedule shall remain in effect without amendment for the three-year period beginning on the date that fees under the schedule take effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of assessments; progressive increments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date of assessments; progressive increments Any assessment of fees under this section by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data shall meet the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data archive center operations; availability of fees for expenses of centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data archive center operations; availability of fees for expenses of centers Fees collected under this section by the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for archived data shall be available to the National Environmental Satellite, Data, and Information Service for expenses incurred in the operation of its data archive centers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report to Congressional committees The Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after November 17, 1988, submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report which sets forth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1534_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other assessment authorities unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other assessment authorities unaffected The authority of the Secretary to assess fees under this section shall be in addition to, and shall not be construed to limit, the authority under any other law to assess fees relating to the environmental data activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including the authority of the Secretary pursuant to section 1307 of title 44. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to assess fees for nautical and aeronautical products of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in addition to those fees authorized under section 1307 of title 44.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>