<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/15c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/15c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/15c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15c"><akn:num>15c</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by State attorneys general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15c. Actions by State attorneys general(a) Parens patriae; monetary relief; damages; prejudgment interest(1) Any attorney general of a State may bring a civil action in the name of such State, as parens patriae on behalf of natural persons residing in such State, in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the defendant, to secure monetary relief as provided in this section for injury sustained by such natural persons to their property by reason of any violation of sections 1 to 7 of this title. The court shall exclude from the amount of monetary relief awarded in such action any amount of monetary relief (A) which duplicates amounts which have been awarded for the same injury, or (B) which is properly allocable to (i) natural persons who have excluded their claims pursuant to subsection (b)(2) of this section, and (ii) any business entity.

(2) The court shall award the State as monetary relief threefold the total damage sustained as described in paragraph (1) of this subsection, and the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee. The court may award under this paragraph, pursuant to a motion by such State promptly made, simple interest on the total damage for the period beginning on the date of service of such State’s pleading setting forth a claim under the antitrust laws and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just in the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this paragraph for any period is just in the circumstances, the court shall consider only—(A) whether such State or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, made motions or asserted claims or defenses so lacking in merit as to show that such party or representative acted intentionally for delay or otherwise acted in bad faith;

(B) whether, in the course of the action involved, such State or the opposing party, or either party’s represe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parens patriae; monetary relief; damages; prejudgment interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Parens patriae; monetary relief; damages; prejudgment interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice; exclusion election; final judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice; exclusion election; final judgment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dismissal or compromise of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dismissal or compromise of action An action under subsection (a)(1) shall not be dismissed or compromised without the approval of the court, and notice of any proposed dismissal or compromise shall be given in such manner as the court directs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorneys’ fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Attorneys’ fees In any action under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>