<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1602"><akn:num>1602</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1602. Definitions and rules of construction(a) The definitions and rules of construction set forth in this section are applicable for the purposes of this subchapter.

(b) Bureau.—The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.

(c) The term “Board” refers to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.

(d) The term “organization” means a corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, trust, estate, partnership, cooperative, or association.

(e) The term “person” means a natural person or an organization.

(f) The term “credit” means the right granted by a creditor to a debtor to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment.

(g) The term “creditor” refers only to a person who both (1) regularly extends, whether in connection with loans, sales of property or services, or otherwise, consumer credit which is payable by agreement in more than four installments or for which the payment of a finance charge is or may be required, and (2) is the person to whom the debt arising from the consumer credit transaction is initially payable on the face of the evidence of indebtedness or, if there is no such evidence of indebtedness, by agreement. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in the case of an open-end credit plan involving a credit card, the card issuer and any person who honors the credit card and offers a discount which is a finance charge are creditors. For the purpose of the requirements imposed under part D of this subchapter and sections 1637(a)(5), 1637(a)(6), 1637(a)(7), 1637(b)(1), 1637(b)(2), 1637(b)(3), 1637(b)(8), and 1637(b)(10) of this title, the term “creditor” shall also include card issuers whether or not the amount due is payable by agreement in more than four installments or the payment of a finance charge is or may be required, and the Bureau shall, by regulation, apply these requirements to such card issuers, to the extent appropriate, even though the requirements are by their terms a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The definitions and rules of construction set forth in this section are applicable for the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “Board” refers to the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “organization” means a corporation, government or governmental subdivision or agency, trust, estate, partnership, cooperative, or association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “person” means a natural person or an organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “credit” means the right granted by a creditor to a debtor to defer payment of debt or to incur debt and defer its payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The term “creditor” refers only to a person who both (1) regularly extends, whether in connection with loans, sales of property or services, or otherwise, consumer credit which is payable by agreement in more than four installments or for which the payment of a finance charge is or may be required, and (2) is the person to whom the debt arising from the consumer credit transaction is initially payable on the face of the evidence of indebtedness or, if there is no such evidence of indebtedness, by agreement. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in the case of an open-end credit plan involving a credit card, the card issuer and any person who honors the credit card and offers a discount which is a finance charge are creditors. For the purpose of the requirements imposed under part D of this subchapter and sections 1637(a)(5), 1637(a)(6), 1637(a)(7), 1637(b)(1), 1637(b)(2), 1637(b)(3), 1637(b)(8), and 1637(b)(10) of this title, the term “creditor” shall also include card issuers wh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The term “credit sale” refers to any sale in which the seller is a creditor. The term includes any contract in the form of a bailment or lease if the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation for use a sum substantially equivalent to or in excess of the aggregate value of the property and services involved and it is agreed that the bailee or lessee will become, or for no other or a nominal consideration has the option to become, the owner of the property upon full compliance with his obligations under the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The adjective “consumer”, used with reference to a credit transaction, characterizes the transaction as one in which the party to whom credit is offered or extended is a natural person, and the money, property, or services which are the subject of the transaction are primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The terms “open end credit plan” and “open end consumer credit plan” mean a plan under which the creditor reasonably contemplates repeated transactions, which prescribes the terms of such transactions, and which provides for a finance charge which may be computed from time to time on the outstanding unpaid balance. A credit plan or open end consumer credit plan which is an open end credit plan or open end consumer credit plan within the meaning of the preceding sentence is an open end credit plan or open end consumer credit plan even if credit information is verified from time to time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>