<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1615" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1615/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1615/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1615"><akn:num>1615</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of “Rule of 78’s” in connection with mortgage refinancings and other consumer loa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1615. Prohibition on use of “Rule of 78’s” in connection with mortgage refinancings and other consumer loans(a) Prompt refund of unearned interest required(1) In generalIf a consumer prepays in full the financed amount under any consumer credit transaction, the creditor shall promptly refund any unearned portion of the interest charge to the consumer.


(2) Exception for refund of de minimus 11 So in original. Probably should be “de minimis”. amountNo refund shall be required under paragraph (1) with respect to the prepayment of any consumer credit transaction if the total amount of the refund would be less than $1.


(3) Applicability to refinanced transactions and acceleration by the creditorThis subsection shall apply with respect to any prepayment of a consumer credit transaction described in paragraph (1) without regard to the manner or the reason for the prepayment, including—(A) any prepayment made in connection with the refinancing, consolidation, or restructuring of the transaction; and

(B) any prepayment made as a result of the acceleration of the obligation to repay the amount due with respect to the transaction.



(b) Use of “Rule of 78’s” prohibitedFor the purpose of calculating any refund of interest required under subsection (a) for any precomputed consumer credit transaction of a term exceeding 61 months which is consummated after September 30, 1993, the creditor shall compute the refund based on a method which is at least as favorable to the consumer as the actuarial method.


(c) Statement of prepayment amount(1) In generalBefore the end of the 5-day period beginning on the date an oral or written request is received by a creditor from a consumer for the disclosure of the amount due on any precomputed consumer credit account, the creditor or assignee shall provide the consumer with a statement of—(A) the amount necessary to prepay the account in full; and

(B) if the amount disclosed pursuant to subparagraph (A) includes an amount which is requ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt refund of unearned interest required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prompt refund of unearned interest required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of “Rule of 78’s” prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of “Rule of 78’s” prohibited For the purpose of calculating any refund of interest required under subsection (a) for any precomputed consumer credit transaction of a term exceeding 61 months which is consummated after September 30, 1993, the creditor shall compute the refund based on a method which is at least as favorable to the consumer as the actuarial method.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of prepayment amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statement of prepayment amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1615_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>