<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1631"><akn:num>1631</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1631. Disclosure requirements(a) Duty of creditor or lessor respecting one or more than one obligorSubject to subsection (b), a creditor or lessor shall disclose to the person who is obligated on a consumer lease or a consumer credit transaction the information required under this subchapter. In a transaction involving more than one obligor, a creditor or lessor, except in a transaction under section 1635 of this title, need not disclose to more than one of such obligors if the obligor given disclosure is a primary obligor.


(b) Creditor or lessor required to make disclosureIf a transaction involves one creditor as defined in section 1602(f) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, or one lessor as defined in section 1667(3) of this title, such creditor or lessor shall make the disclosures. If a transaction involves more than one creditor or lessor, only one creditor or lessor shall by required to make the disclosures. The Bureau shall by regulation specify which creditor or lessor shall make the disclosures.


(c) Estimates as satisfying statutory requirements; basis of disclosure for per diem interestThe Bureau may provide by regulation that any portion of the information required to be disclosed by this subchapter may be given in the form of estimates where the provider of such information is not in a position to know exact information. In the case of any consumer credit transaction a portion of the interest on which is determined on a per diem basis and is to be collected upon the consummation of such transaction, any disclosure with respect to such portion of interest shall be deemed to be accurate for purposes of this subchapter if the disclosure is based on information actually known to the creditor at the time that the disclosure documents are being prepared for the consummation of the transaction.


(d) Tolerances for numerical disclosuresThe Bureau shall determine whether tolerances for numerical disclosures other than the annual percentage </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of creditor or lessor respecting one or more than one obligor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duty of creditor or lessor respecting one or more than one obligor Subject to subsection (b), a creditor or lessor shall disclose to the person who is obligated on a consumer lease or a consumer credit transaction the information required under this subchapter. In a transaction involving more than one obligor, a creditor or lessor, except in a transaction under section 1635 of this title, need not disclose to more than one of such obligors if the obligor given disclosure is a primary obligor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditor or lessor required to make disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Creditor or lessor required to make disclosure If a transaction involves one creditor as defined in section 1602(f) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, or one lessor as defined in section 1667(3) of this title, such creditor or lessor shall make the disclosures. If a transaction involves more than one creditor or lessor, only one creditor or lessor shall by required to make the disclosures. The Bureau shall by regulation specify which creditor or lessor shall make the disclosures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimates as satisfying statutory requirements; basis of disclosure for per diem interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Estimates as satisfying statutory requirements; basis of disclosure for per diem interest The Bureau may provide by regulation that any portion of the information required to be disclosed by this subchapter may be given in the form of estimates where the provider of such information is not in a position to know exact information. In the case of any consumer credit transaction a portion of the interest on which is determined on a per diem basis and is to be collected upon the consummation of such transaction, any disclosure with respect to such portion of interest shall be deemed to be accurate for purposes of this subchapter if the disclosure is based on information actually known to the creditor at the time that the disclosure documents are being prepared for the consummation of the transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tolerances for numerical disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tolerances for numerical disclosures The Bureau shall determine whether tolerances for numerical disclosures other than the annual percentage rate are necessary to facilitate compliance with this subchapter, and if it determines that such tolerances are necessary to facilitate compliance, it shall by regulation permit disclosures within such tolerances. The Bureau shall exercise its authority to permit tolerances for numerical disclosures other than the annual percentage rate so that such tolerances are narrow enough to prevent such tolerances from resulting in misleading disclosures or disclosures that circumvent the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>