<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1632"><akn:num>1632</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of disclosure; additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1632. Form of disclosure; additional information(a) Information clearly and conspicuously disclosed; “annual percentage rate” and “finance charge”; order of disclosures and use of different terminologyInformation required by this subchapter shall be disclosed clearly and conspicuously, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau. The terms “annual percentage rate” and “finance charge” shall be disclosed more conspicuously than other terms, data, or information provided in connection with a transaction, except information relating to the identify of the creditor. Except as provided in subsection (c), regulations of the Bureau need not require that disclosures pursuant to this subchapter be made in the order set forth in this subchapter and, except as otherwise provided, may permit the use of terminology different from that employed in this subchapter if it conveys substantially the same meaning.


(b) Optional information by creditor or lessorAny creditor or lessor may supply additional information or explanation with any disclosures required under parts D and E and, except as provided in sections 1637a(b)(3) and 1638(b)(1) of this title, under this part.


(c) Tabular format required for certain disclosures under section 1637(c)(1) In generalThe information described in paragraphs (1)(A), (3)(B)(i)(I), (4)(A), and (4)(C)(i)(I) of section 1637(c) of this title shall be—(A) disclosed in the form and manner which the Bureau shall prescribe by regulations; and

(B) placed in a conspicuous and prominent location on or with any written application, solicitation, or other document or paper with respect to which such disclosure is required.


(2) Tabular format(A) Form of table to be prescribedIn the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection, the Bureau shall require that the disclosure of such information shall, to the extent the Bureau determines to be practicable and appropriate, be in the form of a table which—(i) contains clear and concise hea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information clearly and conspicuously disclosed; “annual percentage rate” and “finance charge”; order of disclosures and use of different terminology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information clearly and conspicuously disclosed; “annual percentage rate” and “finance charge”; order of disclosures and use of different terminology Information required by this subchapter shall be disclosed clearly and conspicuously, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau. The terms “annual percentage rate” and “finance charge” shall be disclosed more conspicuously than other terms, data, or information provided in connection with a transaction, except information relating to the identify of the creditor. Except as provided in subsection (c), regulations of the Bureau need not require that disclosures pursuant to this subchapter be made in the order set forth in this subchapter and, except as otherwise provided, may permit the use of terminology different from that employed in this subchapter if it conveys substantially the same meaning.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional information by creditor or lessor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Optional information by creditor or lessor Any creditor or lessor may supply additional information or explanation with any disclosures required under parts D and E and, except as provided in sections 1637a(b)(3) and 1638(b)(1) of this title, under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tabular format required for certain disclosures under section 1637(c)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tabular format required for certain disclosures under section 1637(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional electronic disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional electronic disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>