<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1635" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1635/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1635/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1635"><akn:num>1635</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of rescission as to certain transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1635. Right of rescission as to certain transactions(a) Disclosure of obligor’s right to rescindExcept as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any consumer credit transaction (including opening or increasing the credit limit for an open end credit plan) in which a security interest, including any such interest arising by operation of law, is or will be retained or acquired in any property which is used as the principal dwelling of the person to whom credit is extended, the obligor shall have the right to rescind the transaction until midnight of the third business day following the consummation of the transaction or the delivery of the information and rescission forms required under this section together with a statement containing the material disclosures required under this subchapter, whichever is later, by notifying the creditor, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau, of his intention to do so. The creditor shall clearly and conspicuously disclose, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau, to any obligor in a transaction subject to this section the rights of the obligor under this section. The creditor shall also provide, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau, appropriate forms for the obligor to exercise his right to rescind any transaction subject to this section.


(b) Return of money or property following rescissionWhen an obligor exercises his right to rescind under subsection (a), he is not liable for any finance or other charge, and any security interest given by the obligor, including any such interest arising by operation of law, becomes void upon such a rescission. Within 20 days after receipt of a notice of rescission, the creditor shall return to the obligor any money or property given as earnest money, downpayment, or otherwise, and shall take any action necessary or appropriate to reflect the termination of any security interest created under the transaction. If the creditor has delivered any property to the obligo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of obligor’s right to rescind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosure of obligor’s right to rescind Except as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any consumer credit transaction (including opening or increasing the credit limit for an open end credit plan) in which a security interest, including any such interest arising by operation of law, is or will be retained or acquired in any property which is used as the principal dwelling of the person to whom credit is extended, the obligor shall have the right to rescind the transaction until midnight of the third business day following the consummation of the transaction or the delivery of the information and rescission forms required under this section together with a statement containing the material disclosures required under this subchapter, whichever is later, by notifying the creditor, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau, of his intention to do so. The creditor shall clearly and conspicuously disclose, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau, to any obligor in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of money or property following rescission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Return of money or property following rescission When an obligor exercises his right to rescind under subsection (a), he is not liable for any finance or other charge, and any security interest given by the obligor, including any such interest arising by operation of law, becomes void upon such a rescission. Within 20 days after receipt of a notice of rescission, the creditor shall return to the obligor any money or property given as earnest money, downpayment, or otherwise, and shall take any action necessary or appropriate to reflect the termination of any security interest created under the transaction. If the creditor has delivered any property to the obligor, the obligor may retain possession of it. Upon the performance of the creditor’s obligations under this section, the obligor shall tender the property to the creditor, except that if return of the property in kind would be impracticable or inequitable, the obligor shall tender its reasonable value. Tender shall be made at </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rebuttable presumption of delivery of required disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rebuttable presumption of delivery of required disclosures Notwithstanding any rule of evidence, written acknowledgment of receipt of any disclosures required under this subchapter by a person to whom information, forms, and a statement is required to be given pursuant to this section does no more than create a rebuttable presumption of delivery thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification and waiver of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Modification and waiver of rights The Bureau may, if it finds that such action is necessary in order to permit homeowners to meet bona fide personal financial emergencies, prescribe regulations authorizing the modification or waiver of any rights created under this section to the extent and under the circumstances set forth in those regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempted transactions; reapplication of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exempted transactions; reapplication of provisions This section does not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limit for exercise of right</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Time limit for exercise of right An obligor’s right of rescission shall expire three years after the date of consummation of the transaction or upon the sale of the property, whichever occurs first, notwithstanding the fact that the information and forms required under this section or any other disclosures required under this part have not been delivered to the obligor, except that if (1) any agency empowered to enforce the provisions of this subchapter institutes a proceeding to enforce the provisions of this section within three years after the date of consummation of the transaction, (2) such agency finds a violation of this section, and (3) the obligor’s right to rescind is based in whole or in part on any matter involved in such proceeding, then the obligor’s right of rescission shall expire three years after the date of consummation of the transaction or upon the earlier sale of the property, or upon the expiration of one year following the conclusion of the proceeding, or an</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional relief In any action in which it is determined that a creditor has violated this section, in addition to rescission the court may award relief under section 1640 of this title for violations of this subchapter not relating to the right to rescind.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on rescission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on rescission An obligor shall have no rescission rights arising solely from the form of written notice used by the creditor to inform the obligor of the rights of the obligor under this section, if the creditor provided the obligor the appropriate form of written notice published and adopted by the Bureau, or a comparable written notice of the rights of the obligor, that was properly completed by the creditor, and otherwise complied with all other requirements of this section regarding notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rescission rights in foreclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rescission rights in foreclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>