<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1637" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1637/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1637/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1637"><akn:num>1637</akn:num><akn:heading>Open end consumer credit plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1637. Open end consumer credit plans(a) Required disclosures by creditorBefore opening any account under an open end consumer credit plan, the creditor shall disclose to the person to whom credit is to be extended each of the following items, to the extent applicable:(1) The conditions under which a finance charge may be imposed, including the time period (if any) within which any credit extended may be repaid without incurring a finance charge, except that the creditor may, at his election and without disclosure, impose no such finance charge if payment is received after the termination of such time period. If no such time period is provided, the creditor shall disclose such fact.

(2) The method of determining the balance upon which a finance charge will be imposed.

(3) The method of determining the amount of the finance charge, including any minimum or fixed amount imposed as a finance charge.

(4) Where one or more periodic rates may be used to compute the finance charge, each such rate, the range of balances to which it is applicable, and the corresponding nominal annual percentage rate determined by multiplying the periodic rate by the number of periods in a year.

(5) Identification of other charges which may be imposed as part of the plan, and their method of computation, in accordance with regulations of the Bureau.

(6) In cases where the credit is or will be secured, a statement that a security interest has been or will be taken in (A) the property purchased as part of the credit transaction, or (B) property not purchased as part of the credit transaction identified by item or type.

(7) A statement, in a form prescribed by regulations of the Bureau of the protection provided by sections 1666 and 1666i of this title to an obligor and the creditor’s responsibilities under sections 1666a and 1666i of this title. With respect to one billing cycle per calendar year, at intervals of not less than six months or more than eighteen months, the creditor shall t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosures by creditor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required disclosures by creditor Before opening any account under an open end consumer credit plan, the creditor shall disclose to the person to whom credit is to be extended each of the following items, to the extent applicable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement required with each billing cycle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statement required with each billing cycle The creditor of any account under an open end consumer credit plan shall transmit to the obligor, for each billing cycle at the end of which there is an outstanding balance in that account or with respect to which a finance charge is imposed, a statement setting forth each of the following items to the extent applicable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure in credit and charge card applications and solicitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure in credit and charge card applications and solicitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure prior to renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure prior to renewal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rules for disclosures under subsections (c) and (d)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other rules for disclosures under subsections (c) and (d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of range of certain fees which vary by State allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure of range of certain fees which vary by State allowed If the amount of any fee required to be disclosed by a credit or charge card issuer under paragraph (1)(B), (3)(B)(i)(II), (4)(B), or (4)(C)(i)(II) of subsection (c) varies from State to State, the card issuer may disclose the range of such fees for purposes of subsection (c) in lieu of the amount for each applicable State, if such disclosure includes a statement that the amount of such fee varies from State to State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance in connection with certain open end credit card plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Insurance in connection with certain open end credit card plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on certain actions for failure to incur finance charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition on certain actions for failure to incur finance charges A creditor of an account under an open end consumer credit plan may not terminate an account prior to its expiration date solely because the consumer has not incurred finance charges on the account. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a creditor from terminating an account for inactivity in 3 or more consecutive months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance notice of rate increase and other changes required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Advance notice of rate increase and other changes required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on penalties for on-time payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Prohibition on penalties for on-time payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>