<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1638" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1638/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1638/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1638"><akn:num>1638</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions other than under an open end credit plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1638. Transactions other than under an open end credit plan(a) Required disclosures by creditorFor each consumer credit transaction other than under an open end credit plan, the creditor shall disclose each of the following items, to the extent applicable:(1) The identity of the creditor required to make disclosure.

(2)(A) The “amount financed”, using that term, which shall be the amount of credit of which the consumer has actual use. This amount shall be computed as follows, but the computations need not be disclosed and shall not be disclosed with the disclosures conspicuously segregated in accordance with subsection (b)(1):(i) take the principal amount of the loan or the cash price less downpayment and trade-in;

(ii) add any charges which are not part of the finance charge or of the principal amount of the loan and which are financed by the consumer, including the cost of any items excluded from the finance charge pursuant to section 1605 of this title; and

(iii) subtract any charges which are part of the finance charge but which will be paid by the consumer before or at the time of the consummation of the transaction, or have been withheld from the proceeds of the credit.


(B) In conjunction with the disclosure of the amount financed, a creditor shall provide a statement of the consumer’s right to obtain, upon a written request, a written itemization of the amount financed. The statement shall include spaces for a “yes” and “no” indication to be initialed by the consumer to indicate whether the consumer wants a written itemization of the amount financed. Upon receiving an affirmative indication, the creditor shall provide, at the time other disclosures are required to be furnished, a written itemization of the amount financed. For the purposes of this subparagraph, “itemization of the amount financed” means a disclosure of the following items, to the extent applicable:(i) the amount that is or will be paid directly to the consumer;

(ii) the amount that is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosures by creditor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required disclosures by creditor For each consumer credit transaction other than under an open end credit plan, the creditor shall disclose each of the following items, to the extent applicable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and timing of disclosures; residential mortgage transaction requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form and timing of disclosures; residential mortgage transaction requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of disclosures on unsolicited mailed or telephone purchase orders or loan requests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Timing of disclosures on unsolicited mailed or telephone purchase orders or loan requests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of disclosure in cases of an addition of a deferred payment price to an existing outstanding balance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing of disclosure in cases of an addition of a deferred payment price to an existing outstanding balance If a consumer credit sale is one of a series of consumer credit sales transactions made pursuant to an agreement providing for the addition of the deferred payment price of that sale to an existing outstanding balance, and the person to whom the credit is extended has approved in writing both the annual percentage rate or rates and the method of computing the finance charge or charges, and the creditor retains no security interest in any property as to which he has received payments aggregating the amount of the sales price including any finance charges attributable thereto, then the disclosure required under subsection (a) for the particular sale may be made at any time not later than the date the first payment for that sale is due. For the purposes of this subsection, in the case of items purchased on different dates, the first purchased shall be deemed first paid for, and </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and disclosure with respect to private education loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Terms and disclosure with respect to private education loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic statements for residential mortgage loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic statements for residential mortgage loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>