<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1639e"><akn:num>1639e</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal independence requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1639e. Appraisal independence requirements(a) In generalIt shall be unlawful, in extending credit or in providing any services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of the consumer, to engage in any act or practice that violates appraisal independence as described in or pursuant to regulations prescribed under this section.


(b) Appraisal independenceFor purposes of subsection (a), acts or practices that violate appraisal independence shall include—(1) any appraisal of a property offered as security for repayment of the consumer credit transaction that is conducted in connection with such transaction in which a person with an interest in the underlying transaction compensates, coerces, extorts, colludes, instructs, induces, bribes, or intimidates a person, appraisal management company, firm, or other entity conducting or involved in an appraisal, or attempts, to compensate, coerce, extort, collude, instruct, induce, bribe, or intimidate such a person, for the purpose of causing the appraised value assigned, under the appraisal, to the property to be based on any factor other than the independent judgment of the appraiser;

(2) mischaracterizing, or suborning any mischaracterization of, the appraised value of the property securing the extension of the credit;

(3) seeking to influence an appraiser or otherwise to encourage a targeted value in order to facilitate the making or pricing of the transaction; and

(4) withholding or threatening to withhold timely payment for an appraisal report or for appraisal services rendered when the appraisal report or services are provided for in accordance with the contract between the parties.


(c) ExceptionsThe requirements of subsection (b) shall not be construed as prohibiting a mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage banker, real estate broker, appraisal management company, employee of an appraisal management company, consumer, or any other person with an interest in a real estate transactio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general It shall be unlawful, in extending credit or in providing any services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of the consumer, to engage in any act or practice that violates appraisal independence as described in or pursuant to regulations prescribed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal independence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appraisal independence For purposes of subsection (a), acts or practices that violate appraisal independence shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions The requirements of subsection (b) shall not be construed as prohibiting a mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage banker, real estate broker, appraisal management company, employee of an appraisal management company, consumer, or any other person with an interest in a real estate transaction from asking an appraiser to undertake 1 or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions on conflicts of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibitions on conflicts of interest No certified or licensed appraiser conducting, and no appraisal management company procuring or facilitating, an appraisal in connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer may have a direct or indirect interest, financial or otherwise, in the property or transaction involving the appraisal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mandatory reporting Any mortgage lender, mortgage broker, mortgage banker, real estate broker, appraisal management company, employee of an appraisal management company, or any other person involved in a real estate transaction involving an appraisal in connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by the principal dwelling of a consumer who has a reasonable basis to believe an appraiser is failing to comply with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, is violating applicable laws, or is otherwise engaging in unethical or unprofessional conduct, shall refer the matter to the applicable State appraiser certifying and licensing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No extension of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No extension of credit In connection with a consumer credit transaction secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling, a creditor who knows, at or before loan consummation, of a violation of the appraisal independence standards established in subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (b) or (d) shall not extend credit based on such appraisal unless the creditor documents that the creditor has acted with reasonable diligence to determine that the appraisal does not materially misstate or misrepresent the value of such dwelling.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and interpretive guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rules and interpretive guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal report portability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appraisal report portability Consistent with the requirements of this section, the Board, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau may jointly issue regulations that address the issue of appraisal report portability, including regulations that ensure the portability of the appraisal report between lenders for a consumer credit transaction secured by a 1-4 unit single family residence that is the principal dwelling of the consumer, or mortgage brokerage services for such a transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customary and reasonable fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Customary and reasonable fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639e_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Sunset Effective on the date the interim final regulations are promulgated pursuant to subsection (g), the Home Valuation Code of Conduct announced by the Federal Housing Finance Agency on December 23, 2008, shall have no force or effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>