<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1639/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1639"><akn:num>1639</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for certain mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1639. Requirements for certain mortgages(a) Disclosures(1) Specific disclosuresIn addition to other disclosures required under this subchapter, for each mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the creditor shall provide the following disclosures in conspicuous type size:(A) “You are not required to complete this agreement merely because you have received these disclosures or have signed a loan application.”.

(B) “If you obtain this loan, the lender will have a mortgage on your home. You could lose your home, and any money you have put into it, if you do not meet your obligations under the loan.”.


(2) Annual percentage rateIn addition to the disclosures required under paragraph (1), the creditor shall disclose—(A) in the case of a credit transaction with a fixed rate of interest, the annual percentage rate and the amount of the regular monthly payment; or

(B) in the case of any other credit transaction, the annual percentage rate of the loan, the amount of the regular monthly payment, a statement that the interest rate and monthly payment may increase, and the amount of the maximum monthly payment, based on the maximum interest rate allowed pursuant to section 3806 of title 12.



(b) Time of disclosures(1) In generalThe disclosures required by this section shall be given not less than 3 business days prior to consummation of the transaction.


(2) New disclosures required(A) In generalAfter providing the disclosures required by this section, a creditor may not change the terms of the extension of credit if such changes make the disclosures inaccurate, unless new disclosures are provided that meet the requirements of this section.


(B) Telephone disclosureA creditor may provide new disclosures pursuant to subparagraph (A) by telephone, if—(i) the change is initiated by the consumer; and

(ii) at the consummation of the transaction under which the credit is extended—(I) the creditor provides to the consumer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time of disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No prepayment penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No prepayment penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations after default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations after default A mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 1 of this title may not provide for an interest rate applicable after default that is higher than the interest rate that applies before default. If the date of maturity of a mortgage referred to in subsection 33 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 1602(aa) 1 of this title is accelerated due to default and the consumer is entitled to a rebate of interest, that rebate shall be computed by any method that is not less favorable than the actuarial method (as that term is defined in section 1615(d) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No balloon payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No balloon payments No high-cost mortgage may contain a scheduled payment that is more than twice as large as the average of earlier scheduled payments. This subsection shall not apply when the payment schedule is adjusted to the seasonal or irregular income of the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No negative amortization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No negative amortization A mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 1 of this title may not include terms under which the outstanding principal balance will increase at any time over the course of the loan because the regular periodic payments do not cover the full amount of interest due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No prepaid payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No prepaid payments A mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 1 of this title may not include terms under which more than 2 periodic payments required under the loan are consolidated and paid in advance from the loan proceeds provided to the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on extending credit without regard to payment ability of consumer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition on extending credit without regard to payment ability of consumer A creditor shall not engage in a pattern or practice of extending credit to consumers under mortgages referred to in section 1602(aa) 1 of this title based on the consumers’ collateral without regard to the consumers’ repayment ability, including the consumers’ current and expected income, current obligations, and employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for payments under home improvement contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirements for payments under home improvement contracts A creditor shall not make a payment to a contractor under a home improvement contract from amounts extended as credit under a mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 1 of this title, other than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommended default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Recommended default No creditor shall recommend or encourage default on an existing loan or other debt prior to and in connection with the closing or planned closing of a high-cost mortgage that refinances all or any portion of such existing loan or debt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>