<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1641" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1641/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1641/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1641"><akn:num>1641</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of assignees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1641. Liability of assignees(a) PrerequisitesExcept as otherwise specifically provided in this subchapter, any civil action for a violation of this subchapter or proceeding under section 1607 of this title which may be brought against a creditor may be maintained against any assignee of such creditor only if the violation for which such action or proceeding is brought is apparent on the face of the disclosure statement, except where the assignment was involuntary. For the purpose of this section, a violation apparent on the face of the disclosure statement includes, but is not limited to (1) a disclosure which can be determined to be incomplete or inaccurate from the face of the disclosure statement or other documents assigned, or (2) a disclosure which does not use the terms required to be used by this subchapter.


(b) Proof of compliance with statutory provisionsExcept as provided in section 1635(c) of this title, in any action or proceeding by or against any subsequent assignee of the original creditor without knowledge to the contrary by the assignee when he acquires the obligation, written acknowledgement of receipt by a person to whom a statement is required to be given pursuant to this subchapter shall be conclusive proof of the delivery thereof and, except as provided in subsection (a), of compliance with this part. This section does not affect the rights of the obligor in any action against the original creditor.


(c) Right of rescission by consumer unaffectedAny consumer who has the right to rescind a transaction under section 1635 of this title may rescind the transaction as against any assignee of the obligation.


(d) Rights upon assignment of certain mortgages(1) In generalAny person who purchases or is otherwise assigned a mortgage referred to in section 1602(aa) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall be subject to all claims and defenses with respect to that mortgage that the consumer could assert against the creditor of the mo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prerequisites Except as otherwise specifically provided in this subchapter, any civil action for a violation of this subchapter or proceeding under section 1607 of this title which may be brought against a creditor may be maintained against any assignee of such creditor only if the violation for which such action or proceeding is brought is apparent on the face of the disclosure statement, except where the assignment was involuntary. For the purpose of this section, a violation apparent on the face of the disclosure statement includes, but is not limited to (1) a disclosure which can be determined to be incomplete or inaccurate from the face of the disclosure statement or other documents assigned, or (2) a disclosure which does not use the terms required to be used by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of compliance with statutory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proof of compliance with statutory provisions Except as provided in section 1635(c) of this title, in any action or proceeding by or against any subsequent assignee of the original creditor without knowledge to the contrary by the assignee when he acquires the obligation, written acknowledgement of receipt by a person to whom a statement is required to be given pursuant to this subchapter shall be conclusive proof of the delivery thereof and, except as provided in subsection (a), of compliance with this part. This section does not affect the rights of the obligor in any action against the original creditor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of rescission by consumer unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Right of rescission by consumer unaffected Any consumer who has the right to rescind a transaction under section 1635 of this title may rescind the transaction as against any assignee of the obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights upon assignment of certain mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rights upon assignment of certain mortgages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of assignee for consumer credit transactions secured by real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liability of assignee for consumer credit transactions secured by real property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of servicer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of servicer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of new creditor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice of new creditor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>