<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1647" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1647/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1647/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1647"><akn:num>1647</akn:num><akn:heading>Home equity plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1647. Home equity plans(a) Index requirementIn the case of extensions of credit under an open end consumer credit plan which are subject to a variable rate and are secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling, the index or other rate of interest to which changes in the annual percentage rate are related shall be based on an index or rate of interest which is publicly available and is not under the control of the creditor.


(b) Grounds for acceleration of outstanding balanceA creditor may not unilaterally terminate any account under an open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling and require the immediate repayment of any outstanding balance at such time, except in the case of—(1) fraud or material misrepresentation on the part of the consumer in connection with the account;

(2) failure by the consumer to meet the repayment terms of the agreement for any outstanding balance; or

(3) any other action or failure to act by the consumer which adversely affects the creditor’s security for the account or any right of the creditor in such security.


This subsection does not apply to reverse mortgage transactions.

(c) Change in terms(1) In generalNo open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling may contain a provision which permits a creditor to change unilaterally any term required to be disclosed under section 1637a(a) of this title or any other term, except a change in insignificant terms such as the address of the creditor for billing purposes.


(2) Certain changes not precludedNotwithstanding the provisions of subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraph”. (1), a creditor may make any of the following changes:(A) Change the index and margin applicable to extensions of credit under such plan if the index used by the creditor is no longer available and the substitute index and margin would result in a substantially similar in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Index requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Index requirement In the case of extensions of credit under an open end consumer credit plan which are subject to a variable rate and are secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling, the index or other rate of interest to which changes in the annual percentage rate are related shall be based on an index or rate of interest which is publicly available and is not under the control of the creditor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grounds for acceleration of outstanding balance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grounds for acceleration of outstanding balance A creditor may not unilaterally terminate any account under an open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by a consumer’s principal dwelling and require the immediate repayment of any outstanding balance at such time, except in the case of— This subsection does not apply to reverse mortgage transactions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change in terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Change in terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms changed after application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms changed after application If any term or condition described in section 1637a(a) of this title which is disclosed to a consumer in connection with an application to open an account under an open end consumer credit plan described in such section (other than a variable feature of the plan) changes before the account is opened, and if, as a result of such change, the consumer elects not to enter into the plan agreement, the creditor shall refund all fees paid by the consumer in connection with such application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements relating to refunds and imposition of nonrefundable fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional requirements relating to refunds and imposition of nonrefundable fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>