<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665b"><akn:num>1665b</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising of open end consumer credit plans secured by consumer’s principal dwelling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665b. Advertising of open end consumer credit plans secured by consumer’s principal dwelling(a) In generalIf any advertisement to aid, promote, or assist, directly or indirectly, the extension of consumer credit through an open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by the consumer’s principal dwelling states, affirmatively or negatively, any of the specific terms of the plan, including any periodic payment amount required under such plan, such advertisement shall also clearly and conspicuously set forth the following information, in such form and manner as the Bureau may require:(1) Loan fees and opening cost estimatesAny loan fee the amount of which is determined as a percentage of the credit limit applicable to an account under the plan and an estimate of the aggregate amount of other fees for opening the account, based on the creditor’s experience with the plan and stated as a single amount or as a reasonable range.


(2) Periodic ratesIn any case in which periodic rates may be used to compute the finance charge, the periodic rates expressed as an annual percentage rate.


(3) Highest annual percentage rateThe highest annual percentage rate which may be imposed under the plan.


(4) Other informationAny other information the Bureau may by regulation require.



(b) Tax deductibility(1) In generalIf any advertisement described in subsection (a) contains a statement that any interest expense incurred with respect to the plan is or may be tax deductible, the advertisement shall not be misleading with respect to such deductibility.


(2) Credit in excess of fair market valueEach advertisement described in subsection (a) that relates to an extension of credit that may exceed the fair market value of the dwelling, and which advertisement is disseminated in paper form to the public or through the Internet, as opposed to by radio or television, shall include a clear and conspicuous statement that—(A) the interest on the portion of the c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If any advertisement to aid, promote, or assist, directly or indirectly, the extension of consumer credit through an open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by the consumer’s principal dwelling states, affirmatively or negatively, any of the specific terms of the plan, including any periodic payment amount required under such plan, such advertisement shall also clearly and conspicuously set forth the following information, in such form and manner as the Bureau may require:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax deductibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tax deductibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain terms prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certain terms prohibited No advertisement described in subsection (a) with respect to any home equity account may refer to such loan as “free money” or use other terms determined by the Bureau by regulation to be misleading.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discounted initial rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Discounted initial rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Balloon payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Balloon payment If any advertisement described in subsection (a) contains a statement regarding the minimum monthly payment under the plan, the advertisement shall also disclose, if applicable, the fact that the plan includes a balloon payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Balloon payment” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Balloon payment” defined For purposes of this section and section 1637a of this title, the term “balloon payment” means, with respect to any open end consumer credit plan under which extensions of credit are secured by the consumer’s principal dwelling, any repayment option under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>