<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1665c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665c"><akn:num>1665c</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest rate reduction on open end consumer credit plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665c. Interest rate reduction on open end consumer credit plans(a) In generalIf a creditor increases the annual percentage rate applicable to a credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, based on factors including the credit risk of the obligor, market conditions, or other factors, the creditor shall consider changes in such factors in subsequently determining whether to reduce the annual percentage rate for such obligor.


(b) RequirementsWith respect to any credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, the creditor shall—(1) maintain reasonable methodologies for assessing the factors described in subsection (a);

(2) not less frequently than once every 6 months, review accounts as to which the annual percentage rate has been increased since January 1, 2009, to assess whether such factors have changed (including whether any risk has declined);

(3) reduce the annual percentage rate previously increased when a reduction is indicated by the review; and

(4) in the event of an increase in the annual percentage rate, provide in the written notice required under section 1637(i) of this title a statement of the reasons for the increase.


(c) Rule of constructionThis section shall not be construed to require a reduction in any specific amount.


(d) RulemakingThe Bureau 11 So in original. Probably should be “Board”. shall issue final rules not later than 9 months after May 22, 2009, to implement the requirements of and evaluate compliance with this section, and subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall become effective 15 months after May 22, 2009.


(Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 148, as added Pub. L. 111–24, title I, § 101(c), May 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1737; amended Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100A(2), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2107.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2010—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 111–203 substituted “Bureau” for “Board”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2010 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 111–203 effective on the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If a creditor increases the annual percentage rate applicable to a credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, based on factors including the credit risk of the obligor, market conditions, or other factors, the creditor shall consider changes in such factors in subsequently determining whether to reduce the annual percentage rate for such obligor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements With respect to any credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan, the creditor shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction This section shall not be construed to require a reduction in any specific amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rulemaking The Bureau 11 So in original. Probably should be “Board”. shall issue final rules not later than 9 months after May 22, 2009, to implement the requirements of and evaluate compliance with this section, and subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall become effective 15 months after May 22, 2009.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>