<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1666d"><akn:num>1666d</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of credit balances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1666d. Treatment of credit balances
Whenever a credit balance in excess of $1 is created in connection with a consumer credit transaction through (1) transmittal of funds to a creditor in excess of the total balance due on an account, (2) rebates of unearned finance charges or insurance premiums, or (3) amounts otherwise owed to or held for the benefit of an obligor, the creditor shall—(A) credit the amount of the credit balance to the consumer’s account;

(B) refund any part of the amount of the remaining credit balance, upon request of the consumer; and

(C) make a good faith effort to refund to the consumer by cash, check, or money order any part of the amount of the credit balance remaining in the account for more than six months, except that no further action is required in any case in which the consumer’s current location is not known by the creditor and cannot be traced through the consumer’s last known address or telephone number.

(Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 165, as added Pub. L. 93–495, title III, § 306, Oct. 28, 1974, 88 Stat. 1514; amended Pub. L. 96–221, title VI, § 621(a), Mar. 31, 1980, 94 Stat. 184.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1980—Pub. L. 96–221 substituted provisions relating to duties of creditor whenever a credit balance in excess of $1 is created in connection with a consumer credit transaction, for provisions relating to duties of creditor whenever an obligor transmits funds to creditor in excess of the total balance due on an open end consumer credit account.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1980 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 96–221 effective on expiration of two years and six months after Mar. 31, 1980, with all regulations, forms, and clauses required to be prescribed to be promulgated at least one year prior to such effective date, and allowing any creditor to comply with any amendments, in accordance with the regulations, forms, and clauses prescribed by the Board prior to such effective date, see section 625 o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666d_A"><akn:num>(A)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(A) credit the amount of the credit balance to the consumer’s account;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666d_B"><akn:num>(B)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(B) refund any part of the amount of the remaining credit balance, upon request of the consumer; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666d_C"><akn:num>(C)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(C) make a good faith effort to refund to the consumer by cash, check, or money order any part of the amount of the credit balance remaining in the account for more than six months, except that no further action is required in any case in which the consumer’s current location is not known by the creditor and cannot be traced through the consumer’s last known address or telephone number.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>