<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1666j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1666j"><akn:num>1666j</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1666j. Applicability of State laws(a) Consistency of provisionsThis part does not annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any person subject to the provisions of this part from complying with, the laws of any State with respect to credit billing practices, except to the extent that those laws are inconsistent with any provision of this part, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. The Bureau is authorized to determine whether such inconsistencies exist. The Bureau may not determine that any State law is inconsistent with any provision of this part if the Bureau determines that such law gives greater protection to the consumer.


(b) Exemptions by Bureau from credit billing requirementsThe Bureau shall by regulation exempt from the requirements of this part any class of credit transactions within any State if it determines that under the law of that State that class of transactions is subject to requirements substantially similar to those imposed under this part or that such law gives greater protection to the consumer, and that there is adequate provision for enforcement.


(c) Finance charge or other charge for credit for sales transactions involving cash discountsNotwithstanding any other provisions of this subchapter, any discount offered under section 1666f(b) of this title shall not be considered a finance charge or other charge for credit under the usury laws of any State or under the laws of any State relating to disclosure of information in connection with credit transactions, or relating to the types, amounts or rates of charges, or to any element or elements of charges permissible under such laws in connection with the extension or use of credit.


(Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 173, formerly § 171, as added Pub. L. 93–495, title III, § 306, Oct. 28, 1974, 88 Stat. 1516; amended Pub. L. 94–222, § 3(d), Feb. 27, 1976, 90 Stat. 198; renumbered § 173, Pub. L. 111–24, title I, § 101(b)(1), May 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1736; Pub. L. 111–203, title X, §§ 1087, 11</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consistency of provisions This part does not annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any person subject to the provisions of this part from complying with, the laws of any State with respect to credit billing practices, except to the extent that those laws are inconsistent with any provision of this part, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. The Bureau is authorized to determine whether such inconsistencies exist. The Bureau may not determine that any State law is inconsistent with any provision of this part if the Bureau determines that such law gives greater protection to the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions by Bureau from credit billing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions by Bureau from credit billing requirements The Bureau shall by regulation exempt from the requirements of this part any class of credit transactions within any State if it determines that under the law of that State that class of transactions is subject to requirements substantially similar to those imposed under this part or that such law gives greater protection to the consumer, and that there is adequate provision for enforcement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1666j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finance charge or other charge for credit for sales transactions involving cash discounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Finance charge or other charge for credit for sales transactions involving cash discounts Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subchapter, any discount offered under section 1666f(b) of this title shall not be considered a finance charge or other charge for credit under the usury laws of any State or under the laws of any State relating to disclosure of information in connection with credit transactions, or relating to the types, amounts or rates of charges, or to any element or elements of charges permissible under such laws in connection with the extension or use of credit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>