<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1667f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1667f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1667f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1667f"><akn:num>1667f</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1667f. Regulations(a) Regulations authorized(1) In generalThe Bureau shall prescribe regulations to update and clarify the requirements and definitions applicable to lease disclosures and contracts, and any other issues specifically related to consumer leasing, to the extent that the Bureau determines such action to be necessary—(A) to carry out this part;

(B) to prevent any circumvention of this part; or

(C) to facilitate compliance with the requirements of the 11 So in original. Probably should be “this”. part.


(2) Classifications, adjustmentsAny regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) may contain classifications and differentiations, and may provide for adjustments and exceptions for any class of transactions, as the Bureau considers appropriate.



(b) Model disclosure(1) PublicationThe Bureau shall establish and publish model disclosure forms to facilitate compliance with the disclosure requirements of this part and to aid the consumer in understanding the transaction to which the subject disclosure form relates.


(2) Use of automated equipmentIn establishing model forms under this subsection, the Bureau shall consider the use by lessors of data processing or similar automated equipment.


(3) Use optionalA lessor may utilize a model disclosure form established by the Bureau under this subsection for purposes of compliance with this part, at the discretion of the lessor.


(4) Effect of useAny lessor who properly uses the material aspects of any model disclosure form established by the Bureau under this subsection shall be deemed to be in compliance with the disclosure requirements to which the form relates.



(Pub. L. 90–321, title I, § 187, as added Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2605(b)(1), Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–471; amended Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1100A(2), (10), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2107, 2109.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2010—Pub. L. 111–203, § 1100A(2), (10), substituted “Bureau” for “Board”, “the Bureau” for “the Board”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Model disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>