<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681i"><akn:num>1681i</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure in case of disputed accuracy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681i. Procedure in case of disputed accuracy(a) Reinvestigations of disputed information(1) Reinvestigation required(A) In generalSubject to subsection (f) and except as provided in subsection (g), if the completeness or accuracy of any item of information contained in a consumer’s file at a consumer reporting agency is disputed by the consumer and the consumer notifies the agency directly, or indirectly through a reseller, of such dispute, the agency shall, free of charge, conduct a reasonable reinvestigation to determine whether the disputed information is inaccurate and record the current status of the disputed information, or delete the item from the file in accordance with paragraph (5), before the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the agency receives the notice of the dispute from the consumer or reseller.


(B) Extension of period to reinvestigateExcept as provided in subparagraph (C), the 30-day period described in subparagraph (A) may be extended for not more than 15 additional days if the consumer reporting agency receives information from the consumer during that 30-day period that is relevant to the reinvestigation.


(C) Limitations on extension of period to reinvestigateSubparagraph (B) shall not apply to any reinvestigation in which, during the 30-day period described in subparagraph (A), the information that is the subject of the reinvestigation is found to be inaccurate or incomplete or the consumer reporting agency determines that the information cannot be verified.



(2) Prompt notice of dispute to furnisher of information(A) In generalBefore the expiration of the 5-business-day period beginning on the date on which a consumer reporting agency receives notice of a dispute from any consumer or a reseller in accordance with paragraph (1), the agency shall provide notification of the dispute to any person who provided any item of information in dispute, at the address and in the manner established with the person. The notice</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reinvestigations of disputed information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reinvestigations of disputed information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of dispute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statement of dispute If the reinvestigation does not resolve the dispute, the consumer may file a brief statement setting forth the nature of the dispute. The consumer reporting agency may limit such statements to not more than one hundred words if it provides the consumer with assistance in writing a clear summary of the dispute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of consumer dispute in subsequent consumer reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of consumer dispute in subsequent consumer reports Whenever a statement of a dispute is filed, unless there is reasonable grounds to believe that it is frivolous or irrelevant, the consumer reporting agency shall, in any subsequent consumer report containing the information in question, clearly note that it is disputed by the consumer and provide either the consumer’s statement or a clear and accurate codification or summary thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of deletion of disputed information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of deletion of disputed information Following any deletion of information which is found to be inaccurate or whose accuracy can no longer be verified or any notation as to disputed information, the consumer reporting agency shall, at the request of the consumer, furnish notification that the item has been deleted or the statement, codification or summary pursuant to subsection (b) or (c) to any person specifically designated by the consumer who has within two years prior thereto received a consumer report for employment purposes, or within six months prior thereto received a consumer report for any other purpose, which contained the deleted or disputed information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of complaints and report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of complaints and report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reinvestigation requirement applicable to resellers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reinvestigation requirement applicable to resellers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute process for veteran’s medical debt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Dispute process for veteran’s medical debt</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>