<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681v"><akn:num>1681v</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures to governmental agencies for counterterrorism purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681v. Disclosures to governmental agencies for counterterrorism purposes(a) DisclosureNotwithstanding section 1681b of this title or any other provision of this subchapter, a consumer reporting agency shall furnish a consumer report of a consumer and all other information in a consumer’s file to a government agency authorized to conduct investigations of, or intelligence or counterintelligence activities or analysis related to, international terrorism when presented with a written certification by such government agency that such information is necessary for the agency’s conduct or such investigation, activity or analysis and that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of such information.


(b) Form of certificationThe certification described in subsection (a) shall be signed by a supervisory official designated by the head of a Federal agency or an officer of a Federal agency whose appointment to office is required to be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(c) Prohibition of certain disclosure(1) Prohibition(A) In generalIf a certification is issued under subparagraph (B) and notice of the right to judicial review under subsection (d) is provided, no consumer reporting agency that receives a request under subsection (a), or officer, employee, or agent thereof, shall disclose or specify in any consumer report, that a government agency described in subsection (a) has sought or obtained access to information or records under subsection (a).


(B) CertificationThe requirements of subparagraph (A) shall apply if the head of the government agency described in subsection (a), or a designee, certifies that the absence of a prohibition of disclosure under this subsection may result in—(i) a danger to the national security of the United States;

(ii) interference with a criminal, counterterrorism, or counterintelligence investigation;

(iii) interference with dip</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosure Notwithstanding section 1681b of this title or any other provision of this subchapter, a consumer reporting agency shall furnish a consumer report of a consumer and all other information in a consumer’s file to a government agency authorized to conduct investigations of, or intelligence or counterintelligence activities or analysis related to, international terrorism when presented with a written certification by such government agency that such information is necessary for the agency’s conduct or such investigation, activity or analysis and that includes a term that specifically identifies a consumer or account to be used as the basis for the production of such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form of certification The certification described in subsection (a) shall be signed by a supervisory official designated by the head of a Federal agency or an officer of a Federal agency whose appointment to office is required to be made by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of certain disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition of certain disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in section 1681u of this title shall be construed to limit the authority of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safe harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Safe harbor Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, any consumer reporting agency or agent or employee thereof making disclosure of consumer reports or other information pursuant to this section in good-faith reliance upon a certification of a government agency pursuant to the provisions of this section shall not be liable to any person for such disclosure under this subchapter, the constitution of any State, or any law or regulation of any State or any political subdivision of any State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681v_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>