<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681j"><akn:num>1681j</akn:num><akn:heading>Charges for certain disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681j. Charges for certain disclosures(a) Free annual disclosure(1) Nationwide consumer reporting agencies(A) In generalAll consumer reporting agencies described in subsections (p) and (w) 11 See References in Text note below. of section 1681a of this title shall make all disclosures pursuant to section 1681g of this title once during any 12-month period upon request of the consumer and without charge to the consumer.


(B) Centralized sourceSubparagraph (A) shall apply with respect to a consumer reporting agency described in section 1681a(p) of this title only if the request from the consumer is made using the centralized source established for such purpose in accordance with section 211(c) 1 of the Fair and Accurate Credit Transactions Act of 2003.


(C) Nationwide specialty consumer reporting agency(i) In generalThe Commission 22 So in original. Probably should be “Bureau”. shall prescribe regulations applicable to each consumer reporting agency described in section 1681a(w) 1 of this title to require the establishment of a streamlined process for consumers to request consumer reports under subparagraph (A), which shall include, at a minimum, the establishment by each such agency of a toll-free telephone number for such requests.


(ii) ConsiderationsIn prescribing regulations under clause (i), the Bureau shall consider—(I) the significant demands that may be placed on consumer reporting agencies in providing such consumer reports;

(II) appropriate means to ensure that consumer reporting agencies can satisfactorily meet those demands, including the efficacy of a system of staggering the availability to consumers of such consumer reports; and

(III) the ease by which consumers should be able to contact consumer reporting agencies with respect to access to such consumer reports.


(iii) Date of issuanceThe Commission 2 shall issue the regulations required by this subparagraph in final form not later than 6 months after December 4, 2003.


(iv) Consideration of a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free annual disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Free annual disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free disclosure after adverse notice to consumer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Free disclosure after adverse notice to consumer Each consumer reporting agency that maintains a file on a consumer shall make all disclosures pursuant to section 1681g of this title without charge to the consumer if, not later than 60 days after receipt by such consumer of a notification pursuant to section 1681m of this title, or of a notification from a debt collection agency affiliated with that consumer reporting agency stating that the consumer’s credit rating may be or has been adversely affected, the consumer makes a request under section 1681g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free disclosure under certain other circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Free disclosure under certain other circumstances Upon the request of the consumer, a consumer reporting agency shall make all disclosures pursuant to section 1681g of this title once during any 12-month period without charge to that consumer if the consumer certifies in writing that the consumer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free disclosures in connection with fraud alerts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Free disclosures in connection with fraud alerts Upon the request of a consumer, a consumer reporting agency described in section 1681a(p) of this title shall make all disclosures pursuant to section 1681g of this title without charge to the consumer, as provided in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2) of section 1681c–1 of this title, as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other charges prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other charges prohibited A consumer reporting agency shall not impose any charge on a consumer for providing any notification required by this subchapter or making any disclosure required by this subchapter, except as authorized by subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable charges allowed for certain disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reasonable charges allowed for certain disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681j_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of deceptive marketing of credit reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prevention of deceptive marketing of credit reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>