<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681e"><akn:num>1681e</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681e. Compliance procedures(a) Identity and purposes of credit usersEvery consumer reporting agency shall maintain reasonable procedures designed to avoid violations of section 1681c of this title and to limit the furnishing of consumer reports to the purposes listed under section 1681b of this title. These procedures shall require that prospective users of the information identify themselves, certify the purposes for which the information is sought, and certify that the information will be used for no other purpose. Every consumer reporting agency shall make a reasonable effort to verify the identity of a new prospective user and the uses certified by such prospective user prior to furnishing such user a consumer report. No consumer reporting agency may furnish a consumer report to any person if it has reasonable grounds for believing that the consumer report will not be used for a purpose listed in section 1681b of this title.


(b) Accuracy of reportWhenever a consumer reporting agency prepares a consumer report it shall follow reasonable procedures to assure maximum possible accuracy of the information concerning the individual about whom the report relates.


(c) Disclosure of consumer reports by users allowedA consumer reporting agency may not prohibit a user of a consumer report furnished by the agency on a consumer from disclosing the contents of the report to the consumer, if adverse action against the consumer has been taken by the user based in whole or in part on the report.


(d) Notice to users and furnishers of information(1) Notice requirementA consumer reporting agency shall provide to any person—(A) who regularly and in the ordinary course of business furnishes information to the agency with respect to any consumer; or

(B) to whom a consumer report is provided by the agency;


a notice of such person’s responsibilities under this subchapter.

(2) Content of noticeThe Bureau shall prescribe the content of notices under paragraph (1), and a consu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identity and purposes of credit users</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Identity and purposes of credit users Every consumer reporting agency shall maintain reasonable procedures designed to avoid violations of section 1681c of this title and to limit the furnishing of consumer reports to the purposes listed under section 1681b of this title. These procedures shall require that prospective users of the information identify themselves, certify the purposes for which the information is sought, and certify that the information will be used for no other purpose. Every consumer reporting agency shall make a reasonable effort to verify the identity of a new prospective user and the uses certified by such prospective user prior to furnishing such user a consumer report. No consumer reporting agency may furnish a consumer report to any person if it has reasonable grounds for believing that the consumer report will not be used for a purpose listed in section 1681b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accuracy of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accuracy of report Whenever a consumer reporting agency prepares a consumer report it shall follow reasonable procedures to assure maximum possible accuracy of the information concerning the individual about whom the report relates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of consumer reports by users allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure of consumer reports by users allowed A consumer reporting agency may not prohibit a user of a consumer report furnished by the agency on a consumer from disclosing the contents of the report to the consumer, if adverse action against the consumer has been taken by the user based in whole or in part on the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to users and furnishers of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice to users and furnishers of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of consumer report for resale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procurement of consumer report for resale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>