<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1681s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681s"><akn:num>1681s</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681s. Administrative enforcement(a) Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission(1) In generalThe Federal Trade Commission shall be authorized to enforce compliance with the requirements imposed by this subchapter under the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.), with respect to consumer reporting agencies and all other persons subject thereto, except to the extent that enforcement of the requirements imposed under this subchapter is specifically committed to some other Government agency under any of subparagraphs (A) through (G) of subsection (b)(1), and subject to subtitle B of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 [12 U.S.C. 5511 et seq.], subsection (b).11 So in original. For the purpose of the exercise by the Federal Trade Commission of its functions and powers under the Federal Trade Commission Act, a violation of any requirement or prohibition imposed under this subchapter shall constitute an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce, in violation of section 5(a) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 45(a)), and shall be subject to enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission under section 5(b) of that Act [15 U.S.C. 45(b)] with respect to any consumer reporting agency or person that is subject to enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission pursuant to this subsection, irrespective of whether that person is engaged in commerce or meets any other jurisdictional tests under the Federal Trade Commission Act. The Federal Trade Commission shall have such procedural, investigative, and enforcement powers, including the power to issue procedural rules in enforcing compliance with the requirements imposed under this subchapter and to require the filing of reports, the production of documents, and the appearance of witnesses, as though the applicable terms and conditions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were part of this subchapter. Any person violating any of the provisions of this subchapter shall be subject to the penalties and e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement by other agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State action for violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State action for violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement under other authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement under other authority For the purpose of the exercise by any agency referred to in subsection (b) of its powers under any Act referred to in that subsection, a violation of any requirement imposed under this subchapter shall be deemed to be a violation of a requirement imposed under that Act. In addition to its powers under any provision of law specifically referred to in subsection (b), each of the agencies referred to in that subsection may exercise, for the purpose of enforcing compliance with any requirement imposed under this subchapter any other authority conferred on it by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulatory authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of consumer complaint investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination of consumer complaint investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681s_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau regulation of coding of trade names</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bureau regulation of coding of trade names If the Bureau determines that a person described in paragraph (9) of section 1681s–2(a) of this title has not met the requirements of such paragraph, the Bureau shall take action to ensure the person’s compliance with such paragraph, which may include issuing model guidance or prescribing reasonable policies and procedures, as necessary to ensure that such person complies with such paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>