<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1691b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1691b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1691b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1691b"><akn:num>1691b</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of regulations by the Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1691b. Promulgation of regulations by the Bureau(a) In generalThe Bureau shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. These regulations may contain but are not limited to such classifications, differentiation, or other provision, and may provide for such adjustments and exceptions for any class of transactions, as in the judgment of the Bureau are necessary or proper to effectuate the purposes of this subchapter, to prevent circumvention or evasion thereof, or to facilitate or substantiate compliance therewith.


(b) Exempt transactionsSuch regulations may exempt from the provisions of this subchapter any class of transactions that are not primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, or business or commercial loans made available by a financial institution, except that a particular type within a class of such transactions may be exempted if the Bureau determines, after making an express finding that the application of this subchapter or of any provision of this subchapter of such transaction would not contribute substantially to effecting the purposes of this subchapter.


(c) Limitation on exemptionsAn exemption granted pursuant to subsection (b) shall be for no longer than five years and shall be extended only if the Bureau makes a subsequent determination, in the manner described by such paragraph,11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection,”. that such exemption remains appropriate.


(d) Maintenance of recordsPursuant to Bureau regulations, entities making business or commercial loans shall maintain such records or other data relating to such loans as may be necessary to evidence compliance with this subsection 22 So in original. or enforce any action pursuant to the authority of this chapter. In no event shall such records or data be maintained for a period of less than one year. The Bureau shall promulgate regulations to implement this paragraph 33 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. in the manner pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Bureau shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. These regulations may contain but are not limited to such classifications, differentiation, or other provision, and may provide for such adjustments and exceptions for any class of transactions, as in the judgment of the Bureau are necessary or proper to effectuate the purposes of this subchapter, to prevent circumvention or evasion thereof, or to facilitate or substantiate compliance therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exempt transactions Such regulations may exempt from the provisions of this subchapter any class of transactions that are not primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, or business or commercial loans made available by a financial institution, except that a particular type within a class of such transactions may be exempted if the Bureau determines, after making an express finding that the application of this subchapter or of any provision of this subchapter of such transaction would not contribute substantially to effecting the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on exemptions An exemption granted pursuant to subsection (b) shall be for no longer than five years and shall be extended only if the Bureau makes a subsequent determination, in the manner described by such paragraph,11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection,”. that such exemption remains appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maintenance of records Pursuant to Bureau regulations, entities making business or commercial loans shall maintain such records or other data relating to such loans as may be necessary to evidence compliance with this subsection 22 So in original. or enforce any action pursuant to the authority of this chapter. In no event shall such records or data be maintained for a period of less than one year. The Bureau shall promulgate regulations to implement this paragraph 33 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. in the manner prescribed by chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of denial of loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of denial of loan The Bureau shall provide in regulations that an applicant for a business or commercial loan shall be provided a written notice of such applicant’s right to receive a written statement of the reasons for the denial of such loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Board authority Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Board shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purposes of this subchapter with respect to a person described in section 5519(a) of title 12. These regulations may contain but are not limited to such classifications, differentiation, or other provision, and may provide for such adjustments and exceptions for any class of transactions, as in the judgment of the Board are necessary or proper to effectuate the purposes of this subchapter, to prevent circumvention or evasion thereof, or to facilitate or substantiate compliance therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1691b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Deference Notwithstanding any power granted to any Federal agency under this subchapter, the deference that a court affords to a Federal agency with respect to a determination made by such agency relating to the meaning or interpretation of any provision of this subchapter that is subject to the jurisdiction of such agency shall be applied as if that agency were the only agency authorized to apply, enforce, interpret, or administer the provisions of this subchapter 44 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>