<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693l–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693l–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693l–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1693l_1"><akn:num>1693l–1</akn:num><akn:heading>General-use prepaid cards, gift certificates, and store gift cards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1693l–1. General-use prepaid cards, gift certificates, and store gift cards(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Dormancy fee; inactivity charge or feeThe terms “dormancy fee” and “inactivity charge or fee” mean a fee, charge, or penalty for non-use or inactivity of a gift certificate, store gift card, or general-use prepaid card.


(2) General use 11 So in original. Probably should be “General-use”. prepaid card, gift certificate, and store gift card(A) General-use prepaid cardThe term “general-use prepaid card” means a card or other payment code or device issued by any person that is—(i) redeemable at multiple, unaffiliated merchants or service providers, or automated teller machines;

(ii) issued in a requested amount, whether or not that amount may, at the option of the issuer, be increased in value or reloaded if requested by the holder;

(iii) purchased or loaded on a prepaid basis; and

(iv) honored, upon presentation, by merchants for goods or services, or at automated teller machines.


(B) Gift certificateThe term “gift certificate” means an electronic promise that is—(i) redeemable at a single merchant or an affiliated group of merchants that share the same name, mark, or logo;

(ii) issued in a specified amount that may not be increased or reloaded;

(iii) purchased on a prepaid basis in exchange for payment; and

(iv) honored upon presentation by such single merchant or affiliated group of merchants for goods or services.


(C) Store gift cardThe term “store gift card” means an electronic promise, plastic card, or other payment code or device that is—(i) redeemable at a single merchant or an affiliated group of merchants that share the same name, mark, or logo;

(ii) issued in a specified amount, whether or not that amount may be increased in value or reloaded at the request of the holder;

(iii) purchased on a prepaid basis in exchange for payment; and

(iv) honored upon presentation by such single merchant or affi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693l_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693l_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on imposition of fees or charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on imposition of fees or charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693l_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on sale of gift cards with expiration dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on sale of gift cards with expiration dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693l_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>