<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1693f"><akn:num>1693f</akn:num><akn:heading>Error resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1693f. Error resolution(a) Notification to financial institution of errorIf a financial institution, within sixty days after having transmitted to a consumer documentation pursuant to section 1693d(a), (c), or (d) of this title or notification pursuant to section 1693d(b) of this title, receives oral or written notice in which the consumer—(1) sets forth or otherwise enables the financial institution to identify the name and account number of the consumer;

(2) indicates the consumer’s belief that the documentation, or, in the case of notification pursuant to section 1693d(b) of this title, the consumer’s account, contains an error and the amount of such error; and

(3) sets forth the reasons for the consumer’s belief (where applicable) that an error has occurred,


the financial institution shall investigate the alleged error, determine whether an error has occurred, and report or mail the results of such investigation and determination to the consumer within ten business days. The financial institution may require written confirmation to be provided to it within ten business days of an oral notification of error if, when the oral notification is made, the consumer is advised of such requirement and the address to which such confirmation should be sent. A financial institution which requires written confirmation in accordance with the previous sentence need not provisionally recredit a consumer’s account in accordance with subsection (c), nor shall the financial institution be liable under subsection (e) if the written confirmation is not received within the ten-day period referred to in the previous sentence.

(b) Correction of error; interestIf the financial institution determines that an error did occur, it shall promptly, but in no event more than one business day after such determination, correct the error, subject to section 1693g of this title, including the crediting of interest where applicable.


(c) Provisional recredit of consumer’s accountIf a financ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to financial institution of error</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification to financial institution of error If a financial institution, within sixty days after having transmitted to a consumer documentation pursuant to section 1693d(a), (c), or (d) of this title or notification pursuant to section 1693d(b) of this title, receives oral or written notice in which the consumer— the financial institution shall investigate the alleged error, determine whether an error has occurred, and report or mail the results of such investigation and determination to the consumer within ten business days. The financial institution may require written confirmation to be provided to it within ten business days of an oral notification of error if, when the oral notification is made, the consumer is advised of such requirement and the address to which such confirmation should be sent. A financial institution which requires written confirmation in accordance with the previous sentence need not provisionally recredit a consumer’s account in accordance with subsecti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Correction of error; interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Correction of error; interest If the financial institution determines that an error did occur, it shall promptly, but in no event more than one business day after such determination, correct the error, subject to section 1693g of this title, including the crediting of interest where applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisional recredit of consumer’s account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provisional recredit of consumer’s account If a financial institution receives notice of an error in the manner and within the time period specified in subsection (a), it may, in lieu of the requirements of subsections (a) and (b), within ten business days after receiving such notice provisionally recredit the consumer’s account for the amount alleged to be in error, subject to section 1693g of this title, including interest where applicable, pending the conclusion of its investigation and its determination of whether an error has occurred. Such investigation shall be concluded not later than forty-five days after receipt of notice of the error. During the pendency of the investigation, the consumer shall have full use of the funds provisionally recredited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Absence of error; finding; explanation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Absence of error; finding; explanation If the financial institution determines after its investigation pursuant to subsection (a) or (c) that an error did not occur, it shall deliver or mail to the consumer an explanation of its findings within 3 business days after the conclusion of its investigation, and upon request of the consumer promptly deliver or mail to the consumer reproductions of all documents which the financial institution relied on to conclude that such error did not occur. The financial institution shall include notice of the right to request reproductions with the explanation of its findings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treble damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treble damages If in any action under section 1693m 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the court finds that— then the consumer shall be entitled to treble damages determined under section 1693m(a)(1) 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acts constituting error</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Acts constituting error For the purpose of this section, an error consists of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>