<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1693n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1693n"><akn:num>1693n</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1693n. Criminal liability(a) Violations respecting giving of false or inaccurate information, failure to provide information, and failure to comply with provisions of this subchapterWhoever knowingly and willfully—(1) gives false or inaccurate information or fails to provide information which he is required to disclose by this subchapter or any regulation issued thereunder; or

(2) otherwise fails to comply with any provision of this subchapter;


shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.

(b) Violations affecting interstate or foreign commerceWhoever—(1) knowingly, in a transaction affecting interstate or foreign commerce, uses or attempts or conspires to use any counterfeit, fictitious, altered, forged, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained debit instrument to obtain money, goods, services, or anything else of value which within any one-year period has a value aggregating $1,000 or more; or

(2) with unlawful or fraudulent intent, transports or attempts or conspires to transport in interstate or foreign commerce a counterfeit, fictitious, altered, forged, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained debit instrument knowing the same to be counterfeit, fictitious, altered, forged, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained; or

(3) with unlawful or fraudulent intent, uses any instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce to sell or transport a counterfeit, fictitious, altered, forged, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained debit instrument knowing the same to be counterfeit, fictitious, altered, forged, lost, stolen, or fraudulently obtained; or

(4) knowingly receives, conceals, uses, or transports money, goods, services, or anything else of value (except tickets for interstate or foreign transportation) which (A) within any one-year period has a value aggregating $1,000 or more, (B) has moved in or is part of, or which constitutes interstate or foreign commerce, and (C) has been obtained with a counterfeit, fictitious, altere</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations respecting giving of false or inaccurate information, failure to provide information, and failure to comply with provisions of this subchapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations respecting giving of false or inaccurate information, failure to provide information, and failure to comply with provisions of this subchapter Whoever knowingly and willfully— shall be fined not more than $5,000 or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations affecting interstate or foreign commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Violations affecting interstate or foreign commerce Whoever— shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned not more than ten years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1693n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Debit instrument” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Debit instrument” defined As used in this section, the term “debit instrument” means a card, code, or other device, other than a check, draft, or similar paper instrument, by the use of which a person may initiate an electronic fund transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>