<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704"><akn:num>1704</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of subdivisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704. Registration of subdivisions(a) Filing of statement of recordA subdivision may be registered by filing with the Director a statement of record, meeting the requirements of this chapter and such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Director in furtherance of the provisions of this chapter. A statement of record shall be deemed effective only as to the lots specified therein.


(b) Payment of fees; use by DirectorAt the time of filing a statement of record, or any amendment thereto, the developer shall pay to the Director a fee, not in excess of $1,000, in accordance with a schedule to be fixed by the regulations of the Director, which fees may be used by the Director to cover all or part of the cost of rendering services under this chapter, and such expenses as are paid from such fees shall be considered nonadministrative.


(c) Filing deemed to have taken place upon receipt of statement of record accompanied by feeThe filing with the Director of a statement of record, or of an amendment thereto, shall be deemed to have taken place upon the receipt thereof, accompanied by payment of the fee required by subsection (b).


(d) Availability of information to publicThe information contained in or filed with any statement of record shall be made available to the public under such regulations as the Director may prescribe and copies thereof shall be furnished to every applicant at such reasonable charge as the Director may prescribe.


(Pub. L. 90–448, title XIV, § 1405, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 592; Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1098A(1), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2105.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2010—Pub. L. 111–203 substituted “Director” for “Secretary” wherever appearing.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2010 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 111–203 effective on the designated transfer date, see section 1100H of Pub. L. 111–203, set out as a note under section 552a of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.

Effective Dat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of statement of record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing of statement of record A subdivision may be registered by filing with the Director a statement of record, meeting the requirements of this chapter and such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Director in furtherance of the provisions of this chapter. A statement of record shall be deemed effective only as to the lots specified therein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of fees; use by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of fees; use by Director At the time of filing a statement of record, or any amendment thereto, the developer shall pay to the Director a fee, not in excess of $1,000, in accordance with a schedule to be fixed by the regulations of the Director, which fees may be used by the Director to cover all or part of the cost of rendering services under this chapter, and such expenses as are paid from such fees shall be considered nonadministrative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing deemed to have taken place upon receipt of statement of record accompanied by fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Filing deemed to have taken place upon receipt of statement of record accompanied by fee The filing with the Director of a statement of record, or of an amendment thereto, shall be deemed to have taken place upon the receipt thereof, accompanied by payment of the fee required by subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of information to public The information contained in or filed with any statement of record shall be made available to the public under such regulations as the Director may prescribe and copies thereof shall be furnished to every applicant at such reasonable charge as the Director may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>