<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1709" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1709/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1709/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1709"><akn:num>1709</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1709. Civil liabilities(a) Violations; relief recoverableA purchaser or lessee may bring an action at law or in equity against a developer or agent if the sale or lease was made in violation of section 1703(a) of this title. In a suit authorized by this subsection, the court may order damages, specific performance, or such other relief as the court deems fair, just, and equitable. In determining such relief the court may take into account, but not be limited to, the following factors: the contract price of the lot or leasehold; the amount the purchaser or lessee actually paid; the cost of any improvements to the lot; the fair market value of the lot or leasehold at the time relief is determined; and the fair market value of the lot or leasehold at the time such lot was purchased or leased.


(b) Enforcement of rights by purchaser or lesseeA purchaser or lessee may bring an action at law or in equity against the seller or lessor (or successor thereof) to enforce any right under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (e) of section 1703 of this title.


(c) Amounts recoverableThe amount recoverable in a suit authorized by this section may include, in addition to matters specified in subsections (a) and (b), interest, court costs, and reasonable amounts for attorneys’ fees, independent appraisers’ fees, and travel to and from the lot.


(d) ContributionsEvery person who becomes liable to make any payment under this section may recover contribution as in cases of contract from any person who, if sued separately, would have been liable to make the same payment.


(Pub. L. 90–448, title XIV, § 1410, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 595; Pub. L. 96–153, title IV, § 405, Dec. 21, 1979, 93 Stat. 1130.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1979—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 96–153 substituted provisions relating to violations of section 1703(a) of this title and scope of relief authorized in suits brought against such violations, for provisions relating to suits for untrue statements or omissions to state materi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations; relief recoverable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations; relief recoverable A purchaser or lessee may bring an action at law or in equity against a developer or agent if the sale or lease was made in violation of section 1703(a) of this title. In a suit authorized by this subsection, the court may order damages, specific performance, or such other relief as the court deems fair, just, and equitable. In determining such relief the court may take into account, but not be limited to, the following factors: the contract price of the lot or leasehold; the amount the purchaser or lessee actually paid; the cost of any improvements to the lot; the fair market value of the lot or leasehold at the time relief is determined; and the fair market value of the lot or leasehold at the time such lot was purchased or leased.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of rights by purchaser or lessee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement of rights by purchaser or lessee A purchaser or lessee may bring an action at law or in equity against the seller or lessor (or successor thereof) to enforce any right under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (e) of section 1703 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts recoverable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amounts recoverable The amount recoverable in a suit authorized by this section may include, in addition to matters specified in subsections (a) and (b), interest, court costs, and reasonable amounts for attorneys’ fees, independent appraisers’ fees, and travel to and from the lot.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contributions Every person who becomes liable to make any payment under this section may recover contribution as in cases of contract from any person who, if sued separately, would have been liable to make the same payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>