<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1717a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1717a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1717a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1717a"><akn:num>1717a</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1717a. Civil money penalties(a) In general(1) AuthorityWhenever any person knowingly and materially violates any of the provisions of this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order issued under this chapter, the Director may impose a civil money penalty on such person in accordance with the provisions of this section. The penalty shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Director imposes other administrative sanctions.


(2) Amount of penaltyThe amount of the penalty, as determined by the Director, may not exceed $1,000 for each violation, except that the maximum penalty for all violations by a particular person during any 1-year period shall not exceed $1,000,000. Each violation of this chapter, or any rule, regulation, or order issued under this chapter, shall constitute a separate violation with respect to each sale or lease or offer to sell or lease. In the case of a continuing violation, as determined by the Director, each day shall constitute a separate violation.



(b) Agency procedures(1) EstablishmentThe Director shall establish standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under subsection (a). The standards and procedures—(A) shall provide for the imposition of a penalty only after a person has been given an opportunity for a hearing on the record; and

(B) may provide for review by the Director of any determination or order, or interlocutory ruling, arising from a hearing.


(2) Final ordersIf no hearing is requested within 15 days of receipt of the notice of opportunity for hearing, the imposition of the penalty shall constitute a final and unappealable determination. If the Director reviews the determination or order, the Director may affirm, modify, or reverse that determination or order. If the Director does not review the determination or order within 90 days of the issuance of the determination or order, the determination or order</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agency procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of agency determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Judicial review of agency determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to collect penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Action to collect penalty If any person fails to comply with the determination or order of the Director imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (a), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by subsections (b) and (c), the Director may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in any appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the person and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the discretion of the court, include any attorneys fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s 1 determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Settlement by Director The Director may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Knowingly” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Knowingly” defined The term “knowingly” means having actual knowledge of or acting with deliberate ignorance of or reckless disregard for the prohibitions under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Director shall issue such regulations as the Director deems appropriate to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1717a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of penalties for administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of penalties for administration Civil money penalties collected under this section shall be paid to the Director and, upon approval in an appropriation Act, may be used by the Director to cover all or part of the cost of rendering services under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>