<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1825" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1825/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1825/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1825"><akn:num>1825</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1825. Violations and penalties(a) Criminal acts and penalties(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, any person who knowingly violates section 1824 of this title shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than $3,000, or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.

(2)(A) If any person knowingly violates section 1824 of this title, after one or more prior convictions of such person for such a violation have become final, such person shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than two years, or both.

(B) Any person who knowingly makes, or causes to be made, a false entry or statement in any report required under this chapter; who knowingly makes, or causes to be made, any false entry in any account, record, or memorandum required to be established and maintained by any person or in any notification or other information required to be submitted to the Secretary under section 1823 of this title; who knowingly neglects or fails to make or cause to be made, full, true, and correct entries in such accounts, records, memoranda, notification, or other materials; who knowingly removes any such documentary evidence out of the jurisdiction of the United States; who knowingly mutilates, alters, or by any other means falsifies any such documentary evidence; or who knowingly refuses to submit any such documentary evidence to the Secretary for inspection and copying shall be guilty of an offense against the United States, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned for not more than three years, or both.

(C) Any person who forcibly assaults, resists, opposes, impedes, intimidates, or interferes with any person while engaged in or on account of the performance of his official duties under this chapter shall be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than three years, or both. Whoever, in the commission of such acts, uses a deadly or dangerous weapon shall </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1825_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal acts and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criminal acts and penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1825_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties; review and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil penalties; review and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1825_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification of offenders; orders; civil penalties applicable; enforcement procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disqualification of offenders; orders; civil penalties applicable; enforcement procedures In addition to any fine, imprisonment, or civil penalty authorized under this section, any person who was convicted under subsection (a) or who paid a civil penalty assessed under subsection (b) or is subject to a final order under such subsection assessing a civil penalty for any violation of any provision of this chapter or any regulation issued under this chapter may be disqualified by order of the Secretary, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing before the Secretary, from showing or exhibiting any horse, judging or managing any horse show, horse exhibition, or horse sale or auction for a period of not less than one year for the first violation and not less than five years for any subsequent violation. Any person who knowingly fails to obey an order of disqualification shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $3,000 for each violation. Any horse show, horse exhibition, o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1825_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production of witnesses and books, papers, and documents; depositions; fees; presumptions; jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Production of witnesses and books, papers, and documents; depositions; fees; presumptions; jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1825_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detention of horses; seizure and condemnation of equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Detention of horses; seizure and condemnation of equipment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>