<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1850" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1850/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/1850/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1850"><akn:num>1850</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Government’s interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1850. Protection of Government’s interest(a) Attorney General, enforcement authority; payments into emergency loan guarantee fundThe Attorney General shall take such action as may be appropriate to enforce any right accruing to the United States or any officer or agency thereof as a result of the issuance of guarantees under this chapter. Any sums recovered pursuant to this section shall be paid into the emergency loan guarantee fund.


(b) Recovery rights; subrogationThe Board shall be entitled to recover from the borrower, or any other person liable therefor, the amount of any payments made pursuant to any guarantee agreement entered into under this chapter, and upon making any such payment, the Board shall be subrogated to all the rights of the recipient thereof.


(Pub. L. 92–70, § 11, Aug. 9, 1971, 85 Stat. 181.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1850_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General, enforcement authority; payments into emergency loan guarantee fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Attorney General, enforcement authority; payments into emergency loan guarantee fund The Attorney General shall take such action as may be appropriate to enforce any right accruing to the United States or any officer or agency thereof as a result of the issuance of guarantees under this chapter. Any sums recovered pursuant to this section shall be paid into the emergency loan guarantee fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1850_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery rights; subrogation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recovery rights; subrogation The Board shall be entitled to recover from the borrower, or any other person liable therefor, the amount of any payments made pursuant to any guarantee agreement entered into under this chapter, and upon making any such payment, the Board shall be subrogated to all the rights of the recipient thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>