<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2052"><akn:num>2052</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2052. Definitions(a) In generalIn this chapter:(1) Appropriate Congressional committeesThe term “appropriate Congressional committees” means the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.


(2) Children’s productThe term “children’s product” means a consumer product designed or intended primarily for children 12 years of age or younger. In determining whether a consumer product is primarily intended for a child 12 years of age or younger, the following factors shall be considered:(A) A statement by a manufacturer about the intended use of such product, including a label on such product if such statement is reasonable.

(B) Whether the product is represented in its packaging, display, promotion, or advertising as appropriate for use by children 12 years of age or younger.

(C) Whether the product is commonly recognized by consumers as being intended for use by a child 12 years of age or younger.

(D) The Age Determination Guidelines issued by the Commission staff in September 2002, and any successor to such guidelines.


(3) CommerceThe term “commerce” means trade, traffic, commerce, or transportation—(A) between a place in a State and any place outside thereof, or

(B) which affects trade, traffic, commerce, or transportation described in subparagraph (A).


(4) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Consumer Product Safety Commission, established by section 2053 of this title.


(5) Consumer productThe term “consumer product” means any article, or component part thereof, produced or distributed (i) for sale to a consumer for use in or around a permanent or temporary household or residence, a school, in recreation, or otherwise, or (ii) for the personal use, consumption or enjoyment of a consumer in or around a permanent or temporary household or residence, a school, in recreation, or otherwise; but such term does not include—(A) any article which is not customarily </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common carriers, contract carriers, third-party logistics provider, and freight forwarders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Common carriers, contract carriers, third-party logistics provider, and freight forwarders A common carrier, contract carrier, third-party logistics provider, or freight forwarder shall not, for purposes of this chapter, be deemed to be a manufacturer, distributor, or retailer of a consumer product solely by reason of receiving or transporting a consumer product in the ordinary course of its business as such a carrier or forwarder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>