<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2056f"><akn:num>2056f</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer product safety standard to protect against tip-over of clothing storage units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2056f. Consumer product safety standard to protect against tip-over of clothing storage units(a) Clothing storage unit definedIn this section, the term “clothing storage unit” means any free-standing furniture item manufactured in the United States or imported for use in the United States that is intended for the storage of clothing, typical of bedroom furniture.


(b) CPSC determination of scopeThe Consumer Product Safety Commission shall specify the types of furniture items within the scope of subsection (a) as part of a standard promulgated under this section based on tip-over data as reasonably necessary to protect children up to 72 months of age from injury or death.


(c) Consumer product safety standard required(1) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (f)(1), not later than 1 year after December 29, 2022, the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall—(A) in consultation with representatives of consumer groups, clothing storage unit manufacturers, craft or handmade furniture manufacturers, and independent child product engineers and experts, examine and assess the effectiveness of any voluntary consumer product safety standards for clothing storage units; and

(B) in accordance with section 553 of title 5 and paragraph (2), promulgate a final consumer product safety standard for clothing storage units to protect children from tip-over-related death or injury, that shall take effect 180 days after the date of promulgation or such a later date as the Commission determines appropriate.


(2) RequirementsThe standard promulgated under paragraph (1) shall protect children from tip-over-related death or injury with—(A) tests that simulate the weight of children up to 60 pounds;

(B) objective, repeatable, reproducible, and measurable tests or series of tests that simulate real-world use and account for impacts on clothing storage unit stability that may result from placement on carpeted surfaces, drawers with items in them, multiple open drawers, and dynamic </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clothing storage unit defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Clothing storage unit defined In this section, the term “clothing storage unit” means any free-standing furniture item manufactured in the United States or imported for use in the United States that is intended for the storage of clothing, typical of bedroom furniture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>CPSC determination of scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) CPSC determination of scope The Consumer Product Safety Commission shall specify the types of furniture items within the scope of subsection (a) as part of a standard promulgated under this section based on tip-over data as reasonably necessary to protect children up to 72 months of age from injury or death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer product safety standard required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consumer product safety standard required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of voluntary standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adoption of voluntary standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of voluntary standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Revision of voluntary standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsequent rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>