<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2056c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2056c"><akn:num>2056c</akn:num><akn:heading>Sulfur content in drywall standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2056c. Sulfur content in drywall standard(a) Rule on sulfur content in drywall requiredExcept as provided in subsection (c), not later than 2 years after January 14, 2013, the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall promulgate a final rule pertaining to drywall manufactured or imported for use in the United States that limits sulfur content to a level not associated with elevated rates of corrosion in the home.


(b) Rule making; consumer product safety standardA rule under subsection (a)—(1) shall be promulgated in accordance with section 553 of title 5; and

(2) shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 2058 of this title.


(c) Exception(1) Voluntary standardSubsection (a) shall not apply if the Commission determines that—(A) a voluntary standard pertaining to drywall manufactured or imported for use in the United States limits sulfur content to a level not associated with elevated rates of corrosion in the home;

(B) such voluntary standard is or will be in effect not later than two years after January 14, 2013; and

(C) such voluntary standard is developed by Subcommittee C11.01 on Specifications and Test Methods for Gypsum Products of ASTM International.


(2) Federal RegisterAny determination made under paragraph (1) shall be published in the Federal Register.



(d) Treatment of voluntary standard for purposes of enforcementIf the Commission determines that a voluntary standard meets the conditions in subsection (c)(1), the sulfur content limit in such voluntary standard shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 2058 of this title beginning on the date that is the later of—(1) 180 days after publication of the Commission’s determination under subsection (c); or

(2) the effective date contained in the voluntary standard.


(e) Revision of voluntary standardIf the sulfur content limit of a voluntary standard that met the conditions of subsection (c)(1) is subsequently revised, the organi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule on sulfur content in drywall required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rule on sulfur content in drywall required Except as provided in subsection (c), not later than 2 years after January 14, 2013, the Consumer Product Safety Commission shall promulgate a final rule pertaining to drywall manufactured or imported for use in the United States that limits sulfur content to a level not associated with elevated rates of corrosion in the home.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule making; consumer product safety standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rule making; consumer product safety standard A rule under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of voluntary standard for purposes of enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of voluntary standard for purposes of enforcement If the Commission determines that a voluntary standard meets the conditions in subsection (c)(1), the sulfur content limit in such voluntary standard shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 2058 of this title beginning on the date that is the later of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of voluntary standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Revision of voluntary standard If the sulfur content limit of a voluntary standard that met the conditions of subsection (c)(1) is subsequently revised, the organization responsible for the standard shall notify the Commission no later than 60 days after final approval of the revision. The sulfur content limit of the revised voluntary standard shall become enforceable as a Commission rule promulgated under section 2058 of this title, in lieu of the prior version, effective 180 days after the Commission is notified of the revision (or such later date as the Commission considers appropriate), unless within 90 days after receiving that notice the Commission determines that the sulfur content limit of the revised voluntary standard does not meet the requirements of subsection (c)(1)(A), in which case the Commission shall continue to enforce the prior version.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2056c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Future rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Future rulemaking The Commission, at any time subsequent to publication of the consumer product safety rule required by subsection (a) or a determination under subsection (c), may initiate a rulemaking in accordance with section 553 of title 5 to modify the sulfur content limit or to include any provision relating only to the composition or characteristics of drywall that the Commission determines is reasonably necessary to protect public health or safety. Any rule promulgated under this subsection shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule promulgated under section 2058 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>