<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2057c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2057c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2057c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2057c"><akn:num>2057c</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on sale of certain products containing specified phthalates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2057c. Prohibition on sale of certain products containing specified phthalates(a) Prohibition on the sale of certain products containing phthalatesBeginning on the date that is 180 days after August 14, 2008, it shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture for sale, offer for sale, distribute in commerce, or import into the United States any children’s toy or child care article that contains concentrations of more than 0.1 percent of di-(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP), dibutyl phthalate (DBP), or benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP).


(b) Prohibition on the sale of additional products containing certain phthalates(1) Interim prohibitionBeginning on the date that is 180 days after August 14, 2008, and until a final rule is promulgated under paragraph (3), it shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture for sale, offer for sale, distribute in commerce, or import into the United States any children’s toy that can be placed in a child’s mouth or child care article that contains concentrations of more than 0.1 percent of diisononyl phthalate (DINP), diisodecyl phthalate (DIDP), or di-n-octyl phthalate (DnOP).


(2) Chronic Hazard Advisory Panel(A) AppointmentNot earlier than 180 days after August 14, 2008, the Commission shall begin the process of appointing a Chronic Hazard Advisory Panel pursuant to the procedures of section 28 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2077) to study the effects on children’s health of all phthalates and phthalate alternatives as used in children’s toys and child care articles.


(B) ExaminationThe panel shall, within 18 months after its appointment under subparagraph (A), complete an examination of the full range of phthalates that are used in products for children and shall—(i) examine all of the potential health effects (including endocrine disrupting effects) of the full range of phthalates;

(ii) consider the potential health effects of each of these phthalates both in isolation and in combination with other phthalates;

(iii</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on the sale of certain products containing phthalates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on the sale of certain products containing phthalates Beginning on the date that is 180 days after August 14, 2008, it shall be unlawful for any person to manufacture for sale, offer for sale, distribute in commerce, or import into the United States any children’s toy or child care article that contains concentrations of more than 0.1 percent of di-(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP), dibutyl phthalate (DBP), or benzyl butyl phthalate (BBP).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on the sale of additional products containing certain phthalates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on the sale of additional products containing certain phthalates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application Effective on August 12, 2011,11 See References in Text note below. subsections (a) and (b)(1) and any rule promulgated under subsection (b)(3) shall apply to any plasticized component part of a children’s toy or child care article or any other component part of a children’s toy or child care article that is made of other materials that may contain phthalates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for inaccessible component parts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusion for inaccessible component parts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of violation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of violation A violation of subsection (a) or (b)(1) or any rule promulgated by the Commission under subsection (b)(3) shall be treated as a violation of section 19(a)(1) of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2068(a)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as consumer product safety standards; effect on State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment as consumer product safety standards; effect on State laws Subsections (a) and (b)(1) and any rule promulgated under subsection (b)(3) shall be considered consumer product safety standards under the Consumer Product Safety Act [15 U.S.C. 2051 et seq.]. Nothing in this section or the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2051 et seq.) shall be construed to preempt or otherwise affect any State requirement with respect to any phthalate alternative not specifically regulated in a consumer product safety standard under the Consumer Product Safety Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2057c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>