<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2058" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2058/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2058/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2058"><akn:num>2058</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for consumer product safety rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2058. Procedure for consumer product safety rules(a) Commencement of proceeding; publication of prescribed notice of proposed rulemaking; transmittal of noticeA proceeding for the development of a consumer product safety rule may be commenced by the publication in the Federal Register of an advance notice of proposed rulemaking which shall—(1) identify the product and the nature of the risk of injury associated with the product;

(2) include a summary of each of the regulatory alternatives under consideration by the Commission (including voluntary consumer product safety standards);

(3) include information with respect to any existing standard known to the Commission which may be relevant to the proceedings, together with a summary of the reasons why the Commission believes preliminarily that such standard does not eliminate or adequately reduce the risk of injury identified in paragraph (1);

(4) invite interested persons to submit to the Commission, within such period as the Commission shall specify in the notice (which period shall not be less than 30 days or more than 60 days after the date of publication of the notice), comments with respect to the risk of injury identified by the Commission, the regulatory alternatives being considered, and other possible alternatives for addressing the risk;

(5) invite any person (other than the Commission) to submit to the Commission, within such period as the Commission shall specify in the notice (which period shall not be less than 30 days after the date of publication of the notice), an existing standard or a portion of a standard as a proposed consumer product safety standard; and

(6) invite any person (other than the Commission) to submit to the Commission, within such period as the Commission shall specify in the notice (which period shall not be less than 30 days after the date of publication of the notice), a statement of intention to modify or develop a voluntary consumer product safety standard to address the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of proceeding; publication of prescribed notice of proposed rulemaking; transmittal of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commencement of proceeding; publication of prescribed notice of proposed rulemaking; transmittal of notice A proceeding for the development of a consumer product safety rule may be commenced by the publication in the Federal Register of an advance notice of proposed rulemaking which shall— The Commission shall transmit such notice within 10 calendar days to the appropriate Congressional committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary standard; publication as proposed rule; notice of reliance of Commission on standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Voluntary standard; publication as proposed rule; notice of reliance of Commission on standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of proposed rule; preliminary regulatory analysis; contents; transmittal of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication of proposed rule; preliminary regulatory analysis; contents; transmittal of notice No consumer product safety rule may be proposed by the Commission unless the Commission publishes in the Federal Register the text of the proposed rule, including any alternatives, which the Commission proposes to promulgate, together with a preliminary regulatory analysis containing— The Commission shall transmit such notice within 10 calendar days to the appropriate Congressional committees. Any proposed consumer product safety rule shall be issued within twelve months after the date of publication of the notice, unless the Commission determines that such proposed rule is not reasonably necessary to eliminate or reduce the risk of injury associated with the product or is not in the public interest. The Commission may extend the twelve-month period for good cause. If the Commission extends such period, it shall immediately transmit notice of such extension to the appropriate Congressiona</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of rule; time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Promulgation of rule; time</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expression of risk of injury; consideration of available product data; needs of elderly and handicapped</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expression of risk of injury; consideration of available product data; needs of elderly and handicapped A consumer product safety rule shall express in the rule itself the risk of injury which the standard is designed to eliminate or reduce. In promulgating such a rule the Commission shall consider relevant available product data including the results of research, development, testing, and investigation activities conducted generally and pursuant to this chapter. In the promulgation of such a rule the Commission shall also consider and take into account the special needs of elderly and handicapped persons to determine the extent to which such persons may be adversely affected by such rule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; final regulatory analysis; judicial review of rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Findings; final regulatory analysis; judicial review of rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of rule or standard; stockpiling of product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date of rule or standard; stockpiling of product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment or revocation of rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amendment or revocation of rule The Commission may by rule amend or revoke any consumer product safety rule. Such amendment or revocation shall specify the date on which it is to take effect which shall not exceed 180 days from the date the amendment or revocation is published unless the Commission finds for good cause shown that a later effective date is in the public interest and publishes its reasons for such finding. Where an amendment involves a material change in a consumer product safety rule, sections 2056 and 2057 of this title, and subsections (a) through (g) of this section shall apply. In order to revoke a consumer product safety rule, the Commission shall publish a proposal to revoke such rule in the Federal Register, and allow oral and written presentations in accordance with subsection (d)(2) of this section. It may revoke such rule only if it determines that the rule is not reasonably necessary to eliminate or reduce an unreasonable risk of injury associated with th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2058_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition to initiate rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Petition to initiate rulemaking The Commission shall grant, in whole or in part, or deny any petition under section 553(e) of title 5 requesting the Commission to initiate a rulemaking, within a reasonable time after the date on which such petition is filed. The Commission shall state the reasons for granting or denying such petition. The Commission may not deny any such petition on the basis of a voluntary standard unless the voluntary standard is in existence at the time of the denial of the petition, the Commission has determined that the voluntary standard is likely to result in the elimination or adequate reduction of the risk of injury identified in the petition, and it is likely that there will be substantial compliance with the standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>