<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/205l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/205l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/205l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_205l"><akn:num>205l</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation in acquisition of construction services and materials for Federal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 205l. Implementation in acquisition of construction services and materials for Federal facilities(a) In generalConstruction services and materials for Federal facilities shall be procured in accordance with the policies and procedures set forth in the provisions of title 10, referred to in section 3016 of such title as “chapter 137 legacy provisions”, section 3453 of such title, division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, and section 205b(2) of this title. Determination of a design method shall be based upon preliminary market research as required under section 3453(c) of title 10 and section 3307(d) of title 41. If the requirements of this subchapter conflict with the provisions of section 3453 of title 10 or section 3307(b) to (d) of title 41, then the provisions of such sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 3453 or 3307(b) to (d) shall take precedence.


(b) Concrete masonry unitsIn carrying out the policy set forth in section 205b of this title (with particular emphasis on the policy set forth in paragraph (2) of that section) a Federal agency may require that specifications for the acquisition of structures or systems of concrete masonry be expressed under the metric system of measurement, but may not incorporate specifications, that can only be satisfied by hard-metric versions of concrete masonry units, in a solicitation for design or construction of a Federal facility within the United States or its territories, or a portion of said Federal facility, unless the head of the agency determines in writing that—(1) hard-metric specifications are necessary in a contract for the repair or replacement of parts of Federal facilities in existence or under construction upon the effective date of the Savings in Construction Act of 1996; or

(2) the following 2 criteria are met:(A) the application requires hard-metric concrete masonry units to coordinate dimensionally into 100 millimeter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Construction services and materials for Federal facilities shall be procured in accordance with the policies and procedures set forth in the provisions of title 10, referred to in section 3016 of such title as “chapter 137 legacy provisions”, section 3453 of such title, division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, and section 205b(2) of this title. Determination of a design method shall be based upon preliminary market research as required under section 3453(c) of title 10 and section 3307(d) of title 41. If the requirements of this subchapter conflict with the provisions of section 3453 of title 10 or section 3307(b) to (d) of title 41, then the provisions of such sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 3453 or 3307(b) to (d) shall take precedence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concrete masonry units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Concrete masonry units In carrying out the policy set forth in section 205b of this title (with particular emphasis on the policy set forth in paragraph (2) of that section) a Federal agency may require that specifications for the acquisition of structures or systems of concrete masonry be expressed under the metric system of measurement, but may not incorporate specifications, that can only be satisfied by hard-metric versions of concrete masonry units, in a solicitation for design or construction of a Federal facility within the United States or its territories, or a portion of said Federal facility, unless the head of the agency determines in writing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recessed lighting fixtures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recessed lighting fixtures In carrying out the policy set forth in section 205b of this title (with particular emphasis on the policy set forth in paragraph (2) of that section) a Federal agency may require that specifications for the acquisition of structures or systems of recessed lighting fixtures be expressed under the metric system of measurement, but may not incorporate specifications, that can only be satisfied by hard-metric versions of recessed lighting fixtures, in a solicitation for design or construction of a Federal facility within the United States or its territories unless the head of the agency determines in writing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation The provisions of subsections (b) and (c) of this section shall not apply to Federal contracts to acquire construction products for the construction of facilities outside of the United States and its territories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 108–423, § 6, Nov. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2402</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_205l_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agency ombudsman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>