<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2063" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2063/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2063/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2063"><akn:num>2063</akn:num><akn:heading>Product certification and labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2063. Product certification and labeling(a) Certification accompanying product; products with more than one manufacturer(1) General conformity certification.—Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), every manufacturer of a product which is subject to a consumer product safety rule under this chapter or similar rule, ban, standard, or regulation under any other Act enforced by the Commission and which is imported for consumption or warehousing or distributed in commerce (and the private labeler of such product if such product bears a private label) shall issue a certificate which—(A) shall certify, based on a test of each product or upon a reasonable testing program, that such product complies with all rules, bans, standards, or regulations applicable to the product under this chapter or any other Act enforced by the Commission; and

(B) shall specify each such rule, ban, standard, or regulation applicable to the product.


(2) Third party testing requirement.—Effective on the dates provided in paragraph (3), before importing for consumption or warehousing or distributing in commerce any children’s product that is subject to a children’s product safety rule, every manufacturer of such children’s product (and the private labeler of such children’s product if such children’s product bears a private label) shall—(A) submit sufficient samples of the children’s product, or samples that are identical in all material respects to the product, to a third party conformity assessment body accredited under paragraph (3) to be tested for compliance with such children’s product safety rule; and

(B) based on such testing, issue a certificate that certifies that such children’s product complies with the children’s product safety rule based on the assessment of a third party conformity assessment body accredited to conduct such tests.


A manufacturer or private labeler shall issue either a separate certificate for each children’s product safety rule applicable to a product o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification accompanying product; products with more than one manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certification accompanying product; products with more than one manufacturer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules to establish reasonable testing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules to establish reasonable testing programs The Commission may by rule prescribe reasonable testing programs for any product which is subject to a consumer product safety rule under this chapter, or a similar rule, regulation, standard, or ban under any other Act enforced by the Commission, and for which a certificate is required under subsection (a). Any test or testing program on the basis of which a certificate is issued under subsection (a) may, at the option of the person required to certify the product, be conducted by an independent third party qualified to perform such tests, unless the Commission, by rule, requires testing by an independent third party for a particular rule, regulation, standard, or ban, or for a particular class of products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and contents of labels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form and contents of labels The Commission may by rule require the use and prescribe the form and content of labels which contain the following information (or that portion of it specified in the rule)— Such labels, where practicable, may be required by the Commission to be permanently marked on or affixed to any such consumer product. The Commission may, in appropriate cases, permit information required under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection to be coded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional regulations for third party testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional regulations for third party testing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal of accreditation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Requirements for certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Compliance of any children’s product with third party testing and certification or general conformity certification requirements under this section shall not be construed to exempt such children’s product from any requirement that such product actually be in conformity with all applicable rules, regulation, standards, or ban under any Act enforced by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2063_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for advertisements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirement for advertisements No advertisement for a consumer product or label or packaging of such product may contain a reference to a consumer product safety rule or a voluntary consumer product safety standard unless such product conforms with the applicable safety requirements of such rule or standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>