<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2078" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2078/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2078/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2078"><akn:num>2078</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with States and other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2078. Cooperation with States and other Federal agencies(a) Programs to promote Federal-State cooperationThe Commission shall establish a program to promote Federal-State cooperation for the purposes of carrying out this chapter. In implementing such program the Commission may—(1) accept from any State or local authorities engaged in activities relating to health, safety, or consumer protection assistance in such functions as injury data collection, investigation, and educational programs, as well as other assistance in the administration and enforcement of this chapter which such States or localities may be able and willing to provide and, if so agreed, may pay in advance or otherwise for the reasonable cost of such assistance, and

(2) commission any qualified officer or employee of any State or local agency as an officer of the Commission for the purpose of conducting examinations, investigations, and inspections.


(b) Appropriateness of State and local programsIn determining whether such proposed State and local programs are appropriate in implementing the purposes of this chapter, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to programs which establish separate State and local agencies to consolidate functions relating to product safety and other consumer protection activities.


(c) Cooperation of Federal departments and agenciesThe Commission may obtain from any Federal department or agency such statistics, data, program reports, and other materials as it may deem necessary to carry out its functions under this chapter. Each such department or agency may cooperate with the Commission and, to the extent permitted by law, furnish such materials to it. The Commission and the heads of other departments and agencies engaged in administering programs related to product safety shall, to the maximum extent practicable, cooperate and consult in order to insure fully coordinated efforts.


(d) Utilization of National Institute of Standards and TechnologyThe Com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs to promote Federal-State cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Programs to promote Federal-State cooperation The Commission shall establish a program to promote Federal-State cooperation for the purposes of carrying out this chapter. In implementing such program the Commission may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriateness of State and local programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriateness of State and local programs In determining whether such proposed State and local programs are appropriate in implementing the purposes of this chapter, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to programs which establish separate State and local agencies to consolidate functions relating to product safety and other consumer protection activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of Federal departments and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation of Federal departments and agencies The Commission may obtain from any Federal department or agency such statistics, data, program reports, and other materials as it may deem necessary to carry out its functions under this chapter. Each such department or agency may cooperate with the Commission and, to the extent permitted by law, furnish such materials to it. The Commission and the heads of other departments and agencies engaged in administering programs related to product safety shall, to the maximum extent practicable, cooperate and consult in order to insure fully coordinated efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of National Institute of Standards and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Utilization of National Institute of Standards and Technology The Commission shall, to the maximum extent practicable, utilize the resources and facilities of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, on a reimbursable basis, to perform research and analyses related to risks of injury associated with consumer products (including fire and flammability risks), to develop test methods, to conduct studies and investigations, and to provide technical advice and assistance in connection with the functions of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copies of accident or investigation reports to other agencies; conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Copies of accident or investigation reports to other agencies; conditions Notwithstanding section 2055(a)(3) of this title, the Commission may provide to another Federal agency or a State or local agency or authority engaged in activities relating to health, safety, or consumer protection, copies of any accident or investigation report made under this chapter by any officer, employee, or agent of the Commission only if (1) information which under section 2055(a)(2) of this title is to be considered confidential is not included in any copy of such report which is provided under this subsection; and (2) each Federal agency and State and local agency and authority which is to receive under this subsection a copy of such report provides assurances satisfactory to the Commission that the identity of any injured person and any person who treated an injured person will not, without the consent of the person identified, be included in— which the agency or authority makes available to any m</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of information with Federal, State, local, and foreign government agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sharing of information with Federal, State, local, and foreign government agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2078_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to State health departments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notification to State health departments Whenever the Commission is notified of any voluntary corrective action taken by a manufacturer (or a retailer in the case of a retailer selling a product under its own label) in consultation with the Commission, or issues an order under section 2064(c) or (d) of this title with respect to any product, the Commission shall notify each State’s health department (or other agency designated by the State) of such voluntary corrective action or order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>