<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2079" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2079/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2079/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2079"><akn:num>2079</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2079. Transfers of functions(a) Hazardous substances and poisonsThe functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act [15 U.S.C. 1261 et seq.] and the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 [15 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission. The functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], to the extent such functions relate to the administration and enforcement of the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970, are transferred to the Commission.


(b) Flammable fabricsThe functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Federal Trade Commission under the Flammable Fabrics Act [15 U.S.C. 1191 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission. The functions of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.], to the extent such functions relate to the administration and enforcement of the Flammable Fabrics Act, are transferred to the Commission.


(c) Household refrigeratorsThe functions of the Secretary of Commerce and the Federal Trade Commission under the Act of August 2, 1956 [15 U.S.C. 1211 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission.


(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 237, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3076

(e) Transfer of personnel, property, records, etc.; continued application of orders, rules, etc.(1)(A) All personnel, property, records, obligations, and commitments, which are used primarily with respect to any function transferred under the provisions of subsections (a), (b) and (c) of this section shall be transferred to the Commission, except those associated with fire and flammability research in the National Institute of Standards and Technology. The transfer of personnel pursuant to this paragraph shall be without reduction in classification or compensation for one year after such transfer, except that the Chairman of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous substances and poisons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hazardous substances and poisons The functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act [15 U.S.C. 1261 et seq.] and the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 [15 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission. The functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], to the extent such functions relate to the administration and enforcement of the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970, are transferred to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flammable fabrics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Flammable fabrics The functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Federal Trade Commission under the Flammable Fabrics Act [15 U.S.C. 1191 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission. The functions of the Federal Trade Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.], to the extent such functions relate to the administration and enforcement of the Flammable Fabrics Act, are transferred to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Household refrigerators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Household refrigerators The functions of the Secretary of Commerce and the Federal Trade Commission under the Act of August 2, 1956 [15 U.S.C. 1211 et seq.] are transferred to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 110–314, title II, § 237, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3076</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of personnel, property, records, etc.; continued application of orders, rules, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer of personnel, property, records, etc.; continued application of orders, rules, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2079_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Function” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Function” defined For purposes of this section, (1) the term “function” includes power and duty, and (2) the transfer of a function, under any provision of law, of an agency or the head of a department shall also be a transfer of all functions under such law which are exercised by any office or officer of such agency, or department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>