<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2084" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2084/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2084/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2084"><akn:num>2084</akn:num><akn:heading>Information reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2084. Information reporting(a) Notification of settlements or judgmentsIf a particular model of a consumer product is the subject of at least 3 civil actions that have been filed in Federal or State court for death or grievous bodily injury which in each of the 24-month periods defined in subsection (b) result in either a final settlement involving the manufacturer or a court judgment in favor of the plaintiff, the manufacturer of such product shall, in accordance with subsection (c), report to the Commission each such civil action within 30 days after the final settlement or court judgment in the third of such civil actions, and, within 30 days after any subsequent settlement or judgment in that 24-month period, any other such action.


(b) Calculation of 24-month periodsThe 24-month periods referred to in subsection (a) are the 24-month period commencing on January 1, 1991, and subsequent 24-month periods beginning on January 1 of the calendar year that is two years following the beginning of the previous 24-month period.


(c) Information required to be reported(1) The information required by subsection (a) to be reported to the Commission, with respect to each civil action described in subsection (a), shall include and in addition to any voluntary information provided under paragraph (2) shall be limited to the following:(A) The name and address of the manufacturer.

(B) The model and model number or designation of the consumer product subject to the civil action.

(C) A statement as to whether the civil action alleged death or grievous bodily injury, and in the case of an allegation of grievous bodily injury, a statement of the category of such injury.

(D) A statement as to whether the civil action resulted in a final settlement or a judgment in favor of the plaintiff.

(E) in 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. the case of a judgment in favor of the plaintiff, the name of the civil action, the number assigned the civil action, and the court i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2084_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of settlements or judgments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification of settlements or judgments If a particular model of a consumer product is the subject of at least 3 civil actions that have been filed in Federal or State court for death or grievous bodily injury which in each of the 24-month periods defined in subsection (b) result in either a final settlement involving the manufacturer or a court judgment in favor of the plaintiff, the manufacturer of such product shall, in accordance with subsection (c), report to the Commission each such civil action within 30 days after the final settlement or court judgment in the third of such civil actions, and, within 30 days after any subsequent settlement or judgment in that 24-month period, any other such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2084_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of 24-month periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Calculation of 24-month periods The 24-month periods referred to in subsection (a) are the 24-month period commencing on January 1, 1991, and subsequent 24-month periods beginning on January 1 of the calendar year that is two years following the beginning of the previous 24-month period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2084_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required to be reported</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information required to be reported</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2084_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report not deemed an admission of liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report not deemed an admission of liability The reporting of a civil action described in subsection (a) by a manufacturer shall not constitute an admission of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2084_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>