<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2089" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2089/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2089/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2089"><akn:num>2089</akn:num><akn:heading>All-terrain vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2089. All-terrain vehicles(a) In general(1) Mandatory standardNotwithstanding any other provision of law, within 90 days after August 14, 2008, the Commission shall publish in the Federal Register as a mandatory consumer product safety standard the American National Standard for Four Wheel All-Terrain Vehicles Equipment Configuration, and Performance Requirements developed by the Specialty Vehicle Institute of America (American National Standard ANSI/SVIA–1–2007). The standard shall take effect 150 days after it is published.


(2) Compliance with standardAfter the standard takes effect, it shall be unlawful for any manufacturer or distributor to import into or distribute in commerce in the United States any new assembled or unassembled all-terrain vehicle unless—(A) the all-terrain vehicle complies with each applicable provision of the standard;

(B) the ATV is subject to an ATV action plan filed with the Commission before August 14, 2008, or subsequently filed with and approved by the Commission, and bears a label certifying such compliance and identifying the manufacturer, importer or private labeler and the ATV action plan to which it is subject; and

(C) the manufacturer or distributor is in compliance with all provisions of the applicable ATV action plan.


(3) ViolationThe failure to comply with any requirement of paragraph (2) shall be deemed to be a failure to comply with a consumer product safety standard under this chapter and subject to all of the penalties and remedies available under this chapter.


(4) Compliant models with additional featuresParagraph (2) shall not be construed to prohibit the distribution in commerce of new all-terrain vehicles that comply with the requirements of that paragraph but also incorporate characteristics or components that are not covered by those requirements. Any such characteristics or components shall be subject to the requirements of section 2064 of this title.



(b) Modification of standard(1) ANSI revisionsIf th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2089_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2089_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Modification of standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2089_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for 3-wheeled all-terrain vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for 3-wheeled all-terrain vehicles Until a mandatory consumer product safety standard applicable to 3-wheeled all-terrain vehicles promulgated pursuant to this chapter is in effect, new 3-wheeled all-terrain vehicles may not be imported into or distributed in commerce in the United States. Any violation of this subsection shall be considered to be a violation of section 2068(a)(1) of this title and may also be enforced under section 2066 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2089_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Further proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Further proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2089_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>