<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2090" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2090/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2090/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2090"><akn:num>2090</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program for carbon monoxide poisoning prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2090. Grant program for carbon monoxide poisoning prevention(a) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations authorized under subsection (f), the Commission shall establish a grant program to provide assistance to States and Tribal organizations that are eligible under subsection (b) to carry out the carbon monoxide poisoning prevention activities described in subsection (e).


(b) EligibilityFor the purposes of this section, an eligible State or Tribal organization is any State or Tribal organization that—(1) demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Commission that the State or Tribal organization has adopted a statute or a rule, regulation, or similar measure with the force and effect of law, requiring compliant carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units in accordance with NFPA 72, the IFC, or the IRC; and

(2) submits an application—(A) to the Commission at such time, in such form, and containing such additional information as the Commission may require; and

(B) that may be filed on behalf of the State or Tribal organization by the fire safety code enforcement agency of that State or Tribal organization.



(c) Grant amountThe Commission shall determine the amount of each grant awarded under this section.


(d) Selection of grant recipientsIn selecting eligible States and Tribal organizations for the award of grants under this section, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to an eligible State or Tribal organization that demonstrates a reasonable need for funding under this section and that—(1) requires the installation of one or more compliant carbon monoxide alarms in a new or existing educational facility, childcare facility, health care facility, adult dependent care facility, government building, restaurant, theater, lodging establishment, or dwelling unit—(A) within which a fuel-burning appliance, including a furnace, boiler, water heater, fireplace, or any other apparatus, appliance, or device that burns fuel, is inst</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the availability of appropriations authorized under subsection (f), the Commission shall establish a grant program to provide assistance to States and Tribal organizations that are eligible under subsection (b) to carry out the carbon monoxide poisoning prevention activities described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility For the purposes of this section, an eligible State or Tribal organization is any State or Tribal organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant amount The Commission shall determine the amount of each grant awarded under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection of grant recipients In selecting eligible States and Tribal organizations for the award of grants under this section, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to an eligible State or Tribal organization that demonstrates a reasonable need for funding under this section and that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of grant funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2090_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report Not later than 1 year after the last day of each fiscal year in which grants are awarded under this section, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that evaluates the implementation of the grant program required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>