<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2101"><akn:num>2101</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2101. Marking requirements(a) Political itemsThe manufacture in the United States, or the importation into the United States, for introduction into or distribution in commerce of any imitation political item which is not plainly and permanently marked with the calendar year in which such item was manufactured, is unlawful and is an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].


(b) Coins and other numismatic itemsThe manufacture in the United States, or the importation into the United States, for introduction into or distribution in commerce, or the sale in commerce of any imitation numismatic item which is not plainly and permanently marked “copy”, is unlawful and is an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].


(c) Rules and regulationsThe Federal Trade Commission shall prescribe rules for determining the manner and form in which items described in subsection (a) or (b) shall be permanently marked.


(d) Provision of assistance or supportIt shall be a violation of subsection (a) or (b) for a person to provide substantial assistance or support to any manufacturer, importer, or seller if that person knows or should have known that the manufacturer, importer, or seller is engaged in any act or practice that violates subsection (a) or (b).


(e) ExemptionSubsections (a) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. (b), and (d), and regulations under subsection (c), shall not apply to any common carrier or contract carrier or freight forwarder with respect to an imitation political item or imitation numismatic item received, shipped, delivered, or handled by it for shipment in the ordinary course of its business.


(Pub. L. 93–167, § 2, Nov. 29, 1973, 87 Stat. 686; Pub. L. 113–288, § 2(1), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3281.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Political items The manufacture in the United States, or the importation into the United States, for introduction into or distribution in commerce of any imitation political item which is not plainly and permanently marked with the calendar year in which such item was manufactured, is unlawful and is an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coins and other numismatic items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coins and other numismatic items The manufacture in the United States, or the importation into the United States, for introduction into or distribution in commerce, or the sale in commerce of any imitation numismatic item which is not plainly and permanently marked “copy”, is unlawful and is an unfair or deceptive act or practice in commerce under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules and regulations The Federal Trade Commission shall prescribe rules for determining the manner and form in which items described in subsection (a) or (b) shall be permanently marked.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of assistance or support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of assistance or support It shall be a violation of subsection (a) or (b) for a person to provide substantial assistance or support to any manufacturer, importer, or seller if that person knows or should have known that the manufacturer, importer, or seller is engaged in any act or practice that violates subsection (a) or (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2101_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption Subsections (a) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. (b), and (d), and regulations under subsection (c), shall not apply to any common carrier or contract carrier or freight forwarder with respect to an imitation political item or imitation numismatic item received, shipped, delivered, or handled by it for shipment in the ordinary course of its business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>