<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2203"><akn:num>2203</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2203. Definitions
As used in this chapter, the term—(1) “Academy” means the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control;

(2) “Administration” means the United States Fire Administration established pursuant to section 2204 of this title;

(3) “Administrator” means, except as otherwise provided, the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, within the Federal Emergency Management Agency;

(4) “Administrator of FEMA” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;

(5) “fire service” means any organization in any State consisting of personnel, apparatus, and equipment which has as its purpose protecting property and maintaining the safety and welfare of the public from the dangers of fire, including a private firefighting brigade. The personnel of any such organization may be paid employees or unpaid volunteers or any combination thereof. The location of any such organization and its responsibility for extinguishment and suppression of fires may include, but need not be limited to, a Federal installation, a State, city, town, borough, parish, county, Indian tribe, fire district, fire protection district, rural fire district, or other special district. The terms “fire prevention”, “firefighting”, and “fire control” relate to activities conducted by a fire service;

(6) “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304 of title 25 and “tribal” means of or pertaining to an Indian tribe;

(7) “local” means of or pertaining to any city, town, county, special purpose district, unincorporated territory, or other political subdivision of a State;

(8) “place of public accommodation affecting commerce” means any inn, hotel, or other establishment not owned by the Federal Government that provides lodging to transient guests, except that such term does not include an establishment treated as an apartment building for purposes of any State or local law or regulation or an establishment located within a building that contains </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “Academy” means the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “Administration” means the United States Fire Administration established pursuant to section 2204 of this title;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “Administrator” means, except as otherwise provided, the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration, within the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) “Administrator of FEMA” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “fire service” means any organization in any State consisting of personnel, apparatus, and equipment which has as its purpose protecting property and maintaining the safety and welfare of the public from the dangers of fire, including a private firefighting brigade. The personnel of any such organization may be paid employees or unpaid volunteers or any combination thereof. The location of any such organization and its responsibility for extinguishment and suppression of fires may include, but need not be limited to, a Federal installation, a State, city, town, borough, parish, county, Indian tribe, fire district, fire protection district, rural fire district, or other special district. The terms “fire prevention”, “firefighting”, and “fire control” relate to activities conducted by a fire service;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “Indian tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304 of title 25 and “tribal” means of or pertaining to an Indian tribe;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “local” means of or pertaining to any city, town, county, special purpose district, unincorporated territory, or other political subdivision of a State;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “place of public accommodation affecting commerce” means any inn, hotel, or other establishment not owned by the Federal Government that provides lodging to transient guests, except that such term does not include an establishment treated as an apartment building for purposes of any State or local law or regulation or an establishment located within a building that contains not more than 5 rooms for rent or hire and that is actually occupied as a residence by the proprietor of such establishment;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) “Secretary” means, except as otherwise provided, the Secretary of Homeland Security;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2203_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “State” has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 6.11 So in original. The period probably should be “; and”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>