<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2204"><akn:num>2204</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Fire Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2204. United States Fire Administration(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established in the Department of Commerce an agency which shall be known as the United States Fire Administration.


(b) AdministratorThere shall be at the head of the Administration the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration. The Administrator shall be appointed by the President and shall be compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule pay rates (5 U.S.C. 5315). The Administrator shall report and be responsible to the Administrator of FEMA.


(c) Deputy AdministratorThe Administrator may appoint a Deputy Administrator, who shall—(1) perform such functions as the Administrator shall from time to time assign or delegate; and

(2) act as Administrator during the absence or disability of the Administrator or in the event of a vacancy in the office of Administrator.


(Pub. L. 93–498, § 5, Oct. 29, 1974, 88 Stat. 1536; Pub. L. 95–422, § 2(a)(1), Oct. 5, 1978, 92 Stat. 932; Pub. L. 106–503, title I, § 110(a)(2)(B)(i), Nov. 13, 2000, 114 Stat. 2302; Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(f)(2), Aug. 10, 2012, 126 Stat. 1284; Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVIII, §§ 1802(b)(1), 1812, Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2100, 2117.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2013—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 112–239, § 1802(b)(1), substituted “Administrator of FEMA” for “Director”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 112–239, § 1812, amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “There shall be in the Administration a Deputy Administrator of the United States Fire Administration who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall be compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for level V of the Executive Schedule pay rates (5 U.S.C. 5316). The Deputy Administrator shall perform such functions as the Administrator shall from time to time assign or delegate, and shall act as Administrator during the absence or disability of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established in the Department of Commerce an agency which shall be known as the United States Fire Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrator There shall be at the head of the Administration the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration. The Administrator shall be appointed by the President and shall be compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule pay rates (5 U.S.C. 5315). The Administrator shall report and be responsible to the Administrator of FEMA.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deputy Administrator The Administrator may appoint a Deputy Administrator, who shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>