<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2207" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2207/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2207/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2207"><akn:num>2207</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2207. Fire technology(a) DevelopmentThe Administrator shall conduct a continuing program of development, testing, and evaluation of equipment for use by the Nation’s fire, rescue, and civil defense services, with the aim of making available improved suppression, protective, auxiliary, and warning devices incorporating the latest technology. Attention shall be given to the standardization, compatibility, and interchangeability of such equipment. Such development, testing, and evaluation activities shall include, but need not be limited to—(1) safer, less cumbersome articles of protective clothing, including helmets, boots, and coats;

(2) breathing apparatus with the necessary duration of service, reliability, low weight, and ease of operation for practical use;

(3) safe and reliable auxiliary equipment for use in fire prevention, detection, and control, such as fire location detectors, visual and audio communications equipment, and mobile equipment;

(4) special clothing and equipment needed for forest fires, brush fires, oil and gasoline fires, aircraft fires and crash rescue, fires occurring aboard waterborne vessels, and in other special firefighting situations;

(5) fire detectors and related equipment for residential use with high sensitivity and reliability, and which are sufficiently inexpensive to purchase, install, and maintain to insure wide acceptance and use;

(6) in-place fire prevention systems of low cost and of increased reliability and effectiveness;

(7) methods of testing fire alarms and fire protection devices and systems on a non-interference basis;

(8) the development of purchase specifications, standards, and acceptance and validation test procedures for all such equipment and devices; and

(9) operation tests, demonstration projects, and fire investigations in support of the activities set forth in this section.


(b) Limitation on manufacture and sale of equipmentThe Administration shall not engage in the manufacture or sale of any equip</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development The Administrator shall conduct a continuing program of development, testing, and evaluation of equipment for use by the Nation’s fire, rescue, and civil defense services, with the aim of making available improved suppression, protective, auxiliary, and warning devices incorporating the latest technology. Attention shall be given to the standardization, compatibility, and interchangeability of such equipment. Such development, testing, and evaluation activities shall include, but need not be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on manufacture and sale of equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on manufacture and sale of equipment The Administration shall not engage in the manufacture or sale of any equipment or device developed pursuant to this section, except to the extent that it deems it necessary to adequately develop, test, or evaluate such equipment or device.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management studies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural and wildland-urban interface assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rural and wildland-urban interface assistance The Administrator may, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Wildland Fire Leadership Council, assist the fire services of the United States, directly or through contracts, grants, or other forms of assistance, in sponsoring and encouraging research into approaches, techniques, systems, equipment, and land-use policies to improve fire prevention and control in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance to other Federal agencies At the request of other Federal agencies, including the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, the Administrator may provide assistance in fire prevention and control technologies, including methods of containing insect-infested forest fires and limiting dispersal of resultant fire particle smoke, and methods of measuring and tracking the dispersal of fine particle smoke resulting from fires of insect-infested fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology evaluation and standards development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technology evaluation and standards development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination In establishing and conducting programs under this section, the Administrator shall take full advantage of applicable technological developments made by other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, by State and local governments, and by business, industry, and nonprofit associations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of research results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of research results</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>