<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2209" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2209/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2209/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2209"><akn:num>2209</akn:num><akn:heading>Master plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2209. Master plans(a) Encouragement by AdministratorThe establishment of master plans for fire prevention and control are the responsibility of the States and the political subdivisions thereof. The Administrator is authorized to encourage and assist such States and political subdivisions in such planning activities, consistent with his powers and duties under this chapter.


(b) Mutual aid systems(1) In generalThe Administrator shall provide technical assistance and training to State and local fire service officials to establish nationwide and State mutual aid systems for dealing with national emergencies that—(A) include threat assessment and equipment deployment strategies;

(B) include means of collecting asset and resource information to provide accurate and timely data for regional deployment; and

(C) are consistent with the Federal Response Plan.


(2) Model mutual aid plansThe Administrator shall develop and make available to State and local fire service officials model mutual aid plans for both intrastate and interstate assistance.



(c) “Master plan” definedFor the purposes of this section, a “master plan” is one which will result in the planning and implementation in the area involved of a general program of action for fire prevention and control. Such master plan is reasonably expected to include (1) a survey of the resources and personnel of existing fire services and an analysis of the effectiveness of the fire and building codes in such area; (2) an analysis of short and long term fire prevention and control needs in such area; (3) a plan to meet the fire prevention and control needs in such area; and (4) an estimate of cost and realistic plans for financing the implementation of the plan and operation on a continuing basis and a summary of problems that are anticipated in implementing such master plan.


(Pub. L. 93–498, § 10, Oct. 29, 1974, 88 Stat. 1542; Pub. L. 106–503, title I, § 110(a)(1)(A), Nov. 13, 2000, 114 Stat. 2302; Pub. L. 108–169, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2209_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Encouragement by Administrator The establishment of master plans for fire prevention and control are the responsibility of the States and the political subdivisions thereof. The Administrator is authorized to encourage and assist such States and political subdivisions in such planning activities, consistent with his powers and duties under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2209_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mutual aid systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mutual aid systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2209_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Master plan” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Master plan” defined For the purposes of this section, a “master plan” is one which will result in the planning and implementation in the area involved of a general program of action for fire prevention and control. Such master plan is reasonably expected to include (1) a survey of the resources and personnel of existing fire services and an analysis of the effectiveness of the fire and building codes in such area; (2) an analysis of short and long term fire prevention and control needs in such area; (3) a plan to meet the fire prevention and control needs in such area; and (4) an estimate of cost and realistic plans for financing the implementation of the plan and operation on a continuing basis and a summary of problems that are anticipated in implementing such master plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>