<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2221"><akn:num>2221</akn:num><akn:heading>Arson prevention grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2221. Arson prevention grants(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) ArsonThe term “arson” includes all incendiary and suspicious fires.


(2) OfficeThe term “Office” means the Office of Fire Prevention and Arson Control of the United States Fire Administration.



(b) GrantsThe Administrator, acting through the Office, shall carry out a demonstration program under which not more than 10 grant awards shall be made to States, or consortia of States, for programs relating to arson research, prevention, and control.


(c) GoalsIn carrying out this section, the Administrator shall award 2-year grants on a competitive, merit basis to States, or consortia of States, for projects that promote one or more of the following goals:(1) To improve the training by States leading to professional certification of arson investigators, in accordance with nationally recognized certification standards.

(2) To provide resources for the formation of arson task forces or interagency organizational arrangements involving police and fire departments and other relevant local agencies, such as a State arson bureau and the office of a fire marshal of a State.

(3) To combat fraud as a cause of arson and to advance research at the State and local levels on the significance and prevention of fraud as a motive for setting fires.

(4) To provide for the management of arson squads, including—(A) training courses for fire departments in arson case management, including standardization of investigative techniques and reporting methodology;

(B) the preparation of arson unit management guides; and

(C) the development and dissemination of new public education materials relating to the arson problem.


(5) To combat civil unrest as a cause of arson and to advance research at the State and local levels on the prevention and control of arson linked to urban disorders.

(6) To combat juvenile arson, such as juvenile fire-setter counseling programs and similar intervention programs, and to advance re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants The Administrator, acting through the Office, shall carry out a demonstration program under which not more than 10 grant awards shall be made to States, or consortia of States, for programs relating to arson research, prevention, and control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Goals In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall award 2-year grants on a competitive, merit basis to States, or consortia of States, for projects that promote one or more of the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Structuring of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Structuring of applications The Administrator shall assist grant applicants in structuring their applications so as to ensure that at least one grant is awarded for each goal described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State qualification criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State qualification criteria In order to qualify for a grant under this section, a State, or consortium of States, shall provide assurances adequate to the Administrator that the State or consortium—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Extension A grant awarded under this section may be extended for one or more additional periods, at the discretion of the Administrator, subject to the availability of appropriations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance The Administrator shall provide technical assistance to States in carrying out programs funded by grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consultation and cooperation In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consult and cooperate with other Federal agencies to enhance program effectiveness and avoid duplication of effort, including the conduct of regular meetings initiated by the Administrator with representatives of other Federal agencies concerned with arson and concerned with efforts to develop a more comprehensive profile of the magnitude of the national arson problem.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Assessment Not later than 18 months after May 19, 1994, the Administrator shall submit a report to Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2221_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations Not later than 90 days after May 19, 1994, the Administrator shall issue regulations to implement this section, including procedures for grant applications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>