<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2225a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2225a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2225a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2225a"><akn:num>2225a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibiting Federal funding of conferences held at non-certified places of public accommodation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2225a. Prohibiting Federal funding of conferences held at non-certified places of public accommodation(a) In generalNo Federal funds may be used to sponsor or fund in whole or in part a meeting, convention, conference, or training seminar that is conducted in, or that otherwise uses the rooms, facilities, or services of, a place of public accommodation that does not meet the requirements of the fire prevention and control guidelines described in section 2225 of this title.


(b) Waiver(1) In generalThe head of an agency of the Federal Government sponsoring or funding a particular meeting, convention, conference, or training seminar may waive the prohibition described in subsection (a) if the head of such agency determines that a waiver of such prohibition is necessary in the public interest in the case of such particular event.


(2) Delegation of authorityThe head of an agency of the Federal Government may delegate the authority provided under paragraph (1) to waive the prohibition described in subsection (a) and to determine whether such a waiver is necessary in the public interest to an officer or employee of the agency if such officer or employee is given such authority with respect to all meetings, conventions, conferences, and training seminars sponsored or funded by the agency.



(c) Notice requirements(1) Advertisements and applications(A) Any advertisement for or application for attendance at a meeting, convention, conference, or training seminar sponsored or funded in whole or in part by the Federal Government shall include a notice regarding the prohibition described in subsection (a).

(B) The requirement described in subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of an event for which a head of an agency of the Federal Government, pursuant to subsection (b), waives the prohibition described in subsection (a).


(2) Providing notice to recipients of funds(A) Each Executive department, Government corporation, and independent establishment providing Feder</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2225a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general No Federal funds may be used to sponsor or fund in whole or in part a meeting, convention, conference, or training seminar that is conducted in, or that otherwise uses the rooms, facilities, or services of, a place of public accommodation that does not meet the requirements of the fire prevention and control guidelines described in section 2225 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2225a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2225a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2225a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date The provisions of this section shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year that begins after the expiration of the 425-day period that begins on the date of the publication in the Federal Register of the master list referred to in section 2224(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>