<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2227" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2227/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2227/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2227"><akn:num>2227</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire safety systems in federally assisted buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2227. Fire safety systems in federally assisted buildings(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:(1) The term “affordable cost” means the cost to a Federal agency of leasing office space in a building that is protected by an automatic sprinkler system or equivalent level of safety, which cost is no more than 10 percent greater than the cost of leasing available comparable office space in a building that is not so protected.

(2) The term “automatic sprinkler system” means an electronically supervised, integrated system of piping to which sprinklers are attached in a systematic pattern, and which, when activated by heat from a fire—(A) will protect human lives by discharging water over the fire area, in accordance with the National Fire Protection Association Standard 13, 13D, or 13R, whichever is appropriate for the type of building and occupancy being protected, or any successor standard thereto; and

(B) includes an alarm signaling system with appropriate warning signals (to the extent such alarm systems and warning signals are required by Federal, State, or local laws or regulations) installed in accordance with the National Fire Protection Association Standard 72, or any successor standard thereto.


(3) The term “equivalent level of safety” means an alternative design or system (which may include automatic sprinkler systems), based upon fire protection engineering analysis, which achieves a level of safety equal to or greater than that provided by automatic sprinkler systems.

(4) The term “Federal employee office building” means any office building in the United States, whether owned or leased by the Federal Government, that is regularly occupied by more than 25 full-time Federal employees in the course of their employment.

(5) The term “housing assistance”—(A) means assistance provided by the Federal Government to be used in connection with the provision of housing,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal employee office buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal employee office buildings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Housing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Administrator of General Services, in cooperation with the United States Fire Administration, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Department of Defense, within 2 years after October 26, 1992, shall promulgate regulations to further define the term “equivalent level of safety”, and shall, to the extent practicable, base those regulations on nationally recognized codes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local authority not limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State and local authority not limited Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the power of any State or political subdivision thereof to implement or enforce any law, rule, regulation, or standard that establishes requirements concerning fire prevention and control. Nothing in this section shall be construed to reduce fire resistance requirements which otherwise would have been required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prefire plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prefire plan The head of any Federal agency that owns, leases, or operates a building or housing unit with Federal funds shall invite the local agency or voluntary organization having responsibility for fire protection in the jurisdiction where the building or housing unit is located to prepare, and biennially review, a prefire plan for the building or housing unit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2227_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relation to other requirements In the implementation of this section, the process for meeting space needs in urban areas shall continue to give first consideration to a centralized community business area and adjacent areas of similar character to the extent of any Federal requirement therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>