<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2233" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2233/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2233/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2233"><akn:num>2233</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal of civil liability barriers that discourage the donation of fire equipment to volunteer fire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2233. Removal of civil liability barriers that discourage the donation of fire equipment to volunteer fire companies(a) Liability protectionA person who donates qualified fire control or rescue equipment to a volunteer fire company shall not be liable for civil damages under any State or Federal law for personal injuries, property damage or loss, or death caused by the equipment after the donation.


(b) ExceptionsSubsection (a) does not apply to a person if—(1) the person’s act or omission causing the injury, damage, loss, or death constitutes gross negligence or intentional misconduct;

(2) the person is the manufacturer of the qualified fire control or rescue equipment; or

(3) the person or agency modified or altered the equipment after it had been recertified by an authorized technician as meeting the manufacturer’s specifications.


(c) PreemptionThis section preempts the laws of any State to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with this section, except that notwithstanding subsection (b) this section shall not preempt any State law that provides additional protection from liability for a person who donates fire control or fire rescue equipment to a volunteer fire company.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) PersonThe term “person” includes any governmental or other entity.


(2) Fire control or rescue equipmentThe term “fire control or fire rescue equipment” includes any fire vehicle, fire fighting tool, communications equipment, protective gear, fire hose, or breathing apparatus.


(3) Qualified fire control or rescue equipmentThe term “qualified fire control or rescue equipment” means fire control or fire rescue equipment that has been recertified by an authorized technician as meeting the manufacturer’s specifications.


(4) StateThe term “State” includes the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the Virgin Islands, any other territory or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2233_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability protection A person who donates qualified fire control or rescue equipment to a volunteer fire company shall not be liable for civil damages under any State or Federal law for personal injuries, property damage or loss, or death caused by the equipment after the donation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2233_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions Subsection (a) does not apply to a person if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2233_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preemption This section preempts the laws of any State to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with this section, except that notwithstanding subsection (b) this section shall not preempt any State law that provides additional protection from liability for a person who donates fire control or fire rescue equipment to a volunteer fire company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2233_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2233_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section applies only to liability for injury, damage, loss, or death caused by equipment that, for purposes of subsection (a), is donated on or after the date that is 30 days after March 9, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>