<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2302"><akn:num>2302</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules governing contents of warranties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2302. Rules governing contents of warranties(a) Full and conspicuous disclosure of terms and conditions; additional requirements for contentsIn order to improve the adequacy of information available to consumers, prevent deception, and improve competition in the marketing of consumer products, any warrantor warranting a consumer product to a consumer by means of a written warranty shall, to the extent required by rules of the Commission, fully and conspicuously disclose in simple and readily understood language the terms and conditions of such warranty. Such rules may require inclusion in the written warranty of any of the following items among others:(1) The clear identification of the names and addresses of the warrantors.

(2) The identity of the party or parties to whom the warranty is extended.

(3) The products or parts covered.

(4) A statement of what the warrantor will do in the event of a defect, malfunction, or failure to conform with such written warranty—at whose expense—and for what period of time.

(5) A statement of what the consumer must do and expenses he must bear.

(6) Exceptions and exclusions from the terms of the warranty.

(7) The step-by-step procedure which the consumer should take in order to obtain performance of any obligation under the warranty, including the identification of any person or class of persons authorized to perform the obligations set forth in the warranty.

(8) Information respecting the availability of any informal dispute settlement procedure offered by the warrantor and a recital, where the warranty so provides, that the purchaser may be required to resort to such procedure before pursuing any legal remedies in the courts.

(9) A brief, general description of the legal remedies available to the consumer.

(10) The time at which the warrantor will perform any obligations under the warranty.

(11) The period of time within which, after notice of a defect, malfunction, or failure to conform with the warranty, the warran</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full and conspicuous disclosure of terms and conditions; additional requirements for contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Full and conspicuous disclosure of terms and conditions; additional requirements for contents In order to improve the adequacy of information available to consumers, prevent deception, and improve competition in the marketing of consumer products, any warrantor warranting a consumer product to a consumer by means of a written warranty shall, to the extent required by rules of the Commission, fully and conspicuously disclose in simple and readily understood language the terms and conditions of such warranty. Such rules may require inclusion in the written warranty of any of the following items among others:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of terms to consumer; manner and form for presentation and display of information; duration; extension of period for written warranty or service contract; electronic display of terms of warranty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of terms to consumer; manner and form for presentation and display of information; duration; extension of period for written warranty or service contract; electronic display of terms of warranty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on conditions for written or implied warranty; waiver by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on conditions for written or implied warranty; waiver by Commission No warrantor of a consumer product may condition his written or implied warranty of such product on the consumer’s using, in connection with such product, any article or service (other than article or service provided without charge under the terms of the warranty) which is identified by brand, trade, or corporate name; except that the prohibition of this subsection may be waived by the Commission if— The Commission shall identify in the Federal Register, and permit public comment on, all applications for waiver of the prohibition of this subsection, and shall publish in the Federal Register its disposition of any such application, including the reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation by reference of detailed substantive warranty provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Incorporation by reference of detailed substantive warranty provisions The Commission may by rule devise detailed substantive warranty provisions which warrantors may incorporate by reference in their warranties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to consumer products costing more than $5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability to consumer products costing more than $5 The provisions of this section apply only to warranties which pertain to consumer products actually costing the consumer more than $5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>