<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2506"><akn:num>2506</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2506. Demonstrations(a) Data development; baseline data; acquisition of vehiclesWithin 12 months after September 17, 1976, the Secretary of Energy shall develop data characterizing the present state-of-the-art with respect to electric and hybrid vehicles. The data so developed shall serve as baseline data to be utilized in order (1) to compare improvements in electric and hybrid vehicle technologies; (2) to assist in establishing the performance standards under subsection (b)(1); and (3) to otherwise assist in carrying out the purposes of this section. In developing any such data, the Secretary of Energy shall purchase or lease a reasonable number of such vehicles or enter into such other arrangements as the Secretary of Energy deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.


(b) Performance standards; factors considered; vehicle uses; revision; transmission of standards to Congress(1) Within 15 months after September 17, 1976, the Secretary of Energy shall promulgate rules establishing performance standards for electric and hybrid vehicles to be purchased or leased pursuant to subsection (c)(1). The standards so developed shall take into account the factors of energy conservation, urban traffic characteristics, patterns of use for “second” vehicles, consumer preferences, maintenance needs, battery recharging characteristics, agricultural requirements, materials demand and their ability to be recycled, vehicle safety and insurability, cost, and other relevant considerations, as such factors and considerations particularly apply to or affect vehicles with electric or hybrid propulsion systems. Such standards are to be developed taking into account (A) the best current state-of-the-art, and (B) reasonable estimates as to the future state-of-the-art, based on projections of results from the research and development conducted under section 2505 of this title. In developing such standards, the Secretary of Energy shall consult with appropriate experts co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data development; baseline data; acquisition of vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Data development; baseline data; acquisition of vehicles Within 12 months after September 17, 1976, the Secretary of Energy shall develop data characterizing the present state-of-the-art with respect to electric and hybrid vehicles. The data so developed shall serve as baseline data to be utilized in order (1) to compare improvements in electric and hybrid vehicle technologies; (2) to assist in establishing the performance standards under subsection (b)(1); and (3) to otherwise assist in carrying out the purposes of this section. In developing any such data, the Secretary of Energy shall purchase or lease a reasonable number of such vehicles or enter into such other arrangements as the Secretary of Energy deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance standards; factors considered; vehicle uses; revision; transmission of standards to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Performance standards; factors considered; vehicle uses; revision; transmission of standards to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for vehicle purchase or lease; delivery requirements; demonstration criteria and duration; availability of information for leasing and procurements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracts for vehicle purchase or lease; delivery requirements; demonstration criteria and duration; availability of information for leasing and procurements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arrangements for the demonstration of vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Arrangements for the demonstration of vehicles The Secretary of Energy, in supervising the demonstration of vehicles acquired under subsection (c), shall make such arrangements as may be necessary or appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Displacement of private procurement; reports to congressional committees; reduction of number purchased</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Displacement of private procurement; reports to congressional committees; reduction of number purchased</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>