<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2509"><akn:num>2509</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2509. Loan guarantees(a) Congressional policyIt is the policy of the Congress to assist in the introduction into the Nation’s transportation fleet of electric and hybrid vehicles and to assure that qualified small business concerns and other qualified borrowers are not excluded from participation in such development due to lack of adequate capital. Accordingly, it is the policy of the Congress to provide guarantees of loans made for such purposes.


(b) Encouragement of commercial production; purpose of loansIn order to encourage the commercial production of electric and hybrid vehicles, the Secretary of Energy is authorized to guarantee, and to enter into commitments to guarantee, principal and interest on loans made by lenders to qualified borrowers, primarily small business concerns, for the purposes of—(1) research and development related to electric and hybrid vehicle technology;

(2) prototype development for such vehicles and parts thereof;

(3) construction of capital equipment related to research on, and development and production of, electric and hybrid vehicles and components; or

(4) initial operating expenses associated with the development and production of electric and hybrid vehicles and components.


(c) Maximum amount of loan guaranteeAny guarantee under this section shall apply only to so much of the principal amount of the loan involved as does not exceed 90 percentum of the aggregate cost of the activity with respect to which the loan is made.


(d) Terms and conditions of guaranteeLoan guarantees under this section shall be on such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Energy determines, except that a guarantee shall be made under this section only if—(1) the loan bears interest at a rate not to exceed such annual percent on the principal obligation outstanding as the Secretary of Energy determines to be reasonable, taking into account the range of interest rates prevailing in the private sector for similar loans and risks by the United St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional policy It is the policy of the Congress to assist in the introduction into the Nation’s transportation fleet of electric and hybrid vehicles and to assure that qualified small business concerns and other qualified borrowers are not excluded from participation in such development due to lack of adequate capital. Accordingly, it is the policy of the Congress to provide guarantees of loans made for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement of commercial production; purpose of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Encouragement of commercial production; purpose of loans In order to encourage the commercial production of electric and hybrid vehicles, the Secretary of Energy is authorized to guarantee, and to enter into commitments to guarantee, principal and interest on loans made by lenders to qualified borrowers, primarily small business concerns, for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum amount of loan guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maximum amount of loan guarantee Any guarantee under this section shall apply only to so much of the principal amount of the loan involved as does not exceed 90 percentum of the aggregate cost of the activity with respect to which the loan is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions of guarantee Loan guarantees under this section shall be on such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Energy determines, except that a guarantee shall be made under this section only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum guarantee per loan; maximum of aggregate guarantees; Electric and Hybrid Vehicle Development Fund; establishment, funding, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maximum guarantee per loan; maximum of aggregate guarantees; Electric and Hybrid Vehicle Development Fund; establishment, funding, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified borrower</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Qualified borrower As used in this section, the term “qualified borrower” means any partnership, corporation, or other legal entity which (as determined by the Secretary of Energy) has presented satisfactory evidence of an interest in electric or hybrid vehicle technology and is capable of performing research or completing the development and production of electric or hybrid vehicles or any components thereof in an acceptable manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of principal and interest; default; recovery of losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of principal and interest; default; recovery of losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seven year limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Seven year limitation No loan guarantee shall be made, or interest assistance contracts entered into, pursuant to this section, after the expiration of the 7-year period following September 17, 1976.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizenship of applicant; corporations; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Citizenship of applicant; corporations; waiver An applicant seeking a guarantee under this section must be a citizen or national of the United States. A corporation, partnership, firm, or association shall not be deemed to be a citizen or national of the United States unless the Secretary of Energy determines that it satisfactorily meets all the requirements of section 50501 of title 46, for determining such citizenship, except that the provisions in subsections (a) and (b) of such section 50501 concerning (1) the citizenship of officers or directors of a corporation, and (2) the interest required to be owned in the case of a corporation, association, or partnership operating a vessel in the coastwise trade, shall not be applicable. The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may waive such requirements in the case of a corporation, partnership, firm, or association, controlling interest in which is owned by citizens of countries which are participants in </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2509_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pledge of full faith and credit of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Pledge of full faith and credit of United States The full faith and credit of the United States is pledged to the payment of all obligations incurred under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>