<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2512"><akn:num>2512</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2512. Studies(a) Bias of surface transportation systems; submission of reportThe Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study to determine the existence of any tax, regulatory, traffic, urban design, rural electrical, or other institutional factor which tends or may tend to bias surface transportation systems toward vehicles of particular characteristics. The Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings and conclusions of such study, within 1 year after September 17, 1976. The report shall include any legislative or other recommendations of the Secretary of Energy.


(b) Material demand and pollution effect; impact statementThe Secretary of Energy shall conduct a continuing assessment of the long-range material demand and pollution effects which may result from or in connection with the electrification of urban traffic. Such assessment shall include a statement of the Secretary of Energy’s current findings in each report submitted under section 2513 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. Any environmental impact statement which may be filed under a Federal law with respect to research, development, or demonstration activities under this chapter shall include reference to the matters which are subject to assessment under this subsection.


(c) Incentives to encourage utilization; inclusion of electric vehicles in calculation of average fuel economy; evaluation program; annual report; final report and recommendations to Congress on January 1, 1987The Secretary of Energy shall perform, or cause to be performed, studies and research on incentives to promote broader utilization and consumer acceptance of electric and hybrid vehicle technologies. A description and a statement of the findings of such studies and research activities shall be included in each report submitted under section 2513 1 of this title.(1) The Secretary of Energy in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bias of surface transportation systems; submission of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bias of surface transportation systems; submission of report The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study to determine the existence of any tax, regulatory, traffic, urban design, rural electrical, or other institutional factor which tends or may tend to bias surface transportation systems toward vehicles of particular characteristics. The Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings and conclusions of such study, within 1 year after September 17, 1976. The report shall include any legislative or other recommendations of the Secretary of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Material demand and pollution effect; impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Material demand and pollution effect; impact statement The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a continuing assessment of the long-range material demand and pollution effects which may result from or in connection with the electrification of urban traffic. Such assessment shall include a statement of the Secretary of Energy’s current findings in each report submitted under section 2513 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. Any environmental impact statement which may be filed under a Federal law with respect to research, development, or demonstration activities under this chapter shall include reference to the matters which are subject to assessment under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives to encourage utilization; inclusion of electric vehicles in calculation of average fuel economy; evaluation program; annual report; final report and recommendations to Congress on January 1, 1987</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Incentives to encourage utilization; inclusion of electric vehicles in calculation of average fuel economy; evaluation program; annual report; final report and recommendations to Congress on The Secretary of Energy shall perform, or cause to be performed, studies and research on incentives to promote broader utilization and consumer acceptance of electric and hybrid vehicle technologies. A description and a statement of the findings of such studies and research activities shall be included in each report submitted under section 2513 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety standards and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Safety standards and regulations The Secretary of Transportation shall conduct a study of the current and future applicability of safety standards and regulations to electric and hybrid vehicles. The Secretary of Transportation shall report the results of such study to the Secretary of Energy and the Congress within 1 year after September 17, 1976.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2512_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regenerative braking systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regenerative braking systems The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a study to determine the overall effectiveness and feasibility of including regenerative braking systems on electric and other automobiles in order to recover energy. In such study the Secretary of Energy shall— The Secretary of Energy shall submit a report to the Congress on the findings and conclusions of such study within 1 year after September 17, 1976.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>