<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2602"><akn:num>2602</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2602. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) the 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.

(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “chemical substance” means any organic or inorganic substance of a particular molecular identity, including—(i) any combination of such substances occurring in whole or in part as a result of a chemical reaction or occurring in nature, and

(ii) any element or uncombined radical.


(B) Such term does not include—(i) any mixture,

(ii) any pesticide (as defined in the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act [7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.]) when manufactured, processed, or distributed in commerce for use as a pesticide,

(iii) tobacco or any tobacco product,

(iv) any source material, special nuclear material, or byproduct material (as such terms are defined in the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 [42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.] and regulations issued under such Act),

(v) any article the sale of which is subject to the tax imposed by section 4181 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. 4181] (determined without regard to any exemptions from such tax provided by section 4182 or 4221 or any other provision of such Code) and any component of such an article (limited to shot shells, cartridges, and components of shot shells and cartridges), and

(vi) any food, food additive, drug, cosmetic, or device (as such terms are defined in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 321]) when manufactured, processed, or distributed in commerce for use as a food, food additive, drug, cosmetic, or device.


The term “food” as used in clause (vi) of this subparagraph includes poultry and poultry products (as defined in sections 4(e) and 4(f) of the Poultry Products Inspection Act [21 U.S.C. 453(e) and (f)]), meat and meat food products (as defined in section 1(j) of the Federal Meat Inspection Act [21 U.S.C. 601(j)]), and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “commerce” means trade, traffic, transportation, or other commerce (A) between a place in a State and any place outside of such State, or (B) which affects trade, traffic, transportation, or commerce described in clause (A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “conditions of use” means the circumstances, as determined by the Administrator, under which a chemical substance is intended, known, or reasonably foreseen to be manufactured, processed, distributed in commerce, used, or disposed of.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The terms “distribute in commerce” and “distribution in commerce” when used to describe an action taken with respect to a chemical substance or mixture or article containing a substance or mixture mean to sell, or the sale of, the substance, mixture, or article in commerce; to introduce or deliver for introduction into commerce, or the introduction or delivery for introduction into commerce of, the substance, mixture, or article; or to hold, or the holding of, the substance, mixture, or article after its introduction into commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “environment” includes water, air, and land and the interrelationship which exists among and between water, air, and land and all living things.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “guidance” means any significant written guidance of general applicability prepared by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “health and safety study” means any study of any effect of a chemical substance or mixture on health or the environment or on both, including underlying information and epidemiological studies, studies of occupational exposure to a chemical substance or mixture, toxicological, clinical, and ecological studies of a chemical substance or mixture, and any test performed pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “manufacture” means to import into the customs territory of the United States (as defined in general note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States), produce, or manufacture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2602_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “mixture” means any combination of two or more chemical substances if the combination does not occur in nature and is not, in whole or in part, the result of a chemical reaction; except that such term does include any combination which occurs, in whole or in part, as a result of a chemical reaction if none of the chemical substances comprising the combination is a new chemical substance and if the combination could have been manufactured for commercial purposes without a chemical reaction at the time the chemical substances comprising the combination were combined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>