<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2604" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2604/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2604/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2604"><akn:num>2604</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturing and processing notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2604. Manufacturing and processing notices(a) In general(1)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B) of this paragraph and subsection (h), no person may—(i) manufacture a new chemical substance on or after the 30th day after the date on which the Administrator first publishes the list required by section 2607(b) of this title, or

(ii) manufacture or process any chemical substance for a use which the Administrator has determined, in accordance with paragraph (2), is a significant new use.


(B) A person may take the actions described in subparagraph (A) if—(i) such person submits to the Administrator, at least 90 days before such manufacture or processing, a notice, in accordance with subsection (d), of such person’s intention to manufacture or process such substance and such person complies with any applicable requirement of, or imposed pursuant to, subsection (b), (e), or (f); and

(ii) the Administrator—(I) conducts a review of the notice; and

(II) makes a determination under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (3) and takes the actions required in association with that determination under such subparagraph within the applicable review period.




(2) A determination by the Administrator that a use of a chemical substance is a significant new use with respect to which notification is required under paragraph (1) shall be made by a rule promulgated after a consideration of all relevant factors, including—(A) the projected volume of manufacturing and processing of a chemical substance,

(B) the extent to which a use changes the type or form of exposure of human beings or the environment to a chemical substance,

(C) the extent to which a use increases the magnitude and duration of exposure of human beings or the environment to a chemical substance, and

(D) the reasonably anticipated manner and methods of manufacturing, processing, distribution in commerce, and disposal of a chemical substance.


(3) Review and determination.—Within the applicable review</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of review period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extension of review period The Administrator may for good cause extend for additional periods (not to exceed in the aggregate 90 days) the period, prescribed by subsection (a) or (b). Subject to section 2613 of this title, such an extension and the reasons therefor shall be published in the Federal Register and shall constitute a final agency action subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of notice; publications in the Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Content of notice; publications in the Federal Register</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation pending development of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulation pending development of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection against unreasonable risks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protection against unreasonable risks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement on Administrator finding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Statement on Administrator finding If the Administrator finds in accordance with subsection (a)(3)(C) that a chemical substance or significant new use is not likely to present an unreasonable risk of injury to health or the environment, then notwithstanding any remaining portion of the applicable review period, the submitter of the notice may commence manufacture of the chemical substance or manufacture or processing for the significant new use, and the Administrator shall make public a statement of the Administrator’s finding. Such a statement shall be submitted for publication in the Federal Register as soon as is practicable before the expiration of such period. Publication of such statement in accordance with the preceding sentence is not a prerequisite to the manufacturing or processing of the substance with respect to which the statement is to be published.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>