<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2606"><akn:num>2606</akn:num><akn:heading>Imminent hazards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2606. Imminent hazards(a) Actions authorized and required(1) The Administrator may commence a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States—(A) for seizure of an imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture or any article containing such a substance or mixture,

(B) for relief (as authorized by subsection (b)) against any person who manufactures, processes, distributes in commerce, or uses, or disposes of, an imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture or any article containing such a substance or mixture, or

(C) for both such seizure and relief.


A civil action may be commenced under this paragraph notwithstanding the existence of a determination under section 2604 or 2605 of this title, a rule under section 2603, 2604, or 2605 of this title or subchapter IV, an order under section 2603, 2604, or 2605 of this title or subchapter IV, or a consent agreement under section 2603 of this title, and notwithstanding the pendency of any administrative or judicial proceeding under any provision of this chapter.

(2) If the Administrator has not made a rule under section 2605(a) of this title immediately effective (as authorized by section 2605(d)(3)(A)(i) of this title) with respect to an imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture, the Administrator shall commence in a district court of the United States with respect to such substance or mixture or article containing such substance or mixture a civil action described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1).


(b) Relief authorized(1) The district court of the United States in which an action under subsection (a) is brought shall have jurisdiction to grant such temporary or permanent relief as may be necessary to protect health or the environment from the unreasonable risk (as identified by the Administrator without consideration of costs or other nonrisk factors) associated with the chemical substance, mixture, or article involved in such action.

(2) In the case of an </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions authorized and required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Actions authorized and required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relief authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue and consolidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Venue and consolidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action under section 2605</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Action under section 2605 Where appropriate, concurrently with the filing of an action under subsection (a) or as soon thereafter as may be practicable, the Administrator shall initiate a proceeding for the promulgation of a rule under section 2605(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Representation Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any action under subsection (a), the Administrator may direct attorneys of the Environmental Protection Agency to appear and represent the Administrator in such an action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture” defined For the purposes of subsection (a), the term “imminently hazardous chemical substance or mixture” means a chemical substance or mixture which presents an imminent and unreasonable risk of serious or widespread injury to health or the environment, without consideration of costs or other nonrisk factors. Such a risk to health or the environment shall be considered imminent if it is shown that the manufacture, processing, distribution in commerce, use, or disposal of the chemical substance or mixture, or that any combination of such activities, is likely to result in such injury to health or the environment before a final rule under section 2605 of this title can protect against such risk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>