<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2607" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2607/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2607/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2607"><akn:num>2607</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and retention of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2607. Reporting and retention of information(a) Reports(1) The Administrator shall promulgate rules under which—(A) each person (other than a small manufacturer or processor) who manufactures or processes or proposes to manufacture or process a chemical substance (other than a chemical substance described in subparagraph (B)(ii)) shall maintain such records, and shall submit to the Administrator such reports, as the Administrator may reasonably require, and

(B) each person (other than a small manufacturer or processor) who manufactures or processes or proposes to manufacture or process—(i) a mixture, or

(ii) a chemical substance in small quantities (as defined by the Administrator by rule) solely for purposes of scientific experimentation or analysis or chemical research on, or analysis of, such substance or another substance, including any such research or analysis for the development of a product,


shall maintain records and submit to the Administrator reports but only to the extent the Administrator determines the maintenance of records or submission of reports, or both, is necessary for the effective enforcement of this chapter.


The Administrator may not require in a rule promulgated under this paragraph the maintenance of records or the submission of reports with respect to changes in the proportions of the components of a mixture unless the Administrator finds that the maintenance of such records or the submission of such reports, or both, is necessary for the effective enforcement of this chapter. For purposes of the compilation of the list of chemical substances required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall promulgate rules pursuant to this subsection not later than 180 days after January 1, 1977.

(2) The Administrator may require under paragraph (1) maintenance of records and reporting with respect to the following insofar as known to the person making the report or insofar as reasonably ascertainable:(A) The common or trade name, the chemi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inventory</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Records Any person who manufactures, processes, or distributes in commerce any chemical substance or mixture shall maintain records of significant adverse reactions to health or the environment, as determined by the Administrator by rule, alleged to have been caused by the substance or mixture. Records of such adverse reactions to the health of employees shall be retained for a period of 30 years from the date such reactions were first reported to or known by the person maintaining such records. Any other record of such adverse reactions shall be retained for a period of five years from the date the information contained in the record was first reported to or known by the person maintaining the record. Records required to be maintained under this subsection shall include records of consumer allegations of personal injury or harm to health, reports of occupational disease or injury, and reports or complaints of injury to the environment submitted to the manufacturer, processor, or d</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health and safety studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Health and safety studies The Administrator shall promulgate rules under which the Administrator shall require any person who manufactures, processes, or distributes in commerce or who proposes to manufacture, process, or distribute in commerce any chemical substance or mixture (or with respect to paragraph (2), any person who has possession of a study) to submit to the Administrator—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Administrator of substantial risks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice to Administrator of substantial risks Any person who manufactures, processes, or distributes in commerce a chemical substance or mixture and who obtains information which reasonably supports the conclusion that such substance or mixture presents a substantial risk of injury to health or the environment shall immediately inform the Administrator of such information unless such person has actual knowledge that the Administrator has been adequately informed of such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2607_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Manufacture” and “process” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Manufacture” and “process” defined For purposes of this section, the terms “manufacture” and “process” mean manufacture or process for commercial purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>