<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2617"><akn:num>2617</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2617. Preemption(a) In general(1) Establishment or enforcementExcept as otherwise provided in subsections (c), (d), (e), (f), and (g), and subject to paragraph (2), no State or political subdivision of a State may establish or continue to enforce any of the following:(A) Development of informationA statute or administrative action to require the development of information about a chemical substance or category of chemical substances that is reasonably likely to produce the same information required under section 2603, 2604, or 2605 of this title in—(i) a rule promulgated by the Administrator;

(ii) a consent agreement entered into by the Administrator; or

(iii) an order issued by the Administrator.


(B) Chemical substances found not to present an unreasonable risk or restrictedA statute, criminal penalty, or administrative action to prohibit or otherwise restrict the manufacture, processing, or distribution in commerce or use of a chemical substance—(i) for which the determination described in section 2605(i)(1) of this title is made, consistent with the scope of the risk evaluation under section 2605(b)(4)(D) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; or

(ii) for which a final rule is promulgated under section 2605(a) of this title, after the effective date of the rule issued under section 2605(a) of this title for the chemical substance, consistent with the scope of the risk evaluation under section 2605(b)(4)(D) 1 of this title.


(C) Significant new useA statute or administrative action requiring the notification of a use of a chemical substance that the Administrator has specified as a significant new use and for which the Administrator has required notification pursuant to a rule promulgated under section 2604 of this title.



(2) Effective date of preemptionUnder this subsection, Federal preemption of statutes and administrative actions applicable to specific chemical substances shall not occur until the effective date of the applicable action</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New statutes, criminal penalties, or administrative actions creating prohibitions or other restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New statutes, criminal penalties, or administrative actions creating prohibitions or other restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scope of preemption Federal preemption under subsections (a) and (b) of statutes, criminal penalties, and administrative actions applicable to specific chemical substances shall apply only to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of certain laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preservation of certain laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Savings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>