<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2625" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2625/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2625/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2625"><akn:num>2625</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2625. Administration(a) Cooperation of Federal agenciesUpon request by the Administrator, each Federal department and agency is authorized—(1) to make its services, personnel, and facilities available (with or without reimbursement) to the Administrator to assist the Administrator in the administration of this chapter; and

(2) to furnish to the Administrator such information, data, estimates, and statistics, and to allow the Administrator access to all information in its possession as the Administrator may reasonably determine to be necessary for the administration of this chapter.


(b) Fees(1) The Administrator may, by rule, require the payment from any person required to submit information under section 2603 of this title or a notice or other information to be reviewed by the Administrator under section 2604 of this title, or who manufactures or processes a chemical substance that is the subject of a risk evaluation under section 2605(b) of this title, of a fee that is sufficient and not more than reasonably necessary to defray the cost related to such chemical substance of administering sections 2603, 2604, and 2605 of this title, and collecting, processing, reviewing, and providing access to and protecting from disclosure as appropriate under section 2613 of this title information on chemical substances under this subchapter, including contractor costs incurred by the Administrator. In setting a fee under this paragraph, the Administrator shall take into account the ability to pay of the person required to pay such fee and the cost to the Administrator of carrying out the activities described in this paragraph. Such rules may provide for sharing such a fee in any case in which the expenses of testing are shared under section 2603 or 2604 of this title.

(2) The Administrator, after consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, shall by rule prescribe standards for determining the persons which qualify as small business concerns fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperation of Federal agencies Upon request by the Administrator, each Federal department and agency is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action with respect to categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action with respect to categories</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance office The Administrator shall establish in the Environmental Protection Agency an identifiable office to provide technical and other nonfinancial assistance to manufacturers and processors of chemical substances and mixtures respecting the requirements of this chapter applicable to such manufacturers and processors, the policy of the Agency respecting the application of such requirements to such manufacturers and processors, and the means and methods by which such manufacturers and processors may comply with such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Financial disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of basis and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Statement of basis and purpose Any final order issued under this chapter shall be accompanied by a statement of its basis and purpose. The contents and adequacy of any such statement shall not be subject to judicial review in any respect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistant Administrator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Scientific standards In carrying out sections 2603, 2604, and 2605 of this title, to the extent that the Administrator makes a decision based on science, the Administrator shall use scientific information, technical procedures, measures, methods, protocols, methodologies, or models, employed in a manner consistent with the best available science, and shall consider as applicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weight of scientific evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Weight of scientific evidence The Administrator shall make decisions under sections 2603, 2604, and 2605 of this title based on the weight of the scientific evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2625_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Availability of information Subject to section 2613 of this title, the Administrator shall make available to the public—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>