<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2643" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2643/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2643/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2643"><akn:num>2643</akn:num><akn:heading>EPA regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2643. EPA regulations(a) In generalWithin 360 days after October 22, 1986, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations as described in subsections (b) through (i). With respect to regulations described in subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), and (i), the Administrator shall issue an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking within 60 days after October 22, 1986, and shall propose regulations within 180 days after October 22, 1986. Any regulation promulgated under this section must protect human health and the environment.


(b) InspectionThe Administrator shall promulgate regulations which prescribe procedures, including the use of personnel accredited under section 2646(b) or (c) of this title and laboratories accredited under section 2646(d) of this title, for determining whether asbestos-containing material is present in a school building under the authority of a local educational agency. The regulations shall provide for the exclusion of any school building, or portion of a school building, if (1) an inspection of such school building (or portion) was completed before the effective date of the regulations, and (2) the inspection meets the procedures and other requirements of the regulations under this subchapter or of the “Guidance for Controlling Asbestos-Containing Materials in Buildings” (unless the Administrator determines that an inspection in accordance with the guidance document is inadequate). The regulations shall require inspection of any school building (or portion of a school building) that is not excluded by the preceding sentence.


(c) Circumstances requiring response actions(1) The Administrator shall promulgate regulations which define the appropriate response action in a school building under the authority of a local educational agency in at least the following circumstances:(A) DamageCircumstances in which friable asbestos-containing material or its covering is damaged, deteriorated, or delaminated.


(B) Significant damageCircumstances</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Within 360 days after October 22, 1986, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations as described in subsections (b) through (i). With respect to regulations described in subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), and (i), the Administrator shall issue an advanced notice of proposed rulemaking within 60 days after October 22, 1986, and shall propose regulations within 180 days after October 22, 1986. Any regulation promulgated under this section must protect human health and the environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspection The Administrator shall promulgate regulations which prescribe procedures, including the use of personnel accredited under section 2646(b) or (c) of this title and laboratories accredited under section 2646(d) of this title, for determining whether asbestos-containing material is present in a school building under the authority of a local educational agency. The regulations shall provide for the exclusion of any school building, or portion of a school building, if (1) an inspection of such school building (or portion) was completed before the effective date of the regulations, and (2) the inspection meets the procedures and other requirements of the regulations under this subchapter or of the “Guidance for Controlling Asbestos-Containing Materials in Buildings” (unless the Administrator determines that an inspection in accordance with the guidance document is inadequate). The regulations shall require inspection of any school building (or portion of a school building) th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances requiring response actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Circumstances requiring response actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Response actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation The Administrator shall promulgate regulations requiring the implementation of response actions in school buildings under the authority of a local educational agency and, where appropriate, for the determination of when a response action is completed. Such regulations shall include standards for the education and protection of both workers and building occupants for the following phases of activity:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations and maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Operations and maintenance The Administrator shall promulgate regulations to require implementation of an operations and maintenance and repair program as described in chapter 3 of the “Guidance for Controlling Asbestos-Containing Materials in Buildings” for all friable asbestos-containing material in a school building under the authority of a local educational agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic surveillance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Periodic surveillance The Administrator shall promulgate regulations to require the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation and disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transportation and disposal The Administrator shall promulgate regulations which prescribe standards for transportation and disposal of asbestos-containing waste material to protect human health and the environment. Such regulations shall include such provisions related to the manner in which transportation vehicles are loaded and unloaded as will assure the physical integrity of containers of asbestos-containing waste material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Management plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2643_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Changes in regulations Changes may be made in the regulations promulgated under this section only by rule in accordance with section 553 of title 5. Any such change must protect human health and the environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>