<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2644" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2644/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2644/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2644"><akn:num>2644</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements if EPA fails to promulgate regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2644. Requirements if EPA fails to promulgate regulations(a) In general(1) Failure to promulgateIf the Administrator fails to promulgate within the prescribed period—(A) regulations described in section 2643(b) of this title (relating to inspection);

(B) regulations described in section 2643(c), (d), (e), (f), (g), and (i) of this title (relating to responding to asbestos); or

(C) regulations described in section 2643(h) of this title (relating to transportation and disposal);


each local educational agency shall carry out the requirements described in this section in subsection (b); subsections (c), (d), and (e); or subsection (f); respectively, in accordance with the Environmental Protection Agency’s most current guidance document.

(2) Stay by courtIf the Administrator has promulgated regulations described in paragraph (1)(A), (B), or (C) within the prescribed period, but the effective date of such regulations has been stayed by a court for a period of more than 30 days, a local educational agency shall carry out the pertinent requirements described in this subsection in accordance with the Environmental Protection Agency’s most current guidance document.


(3) Effective periodThe requirements of this section shall be in effect until such time as the Administrator promulgates the pertinent regulations or until the stay is lifted (as the case may be).



(b) Inspection(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the local educational agency, within 540 days after October 22, 1986, shall conduct an inspection for asbestos-containing material, using personnel accredited under section 2646(b) or (c) of this title and laboratories accredited under section 2646(d) of this title, in each school building under its authority.

(2) The local educational agency may exclude from the inspection requirement in paragraph (1) any school building, or portion of a school building, if (A) an inspection of such school building (or portion) was completed before the date on which thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation and maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation and maintenance The local educational agency shall, within 720 days after October 22, 1986, develop and begin implementation of an operation and maintenance plan with respect to friable asbestos-containing material in a school building under its authority. Such plan shall provide for the education of school service and maintenance personnel about safety procedures with respect to asbestos-containing material, including friable asbestos-containing material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Building occupant protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Building occupant protection The local educational agency shall provide for the protection of building occupants during each phase of activity described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2644_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation and disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transportation and disposal The local educational agency shall provide for the transportation and disposal of asbestos in accordance with the most recent version of the Environmental Protection Agency’s “Asbestos Waste Management Guidance” (or any successor to such document).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>