<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2646" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2646/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2646/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2646"><akn:num>2646</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractor and laboratory accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2646. Contractor and laboratory accreditation(a) Contractor accreditationA person may not—(1) inspect for asbestos-containing material in a school building under the authority of a local educational agency or in a public or commercial building,

(2) prepare a management plan for such a school, or

(3) design or conduct response actions, other than the type of action described in sections 2643(f) and 2644(c) of this title, with respect to friable asbestos-containing material in such a school or in a public or commercial building,


unless such person is accredited by a State under subsection (b) or is accredited pursuant to an Administrator-approved course under subsection (c).

(b) Accreditation by State(1) Model plan(A) Persons to be accreditedWithin 180 days after October 22, 1986, the Administrator, in consultation with affected organizations, shall develop a model contractor accreditation plan for States to give accreditation to persons in the following categories:(i) Persons who inspect for asbestos-containing material in school buildings under the authority of a local educational agency or in public or commercial buildings.

(ii) Persons who prepare management plans for such schools.

(iii) Persons who design or carry out response actions, other than the type of action described in sections 2643(f) and 2644(c) of this title, with respect to friable asbestos-containing material in such schools or in public or commercial buildings.


(B) Plan requirementsThe plan shall include a requirement that any person in a category listed in paragraph (1) 11 So in original. Probably should be “subparagraph (A)”. achieve a passing grade on an examination and participate in continuing education to stay informed about current asbestos inspection and response action technology. The examination shall demonstrate the knowledge of the person in areas that the Administrator prescribes as necessary and appropriate in each of the categories. Such examinations may include requiremen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractor accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contractor accreditation A person may not— unless such person is accredited by a State under subsection (b) or is accredited pursuant to an Administrator-approved course under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation by State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accreditation by State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation by Administrator-approved course</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accreditation by Administrator-approved course</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Laboratory accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Laboratory accreditation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance contingent on use of accredited persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Financial assistance contingent on use of accredited persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of EPA-approved courses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) List of EPA-approved courses Not later than August 31, 1988, and every three months thereafter until August 31, 1991, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register a list of all Environmental Protection Agency-approved asbestos training courses for persons to achieve accreditation in each category described in subsection (b)(1)(A) and for laboratories to achieve accreditation. The Administrator may continue publishing such a list after August 31, 1991, at such times as the Administrator considers it useful. The list shall include the name and address of each approved trainer and, to the extent available, a list of all the geographic sites where training courses will take place. The Administrator shall provide a copy of the list to each State official on the list published by the Administrator under section 2645(d)(6) of this title and to each regional office of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>