<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2647" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2647/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2647/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2647"><akn:num>2647</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2647. Enforcement(a) PenaltiesAny local educational agency—(1) which fails to conduct an inspection pursuant to regulations under section 2643(b) of this title or under section 2644(b) of this title,

(2) which knowingly submits false information to the Governor regarding any inspection pursuant to regulations under section 2643(i) of this title or knowingly includes false information in any inspection statement under section 2644(d)(3) of this title,

(3) which fails to develop a management plan pursuant to regulations under section 2643(i) of this title or under section 2644(d) of this title,

(4) which carries out any activity prohibited by section 2655 of this title, or

(5) which knowingly submits false information to the Governor regarding a deferral request under section 2645(d) of this title.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma.


is liable for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which the violation continues. Any civil penalty under this subsection shall be assessed and collected in the same manner, and subject to the same provisions, as in the case of civil penalties assessed and collected under section 2615 of this title. For purposes of this subsection, a “violation” means a failure to comply with respect to a single school building. The court shall order that any civil penalty collected under this subsection be used by the local educational agency for purposes of complying with this subchapter. Any portion of a civil penalty remaining unspent after compliance by a local educational agency is completed shall be deposited into the Asbestos Trust Fund established by section 4022 of title 20.

(b) Relationship to subchapter I of this chapterA local educational agency is not liable for any civil penalty under subchapter I of this chapter for failing or refusing to comply with any rule promulgated or order issued under this subchapter.


(c) Enforcement considerations(1) In determining the amount of a civil penalt</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Penalties Any local educational agency— is liable for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which the violation continues. Any civil penalty under this subsection shall be assessed and collected in the same manner, and subject to the same provisions, as in the case of civil penalties assessed and collected under section 2615 of this title. For purposes of this subsection, a “violation” means a failure to comply with respect to a single school building. The court shall order that any civil penalty collected under this subsection be used by the local educational agency for purposes of complying with this subchapter. Any portion of a civil penalty remaining unspent after compliance by a local educational agency is completed shall be deposited into the Asbestos Trust Fund established by section 4022 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to subchapter I of this chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relationship to subchapter I of this chapter A local educational agency is not liable for any civil penalty under subchapter I of this chapter for failing or refusing to comply with any rule promulgated or order issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement considerations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen complaints</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Citizen complaints Any person may file a complaint with the Administrator or with the Governor of the State in which the school building is located with respect to asbestos-containing material in a school building. If the Administrator or Governor receives a complaint under this subsection containing allegations which provide a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of this chapter has occurred, the Administrator or Governor shall investigate and respond (including taking enforcement action where appropriate) to the complaint within a reasonable period of time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen petitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Citizen petitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen civil actions with respect to EPA regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Citizen civil actions with respect to EPA regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2647_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to attain accreditation; penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Failure to attain accreditation; penalty Any contractor who— and who fails to obtain the accreditation under section 2646 of this title, or in the case of employees to require or provide for the accreditation required, is liable for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which the violation continues, unless such contractor is a direct employee of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>