<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2666" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2666/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2666/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2666"><akn:num>2666</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant assistance to States for radon programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2666. Grant assistance to States for radon programs(a) In generalFor each fiscal year, upon application of the Governor of a State, the Administrator may make a grant, subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator considers appropriate, under this section to the State for the purpose of assisting the State in the development and implementation of programs for the assessment and mitigation of radon.


(b) ApplicationAn application for a grant under this section in any fiscal year shall contain such information as the Administrator shall require, including each of the following:(1) A description of the seriousness and extent of radon exposure in the State.

(2) An identification of the State agency which has the primary responsibility for radon programs and which will receive the grant, a description of the roles and responsibilities of the lead State agency and any other State agencies involved in radon programs, and description of the roles and responsibilities of any municipal, district, or areawide organization involved in radon programs.

(3) A description of the activities and programs related to radon which the State proposes in such year.

(4) A budget specifying Federal and State funding of each element of activity of the grant application.

(5) A 3-year plan which outlines long range program goals and objectives, tasks necessary to achieve them, and resource requirements for the entire 3-year period, including anticipated State funding levels and desired Federal funding levels. This clause shall apply only for the initial year in which a grant application is made.


(c) Eligible activitiesActivities eligible for grant assistance under this section are the following:(1) Survey of radon levels, including special surveys of geographic areas or classes of buildings (such as, among others, public buildings, school buildings, high-risk residential construction types).

(2) Development of public information and educational materials concerning radon a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For each fiscal year, upon application of the Governor of a State, the Administrator may make a grant, subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator considers appropriate, under this section to the State for the purpose of assisting the State in the development and implementation of programs for the assessment and mitigation of radon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application An application for a grant under this section in any fiscal year shall contain such information as the Administrator shall require, including each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible activities Activities eligible for grant assistance under this section are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference to certain States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preference to certain States Beginning in fiscal year 1991, the Administrator shall give a preference for grant assistance under this section to States that have made reasonable efforts to ensure the adoption, by the authorities which regulate building construction within that State or political subdivisions within States, of the model construction standards and techniques for new buildings developed under section 2664 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority activities and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority activities and projects The Administrator shall support eligible activities contained in State applications with the full amount of available funds. In the event that State applications for funds exceed the total funds available in a fiscal year, the Administrator shall give priority to activities or projects proposed by States based on each of the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal share The Federal share of the cost of radon program activities implemented with Federal assistance under this section in any fiscal year shall not exceed 75 percent of the costs incurred by the State in implementing such program in the first year of a grant to such State, 60 percent in the second year, and 50 percent in the third year. Federal assistance shall be made on the condition that the non-Federal share is provided from non-Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to local governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance to local governments States may, at the Governor’s discretion, use funds from grants under this section to assist local governments in implementation of activities eligible for assistance under paragraphs (2), (3), and (6) of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2666_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>