<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2685" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2685/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2685/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2685"><akn:num>2685</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead abatement and measurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2685. Lead abatement and measurement(a) Program to promote lead exposure abatementThe Administrator, in cooperation with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive program to promote safe, effective, and affordable monitoring, detection, and abatement of lead-based paint and other lead exposure hazards.


(b) Standards for environmental sampling laboratories(1) The Administrator shall establish protocols, criteria, and minimum performance standards for laboratory analysis of lead in paint films, soil, and dust. Within 2 years after October 28, 1992, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a program to certify laboratories as qualified to test substances for lead content unless the Administrator determines, by the date specified in this paragraph, that effective voluntary accreditation programs are in place and operating on a nationwide basis at the time of such determination. To be certified under such program, a laboratory shall, at a minimum, demonstrate an ability to test substances accurately for lead content.

(2) Not later than 24 months after October 28, 1992, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall publish and make available to the public a list of certified or accredited environmental sampling laboratories.

(3) If the Administrator determines under paragraph (1) that effective voluntary accreditation programs are in place for environmental sampling laboratories, the Administrator shall review the performance and effectiveness of such programs within 3 years after such determination. If, upon such review, the Administrator determines that the voluntary accreditation programs are not effective in assuring the quality and consistency of laboratory analyses, the Administrator shall, not more than 12 months thereafter, establish a certification program that meets the requirements of paragraph (1).


(c) Exposure studies(1) The Secretary of Health and Hu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program to promote lead exposure abatement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program to promote lead exposure abatement The Administrator, in cooperation with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies, shall conduct a comprehensive program to promote safe, effective, and affordable monitoring, detection, and abatement of lead-based paint and other lead exposure hazards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for environmental sampling laboratories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards for environmental sampling laboratories</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exposure studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exposure studies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2685_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products for lead-based paint activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Products for lead-based paint activities Not later than 30 months after October 28, 1992, the President shall, after notice and opportunity for comment, establish by rule appropriate criteria, testing protocols, and performance characteristics as are necessary to ensure, to the greatest extent possible and consistent with the purposes and policy of this subchapter, that lead-based paint hazard evaluation and reduction products introduced into commerce after a period specified in the rule are effective for the intended use described by the manufacturer. The rule shall identify the types or classes of products that are subject to such rule. The President, in implementation of the rule, shall, to the maximum extent possible, utilize independent testing laboratories, as appropriate, and consult with such entities and others in developing the rules. The President may delegate the authorities under this subsection to the Environmental Protection Agency or the Secretary of Commerce or suc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>