<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2695"><akn:num>2695</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for healthy school environments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2695. Grants for healthy school environments(a) In generalThe Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may provide grants to States for use in—(1) providing technical assistance for programs of the Environmental Protection Agency (including the Tools for Schools Program and the Healthy School Environmental Assessment Tool) to schools for use in addressing environmental issues; and

(2) development and implementation of State school environmental health programs that include—(A) standards for school building design, construction, and renovation; and

(B) identification of ongoing school building environmental problems, including contaminants, hazardous substances, and pollutant emissions, in the State and recommended solutions to address those problems, including assessment of information on the exposure of children to environmental hazards in school facilities.



(b) SunsetThe authority of the Administrator to carry out this section shall expire 5 years after December 19, 2007.


(Pub. L. 94–469, title V, § 501, as added Pub. L. 110–140, title IV, § 461(a), Dec. 19, 2007, 121 Stat. 1640.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSubchapter effective on the date that is 1 day after Dec. 19, 2007, see section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140, set out as a note under section 1824 of Title 2, The Congress.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2695_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may provide grants to States for use in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2695_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sunset The authority of the Administrator to carry out this section shall expire 5 years after December 19, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>