<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2695c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2695c"><akn:num>2695c</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental health program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2695c. Environmental health program(a) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 19, 2007, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and other relevant agencies, shall issue voluntary guidelines for use by the State in developing and implementing an environmental health program for schools that—(1) takes into account the status and findings of Federal initiatives established under this subchapter or subtitle C of title IV of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 [42 U.S.C. 17091 et seq.] and other relevant Federal law with respect to school facilities, including relevant updates on trends in the field, such as the impact of school facility environments on student and staff—(A) health, safety, and productivity; and

(B) disabilities or special needs;


(2) takes into account studies using relevant tools identified or developed in accordance with section 492 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 [42 U.S.C. 17122];

(3) takes into account, with respect to school facilities, each of—(A) environmental problems, contaminants, hazardous substances, and pollutant emissions, including—(i) lead from drinking water;

(ii) lead from materials and products;

(iii) asbestos;

(iv) radon;

(v) the presence of elemental mercury releases from products and containers;

(vi) pollutant emissions from materials and products; and

(vii) any other environmental problem, contaminant, hazardous substance, or pollutant emission that present or may present a risk to the health of occupants of the school facilities or environment;


(B) natural day lighting;

(C) ventilation choices and technologies;

(D) heating and cooling choices and technologies;

(E) moisture control and mold;

(F) maintenance, cleaning, and pest control activities;

(G) acoustics; and

(H) other issues relating to the health, comfort, productivity, and performance of occupants of the school facilities;


(4) provides te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2695c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 2 years after December 19, 2007, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and other relevant agencies, shall issue voluntary guidelines for use by the State in developing and implementing an environmental health program for schools that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2695c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public outreach The Federal Director and Commercial Director shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the public clearinghouse established under section 423 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 [42 U.S.C. 17083] receives and makes available—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>