<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/26b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/26b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/26b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_26b"><akn:num>26b</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of antitrust laws to professional major league baseball</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 26b. Application of antitrust laws to professional major league baseball(a) Major league baseball subject to antitrust lawsSubject to subsections (b) through (d), the conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons in the business of organized professional major league baseball directly relating to or affecting employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level are subject to the antitrust laws to the same extent such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements would be subject to the antitrust laws if engaged in by persons in any other professional sports business affecting interstate commerce.


(b) Limitation of sectionNo court shall rely on the enactment of this section as a basis for changing the application of the antitrust laws to any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements other than those set forth in subsection (a). This section does not create, permit or imply a cause of action by which to challenge under the antitrust laws, or otherwise apply the antitrust laws to, any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements that do not directly relate to or affect employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level, including but not limited to—(1) any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons engaging in, conducting or participating in the business of organized professional baseball relating to or affecting employment to play baseball at the minor league level, any organized professional baseball amateur or first-year player draft, or any reserve clause as applied to minor league players;

(2) the agreement between organized professional major league baseball teams and the teams of the National Association of Professional Baseball Leagues, commonly known as the “Professional Baseball Agreement”, the relationship between organized professional major league baseball and organized professional minor league baseball, or any other matter relating to organized professional baseball’s minor leagu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major league baseball subject to antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Major league baseball subject to antitrust laws Subject to subsections (b) through (d), the conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons in the business of organized professional major league baseball directly relating to or affecting employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level are subject to the antitrust laws to the same extent such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements would be subject to the antitrust laws if engaged in by persons in any other professional sports business affecting interstate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation of section No court shall rely on the enactment of this section as a basis for changing the application of the antitrust laws to any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements other than those set forth in subsection (a). This section does not create, permit or imply a cause of action by which to challenge under the antitrust laws, or otherwise apply the antitrust laws to, any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements that do not directly relate to or affect employment of major league baseball players to play baseball at the major league level, including but not limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing to sue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Standing to sue Only a major league baseball player has standing to sue under this section. For the purposes of this section, a major league baseball player is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_26b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct, acts, practices, or agreements subject to antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conduct, acts, practices, or agreements subject to antitrust laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>