<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2709" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2709/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2709/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2709"><akn:num>2709</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress by Secretary of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2709. Reports to Congress by Secretary of Energy(a) Comprehensive program, etc.As a separate part of the annual report submitted under section 5914(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 42 with respect to the comprehensive plan and program then in effect under section 5905(a) and (b) of title 42, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress an annual report of activities under this chapter. Such report shall include—(1) a current comprehensive program definition for implementing this chapter;

(2) an evaluation of the state of automobile propulsion system research and development in the United States;

(3) the number and amount of contracts and grants made under this chapter;

(4) an analysis of the progress made in developing advanced automobile propulsion system technology; and

(5) suggestions for improvements in advanced automobile propulsion system research and development, including recommendations for legislation.


(b) Study on financial obligation guaranteesThe Secretary of Energy shall conduct a survey of developers, lending institutions, and other appropriate persons or institutions and shall otherwise make a study for the purpose of determining whether, and under what conditions, research, development, demonstration, and commercial availability of advanced automobile propulsion system technology may be aided by the guarantee of financial obligations by the Federal Government. The Secretary of Energy shall report the results of such survey and study to the Congress within 1 year after February 25, 1978. Such report shall include an examination of those stages of advanced automobile propulsion system technology research, development, demonstration, and commercialization for which financial obligation guarantees may be useful or appropriate and shall contain such legislative recommendations as may be necessary.


(Pub. L. 95–238, title III, § 310, Feb. 25, 1978, 92 Stat. 83.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 5914 of title 42, re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2709_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive program, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Comprehensive program, etc. As a separate part of the annual report submitted under section 5914(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 42 with respect to the comprehensive plan and program then in effect under section 5905(a) and (b) of title 42, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress an annual report of activities under this chapter. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2709_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on financial obligation guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Study on financial obligation guarantees The Secretary of Energy shall conduct a survey of developers, lending institutions, and other appropriate persons or institutions and shall otherwise make a study for the purpose of determining whether, and under what conditions, research, development, demonstration, and commercial availability of advanced automobile propulsion system technology may be aided by the guarantee of financial obligations by the Federal Government. The Secretary of Energy shall report the results of such survey and study to the Congress within 1 year after February 25, 1978. Such report shall include an examination of those stages of advanced automobile propulsion system technology research, development, demonstration, and commercialization for which financial obligation guarantees may be useful or appropriate and shall contain such legislative recommendations as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>