<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_278f"><akn:num>278f</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire Research Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 278f. Fire Research Center(a) Establishment; programs of research; functions of Secretary; dissemination of informationThere is hereby established within the Department of Commerce a Fire Research Center which shall have the mission of performing and supporting research on all aspects of fire with the aim of providing scientific and technical knowledge applicable to the prevention and control of fires. The content and priorities of the research program shall be determined in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration. In implementing this section, the Secretary is authorized to conduct, directly or through contracts or grants, a fire research program, including—(1) basic and applied fire research for the purpose of arriving at an understanding of the fundamental processes underlying all aspects of fire. Such research shall include scientific investigations of—(A) the physics and chemistry of combustion processes;

(B) the dynamics of flame ignition, flame spread, and flame extinguishment;

(C) the composition of combustion products developed by various sources and under various environmental conditions;

(D) the early stages of fires in buildings and other structures, structural subsystems and structural components in all other types of fires, including, but not limited to, forest fires, brush fires, fires underground, oil blowout fires, and waterborne fires, with the aim of improving early detection capability;

(E) the behavior of fires involving all types of buildings and other structures and their contents (including mobile homes and highrise buildings, construction materials, floor and wall coverings, coatings, furnishings, and other combustible materials), and all other types of fires, including forest fires, brush fires, fires underground, oil blowout fires, and waterborne fires;

(F) the unique fire hazards arising from the transportation and use, in industrial and professional practices, of combustible gases, fluids, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; programs of research; functions of Secretary; dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; programs of research; functions of Secretary; dissemination of information There is hereby established within the Department of Commerce a Fire Research Center which shall have the mission of performing and supporting research on all aspects of fire with the aim of providing scientific and technical knowledge applicable to the prevention and control of fires. The content and priorities of the research program shall be determined in consultation with the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration. In implementing this section, the Secretary is authorized to conduct, directly or through contracts or grants, a fire research program, including— The Secretary shall insure that the results and advances arising from the work of the research program are disseminated broadly. He shall encourage the incorporation, to the extent applicable and practicable, of such results and advances in building codes, fire codes, and other relevant codes, test methods, fire servic</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations For purposes of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated an amount not to exceed $5,650,000 for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1980, which amount includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>