<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_278k_2"><akn:num>278k–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion awards pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 278k–2. Expansion awards pilot program(a) DefinitionsThe terms used in this section have the meanings given the terms in section 278k of this title.


(b) EstablishmentThe Director shall establish, subject to the availability of appropriations, as a part of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership under sections 278k and 278k–1 of this title, a pilot program of expansion awards among participants described in subsection (c) for the purposes described in subsection (e).


(c) ParticipantsParticipants receiving awards under this section shall be Centers, or a consortium of Centers (as such term is defined in section 278k of this title).


(d) Award amountsSubject to the availability of appropriations, an award for a recipient under this section shall be in an amount equal to the sum of the following:(1) Such amount as the Director considers appropriate as a minimum base funding level for each award under this section.

(2) Such additional amount as the Director considers in proportion to the manufacturing density of the region of the recipient.

(3) Such supplemental amounts as the Director considers appropriate.


(e) Purpose of awardsAn award under this section shall be made for one or more of the following purposes:(1) To provide worker education, training, development, and entrepreneurship training and to connect individuals or business with such services offered in their community, which may include employee ownership and workforce training, including connecting manufacturers with career and technical education entities, institutions of higher education (including community colleges), workforce development boards, labor organizations, and nonprofit job training providers to develop and support training and job placement services, including apprenticeship and online learning platforms, for new and incumbent workers, programming to prevent job losses when adopting new technologies and processes, and development of employee ownership practices.

(2) To pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions The terms used in this section have the meanings given the terms in section 278k of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Director shall establish, subject to the availability of appropriations, as a part of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership under sections 278k and 278k–1 of this title, a pilot program of expansion awards among participants described in subsection (c) for the purposes described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participants Participants receiving awards under this section shall be Centers, or a consortium of Centers (as such term is defined in section 278k of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Award amounts Subject to the availability of appropriations, an award for a recipient under this section shall be in an amount equal to the sum of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Purpose of awards An award under this section shall be made for one or more of the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reimbursement The Director may reimburse Centers for costs incurred by the Centers under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications Applications for awards under this section shall be submitted in such manner, at such time, and containing such information as the Director shall require in consultation with the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Program contribution Recipients of awards under this section shall not be required to provide a matching contribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Global marketplace projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Global marketplace projects In making an award under this section, the Director, in consultation with the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Advisory Board and the Secretary, may take into consideration whether an application has significant potential for enhancing the competitiveness of small and medium-sized United States manufacturers in the global marketplace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>