<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/278k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_278k"><akn:num>278k</akn:num><akn:heading>Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 278k. Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Appropriate committees of congressThe term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.


(2) Area career and technical education schoolThe term “area career and technical education school” has the meaning given the term in section 2302 of title 20.


(3) CenterThe term “Center” means a manufacturing extension center that—(A) is created under subsection (b); and

(B) is affiliated with an eligible entity that applies for and is awarded financial support under subsection (e).


(4) Community collegeThe term “community college” means an institution of higher education (as defined under section 1001(a) of title 20) at which the highest degree that is predominately awarded to students is an associate’s degree.


(5) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a United States-based nonprofit institution, an institution of higher education, or a State, United States territory, local, or tribal government or a consortium thereof.


(6) Historically Black college and universityThe term “historically Black college and university” has the meaning given the term “part B institution” in section 1061 of title 20.


(7) 11 So in original. Two pars. (7) have been enacted. Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 1001 of title 20.


(7) 1 Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership or ProgramThe term “Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership” or “Program” means the program established under subsection (b).


(8) MEP Advisory BoardThe term “MEP Advisory Board” means the Manufacturing Extension Partnership Advisory Board established under subsection (n).22 So in original. Probably should refer to subsec. (m).


(9) Minority-serving institutionThe term “min</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and purpose The Secretary, acting through the Director and, if appropriate, through other Federal officials, shall establish a program to provide assistance for the creation and support of manufacturing extension centers for the transfer of manufacturing technology and best business practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objective</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Objective The objective of the Program shall be to enhance competitiveness, productivity, and technological performance in United States manufacturing through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities The activities of a Center shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reapplication competition for financial assistance after 10 years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reapplication competition for financial assistance after 10 years</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Process plan Not later than 180 days after January 6, 2017, the Secretary shall implement and submit to Congress a plan for how the Institute will conduct an evaluation, competition, and reapplication competition under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_278k_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Operational requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>