<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2801" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2801/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2801/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2801"><akn:num>2801</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2801. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1)(A) The term “franchise” means any contract—(i) between a refiner and a distributor,

(ii) between a refiner and a retailer,

(iii) between a distributor and another distributor, or

(iv) between a distributor and a retailer,


under which a refiner or distributor (as the case may be) authorizes or permits a retailer or distributor to use, in connection with the sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel, a trademark which is owned or controlled by such refiner or by a refiner which supplies motor fuel to the distributor which authorizes or permits such use.

(B) The term “franchise” includes—(i) any contract under which a retailer or distributor (as the case may be) is authorized or permitted to occupy leased marketing premises, which premises are to be employed in connection with the sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel under a trademark which is owned or controlled by such refiner or by a refiner which supplies motor fuel to the distributor which authorizes or permits such occupancy;

(ii) any contract pertaining to the supply of motor fuel which is to be sold, consigned or distributed—(I) under a trademark owned or controlled by a refiner; or

(II) under a contract which has existed continuously since May 15, 1973, and pursuant to which, on May 15, 1973, motor fuel was sold, consigned or distributed under a trademark owned or controlled on such date by a refiner; and


(iii) the unexpired portion of any franchise, as defined by the preceding provisions of this paragraph, which is transferred or assigned as authorized by the provisions of such franchise or by any applicable provision of State law which permits such transfer or assignment without regard to any provision of the franchise.



(2) The term “franchise relationship” means the respective motor fuel marketing or distribution obligations and responsibilities of a franchisor and a franchisee which result from the marketing of motor fuel un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “franchise relationship” means the respective motor fuel marketing or distribution obligations and responsibilities of a franchisor and a franchisee which result from the marketing of motor fuel under a franchise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “franchisor” means a refiner or distributor (as the case may be) who authorizes or permits, under a franchise, a retailer or distributor to use a trademark in connection with the sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “franchisee” means a retailer or distributor (as the case may be) who is authorized or permitted, under a franchise, to use a trademark in connection with the sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “refiner” means any person engaged in the refining of crude oil to produce motor fuel, and includes any affiliate of such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “distributor” means any person, including any affiliate of such person, who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “retailer” means any person who purchases motor fuel for sale to the general public for ultimate consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “marketing premises” means, in the case of any franchise, premises which, under such franchise, are to be employed by the franchisee in connection with sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “leased marketing premises” means marketing premises owned, leased, or in any way controlled by a franchisor and which the franchisee is authorized or permitted, under the franchise, to employ in connection with the sale, consignment, or distribution of motor fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2801_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “contract” means any oral or written agreement. For supply purposes, delivery levels during the same month of the previous year shall be prima facie evidence of an agreement to deliver such levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>