<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2806"><akn:num>2806</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of statutory provisions to State and local laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2806. Relationship of statutory provisions to State and local laws(a) Termination or nonrenewal of franchise(1) To the extent that any provision of this subchapter applies to the termination (or the furnishing of notification with respect thereto) of any franchise, or to the nonrenewal (or the furnishing of notification with respect thereto) of any franchise relationship, no State or any political subdivision thereof may adopt, enforce, or continue in effect any provision of any law or regulation (including any remedy or penalty applicable to any violation thereof) with respect to termination (or the furnishing of notification with respect thereto) of any such franchise or to the nonrenewal (or the furnishing of notification with respect thereto) of any such franchise relationship unless such provision of such law or regulation is the same as the applicable provision of this subchapter.

(2) No State or political subdivision of a State may adopt, enforce, or continue in effect any provision of law (including a regulation) that requires a payment for the goodwill of a franchisee on the termination of a franchise or nonrenewal of a franchise relationship authorized by this subchapter.


(b) Transfer or assignment of franchise(1) Nothing in this subchapter authorizes any transfer or assignment of any franchise or prohibits any transfer or assignment of any franchise as authorized by the provisions of such franchise or by any applicable provision of State law which permits such transfer or assignment without regard to any provision of the franchise.

(2) Nothing in this subchapter shall prohibit any State from specifying the terms and conditions under which any franchise or franchise relationship may be transferred to the designated successor of a franchisee upon the death of the franchisee.


(Pub. L. 95–297, title I, § 106, June 19, 1978, 92 Stat. 332; Pub. L. 103–371, § 5, Oct. 19, 1994, 108 Stat. 3485.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–371,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or nonrenewal of franchise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination or nonrenewal of franchise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or assignment of franchise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer or assignment of franchise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>