<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/282a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/282a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/282a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_282a"><akn:num>282a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of emerging technologies requiring research in metrology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 282a. Assessment of emerging technologies requiring research in metrology
The Board of Assessment of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall include, as part of its annual review, an assessment of emerging technologies which are expected to require research in metrology to keep the Institute abreast of its mission, including process and quality control, engineering databases, advanced materials, electronics and fiber optics, bioprocess engineering, and advanced computing concepts. Such review shall include estimates of the cost of the required effort, required staffing levels, appropriate interaction with industry, including technology transfer, and the period over which the research will be required.
(Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5163(a), Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1450.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is comprised of section 5163(a) of Pub. L. 100–418. Section 5163(b)–(d) of Pub. L. 100–418 enacted provisions set out as a note under section 272 of this title, amended section 3710 of this title, and enacted section 1533 of this title, respectively.
Section was not enacted as part of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act which comprises this chapter.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 282a, Pub. L. 99–574, § 7, Oct. 28, 1986, 100 Stat. 3237, consisted of provisions substantially identical to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>