<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2841"><akn:num>2841</akn:num><akn:heading>Study by Secretary of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2841. Study by Secretary of Energy(a) Consultation with Chairman of Federal Trade Commission, Attorney General, and other agencies deemed appropriate by SecretaryThe Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission and the Attorney General and other agencies as the Secretary deems appropriate, shall conduct a study of the extent to which producers, refiners, and other suppliers of motor fuel subsidize the sale of such motor fuel at retail or wholesale with profits obtained from other operations.


(b) ScopeSuch study shall examine—(1) the role of vertically integrated operations in facilitating subsidization of sales of motor fuel at wholesale or retail;

(2) the extent to which such subsidization is predatory and presents a threat to competition;

(3) the profitability of various segments of the petroleum industry;

(4) the impact of prohibiting such subsidization on the competitive viability of various segments of the petroleum industry, on prices of motor fuel to consumers and on the health and structure of the petroleum industry as a whole; and

(5) such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(c) Notice to interested parties and opportunity to present written and oral data, views and argumentsIn conducting the study required by this section, the Secretary shall give appropriate notice and afford interested persons an opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments concerning such study.


(d) Report to Congress; contents and time for submission; Presidential promulgation of rules establishing interim measures; submission date and duration of interim measures; Congressional approval of interim measures(1) The Secretary shall report the results of the study required by this section, together with such recommendations for legislative action and such statistical evidence as he deems appropriate to the Congress on or before the expiration of the eighteenth month after June 19, 1978.

(2) If th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2841_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with Chairman of Federal Trade Commission, Attorney General, and other agencies deemed appropriate by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consultation with Chairman of Federal Trade Commission, Attorney General, and other agencies deemed appropriate by Secretary The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission and the Attorney General and other agencies as the Secretary deems appropriate, shall conduct a study of the extent to which producers, refiners, and other suppliers of motor fuel subsidize the sale of such motor fuel at retail or wholesale with profits obtained from other operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2841_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope Such study shall examine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2841_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to interested parties and opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice to interested parties and opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments In conducting the study required by this section, the Secretary shall give appropriate notice and afford interested persons an opportunity to present written and oral data, views and arguments concerning such study.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2841_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress; contents and time for submission; Presidential promulgation of rules establishing interim measures; submission date and duration of interim measures; Congressional approval of interim measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to Congress; contents and time for submission; Presidential promulgation of rules establishing interim measures; submission date and duration of interim measures; Congressional approval of interim measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2841_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>