<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/290a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/290a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/290a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290a"><akn:num>290a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290a. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter:(1) Standard reference dataThe term “standard reference data” means data that is—(A) either—(i) quantitative information related to a measurable physical, or chemical, or biological property of a substance or system of substances of known composition and structure;

(ii) measurable characteristics of a physical artifact or artifacts;

(iii) engineering properties or performance characteristics of a system; or

(iv) 1 or more digital data objects that serve—(I) to calibrate or characterize the performance of a detection or measurement system; or

(II) to interpolate or extrapolate, or both, data described in subparagraph (A) through (C); 11 So in original. and



(B) that is critically evaluated as to its reliability under section 290b of this title.


(2) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.


(Pub. L. 90–396, § 2, July 11, 1968, 82 Stat. 340; Pub. L. 114–329, title I, § 108, Jan. 6, 2017, 130 Stat. 2987.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2017—Pub. L. 114–329 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “For the purposes of this chapter—
“(a) The term ‘standard reference data’ means quantitative information, related to a measurable physical or chemical property of a substance or system of substances of known composition and structure, which is critically evaluated as to its reliability under section 290b of this title.
“(b) The term ‘Secretary’ means the Secretary of Commerce.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard reference data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Standard reference data The term “standard reference data” means data that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>