<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2961" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2961/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/2961/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2961"><akn:num>2961</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and decision aid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2961. Study and decision aid(a) Study of consequences of community growth and development; decision aid to assist State and local authorities in managing developmentThe Secretary of Commerce shall conduct a study of the implications and potential consequences of growth and development on urban, suburban, and rural communities. Based upon the findings of the study, the Secretary shall produce a decision aid to assist State and local authorities in planning and managing urban, suburban, and rural growth and development while preserving community character.


(b) Consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agenciesThe Secretary of Commerce shall consult with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies as necessary in carrying out this section.


(c) ReportThe Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Congress a report containing the decision aid produced under subsection (a) no later than January 30, 1992. The Secretary shall notify appropriate State and local authorities that such decision aid is available on request.


(Pub. L. 101–606, title III, § 301, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 3104.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2961_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of consequences of community growth and development; decision aid to assist State and local authorities in managing development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Study of consequences of community growth and development; decision aid to assist State and local authorities in managing development The Secretary of Commerce shall conduct a study of the implications and potential consequences of growth and development on urban, suburban, and rural communities. Based upon the findings of the study, the Secretary shall produce a decision aid to assist State and local authorities in planning and managing urban, suburban, and rural growth and development while preserving community character.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2961_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation with appropriate Federal departments and agencies The Secretary of Commerce shall consult with other appropriate Federal departments and agencies as necessary in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2961_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report The Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Congress a report containing the decision aid produced under subsection (a) no later than January 30, 1992. The Secretary shall notify appropriate State and local authorities that such decision aid is available on request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>