<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3051" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3051/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3051/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3051"><akn:num>3051</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3051. Definitions
In this chapter the following definitions apply:(1) AuthorityThe term “Authority” means the Horseracing Integrity and Safety Authority designated by section 3052(a) of this title.


(2) BreederThe term “breeder” means a person who is in the business of breeding covered horses.


(3) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.


(4) Covered horseThe term “covered horse” means any Thoroughbred horse, or any other horse made subject to this chapter by election of the applicable State racing commission or the breed governing organization for such horse under section 3054(k) 11 So in original. Probably should be “section 3054(l)”. of this title, during the period—(A) beginning on the date of the horse’s first timed and reported workout at a racetrack that participates in covered horseraces or at a training facility; and

(B) ending on the date on which the Authority receives written notice that the horse has been retired.


(5) Covered horseraceThe term “covered horserace” means any horserace involving covered horses that has a substantial relation to interstate commerce, including any Thoroughbred horserace that is the subject of interstate off-track or advance deposit wagers.


(6) Covered personsThe term “covered persons” means all trainers, owners, breeders, jockeys, racetracks, veterinarians, persons (legal and natural) licensed by a State racing commission and the agents, assigns, and employees of such persons and other horse support personnel who are engaged in the care, training, or racing of covered horses.


(7) Equine constituenciesThe term “equine constituencies” means, collectively, owners, breeders, trainers, racetracks, veterinarians, State racing commissions, and jockeys who are engaged in the care, training, or racing of covered horses.


(8) Equine industry representativeThe term “equine industry representative” means an organization regularly and significantly engaged in the equine industry, including organiz</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Authority The term “Authority” means the Horseracing Integrity and Safety Authority designated by section 3052(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breeder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Breeder The term “breeder” means a person who is in the business of breeding covered horses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Commission The term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered horse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Covered horse The term “covered horse” means any Thoroughbred horse, or any other horse made subject to this chapter by election of the applicable State racing commission or the breed governing organization for such horse under section 3054(k) 11 So in original. Probably should be “section 3054(l)”. of this title, during the period—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered horserace</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Covered horserace The term “covered horserace” means any horserace involving covered horses that has a substantial relation to interstate commerce, including any Thoroughbred horserace that is the subject of interstate off-track or advance deposit wagers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Covered persons The term “covered persons” means all trainers, owners, breeders, jockeys, racetracks, veterinarians, persons (legal and natural) licensed by a State racing commission and the agents, assigns, and employees of such persons and other horse support personnel who are engaged in the care, training, or racing of covered horses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equine constituencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Equine constituencies The term “equine constituencies” means, collectively, owners, breeders, trainers, racetracks, veterinarians, State racing commissions, and jockeys who are engaged in the care, training, or racing of covered horses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equine industry representative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Equine industry representative The term “equine industry representative” means an organization regularly and significantly engaged in the equine industry, including organizations that represent the interests of, and whose membership consists of, owners, breeders, trainers, racetracks, veterinarians, State racing commissions, and jockeys.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Horseracing anti-doping and medication control program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Horseracing anti-doping and medication control program The term “horseracing anti-doping and medication control program” means the anti-doping and medication program established under section 3055(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3051_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immediate family member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Immediate family member The term “immediate family member” shall include a spouse, domestic partner, mother, father, aunt, uncle, sibling, or child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>