<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3053" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3053/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3053/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3053"><akn:num>3053</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Trade Commission oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3053. Federal Trade Commission oversight(a) In generalThe Authority shall submit to the Commission, in accordance with such rules as the Commission may prescribe under section 553 of title 5, any proposed rule, or proposed modification to a rule, of the Authority relating to—(1) the bylaws of the Authority;

(2) a list of permitted and prohibited medications, substances, and methods, including allowable limits of permitted medications, substances, and methods;

(3) laboratory standards for accreditation and protocols;

(4) standards for racing surface quality maintenance;

(5) racetrack safety standards and protocols;

(6) a program for injury and fatality data analysis;

(7) a program of research and education on safety, performance, and anti-doping and medication control;

(8) a description of safety, performance, and anti-doping and medication control rule violations applicable to covered horses and covered persons;

(9) a schedule of civil sanctions for violations;

(10) a process or procedures for disciplinary hearings; and

(11) a formula or methodology for determining assessments described in section 3052(f) of this title.


(b) Publication and comment(1) In generalThe Commission shall—(A) publish in the Federal Register each proposed rule or modification submitted under subsection (a); and

(B) provide an opportunity for public comment.


(2) Approval requiredA proposed rule, or a proposed modification to a rule, of the Authority shall not take effect unless the proposed rule or modification has been approved by the Commission.



(c) Decision on proposed rule or modification to a rule(1) In generalNot later than 60 days after the date on which a proposed rule or modification is published in the Federal Register, the Commission shall approve or disapprove the proposed rule or modification.


(2) ConditionsThe Commission shall approve a proposed rule or modification if the Commission finds that the proposed rule or modification is consistent with—(A) this c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3053_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Authority shall submit to the Commission, in accordance with such rules as the Commission may prescribe under section 553 of title 5, any proposed rule, or proposed modification to a rule, of the Authority relating to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3053_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publication and comment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3053_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision on proposed rule or modification to a rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Decision on proposed rule or modification to a rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3053_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed standards and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Proposed standards and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3053_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment by Commission of rules of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amendment by Commission of rules of authority The Commission, by rule in accordance with section 553 of title 5, may abrogate, add to, and modify the rules of the Authority promulgated in accordance with this chapter as the Commission finds necessary or appropriate to ensure the fair administration of the Authority, to conform the rules of the Authority to requirements of this chapter and applicable rules approved by the Commission, or otherwise in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>