<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3054" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3054/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3054/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3054"><akn:num>3054</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of the Commission and the Horseracing Integrity and Safety Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3054. Jurisdiction of the Commission and the Horseracing Integrity and Safety Authority(a) In generalBeginning on the program effective date, the Commission, the Authority, and the anti-doping and medication control enforcement agency, each within the scope of their powers and responsibilities under this chapter, as limited by subsection (j),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (k)”. shall—(1) implement and enforce the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program and the racetrack safety program;

(2) exercise independent and exclusive national authority over—(A) the safety, welfare, and integrity of covered horses, covered persons, and covered horseraces; and

(B) all horseracing safety, performance, and anti-doping and medication control matters for covered horses, covered persons, and covered horseraces; and


(3) have safety, performance, and anti-doping and medication control authority over covered persons similar to such authority of the State racing commissions before the program effective date.


(b) PreemptionThe rules of the Authority promulgated in accordance with this chapter shall preempt any provision of State law or regulation with respect to matters within the jurisdiction of the Authority under this chapter, as limited by subsection (j).1 Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.


(c) Duties(1) In generalThe Authority—(A) shall develop uniform procedures and rules authorizing—(i) access to offices, racetrack facilities, other places of business, books, records, and personal property of covered persons that are used in the care, treatment, training, and racing of covered horses;

(ii) issuance and enforcement of subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum; and

(iii) other investigatory powers of the nature and scope exercised by State racing commissions before the program effective date; and


(B) with respect to an unfair or deceptive act or prac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning on the program effective date, the Commission, the Authority, and the anti-doping and medication control enforcement agency, each within the scope of their powers and responsibilities under this chapter, as limited by subsection (j),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (k)”. shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preemption The rules of the Authority promulgated in accordance with this chapter shall preempt any provision of State law or regulation with respect to matters within the jurisdiction of the Authority under this chapter, as limited by subsection (j).1 Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of covered persons with Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Registration of covered persons with Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement of programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures with respect to rules of Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedures with respect to rules of Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Issuance of guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena and investigatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Subpoena and investigatory authority The Authority shall have subpoena and investigatory authority with respect to civil violations committed under its jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Civil penalties The Authority shall develop a list of civil penalties with respect to the enforcement of rules for covered persons and covered horseraces under its jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Civil actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>