<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3055" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3055/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3055/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3055"><akn:num>3055</akn:num><akn:heading>Horseracing anti-doping and medication control program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3055. Horseracing anti-doping and medication control program(a) Program required(1) In generalNot later than the program effective date, and after notice and an opportunity for public comment in accordance with section 3053 of this title, the Authority shall establish a horseracing anti-doping and medication control program applicable to all covered horses, covered persons, and covered horseraces in accordance with the registration of covered persons under section 3054(d) of this title.


(2) Consideration of other breedsIn developing the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program with respect to a breed of horse that is made subject to this chapter by election of a State racing commission or the breed governing organization for such horse under section 3054(k) 11 So in original. Probably should be “section 3054(l)”. of this title, the Authority shall consider the unique characteristics of such breed.



(b) Considerations in development of programIn developing the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program, the Authority shall take into consideration the following:(1) Covered horses should compete only when they are free from the influence of medications, other foreign substances, and methods that affect their performance.

(2) Covered horses that are injured or unsound should not train or participate in covered races, and the use of medications, other foreign substances, and treatment methods that mask or deaden pain in order to allow injured or unsound horses to train or race should be prohibited.

(3) Rules, standards, procedures, and protocols regulating medication and treatment methods for covered horses and covered races should be uniform and uniformly administered nationally.

(4) To the extent consistent with this chapter, consideration should be given to international anti-doping and medication control standards of the International Federation of Horseracing Authorities and the Principles of Veterinary Medical Ethics of the Americ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in development of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Considerations in development of program In developing the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program, the Authority shall take into consideration the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities The following activities shall be carried out under the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition Except as provided in subsections (e) and (f), the horseracing anti-doping and medication control program shall prohibit the administration of any prohibited or otherwise permitted substance to a covered horse within 48 hours of its next racing start, effective as of the program effective date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advisory committee study and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3055_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Baseline anti-doping and medication control rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Baseline anti-doping and medication control rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>