<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3056" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3056/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3056/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3056"><akn:num>3056</akn:num><akn:heading>Racetrack safety program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3056. Racetrack safety program(a) Establishment and considerations(1) In generalNot later than the program effective date, and after notice and an opportunity for public comment in accordance with section 3053 of this title, the Authority shall establish a racetrack safety program applicable to all covered horses, covered persons, and covered horseraces in accordance with the registration of covered persons under section 3054(d) of this title.


(2) Considerations in development of safety programIn the development of the horseracing safety program for covered horses, covered persons, and covered horseraces, the Authority and the Commission shall take into consideration existing safety standards including the National Thoroughbred Racing Association Safety and Integrity Alliance Code of Standards, the International Federation of Horseracing Authority’s International Agreement on Breeding, Racing, and Wagering, and the British Horseracing Authority’s Equine Health and Welfare program.



(b) Elements of horseracing safety programThe horseracing safety program shall include the following:(1) A set of training and racing safety standards and protocols taking into account regional differences and the character of differing racing facilities.

(2) A uniform set of training and racing safety standards and protocols consistent with the humane treatment of covered horses, which may include lists of permitted and prohibited practices or methods (such as crop use).

(3) A racing surface quality maintenance system that—(A) takes into account regional differences and the character of differing racing facilities; and

(B) may include requirements for track surface design and consistency and established standard operating procedures related to track surface, monitoring, and maintenance (such as standardized seasonal assessment, daily tracking, and measurement).


(4) A uniform set of track safety standards and protocols, that may include rules governing oversight and movement of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and considerations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of horseracing safety program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements of horseracing safety program The horseracing safety program shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities The following activities shall be carried out under the racetrack safety program:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>