<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3058" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3058/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3058/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3058"><akn:num>3058</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of final decisions of the Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3058. Review of final decisions of the Authority(a) Notice of civil sanctions If the Authority imposes a final civil sanction for a violation committed by a covered person pursuant to the rules or standards of the Authority, the Authority shall promptly submit to the Commission notice of the civil sanction in such form as the Commission may require.


(b) Review by administrative law judge(1) In generalWith respect to a final civil sanction imposed by the Authority, on application by the Commission or a person aggrieved by the civil sanction filed not later than 30 days after the date on which notice under subsection (a) is submitted, the civil sanction shall be subject to de novo review by an administrative law judge.


(2) Nature of review(A) In generalIn matters reviewed under this subsection, the administrative law judge shall determine whether—(i) a person has engaged in such acts or practices, or has omitted such acts or practices, as the Authority has found the person to have engaged in or omitted;

(ii) such acts, practices, or omissions are in violation of this chapter or the anti-doping and medication control or racetrack safety rules approved by the Commission; or

(iii) the final civil sanction of the Authority was arbitrary, capricious, an abuse of discretion, or otherwise not in accordance with law.


(B) Conduct of hearingAn administrative law judge shall conduct a hearing under this subsection in such a manner as the Commission may specify by rule, which shall conform to section 556 of title 5.



(3) Decision by administrative law judge(A) In generalWith respect to a matter reviewed under this subsection, an administrative law judge—(i) shall render a decision not later than 60 days after the conclusion of the hearing;

(ii) may affirm, reverse, modify, set aside, or remand for further proceedings, in whole or in part, the final civil sanction of the Authority; and

(iii) may make any finding or conclusion that, in the judgment of the administrati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of civil sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice of civil sanctions If the Authority imposes a final civil sanction for a violation committed by a covered person pursuant to the rules or standards of the Authority, the Authority shall promptly submit to the Commission notice of the civil sanction in such form as the Commission may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by administrative law judge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review by administrative law judge</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Stay of proceedings Review by an administrative law judge or the Commission under this section shall not operate as a stay of a final civil sanction of the Authority unless the administrative law judge or Commission orders such a stay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>