<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_311"><akn:num>311</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 311. Omitted
Editorial Notes
Codification
Section, act Oct. 1, 1890, ch. 1266, § 1, 26 Stat. 653, as amended, relating to the establishment of a Weather Bureau in the Department of Commerce, was omitted because the Weather Bureau was consolidated with the Coast and Geodetic Survey to form a new agency in the Department to be known as the Environmental Science Services Administration, and the office of Chief of the Weather Bureau was abolished, by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. July 13, 1965, 30 F.R. 8819, 79 Stat. 1318, set out as a note below. The Reorg. Plan also transferred to the Secretary of Commerce all functions of the Bureau and the Chief of the Bureau.
Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. Oct. 3, 1970, 35 F.R. 15627, 84 Stat. 2090, set out as a note under section 1511 of this title, abolished the Environmental Science Services Administration, including the offices of Administrator and Deputy Administrator, and established the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration within the Department of Commerce. By Department Organization Order 25–5A, republished 39 F.R. 27486, July 29, 1974, the Secretary of Commerce delegated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration a number of functions vested in him, including his functions under this chapter of the Code. By order of the Acting Associate Administrator, 35 F.R. 19249, Dec. 19, 1970, the following organizational names appearing in chapter IX of subtitle B of Title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, relating to the Administration, were changed: Environmental Science Services Administration to National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (ESSA to NOAA); Coast and Geodetic Survey to National Ocean Survey, and Weather Bureau to National Weather Service.
Prior to Oct. 1, 1890, the functions of the Weather Bureau were exercised by the Signal Corps of the Army. Act October 1, 1890, created the present Bureau in the Department of Agriculture. By Reorg. Plan No. IV of 1940, § 8, eff. June 30, 1940, 5 F.R. </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>