<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3152"><akn:num>3152</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3152. Labor standards(a) Equal wages; increase in employmentAny new program enacted and funded pursuant to the implementation of this chapter shall, subject to any limitations on maximum annual compensation as may be provided in the law authorizing such programs, provide that persons employed are paid equal wages for equal work, and that such policies and programs create a net increase in employment through work that would not otherwise be done or are essential to fulfill national priority purposes.


(b) Wage rates; work limitations of reservoir projects employeesAny person employed in any reservoir project enacted and funded pursuant to the implementation of section 3116(c)(1) of this title, or in any other job created pursuant to implementation of this chapter, shall, subject to any limitations on maximum annual compensation as may be provided in the law authorizing such programs, be paid not less than the pay received by others performing the same type of work for the same employer, and in no case less than the minimum wage under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.]. No person employed in any reservoir project enacted and funded pursuant to implementation of section 3116(c)(1) of this title shall perform work of the type to which sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40 apply, except as otherwise may be specifically authorized by law.


(c) Recommendations of PresidentAny recommendation by the President for legislation to implement any program enacted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, requiring the use of funds under this chapter, and submitted pursuant to the requirements of this chapter, shall contain appropriate wage provisions based upon existing wage standard legislation.


(Pub. L. 95–523, title IV, § 402, Oct. 27, 1978, 92 Stat. 1908.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFor definition of “this chapter”, referred to in text, see References in Text note set out under section 3102 of this title.
The Fair Labor Stand</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3152_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal wages; increase in employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Equal wages; increase in employment Any new program enacted and funded pursuant to the implementation of this chapter shall, subject to any limitations on maximum annual compensation as may be provided in the law authorizing such programs, provide that persons employed are paid equal wages for equal work, and that such policies and programs create a net increase in employment through work that would not otherwise be done or are essential to fulfill national priority purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3152_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wage rates; work limitations of reservoir projects employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wage rates; work limitations of reservoir projects employees Any person employed in any reservoir project enacted and funded pursuant to the implementation of section 3116(c)(1) of this title, or in any other job created pursuant to implementation of this chapter, shall, subject to any limitations on maximum annual compensation as may be provided in the law authorizing such programs, be paid not less than the pay received by others performing the same type of work for the same employer, and in no case less than the minimum wage under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.]. No person employed in any reservoir project enacted and funded pursuant to implementation of section 3116(c)(1) of this title shall perform work of the type to which sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40 apply, except as otherwise may be specifically authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3152_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendations of President Any recommendation by the President for legislation to implement any program enacted pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, requiring the use of funds under this chapter, and submitted pursuant to the requirements of this chapter, shall contain appropriate wage provisions based upon existing wage standard legislation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>