<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3363" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3363/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3363/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3363"><akn:num>3363</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency allocation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3363. Emergency allocation authority(a) In generalIn order to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for high-priority uses of natural gas during any natural gas supply emergency declared under section 3361 of this title, the President may, by order, allocate supplies of natural gas under subsections (b), (c), and (d) to—(1) any interstate pipeline;

(2) any local distribution company—(A) which is served by any interstate pipeline;

(B) which is providing natural gas only for high-priority uses; and

(C) which is in need of deliveries of natural gas to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for high-priority uses of natural gas; and


(3) any person for meeting requirements of high-priority uses of natural gas.


(b) Allocation of certain boiler fuel gas(1) Required findingThe President shall not allocate supplies of natural gas under this subsection unless he finds that—(A) to the maximum extent practicable, emergency purchase authority under section 3362 of this title has been utilized to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for high-priority uses of natural gas;

(B) emergency purchases of natural gas supplies under section 3362 of this title are not likely to satisfy the natural gas requirements for such high-priority uses;

(C) the exercise of authority under this subsection is reasonably necessary to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for such high-priority uses; and

(D) any interstate pipeline or local distribution company receiving such natural gas has ordered the termination of all deliveries of natural gas for other than high-priority uses and attempted to to 11 So in original. the maximum extent practicable to terminate such deliveries.


(2) Allocation authoritySubject to paragraph (1), in order to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for high-priority uses of natural gas, the President may, by order, allocate supplies of natural gas the use of which has been prohibited by the President pursuant to authority under section 7</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to assist in meeting natural gas requirements for high-priority uses of natural gas during any natural gas supply emergency declared under section 3361 of this title, the President may, by order, allocate supplies of natural gas under subsections (b), (c), and (d) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of certain boiler fuel gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation of certain boiler fuel gas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of general pipeline supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation of general pipeline supply</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of user-owned gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation of user-owned gas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation No order may be issued under this section unless the President determines that such order will not require transportation of natural gas by any pipeline in excess of its available transportation capacity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Industry assistance The President may request that representatives of pipelines, local distribution companies, and other persons meet and provide assistance to the President in carrying out his authority under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related transportation and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Related transportation and facilities The President may, by order, require any pipeline to transport natural gas, and to construct and operate such facilities for the transportation of natural gas, as he determines necessary to carry out any order under subsection (b), (c), or (d). Compensation for the costs of any construction or transportation ordered under this subsection shall be determined under subsection (g) and shall be paid by the person to whom supplies of natural gas are ordered allocated under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Monitoring In order to effect the purposes of this part, the President shall monitor the operation of any order made pursuant to this section to assure that natural gas delivered pursuant to this section is applied to high-priority uses only.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3363_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Commission study Not later than June 1, 1979, the Commission shall prepare and submit to the Congress a report regarding whether authority to allocate natural gas, which is not otherwise subject to allocation under this part, is likely to be necessary to meet high-priority uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>