<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3364" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3364/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3364/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3364"><akn:num>3364</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3364. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Information(1) Obtaining of informationIn order to obtain information to carry out his authority under this part, the President may—(A) sign and issue subpenas for the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, records, papers, and other documents;

(B) require any person, by general or special order, to submit answers in writing to interrogatories, requests for reports or for other information, and such answers shall be made within such reasonable period, and under oath or otherwise as the President may determine; and

(c) 11 So in original. Probably should be “(C)”. secure, upon request, any information from any Federal agency.


(2) Enforcement of subpenas and ordersThe appropriate United States district court may, upon petition of the Attorney General at the request of the President, in the case of refusal to obey a subpena or order of the President issued under this subsection, issue an order requiring compliance therewith, and any failure to obey an order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof.



(b) Reporting of prices and volumesIn issuing any order under section 3362 or 3363 of this title, the President shall require that the prices and volumes of natural gas delivered, transported, or contracted for pursuant to such order shall be reported to him on a weekly basis. Such reports shall be made available to the Congress.


(c) Presidential reports to CongressThe President shall report to the Congress, not later than 90 days following the termination under section 3361(b) of this title of any declaration of a natural gas supply emergency (or extension thereof) under section 3361(a) of this title, respecting the exercise of authority under section 3361, 3362, 3363 of this title, or this section.


(d) Delegation of authoritiesThe President may delegate all or any portion of the authority granted to him under section 3361, 3362, 3363 of this title, or this section to such Feder</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of prices and volumes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reporting of prices and volumes In issuing any order under section 3362 or 3363 of this title, the President shall require that the prices and volumes of natural gas delivered, transported, or contracted for pursuant to such order shall be reported to him on a weekly basis. Such reports shall be made available to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential reports to Congress The President shall report to the Congress, not later than 90 days following the termination under section 3361(b) of this title of any declaration of a natural gas supply emergency (or extension thereof) under section 3361(a) of this title, respecting the exercise of authority under section 3361, 3362, 3363 of this title, or this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delegation of authorities The President may delegate all or any portion of the authority granted to him under section 3361, 3362, 3363 of this title, or this section to such Federal officers or agencies as he determines appropriate, and may authorize such redelegation as may be appropriate. Except with respect to section 552 of title 5, any Federal officer or agency to which authority is delegated or redelegated under this subsection shall be subject only to such procedural requirements respecting the exercise of such authority as the President would be subject to if such authority were not so delegated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Antitrust protections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on certain contractual obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on certain contractual obligations There shall be available as a defense to any action brought for breach of contract under Federal or State Law arising out of any act or omission that such act was taken or that such omission occurred for purposes of complying with any order issued under section 3363 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3364_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preemption Any order issued pursuant to this subchapter shall preempt any provision of any program for the allocation, emergency delivery, transportation, or purchase of natural gas established by any State or local government if such program is in conflict with any such order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>