<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3412"><akn:num>3412</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3412. Administrative procedure(a) Administrative Procedure ActSubject to subsection (b), the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 shall apply to any rule or order issued under this chapter having the applicability and effect of a rule as defined in section 551(4) of title 5; except that sections 554, 556, and 557 of such title 5 shall not apply to any order under such section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title.


(b) Opportunity for oral presentationsTo the maximum extent practicable, an opportunity for oral presentation of data, views, and arguments shall be afforded with respect to any proposed rule or order described in subsection (a) (other than an order under section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title). To the maximum extent practicable, such opportunity shall be afforded before the effective date of such rule or order. Such opportunity shall be afforded no later than 30 days after such date in the case of a waiver of the entire comment period under section 553(d)(3) of title 5, and no later than 45 days after such date in all other cases. A transcript shall be made of any such oral presentation.


(c) AdjustmentsThe Commission or any other Federal officer or agency authorized to issue rules or orders described in subsection (a) (other than an order under section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title) shall, by rule, provide for the making of such adjustments, consistent with the other purposes of this chapter, as may be necessary to prevent special hardship, inequity, or an unfair distribution of burdens. Such rule shall establish procedures which are available to any person for the purpose of seeking an interpretation, modification, or rescission of, exception to, or exemption from, such applicable rules or orders. If any person is aggrieved or adversely affected by the denial of a request for adjustment under the preceding sentence, such person may request a review of such denial by the officer or agency and may obtain judicial review in accordanc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Procedure Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative Procedure Act Subject to subsection (b), the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 shall apply to any rule or order issued under this chapter having the applicability and effect of a rule as defined in section 551(4) of title 5; except that sections 554, 556, and 557 of such title 5 shall not apply to any order under such section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for oral presentations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Opportunity for oral presentations To the maximum extent practicable, an opportunity for oral presentation of data, views, and arguments shall be afforded with respect to any proposed rule or order described in subsection (a) (other than an order under section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title). To the maximum extent practicable, such opportunity shall be afforded before the effective date of such rule or order. Such opportunity shall be afforded no later than 30 days after such date in the case of a waiver of the entire comment period under section 553(d)(3) of title 5, and no later than 45 days after such date in all other cases. A transcript shall be made of any such oral presentation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments The Commission or any other Federal officer or agency authorized to issue rules or orders described in subsection (a) (other than an order under section 3361, 3362, or 3363 of this title) shall, by rule, provide for the making of such adjustments, consistent with the other purposes of this chapter, as may be necessary to prevent special hardship, inequity, or an unfair distribution of burdens. Such rule shall establish procedures which are available to any person for the purpose of seeking an interpretation, modification, or rescission of, exception to, or exemption from, such applicable rules or orders. If any person is aggrieved or adversely affected by the denial of a request for adjustment under the preceding sentence, such person may request a review of such denial by the officer or agency and may obtain judicial review in accordance with section 3416 of this title when such denial becomes final. The officer or agency shall, by rule, establish procedures, including</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>