<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3416"><akn:num>3416</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3416. Judicial review(a) Orders(1) In generalThe provisions of this subsection shall apply to judicial review of any order, within the meaning of section 551(6) of title 5 (other than an order assessing a civil penalty under section 3414(b)(4) of this title or any order under section 3362 of this title or any order under section 3363 of this title), issued under this chapter and to any final agency action under this chapter required to be made on the record after an opportunity for an agency hearing.


(2) RehearingAny person aggrieved by any order issued by the Commission in a proceeding under this chapter to which such person is a party may apply for a rehearing within 30 days after the issuance of such order. Any application for rehearing shall set forth the specific ground upon which such application is based. Upon the filing of such application, the Commission may grant or deny the requested rehearing or modify the original order without further hearing. Unless the Commission acts upon such application for rehearing within 30 days after it is filed, such application shall be deemed to have been denied. No person may bring an action under this section to obtain judicial review of any order of the Commission unless—(A) such person shall have made application to the Commission for rehearing under this subsection; and

(B) the Commission shall have finally acted with respect to such application.


For purposes of this section, if the Commission fails to act within 30 days after the filing of such application, such failure to act shall be deemed final agency action with respect to such application.

(3) Authority to modify ordersAt any time before the filing of the record of a proceeding in a United States Court of Appeals, pursuant to paragraph (4), the Commission may, after providing notice it determines reasonable and proper, modify or set aside, in whole or in part, any order issued under the provisions of this chapter.


(4) Judicial reviewAny person who is a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of rules and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review of rules and orders Except as provided in subsections (a) and (c), judicial review of any rule or order, within the meaning of section 551(4) of title 5, issued under this chapter may be obtained in the United States Court of Appeals for any appropriate circuit pursuant to the provisions of chapter 7 of title 5, except that the second sentence of section 705 thereof shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of emergency orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Judicial review of emergency orders Except with respect to enforcement of orders or subpenas under section 3364(a) of this title, the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have exclusive original jurisdiction to review all civil cases and controversies under section 3361, 3362 or 3363 of this title, including any order issued, or other action taken, under such section. The United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction of all appeals from the district courts of the United States in cases and controversies arising under section 3364(a)(2) of this title; such appeals shall be taken by the filing of a notice of appeal with the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit within thirty days after the entry of judgment by the district court. Prior to a final judgment, no court shall have jurisdiction to grant any injunctive relief to stay or defer the implementation of any order issued, or action taken, under sec</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>