<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3608" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3608/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3608/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3608"><akn:num>3608</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial determinations respecting uncon­scionable leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3608. Judicial determinations respecting uncon­scionable leases(a) Lease characteristics; authorization by unit owners; conditions precedent to actionCooperative and condominium unit owners through the unit owners’ association may bring an action seeking a judicial determination that a lease or leases, or portions thereof, were unconscionable at the time they were made. An action may be brought under this section if each such lease has all of the following characteristics:(1) it was made in connection with a cooperative or condominium project;

(2) it was entered into while the cooperative or condominium owners’ association was controlled by the developer either through special developer control or because the developer held a majority of the votes in the owners’ association;

(3) it had to be accepted or ratified by purchasers or through the unit owners’ association as a condition of purchase of a unit in the cooperative or condominium project;

(4) it is for a period of more than twenty-one years or is for a period of less than twenty-one years but contains automatic renewal provisions for a period of more than twenty-one years;

(5) it contains an automatic rent increase clause; and

(6) it was entered into prior to June 4, 1975.


Such action must be authorized by the cooperative or condominium unit owners through a vote of not less than two-thirds of the owners of the units other than units owned by the developer or an affiliate of the developer, and may be brought by the cooperative or condominium unit owners through the units owners’ association. Prior to instituting such action, the cooperative or condominium unit owners must, through a vote of not less than two-thirds of the owners of the units other than units owned by the developer or an affiliate of the developer, agree to enter into negotiation with the lessor and must seek through such negotiation to eliminate or modify any lease terms that are alleged to be unconscionable; if an agreement is not rea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease characteristics; authorization by unit owners; conditions precedent to action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lease characteristics; authorization by unit owners; conditions precedent to action Cooperative and condominium unit owners through the unit owners’ association may bring an action seeking a judicial determination that a lease or leases, or portions thereof, were unconscionable at the time they were made. An action may be brought under this section if each such lease has all of the following characteristics: Such action must be authorized by the cooperative or condominium unit owners through a vote of not less than two-thirds of the owners of the units other than units owned by the developer or an affiliate of the developer, and may be brought by the cooperative or condominium unit owners through the units owners’ association. Prior to instituting such action, the cooperative or condominium unit owners must, through a vote of not less than two-thirds of the owners of the units other than units owned by the developer or an affiliate of the developer, agree to enter into negotiation </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption of unconscionability; rebuttal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presumption of unconscionability; rebuttal A rebuttal presumption of unconscionability exists if it is established that, in addition to the characteristics set forth in subsection (a) of this section, the lease— Once the rebuttable presumption is established, the court, in making its finding, shall consider the lease or portion of the lease to be unconscionable unless proven otherwise by the preponderance of the evidence to the contrary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presentation of evidence after finding of uncon­scionability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presentation of evidence after finding of uncon­scionability Whenever it is claimed, or appears to the court, that a lease or any portion thereof is, or may have been, unconscionable at the time it was made, the parties shall be afforded a reasonable opportunity to present evidence at least as to–</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedial relief; matters considered; attorneys’ fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Remedial relief; matters considered; attorneys’ fees Upon finding that any lease, or portion thereof, is unconscionable, the court shall exercise its authority to grant remedial relief as necessary to avoid an unconscionable result, taking into consideration the economic value of the lease. Such relief may include, but shall not be limited to rescission, reformation, restitution, the award of damages and reasonable attorney fees and court costs. A defendant may recover reasonable attorneys’ fees if the court determines that the cause of action filed by the plantiff 11 So in original. Probably should be “plaintiff”. is frivolous, malicious, or lacking in substantial merit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions allowed after termination of special developer control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Actions allowed after termination of special developer control Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the bringing of an action by cooperative and condominium unit owners’ association, seeking a judicial determination that a lease or leases, or portions thereof, are unconscionable, where such unit owners or a unit owners’ association representing them has, after the termination of special developer control, reached an agreement with a holder of such lease or leases which either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>