<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/37" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/37/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/37/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_37"><akn:num>37</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 37. Immunity from antitrust laws(a) Inapplicability of antitrust lawsExcept as provided in subsection (d), the antitrust laws, and any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, shall not apply to charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts.


(b) ImmunityExcept as provided in subsection (d), any person subjected to any legal proceeding for damages, injunction, penalties, or other relief of any kind under the antitrust laws, or any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, on account of setting or agreeing to rates of return or other terms for, negotiating, issuing, participating in, implementing, or otherwise being involved in the planning, issuance, or payment of charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts shall have immunity from suit under the antitrust laws, including the right not to bear the cost, burden, and risk of discovery and trial, for the conduct set forth in this subsection.


(c) Treatment of certain annuities and trustsAny annuity treated as a charitable gift annuity, or any trust treated as a charitable remainder trust, either—(1) in any filing by the donor with the Internal Revenue Service; or

(2) in any schedule, form, or written document provided by or on behalf of the donee to the donor;


shall be conclusively presumed for the purposes of this section and section 37a of this title to be respectively a charitable gift annuity or a charitable remainder trust, unless there has been a final determination by the Internal Revenue Service that, for fraud or otherwise, the donor’s annuity or trust did not qualify respectively as a charitable gift annuity or charitable remainder trust when created.

(d) LimitationSubsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to the enforcement of a State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, with respect to charitable gift annuities, or charitable remainder trusts, created after the State enacts a statute, not later than December 8, 1998, that expressly provides that s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inapplicability of antitrust laws Except as provided in subsection (d), the antitrust laws, and any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, shall not apply to charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Immunity Except as provided in subsection (d), any person subjected to any legal proceeding for damages, injunction, penalties, or other relief of any kind under the antitrust laws, or any State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, on account of setting or agreeing to rates of return or other terms for, negotiating, issuing, participating in, implementing, or otherwise being involved in the planning, issuance, or payment of charitable gift annuities or charitable remainder trusts shall have immunity from suit under the antitrust laws, including the right not to bear the cost, burden, and risk of discovery and trial, for the conduct set forth in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain annuities and trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of certain annuities and trusts Any annuity treated as a charitable gift annuity, or any trust treated as a charitable remainder trust, either— shall be conclusively presumed for the purposes of this section and section 37a of this title to be respectively a charitable gift annuity or a charitable remainder trust, unless there has been a final determination by the Internal Revenue Service that, for fraud or otherwise, the donor’s annuity or trust did not qualify respectively as a charitable gift annuity or charitable remainder trust when created.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_37_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to the enforcement of a State law similar to any of the antitrust laws, with respect to charitable gift annuities, or charitable remainder trusts, created after the State enacts a statute, not later than December 8, 1998, that expressly provides that subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to such charitable gift annuities and such charitable remainder trusts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>