<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3704b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3704b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3704b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3704b"><akn:num>3704b</akn:num><akn:heading>National Technical Information Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3704b. National Technical Information Service(a) Powers(1) The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Technical Information Service (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) is authorized to do the following:(A) Enter into such contracts, cooperative agreements, joint ventures, and other transactions, in accordance with all relevant provisions of Federal law applicable to such contracts and agreements, and under reasonable terms and conditions, as may be necessary in the conduct of the business of the National Technical Information Service (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Service”).

(B) In addition to the authority regarding fees contained in section 2 of the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the dissemination of technological, scientific, and engineering information to American business and industry, and for other purposes” enacted September 9, 1950 (15 U.S.C. 1152), retain and, subject to appropriations Acts, utilize its net revenues to the extent necessary to implement the plan submitted under subsection (f)(3)(D).

(C) Enter into contracts for the performance of part or all of the functions performed by the Promotion Division of the Service prior to October 24, 1988. The details of any such contract, and a statement of its effect on the operations and personnel of the Service, shall be provided to the appropriate committees of the Congress 30 days in advance of the execution of such contract.

(D) Employ such personnel as may be necessary to conduct the business of the Service.

(E) For the period of October 1, 1991 through September 30, 1992, only, retain and use all earned and unearned monies heretofore or hereafter received, including receipts, revenues, and advanced payments and deposits, to fund all obligations and expenses, including inventories and capital equipment.


An increase or decrease in the personnel of the Service shall not affect or be affected by any ceilings on the number or grade</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of the Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director of the Service The management of the Service shall be vested in a Director who shall report to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Secretary of Commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advisory Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Audits The Secretary of Commerce shall provide for annual independent audits of the Service’s financial statements beginning with fiscal year 1988, to be conducted in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Functions The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Service, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification of Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>