<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3707"><akn:num>3707</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Foundation Cooperative Research Centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3707. National Science Foundation Cooperative Research Centers(a) Establishment and provisionsThe National Science Foundation shall provide assistance for the establishment of Cooperative Research Centers. Such Centers shall be affiliated with a university, or other nonprofit institution, or a group thereof. The objective of the Centers is to enhance technological innovation as provided in section 3705(a) of this title through the conduct of activities as provided in section 3705(b) of this title.


(b) Planning grantsThe National Science Foundation is authorized to make available nonrenewable planning grants to universities or nonprofit institutions for the purpose of developing the plan, as described under section 3705(c)(3) of this title.


(c) Terms and conditionsGrants, contracts, and cooperative agreements entered into by the National Science Foundation in execution of the powers and duties of the National Science Foundation under this chapter shall be governed by the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 [42 U.S.C. 1861 et seq.] and other pertinent Acts.


(Pub. L. 96–480, § 9, formerly § 8, Oct. 21, 1980, 94 Stat. 2316; Pub. L. 99–502, § 9(b)(11), (12), (e)(2)(B), Oct. 20, 1986, 100 Stat. 1796, 1797; renumbered § 9, Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5122(a)(1), Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1438; Pub. L. 106–404, § 7(4), Nov. 1, 2000, 114 Stat. 1745.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe National Science Foundation Act of 1950, referred to in subsec. (c), is act May 10, 1950, ch. 171, 64 Stat. 149, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1861 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1861 of Title 42 and Tables.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 9 of Pub. L. 96–480 was renumbered section 10 and is classified to section 3708 of this title.

Amendments2000—Subsecs. (a), (b). Pub. L. 106–404 made technical amendments to references in original act which a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and provisions The National Science Foundation shall provide assistance for the establishment of Cooperative Research Centers. Such Centers shall be affiliated with a university, or other nonprofit institution, or a group thereof. The objective of the Centers is to enhance technological innovation as provided in section 3705(a) of this title through the conduct of activities as provided in section 3705(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning grants The National Science Foundation is authorized to make available nonrenewable planning grants to universities or nonprofit institutions for the purpose of developing the plan, as described under section 3705(c)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3707_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements entered into by the National Science Foundation in execution of the powers and duties of the National Science Foundation under this chapter shall be governed by the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 [42 U.S.C. 1861 et seq.] and other pertinent Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>