<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3710"><akn:num>3710</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of Federal technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3710. Utilization of Federal technology(a) Policy(1) It is the continuing responsibility of the Federal Government to ensure the full use of the results of the Nation’s Federal investment in research and development. To this end the Federal Government shall strive where appropriate to transfer federally owned or originated technology to State and local governments and to the private sector.

(2) Technology transfer, consistent with mission responsibilities, is a responsibility of each laboratory science and engineering professional.

(3) Each laboratory director shall ensure that efforts to transfer technology are considered positively in laboratory job descriptions, employee promotion policies, and evaluation of the job performance of scientists and engineers in the laboratory.


(b) Establishment of Research and Technology Applications OfficesEach Federal laboratory shall establish an Office of Research and technology Applications. Laboratories having existing organizational structures which perform the functions of this section may elect to combine the Office of Research and Technology Applications within the existing organization. The staffing and funding levels for these offices shall be determined between each Federal laboratory and the Federal agency operating or directing the laboratory, except that (1) each laboratory having 200 or more full-time equivalent scientific, engineering, and related technical positions shall provide one or more full-time equivalent positions as staff for its Office of Research and Technology Applications, and (2) each Federal agency which operates or directs one or more Federal laboratories shall make available sufficient funding, either as a separate line item or from the agency’s research and development budget, to support the technology transfer function at the agency and at its laboratories, including support of the Offices of Research and Technology Applications. Furthermore, individuals filling positions in an Office of R</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Research and Technology Applications Offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Research and Technology Applications Offices Each Federal laboratory shall establish an Office of Research and technology Applications. Laboratories having existing organizational structures which perform the functions of this section may elect to combine the Office of Research and Technology Applications within the existing organization. The staffing and funding levels for these offices shall be determined between each Federal laboratory and the Federal agency operating or directing the laboratory, except that (1) each laboratory having 200 or more full-time equivalent scientific, engineering, and related technical positions shall provide one or more full-time equivalent positions as staff for its Office of Research and Technology Applications, and (2) each Federal agency which operates or directs one or more Federal laboratories shall make available sufficient funding, either as a separate line item or from the agency’s research and development budget, to support</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Research and Technology Applications Offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of Research and Technology Applications Offices It shall be the function of each Office of Research and Technology Applications— Agencies which have established organizational structures outside their Federal laboratories which have as their principal purpose the transfer of federally owned or originated technology to State and local government and to the private sector may elect to perform the functions of this subsection in such organizational structures. No Office of Research and Technology Applications or other organizational structures performing the functions of this subsection shall substantially compete with similar services available in the private sector.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of technical information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dissemination of technical information The National Technical Information Service shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Federal Laboratory Consortium for Technology Transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of Federal Laboratory Consortium for Technology Transfer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency reports on utilization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agency reports on utilization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Functions of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duplication of reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Duplication of reporting The reporting obligations imposed by this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Research equipment The Director of a laboratory, or the head of any Federal agency or department, may loan, lease, or give research equipment that is excess to the needs of the laboratory, agency, or department to an educational institution or nonprofit organization for the conduct of technical and scientific education and research activities. Title of ownership shall transfer with a gift under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>