<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3721"><akn:num>3721</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal loan guarantees for innovative technologies in manufacturing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3721. Federal loan guarantees for innovative technologies in manufacturing(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program to provide loan guarantees for obligations to small- or medium-sized manufacturers for the use or production of innovative technologies.


(b) Eligible projectsA loan guarantee may be made under the program only for a project that re-equips, expands, or establishes a manufacturing facility in the United States—(1) to use an innovative technology or an innovative process in manufacturing;

(2) to manufacture an innovative technology product or an integral component of such a product; or

(3) to commercialize an innovative product, process, or idea that was developed by research funded in whole or in part by a grant from the Federal government.


(c) Eligible borrowerA loan guarantee may be made under the program only for a borrower who is a small- or medium-sized manufacturer, as determined by the Secretary under the criteria established pursuant to subsection (l).


(d) Limitation on amountA loan guarantee shall not exceed an amount equal to 80 percent of the obligation, as estimated at the time at which the loan guarantee is issued.


(e) Limitations on loan guaranteeNo loan guarantee shall be made unless the Secretary determines that—(1) there is a reasonable prospect of repayment of the principal and interest on the obligation by the borrower;

(2) the amount of the obligation (when combined with amounts available to the borrower from other sources) is sufficient to carry out the project;

(3) the obligation is not subordinate to other financing;

(4) the obligation bears interest at a rate that does not exceed a level that the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into account the prevailing rate of interest in the private sector for similar loans and risks; and

(5) the term of an obligation requires full repayment over a period not to exceed the lesser of—(A) 30 years; or

(B) 90 percent of the projected useful life, as determ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program to provide loan guarantees for obligations to small- or medium-sized manufacturers for the use or production of innovative technologies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible projects A loan guarantee may be made under the program only for a project that re-equips, expands, or establishes a manufacturing facility in the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible borrower</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible borrower A loan guarantee may be made under the program only for a borrower who is a small- or medium-sized manufacturer, as determined by the Secretary under the criteria established pursuant to subsection (l).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on amount A loan guarantee shall not exceed an amount equal to 80 percent of the obligation, as estimated at the time at which the loan guarantee is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on loan guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on loan guarantee No loan guarantee shall be made unless the Secretary determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defaults</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Defaults</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Terms and conditions A loan guarantee under this section shall include such detailed terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consultation In establishing the terms and conditions of a loan guarantee under this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>