<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3722b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3722b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/3722b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3722b"><akn:num>3722b</akn:num><akn:heading>Distressed area Recompete Pilot Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3722b. Distressed area Recompete Pilot Program(a) In generalWithin the program authorized under section 3722a of this title, the Secretary is authorized to establish a pilot program, to be known as the “Recompete Pilot Program”, to provide grants to eligible recipients representing eligible areas or Tribal lands to alleviate persistent economic distress and support long-term comprehensive economic development and job creation in eligible areas.


(b) Strategy development grants and cooperative agreementsSubject to available appropriations, the Secretary is authorized, on the application of an eligible recipient, to award up to one half of the number of grants under subsection (e) of section 3722a of this title to eligible recipients to develop a recompete plan and carry out related predevelopment activities.


(c) Strategy implementation grants and cooperative agreementsSubject to available appropriations and subsection (f), the Secretary shall award, on the application of an eligible recipient, at least ten strategy implementation grants, in accordance with a recompete plan review and approved by the Secretary, to carry out coordinated and comprehensive economic development programs and activities in an eligible area, consistent with a recompete plan approved by the Secretary. Such activities may include—(1) workforce development activities of the kind described in section 3722a(f) of this title or other job training and workforce outreach programs oriented to local employer needs, such as—(A) customized job training programs carried out by local community colleges and other training or educational organizations in partnership with local businesses;

(B) workforce outreach programs located in, and targeted to, lower-income and underemployed neighborhoods; and

(C) programs to embed job placement and training services in neighborhood institutions such as churches, housing projects, and community advocacy programs; and

(D) job retention programs and activities, su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Within the program authorized under section 3722a of this title, the Secretary is authorized to establish a pilot program, to be known as the “Recompete Pilot Program”, to provide grants to eligible recipients representing eligible areas or Tribal lands to alleviate persistent economic distress and support long-term comprehensive economic development and job creation in eligible areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy development grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Strategy development grants and cooperative agreements Subject to available appropriations, the Secretary is authorized, on the application of an eligible recipient, to award up to one half of the number of grants under subsection (e) of section 3722a of this title to eligible recipients to develop a recompete plan and carry out related predevelopment activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy implementation grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Strategy implementation grants and cooperative agreements Subject to available appropriations and subsection (f), the Secretary shall award, on the application of an eligible recipient, at least ten strategy implementation grants, in accordance with a recompete plan review and approved by the Secretary, to carry out coordinated and comprehensive economic development programs and activities in an eligible area, consistent with a recompete plan approved by the Secretary. Such activities may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Award amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications To be considered for a grant or cooperative agreement under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to certain grant awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relation to certain grant awards The Secretary shall not require an eligible recipient to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under subsection (b) in order to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $1,000,000,000 to award grants and cooperative agreements under subsection (c) of this section, for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3722b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>