<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/375" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/375/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/375/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_375"><akn:num>375</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 375. Definitions
As used in this chapter, the following definitions apply:(1) Attorney generalThe term “attorney general”, with respect to a State, means the attorney general or other chief law enforcement officer of the State.


(2) Cigarette(A) In generalThe term “cigarette”—(i) has the meaning given that term in section 2341 of title 18; and

(ii) includes—(I) roll-your-own tobacco (as defined in section 5702 of title 26); and

(II) an electronic nicotine delivery system.



(B) ExceptionThe term “cigarette” does not include a cigar (as defined in section 5702 of title 26).



(3) Common carrierThe term “common carrier” means any person (other than a local messenger service or the United States Postal Service) that holds itself out to the general public as a provider for hire of the transportation by water, land, or air of merchandise (regardless of whether the person actually operates the vessel, vehicle, or aircraft by which the transportation is provided) between a port or place and a port or place in the United States.


(4) ConsumerThe term “consumer”—(A) means any person that purchases cigarettes or smokeless tobacco; and

(B) does not include any person lawfully operating as a manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, or retailer of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco.


(5) Delivery saleThe term “delivery sale” means any sale of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco to a consumer if—(A) the consumer submits the order for the sale by means of a telephone or other method of voice transmission, the mails, or the Internet or other online service, or the seller is otherwise not in the physical presence of the buyer when the request for purchase or order is made; or

(B) the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco are delivered to the buyer by common carrier, private delivery service, or other method of remote delivery, or the seller is not in the physical presence of the buyer when the buyer obtains possession of the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco.


(6) Delivery sellerThe term</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Attorney general The term “attorney general”, with respect to a State, means the attorney general or other chief law enforcement officer of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cigarette</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Common carrier The term “common carrier” means any person (other than a local messenger service or the United States Postal Service) that holds itself out to the general public as a provider for hire of the transportation by water, land, or air of merchandise (regardless of whether the person actually operates the vessel, vehicle, or aircraft by which the transportation is provided) between a port or place and a port or place in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Consumer The term “consumer”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Delivery sale The term “delivery sale” means any sale of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco to a consumer if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery seller</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Delivery seller The term “delivery seller” means a person who makes a delivery sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic nicotine delivery system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Electronic nicotine delivery system The term “electronic nicotine delivery system”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Indian country The term “Indian country”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe”, “tribe”, or “tribal” refers to an Indian tribe as defined in section 5304(e) of title 25 or as listed pursuant to section 5131 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Interstate commerce</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>