<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/376a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/376a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/376a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_376a"><akn:num>376a</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 376a. Delivery sales(a) In generalWith respect to delivery sales into a specific State and place, each delivery seller shall comply with—(1) the shipping requirements set forth in subsection (b);

(2) the recordkeeping requirements set forth in subsection (c);

(3) all State, local, tribal, and other laws generally applicable to sales of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco as if the delivery sales occurred entirely within the specific State and place, including laws imposing—(A) excise taxes;

(B) licensing and tax-stamping requirements;

(C) restrictions on sales to minors; and

(D) other payment obligations or legal requirements relating to the sale, distribution, or delivery of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco; and


(4) the tax collection requirements set forth in subsection (d).


(b) Shipping and packaging(1) Required statementFor any shipping package containing cigarettes or smokeless tobacco, the delivery seller shall include on the bill of lading, if any, and on the outside of the shipping package, on the same surface as the delivery address, a clear and conspicuous statement providing as follows: “CIGARETTES/NICOTINE/SMOKELESS TOBACCO: FEDERAL LAW REQUIRES THE PAYMENT OF ALL APPLICABLE EXCISE TAXES, AND COMPLIANCE WITH APPLICABLE LICENSING AND TAX-STAMPING OBLIGATIONS”.


(2) Failure to labelAny shipping package described in paragraph (1) that is not labeled in accordance with that paragraph shall be treated as nondeliverable matter by a common carrier or other delivery service, if the common carrier or other delivery service knows or should know the package contains cigarettes or smokeless tobacco. If a common carrier or other delivery service believes a package is being submitted for delivery in violation of paragraph (1), it may require the person submitting the package for delivery to establish that it is not being sent in violation of paragraph (1) before accepting the package for delivery. Nothing in this paragraph shall require the common carrier or ot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general With respect to delivery sales into a specific State and place, each delivery seller shall comply with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shipping and packaging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Shipping and packaging</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delivery</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of unregistered or noncompliant delivery sellers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) List of unregistered or noncompliant delivery sellers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_376a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Presumption For purposes of this chapter, a delivery sale shall be deemed to have occurred in the State and place where the buyer obtains personal possession of the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco, and a delivery pursuant to a delivery sale is deemed to have been initiated or ordered by the delivery seller.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>