<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4015" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4015/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4015/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4015"><akn:num>4015</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review; admissibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4015. Judicial review; admissibility(a) District court review of grants or denials; erroneous determinationIf the Secretary grants or denies, in whole or in part, an application for a certificate of review or for an amendment to a certificate, or revokes or modifies a certificate pursuant to section 4014(b) of this title, any person aggrieved by such determination may, within 30 days of the determination, bring an action in any appropriate district court of the United States to set aside the determination on the ground that such determination is erroneous.


(b) Exclusive provision for reviewExcept as provided in subsection (a), no action by the Secretary or the Attorney General pursuant to this subchapter shall be subject to judicial review.


(c) Inadmissibility in antitrust proceedingsIf the Secretary denies, in whole or in part, an application for a certificate of review or for an amendment to a certificate, or revokes or amends a certificate, neither the negative determination nor the statement of reasons therefor shall be admissible in evidence, in any administrative or judicial proceeding, in support of any claim under the antitrust laws.


(Pub. L. 97–290, title III, § 305, Oct. 8, 1982, 96 Stat. 1243.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 8, 1982, see section 312 of Pub. L. 97–290, set out as a note under section 4011 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4015_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>District court review of grants or denials; erroneous determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) District court review of grants or denials; erroneous determination If the Secretary grants or denies, in whole or in part, an application for a certificate of review or for an amendment to a certificate, or revokes or modifies a certificate pursuant to section 4014(b) of this title, any person aggrieved by such determination may, within 30 days of the determination, bring an action in any appropriate district court of the United States to set aside the determination on the ground that such determination is erroneous.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4015_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive provision for review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exclusive provision for review Except as provided in subsection (a), no action by the Secretary or the Attorney General pursuant to this subchapter shall be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4015_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inadmissibility in antitrust proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inadmissibility in antitrust proceedings If the Secretary denies, in whole or in part, an application for a certificate of review or for an amendment to a certificate, or revokes or amends a certificate, neither the negative determination nor the statement of reasons therefor shall be admissible in evidence, in any administrative or judicial proceeding, in support of any claim under the antitrust laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>