<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4112"><akn:num>4112</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual agency budget and spending report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4112. Annual agency budget and spending report(1) Annual agency budgetsEach agency represented on the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee shall each include in their agency’s annual budget request to Congress a description of their agency’s projected Arctic research activities and associated budget for the fiscal year covered by the budget request.


(2) Report to CongressBeginning with fiscal year 2025 and annually thereafter until fiscal year 2034, not later than 60 days after the President’s budget request for such fiscal year is submitted to Congress, the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit an annual report to Congress summarizing each agency’s budget request related to Arctic research activities per the information submitted in accordance with paragraph (1).


(Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LIX, § 5912(b), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3442.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023, and not as part of the Arctic Research and Policy Act of 1984 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4112_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual agency budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Annual agency budgets Each agency represented on the Interagency Arctic Research Policy Committee shall each include in their agency’s annual budget request to Congress a description of their agency’s projected Arctic research activities and associated budget for the fiscal year covered by the budget request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4112_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Report to Congress Beginning with fiscal year 2025 and annually thereafter until fiscal year 2034, not later than 60 days after the President’s budget request for such fiscal year is submitted to Congress, the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall submit an annual report to Congress summarizing each agency’s budget request related to Arctic research activities per the information submitted in accordance with paragraph (1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>