<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4406" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4406/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4406/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4406"><akn:num>4406</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4406. Preemption(a) Federal actionExcept as provided in the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), no statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by section 4402 of this title, shall be required by any Federal agency to appear on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.


(b) State and local actionNo statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by section 4402 of this title, shall be required by any State or local statute or regulation to be included on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.


(c) Effect on liability lawNothing in this chapter shall relieve any person from liability at common law or under State statutory law to any other person.


(Pub. L. 99–252, § 7, Feb. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 34; Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title II, § 205(b), June 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1849.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is div. A of Pub. L. 111–31, June 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1776. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2009 Amendment note set out under section 301 of Title 21, Food and Drugs, and Tables.

Amendments2009—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 111–31 substituted “Except as provided in the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), no” for “No”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4406_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal action Except as provided in the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act (and the amendments made by that Act), no statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by section 4402 of this title, shall be required by any Federal agency to appear on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4406_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State and local action No statement relating to the use of smokeless tobacco products and health, other than the statements required by section 4402 of this title, shall be required by any State or local statute or regulation to be included on any package or in any advertisement (unless the advertisement is an outdoor billboard advertisement) of a smokeless tobacco product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4406_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on liability law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect on liability law Nothing in this chapter shall relieve any person from liability at common law or under State statutory law to any other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>