<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45"><akn:num>45</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfair methods of competition unlawful; prevention by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45. Unfair methods of competition unlawful; prevention by Commission(a) Declaration of unlawfulness; power to prohibit unfair practices; inapplicability to foreign trade(1) Unfair methods of competition in or affecting commerce, and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce, are hereby declared unlawful.

(2) The Commission is hereby empowered and directed to prevent persons, partnerships, or corporations, except banks, savings and loan institutions described in section 57a(f)(3) of this title, Federal credit unions described in section 57a(f)(4) of this title, common carriers subject to the Acts to regulate commerce, air carriers and foreign air carriers subject to part A of subtitle VII of title 49, and persons, partnerships, or corporations insofar as they are subject to the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, as amended [7 U.S.C. 181 et seq.], except as provided in section 406(b) of said Act [7 U.S.C. 227(b)], from using unfair methods of competition in or affecting commerce and unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce.

(3) This subsection shall not apply to unfair methods of competition involving commerce with foreign nations (other than import commerce) unless—(A) such methods of competition have a direct, substantial, and reasonably foreseeable effect—(i) on commerce which is not commerce with foreign nations, or on import commerce with foreign nations; or

(ii) on export commerce with foreign nations, of a person engaged in such commerce in the United States; and


(B) such effect gives rise to a claim under the provisions of this subsection, other than this paragraph.


If this subsection applies to such methods of competition only because of the operation of subparagraph (A)(ii), this subsection shall apply to such conduct only for injury to export business in the United States.

(4)(A) For purposes of subsection (a), the term “unfair or deceptive acts or practices” includes such acts or practices involving forei</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of unlawfulness; power to prohibit unfair practices; inapplicability to foreign trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Declaration of unlawfulness; power to prohibit unfair practices; inapplicability to foreign trade</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeding by Commission; modifying and setting aside orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proceeding by Commission; modifying and setting aside orders Whenever the Commission shall have reason to believe that any such person, partnership, or corporation has been or is using any unfair method of competition or unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce, and if it shall appear to the Commission that a proceeding by it in respect thereof would be to the interest of the public, it shall issue and serve upon such person, partnership, or corporation a complaint stating its charges in that respect and containing a notice of a hearing upon a day and at a place therein fixed at least thirty days after the service of said complaint. The person, partnership, or corporation so complained of shall have the right to appear at the place and time so fixed and show cause why an order should not be entered by the Commission requiring such person, partnership, or corporation to cease and desist from the violation of the law so charged in said complaint. Any person, partn</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of order; rehearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of order; rehearing Any person, partnership, or corporation required by an order of the Commission to cease and desist from using any method of competition or act or practice may obtain a review of such order in the court of appeals of the United States, within any circuit where the method of competition or the act or practice in question was used or where such person, partnership, or corporation resides or carries on business, by filing in the court, within sixty days from the date of the service of such order, a written petition praying that the order of the Commission be set aside. A copy of such petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Commission, and thereupon the Commission shall file in the court the record in the proceeding, as provided in section 2112 of title 28. Upon such filing of the petition the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein concurrently with the Commission until the filing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Jurisdiction of court Upon the filing of the record with it the jurisdiction of the court of appeals of the United States to affirm, enforce, modify, or set aside orders of the Commission shall be exclusive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption from liability No order of the Commission or judgement of court to enforce the same shall in anywise relieve or absolve any person, partnership, or corporation from any liability under the Antitrust Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of complaints, orders and other processes; return</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Service of complaints, orders and other processes; return Complaints, orders, and other processes of the Commission under this section may be served by anyone duly authorized by the Commission, either (a) by delivering a copy thereof to the person to be served, or to a member of the partnership to be served, or the president, secretary, or other executive officer or a director of the corporation to be served; or (b) by leaving a copy thereof at the residence or the principal office or place of business of such person, partnership, or corporation; or (c) by mailing a copy thereof by registered mail or by certified mail addressed to such person, partnership, or corporation at his or its residence or principal office or place of business. The verified return by the person so serving said complaint, order, or other process setting forth the manner of said service shall be proof of the same, and the return post office receipt for said complaint, order, or other process mailed by registe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Finality of order An order of the Commission to cease and desist shall become final—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification or setting aside of order by Supreme Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Modification or setting aside of order by Supreme Court If the Supreme Court directs that the order of the Commission be modified or set aside, the order of the Commission rendered in accordance with the mandate of the Supreme Court shall become final upon the expiration of thirty days from the time it was rendered, unless within such thirty days either party has instituted proceedings to have such order corrected to accord with the mandate, in which event the order of the Commission shall become final when so corrected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification or setting aside of order by Court of Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Modification or setting aside of order by Court of Appeals If the order of the Commission is modified or set aside by the court of appeals, and if (1) the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired and no such petition has been duly filed, or (2) the petition for certiorari has been denied, or (3) the decision of the court has been affirmed by the Supreme Court, then the order of the Commission rendered in accordance with the mandate of the court of appeals shall become final on the expiration of thirty days from the time such order of the Commission was rendered, unless within such thirty days either party has instituted proceedings to have such order corrected so that it will accord with the mandate, in which event the order of the Commission shall become final when so corrected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehearing upon order or remand</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rehearing upon order or remand If the Supreme Court orders a rehearing; or if the case is remanded by the court of appeals to the Commission for a rehearing, and if (1) the time allowed for filing a petition for certiorari has expired, and no such petition has been duly filed, or (2) the petition for certiorari has been denied, or (3) the decision of the court has been affirmed by the Supreme Court, then the order of the Commission rendered upon such rehearing shall become final in the same manner as though no prior order of the Commission had been rendered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>