<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45b"><akn:num>45b</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer review protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45b. Consumer review protection(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.


(2) Covered communicationThe term “covered communication” means a written, oral, or pictorial review, performance assessment of, or other similar analysis of, including by electronic means, the goods, services, or conduct of a person by an individual who is party to a form contract with respect to which such person is also a party.


(3) Form contract(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “form contract” means a contract with standardized terms—(i) used by a person in the course of selling or leasing the person’s goods or services; and

(ii) imposed on an individual without a meaningful opportunity for such individual to negotiate the standardized terms.


(B) ExceptionThe term “form contract” does not include an employer-employee or independent contractor contract.



(4) PictorialThe term “pictorial” includes pictures, photographs, video, illustrations, and symbols.



(b) Invalidity of contracts that impede consumer reviews(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a provision of a form contract is void from the inception of such contract if such provision—(A) prohibits or restricts the ability of an individual who is a party to the form contract to engage in a covered communication;

(B) imposes a penalty or fee against an individual who is a party to the form contract for engaging in a covered communication; or

(C) transfers or requires an individual who is a party to the form contract to transfer to any person any intellectual property rights in review or feedback content, with the exception of a non-exclusive license to use the content, that the individual may have in any otherwise lawful covered communication about such person or the goods or services provided by such person.


(2) Rule of constructionNothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to affect—(A) any duty of confidentia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Invalidity of contracts that impede consumer reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Invalidity of contracts that impede consumer reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition It shall be unlawful for a person to offer a form contract containing a provision described as void in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement by States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach for businesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Education and outreach for businesses Not later than 60 days after December 14, 2016, the Commission shall commence conducting education and outreach that provides businesses with non-binding best practices for compliance with this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to State causes of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relation to State causes of action Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any cause of action brought by a person that exists or may exist under State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Savings provision Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit, impair, or supersede the operation of the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.] or any other provision of Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effective dates This section shall take effect on December 14, 2016, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>