<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/45f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45f"><akn:num>45f</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection, verification, and disclosure of information by online marketplaces to inform consumers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45f. Collection, verification, and disclosure of information by online marketplaces to inform consumers(a) Collection and verification of information(1) Collection(A) In generalAn online marketplace shall require any high-volume third party seller on such online marketplace’s platform to provide, not later than 10 days after qualifying as a high-volume third party seller on the platform, the following information to the online marketplace:(i) Bank account(I) In generalA bank account number, or, if such seller does not have a bank account, the name of the payee for payments issued by the online marketplace to such seller.


(II) Provision of informationThe bank account or payee information required under subclause (I) may be provided by the seller in the following ways:(aa) To the online marketplace.

(bb) To a payment processor or other third party contracted by the online marketplace to maintain such information, provided that the online marketplace ensures that it can obtain such information within 3 business days from such payment processor or other third party.



(ii) Contact informationContact information for such seller as follows:(I) With respect to a high-volume third party seller that is an individual, the individual’s name.

(II) With respect to a high-volume third party seller that is not an individual, one of the following forms of contact information:(aa) A copy of a valid government-issued identification for an individual acting on behalf of such seller that includes the individual’s name.

(bb) A copy of a valid government-issued record or tax document that includes the business name and physical address of such seller.



(iii) Tax IDA business tax identification number, or, if such seller does not have a business tax identification number, a taxpayer identification number.


(iv) Working email and phone numberA current working email address and phone number for such seller.



(B) Notification of change; annual certificationAn online marketplace </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and verification of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Collection and verification of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by State attorneys general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement by State attorneys general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Severability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Severability If any provision of this section, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of this section and the application of such provision to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected by the invalidation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relationship to State laws No State or political subdivision of a State, or territory of the United States, may establish or continue in effect any law, regulation, rule, requirement, or standard that conflicts with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date This section shall take effect 180 days after December 29, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>