<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4602"><akn:num>4602</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to Sematech</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4602. Grants to Sematech(a) Authority to make grantsThe Secretary of Defense shall make grants, in accordance with section 6304 of title 31, to Sematech in order to defray expenses incurred by Sematech in conducting research on and development of semiconductor manufacturing technology. The grants shall be made in accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (b).


(b) Memorandum of understandingThe Secretary of Defense shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with Sematech for the purposes of this subchapter. The memorandum of understanding shall require the following:(1) That Sematech have—(A) a charter agreed to by all representatives of the semiconductor industry that are participating members of Sematech; and

(B) an annual operating plan that is developed in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Semiconductor Technology Council.


(2) That the total amount of funds made available to Sematech by Federal, State, and local government agencies for any fiscal year for the support of research and development activities of Sematech under this section may not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of such activities.

(3) That Sematech, in conducting research and development activities pursuant to the memorandum of understanding, cooperate with and draw on the expertise of the national laboratories of the Department of Energy and of colleges and universities in the United States in the field of semiconductor manufacturing technology.

(4) That an independent, commercial auditor be retained (A) to determine the extent to which the funds made available to Sematech by the United States for the research and development activities of Sematech have been expended in a manner that is consistent with the purposes of this subchapter, the charter of Sematech, and the annual operating plan of Sematech, and (B) to submit to the Secretary of Defense, Sematech, and the Comptroller General of the United States an annual report containin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to make grants The Secretary of Defense shall make grants, in accordance with section 6304 of title 31, to Sematech in order to defray expenses incurred by Sematech in conducting research on and development of semiconductor manufacturing technology. The grants shall be made in accordance with a memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Memorandum of understanding The Secretary of Defense shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with Sematech for the purposes of this subchapter. The memorandum of understanding shall require the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of memorandum of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Construction of memorandum of understanding The memorandum of understanding entered into under subsection (b) shall not be considered to be a contract for the purpose of any law or regulation relating to the formation, content, and administration of contracts awarded by the Federal Government and subcontracts under such contracts, including chapter 271 of title 10, section 719 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. App. 2168),11 See References in Text note below. and the Federal Acquisition Regulations, and such provisions of law and regulation shall not apply with respect to the memorandum of understanding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for FY88</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding for FY88 Of the amounts appropriated to the Defense Agencies for fiscal year 1988 for research, development, test, and evaluation, $100,000,000 may be obligated only to make grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>