<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4632"><akn:num>4632</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiconductor research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4632. Semiconductor research and development(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “National Advisory Committee on Semiconductor Research and Development Act of 1988”.


(b) Findings and purposes(1) The Congress finds and declares that—(A) semiconductor technology is playing an ever-increasing role in United States industrial and commercial products and processes, making secure domestic sources of state-of-the-art semiconductors highly desirable;

(B) modern weapons systems are highly dependent on leading edge semiconductor devices, and it is counter to the national security interest to be heavily dependent upon foreign sources for this technology;

(C) governmental responsibilities related to the semiconductor industry are divided among many Federal departments and agencies; and

(D) joint industry-government consideration of semiconductor industry problems is needed at this time.


(2) The purposes of this section are—(A) to establish the National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors; and

(B) to assign to such Committee the responsibility for devising and promulgating a national semiconductor strategy, including research and development, the implementation of which will assure the continued leadership of the United States in semiconductor technology.



(c) Creation of CommitteeThere is hereby created in the executive branch of the Government an independent advisory body to be known as the National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committee”).


(d) Functions(1) The Committee shall—(A) collect and analyze information on the needs and capabilities of industry, the Federal Government, and the scientific and research communities related to semiconductor technology;

(B) identify the components of a successful national semiconductor strategy in accordance with subsection (b)(2)(B);

(C) analyze options, establish priorities, and recommend roles for participants in the national strategy;

(D) assess the rol</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “National Advisory Committee on Semiconductor Research and Development Act of 1988”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings and purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Creation of Committee There is hereby created in the executive branch of the Government an independent advisory body to be known as the National Advisory Committee on Semiconductors (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Membership and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the purposes of this section such sums as may be necessary for the fiscal years 1988, 1989, 1990, 1991, 1992, and 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>