<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4652" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4652/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4652/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4652"><akn:num>4652</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiconductor incentives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4652. Semiconductor incentives(a) Financial assistance program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish in the Department of Commerce a program that, in accordance with the requirements of this section and subject to the availability of appropriations for such purposes, provides Federal financial assistance to covered entities to incentivize investment in facilities and equipment in the United States for the fabrication, assembly, testing, advanced packaging, production, or research and development of semiconductors, materials used to manufacture semiconductors, or semiconductor manufacturing equipment.


(2) Procedure(A) In generalA covered entity shall submit to the Secretary an application that describes the project for which the covered entity is seeking financial assistance under this section.


(B) EligibilityIn order for a covered entity to qualify for financial assistance under this section, the covered entity shall demonstrate to the Secretary, in the application submitted by the covered entity under subparagraph (A), that—(i) the covered entity has a documented interest in constructing, expanding, or modernizing a facility described in paragraph (1) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a semicolon.

(ii) with respect to the project described in clause (i), the covered entity has—(I) been offered a covered incentive;

(II) made commitments to worker and community investment, including through—(aa) training and education benefits paid by the covered entity; and

(bb) programs to expand employment opportunity for economically disadvantaged individuals; and


(III) secured commitments from regional educational and training entities and institutions of higher education to provide workforce training, including programming for training and job placement of economically disadvantaged individuals;

(IV) an executable plan to sustain the facility described in clause (i) without additional Federal financial assistance under this subsection for facili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Financial assistance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination required In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Energy, and the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) GAO reviews The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that, in carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary should allocate funds in a manner that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional assistance for mature technology nodes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional assistance for mature technology nodes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction projects Section 3212 of title 42 shall apply to a construction project that receives financial assistance from the Secretary under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans and loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Loans and loan guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority relating to environmental review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authority relating to environmental review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Oversight Not later than 4 years after disbursement of the first financial award under subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Commerce shall audit the program under this section to assess—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4652_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Prohibition on use of funds No funds made available under this section may be used to construct, modify, or improve a facility outside of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>