<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4728" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4728/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4728/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4728"><akn:num>4728</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental trade promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4728. Environmental trade promotion(a) Statement of policyIt is the policy of the United States to foster the export of United States environmental technologies, goods, and services. In exercising their powers and functions, all appropriate departments and agencies of the United States Government shall encourage and support sales of such technologies, goods, and services.


(b) Environmental Trade Working Group of Trade Promotion Coordination Committee(1) Establishment and purposeThe President shall establish the Environmental Trade Promotion Working Group (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Working Group”) as a subcommittee of the Trade Promotion Coordination Committee (hereafter in this section referred to as the “TPCC”), established under section 4727 of this title. The purpose of the Working Group shall be—(A) to address all issues with respect to the export promotion and export financing of United States environmental technologies, goods, and services; and

(B) to develop a strategy for expanding United States exports of environmental technologies, goods, and services.


(2) MembershipThe members of the Working Group shall be—(A) representatives of the departments and agencies that are represented on the TPCC, who are designated by the head of their respective departments or agencies to advise the head of such department or agency on ways of promoting the export of United States environmental technologies, goods, and services; and

(B) a representative of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(3) ChairpersonThe Secretary of Commerce (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall designate the chairperson of the Working Group from among senior employees of the Department of Commerce. The chairperson shall—(A) assess the effectiveness of United States Government programs for the promotion of exports of environmental technologies, goods, and services;

(B) recommend improvements to such programs, including regulatory changes or addi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Statement of policy It is the policy of the United States to foster the export of United States environmental technologies, goods, and services. In exercising their powers and functions, all appropriate departments and agencies of the United States Government shall encourage and support sales of such technologies, goods, and services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Trade Working Group of Trade Promotion Coordination Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Environmental Trade Working Group of Trade Promotion Coordination Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Technologies Trade Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental Technologies Trade Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Export plans for priority countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Export plans for priority countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Trade information In support of the work of the Working Group, the Secretary shall, as part of the regular market survey and information services activities of the Department of Commerce, make available—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental technologies specialists in United States and Foreign Commercial Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Environmental technologies specialists in United States and Foreign Commercial Service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental training in one-stop shops</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental training in one-stop shops In addition to the training provided under subsection (f)(2)(C), the Secretary shall establish a mechanism to train— in environmental technologies and in the international environmental marketplace, and ensure that such officers receive appropriate training under such mechanism. Such training may be provided by officers or employees of the Department of Commerce, and other United States Government departments and agencies, with appropriate expertise in environmental technologies and the international environmental workplace, and by appropriate representatives of the private sector.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>International regional environmental initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) International regional environmental initiatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental technologies project advocacy calendar and information dissemination program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Environmental technologies project advocacy calendar and information dissemination program The Working Group shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4728_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental technology export alliances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Environmental technology export alliances Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Secretary is authorized to use the Market Development Cooperator Program to support the creation on a regional basis of alliances of private sector entities, nonprofit organizations, and universities, that support the export of environmental technologies, goods, and services and promote the export of products complying with United States environmental, safety, and related requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>