<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/4804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4804"><akn:num>4804</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4804. Membership(a) Composition and representation(1) The Council shall consist of 12 members, of whom—(A) four members shall be appointed by the President, of whom—(i) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in business;

(ii) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in the labor community;

(iii) one shall be a national leader who has been active in public interest activities; and

(iv) one shall be a head of a Federal department or agency;


(B) four members shall be appointed by the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate, acting jointly, of whom—(i) one shall be a national leader with experience or background in business;

(ii) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in the labor community;

(iii) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in the academic community; and

(iv) one shall be a representative of State or local government; and


(C) four members shall be appointed by the Speaker, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, acting jointly, of whom—(i) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in business;

(ii) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in the labor community;

(iii) one shall be a national leader with experience and background in the academic community; and

(iv) one shall be a representative of State or local government.



(2) In addition to the head of a Federal department or agency appointed in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(A)(iv), other Federal officials may participate on an ex-officio basis as requested by the Council.

(3) All members of the Council shall be individuals who have a broad understanding of the United States economy and the United States competitive position internationally.

(4) Not more than 6 members of the Council shall be members of the same political party.


(b) Initial appointmentsThe initial members of the Council shall be appointed within 30 days after </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Composition and representation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial appointments The initial members of the Council shall be appointed within 30 days after August 20, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removal Members of the Council may be removed only for malfeasance in office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conflict of interest A member of the Council shall not serve as an agent for a foreign principal or a lobbyist for a foreign entity (as the terms “lobbyist” and “foreign entity” are defined under section 1602 of title 2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expenses Each member of the Council, while engaged in duties as a member of the Council, shall be paid actual travel expenses, and per diem in lieu of subsistence expenses when away from the usual place of residence of such member, in accordance with subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Quorum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Chairperson The Council shall elect, by a two-thirds vote of the entire Council, a chairperson from among the nongovernmental members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Meetings The Council shall meet at the call of the chairperson or a majority of the members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4804_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Policy actions Except as provided in subsection (g), no action establishing policy shall be taken by the Council unless approved by two-thirds of the entire membership of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>