<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5103"><akn:num>5103</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of scientific research and development program to develop competitive manufacturing te</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5103. Establishment of scientific research and development program to develop competitive manufacturing technologies and increase energy efficiency in steel and aluminum industries(a) General authorityThe Secretary, pursuant to the authority provided under provisions of the Federal Nonnuclear Research and Development Act of 1974 (42 U.S.C. 5901, et seq.), shall reestablish an industrial energy conservation and competitive technology program to conduct scientific research and development of steel and aluminum technologies to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such program shall provide the financial and technical assistance and other incentives which, in the judgment of the Secretary, are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Management planWithin 6 months after November 17, 1988, the Secretary shall publish an update of the management plan to expand the steel research and development initiative to include aluminum and to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The Secretary, from time to time, may further update the management plan. The management plan shall be subject to the following conditions:(1) For newly initiated research and development proposals submitted under the revised management plan, the non-Federal financial share shall equal at least 30 percent of the total cost of any project.

(2) Existing facilities, equipment, supplies, and other property may be included in the non-Federal share under this section only when they are directly relevant to the project.

(3) The knowledge resulting from research and development activities conducted under this chapter shall be developed for the benefit of the domestic companies who provide financial resources to the program.

(4) The Secretary, for a period of up to 5 years after the development of information that—(A) results from research and development activities conducted under this chapter; and

(B) would be a trade secret or commercial or financial information that is privileged or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority The Secretary, pursuant to the authority provided under provisions of the Federal Nonnuclear Research and Development Act of 1974 (42 U.S.C. 5901, et seq.), shall reestablish an industrial energy conservation and competitive technology program to conduct scientific research and development of steel and aluminum technologies to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Such program shall provide the financial and technical assistance and other incentives which, in the judgment of the Secretary, are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management plan Within 6 months after November 17, 1988, the Secretary shall publish an update of the management plan to expand the steel research and development initiative to include aluminum and to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The Secretary, from time to time, may further update the management plan. The management plan shall be subject to the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priorities Within 6 months after November 17, 1988, the Secretary shall publish an update of the research plan. In reviewing research and development activities for possible inclusion in the research plan, the Secretary shall consider the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry participation and review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Industry participation and review The Secretary shall arrange for participation and review by representatives of each affected industry and by labor in the updating of the management and research plans and in the evaluation of the progress of research and development activities for their industry conducted under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>