<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5107" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5107/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5107/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5107"><akn:num>5107</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5107. Reports
The Secretary shall prepare and submit annually to the President and the Congress at the close of each fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2008, a complete report of the research and development activities carried out under this chapter during the fiscal year involved, including the actual and anticipated obligation of funds, for such activities, together with such recommendations as the Secretary may consider appropriate for further legislative, administrative, and other actions, including actions by the American steel, aluminum, copper, and other metals industries, which should be taken in order to achieve the purposes of this chapter. The report submitted at the close of fiscal year 1991 shall also contain a complete summary of activities under the management plan and the research plan from the first year of their operation, along with an analysis of the extent to which they have succeeded in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter. The reports submitted at the close of fiscal years 1993, 1995, and 1997 shall also contain a complete summary of activities under the management plan and the research plan from the first year of their operation, along with an analysis of the extent to which they have succeeded in accomplishing the purposes of this chapter.
(Pub. L. 100–680, § 8, Nov. 17, 1988, 102 Stat. 4076; Pub. L. 102–486, title XXI, § 2106(a)(2), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3070; Pub. L. 110–229, title VI, § 602(c)(2), May 8, 2008, 122 Stat. 853.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2008—Pub. L. 110–229 inserted “, beginning with fiscal year 2008,” after “close of each fiscal year”.
1992—Pub. L. 102–486 inserted sentence at end relating to reports submitted at the close of fiscal years 1993, 1995, and 1997.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Reporting RequirementsFor termination, effective May 15, 2000, of provisions in this section relating to submitting annual report to Congress, see section 3003 of Pub. L. 104–66, as amended, se</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>