<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/52" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/52/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/52/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_52"><akn:num>52</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of false advertisements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 52. Dissemination of false advertisements(a) UnlawfulnessIt shall be unlawful for any person, partnership, or corporation to disseminate, or cause to be disseminated, any false advertisement—(1) By United States mails, or in or having an effect upon commerce, by any means, for the purpose of inducing, or which is likely to induce, directly or indirectly the purchase of food, drugs, devices, services, or cosmetics; or

(2) By any means, for the purpose of inducing, or which is likely to induce, directly or indirectly, the purchase in or having an effect upon commerce, of food, drugs, devices, services, or cosmetics.


(b) Unfair or deceptive act or practiceThe dissemination or the causing to be disseminated of any false advertisement within the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be an unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce within the meaning of section 45 of this title.


(Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, § 12, as added Mar. 21, 1938, ch. 49, § 4, 52 Stat. 114; amended Pub. L. 93–637, title II, § 201(c), Jan. 4, 1975, 88 Stat. 2193; Pub. L. 103–297, § 8, Aug. 16, 1994, 108 Stat. 1550.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–297 inserted “services,” after “devices,” in pars. (1) and (2).
1975—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 93–637 substituted “in or having an effect upon commerce,” for “in commerce”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 93–637 substituted “in or affecting commerce” for “in commerce”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Information About Scams Related to COVID–19Pub. L. 116–287, § 2, Jan. 5, 2021, 134 Stat. 4882, provided that:
“(a) Dissemination of Information.—“(1) In general.—As expeditiously as possible after the date of the enactment of this Act [Jan. 5, 2021], the Commission, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Postmaster General, the Chief Postal Inspector, and the Internet Crime Complaint Center, shall develop and disseminate information to the public about scam</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_52_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawfulness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unlawfulness It shall be unlawful for any person, partnership, or corporation to disseminate, or cause to be disseminated, any false advertisement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_52_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfair or deceptive act or practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unfair or deceptive act or practice The dissemination or the causing to be disseminated of any false advertisement within the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be an unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce within the meaning of section 45 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>