<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5209" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5209/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5209/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5209"><akn:num>5209</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5209. Technology transfer(a) PromotionIn pursuance of the goals of this chapter, all Federal departments and agencies shall conduct technology transfer activities as appropriate to the overall mission of each department or agency to—(1) complement basic superconductivity research by promoting the rapid development of manufacturing and processing technologies necessary for the commercialization of high-temperature superconductors; and

(2) promote collaborative arrangements and consortia of industry (which shall include small business) in order to lower the barriers to deployment of advanced high-temperature superconductor technology; such consortia to also include, as appropriate, universities and independent research organizations.


(b) Impediments to commercializationThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, shall identify those Federal policies and regulations which impede the ability of the private sector to undertake long-term investment programs to commercialize superconductivity applications.


(Pub. L. 100–697, § 10, Nov. 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 4616.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5209_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promotion In pursuance of the goals of this chapter, all Federal departments and agencies shall conduct technology transfer activities as appropriate to the overall mission of each department or agency to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5209_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impediments to commercialization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Impediments to commercialization The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, shall identify those Federal policies and regulations which impede the ability of the private sector to undertake long-term investment programs to commercialize superconductivity applications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>