<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5305"><akn:num>5305</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5305. Review(a) Evaluation of research activitiesThe Secretary shall regularly monitor and evaluate the research activities of the applicants selected. After considering the reports of the Board provided for in section 5306(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall determine whether each applicant selected has complied with the management plan submitted in the original proposal and any modifications made since.


(b) Annual reportEach selected applicant in the program shall provide an annual report to the Secretary that explains the progress made, compliance with the management plan, whether changes are needed and are being made to the management plan, and what new research is planned.


(c) Discontinuation of fundingIn the event a selected applicant has substantially failed in the implementation of the management plan and research activities, the Secretary shall discontinue funding.


(d) Solicitation of new proposalsUpon completion or discontinuance of any research activity authorized in section 5304 of this title, the Secretary shall, using available funds appropriated pursuant to this chapter, solicit new research proposals as set forth under the terms of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 101–425, § 6, Oct. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 918.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluation of research activities The Secretary shall regularly monitor and evaluate the research activities of the applicants selected. After considering the reports of the Board provided for in section 5306(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall determine whether each applicant selected has complied with the management plan submitted in the original proposal and any modifications made since.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual report Each selected applicant in the program shall provide an annual report to the Secretary that explains the progress made, compliance with the management plan, whether changes are needed and are being made to the management plan, and what new research is planned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discontinuation of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discontinuation of funding In the event a selected applicant has substantially failed in the implementation of the management plan and research activities, the Secretary shall discontinue funding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of new proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Solicitation of new proposals Upon completion or discontinuance of any research activity authorized in section 5304 of this title, the Secretary shall, using available funds appropriated pursuant to this chapter, solicit new research proposals as set forth under the terms of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>