<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5306"><akn:num>5306</akn:num><akn:heading>Industrial Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5306. Industrial Advisory Board(a) Establishment of BoardWithin 120 days after October 15, 1990, the Secretary, after consulting with representatives of trade and technical associations of the metal casting industry, shall establish an Industrial Advisory Board (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Board”) to provide guidance and oversight in implementing the selection criteria and operation of the program. The Board shall be composed of nine members who are selected by the Secretary, a majority of whom shall be individuals from the metal casting industry or individuals affiliated with the industry. At least one member of the Board shall be chosen from each of the four census regions of the country. Each Board member shall serve for a term not to exceed five years, but may be reappointed for successive terms.


(b) Review and recommendations(1) Within 180 days after October 15, 1990, and annually thereafter, the Board shall develop from the general research areas identified in section 5304(d) of this title and submit to the Secretary a list of Metal Casting Research Priorities. Such list shall, to the greatest extent possible, identify specific areas of research that would be considered of a priority nature to the United States metal casting industry.

(2) On an annual basis the Board shall—(A) review the Secretary’s solicitation and selection of research proposals and make recommendations as to how each such activity can be altered so as to better achieve the purposes of this chapter; and

(B) review the research activities of each selected applicant, and the selected applicant’s management plan, and report its findings and recommendations to the Secretary.



(Pub. L. 101–425, § 7, Oct. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 918.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Advisory BoardsAdvisory boards established after Jan. 5, 1973, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Board Within 120 days after October 15, 1990, the Secretary, after consulting with representatives of trade and technical associations of the metal casting industry, shall establish an Industrial Advisory Board (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Board”) to provide guidance and oversight in implementing the selection criteria and operation of the program. The Board shall be composed of nine members who are selected by the Secretary, a majority of whom shall be individuals from the metal casting industry or individuals affiliated with the industry. At least one member of the Board shall be chosen from each of the four census regions of the country. Each Board member shall serve for a term not to exceed five years, but may be reappointed for successive terms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review and recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>