<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/5308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5308"><akn:num>5308</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of proprietary rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5308. Protection of proprietary rights(a) Proprietary rightsNo trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, under the meaning of section 552(b)(4) of title 5, which is obtained from a company as a result of activities under this chapter shall be disclosed.


(b) Commercial informationThe Secretary, for a period of up to 5 years after the development of information that—(1) results from research and development activities conducted under this chapter; and

(2) would be a trade secret or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, under the meaning of section 552(b)(4) of title 5, if the information had been obtained from a company,


may provide appropriate protection against the dissemination of such information, including exemption from subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.

(c) Patent rightsWith respect to patent rights, the Institutes shall be treated in the same manner as are nonprofit organizations and small business firms under chapter 18 of title 35, notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary contained in that chapter.


(Pub. L. 101–425, § 9, Oct. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 919.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proprietary rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proprietary rights No trade secrets or commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential, under the meaning of section 552(b)(4) of title 5, which is obtained from a company as a result of activities under this chapter shall be disclosed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commercial information The Secretary, for a period of up to 5 years after the development of information that— may provide appropriate protection against the dissemination of such information, including exemption from subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patent rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Patent rights With respect to patent rights, the Institutes shall be treated in the same manner as are nonprofit organizations and small business firms under chapter 18 of title 35, notwithstanding any provisions to the contrary contained in that chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>