<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–2a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–2a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–2a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_57b_2a"><akn:num>57b–2a</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality and delayed notice of compulsory process for certain third parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 57b–2a. Confidentiality and delayed notice of compulsory process for certain third parties(a) Application with other lawsThe Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) and chapter 121 of title 18 shall apply with respect to the Commission, except as otherwise provided in this section.


(b) Procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosureThe procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosure under the Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) and chapter 121 of title 18, including procedures for extensions of such delays or prohibitions, shall be available to the Commission, provided that, notwithstanding any provision therein—(1) a court may issue an order delaying notification or prohibiting disclosure (including extending such an order) in accordance with the procedures of section 1109 of the Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3409) (if notification would otherwise be required under that Act), or section 2705 of title 18 (if notification would otherwise be required under chapter 121 of that title), if the presiding judge or magistrate judge finds that there is reason to believe that such notification or disclosure may cause an adverse result as defined in subsection (g) of this section; and

(2) if notification would otherwise be required under chapter 121 of title 18, the Commission may delay notification (including extending such a delay) upon the execution of a written certification in accordance with the procedures of section 2705 of that title if the Commission finds that there is reason to believe that notification may cause an adverse result as defined in subsection (g) of this section.


(c) Ex parte application by Commission(1) In generalIf neither notification nor delayed notification by the Commission is required under the Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) or chapter 121 of title 18, the Commission may apply ex parte to a presiding judge or magistrate judge for an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application with other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application with other laws The Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) and chapter 121 of title 18 shall apply with respect to the Commission, except as otherwise provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosure The procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosure under the Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) and chapter 121 of title 18, including procedures for extensions of such delays or prohibitions, shall be available to the Commission, provided that, notwithstanding any provision therein—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte application by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ex parte application by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No liability for failure to notify</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No liability for failure to notify If neither notification nor delayed notification by the Commission is required under the Right to Financial Privacy Act (12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.) or chapter 121 of title 18, the recipient of compulsory process issued by the Commission under this subchapter shall not be liable under any law or regulation of the United States, or under the constitution, or any law or regulation, of any State, political subdivision of a State, territory of the United States, or the District of Columbia, or under any contract or other legally enforceable agreement, for failure to provide notice to any person that such process has been issued or that the recipient has provided information in response to such process. The preceding sentence does not exempt any recipient from liability for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue and procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Venue and procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section not to apply to antitrust investigations or proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Section not to apply to antitrust investigations or proceedings This section shall not apply to an investigation or proceeding related to the administration of Federal antitrust laws or foreign antitrust laws (as defined in paragraphs (5) and (7), respectively, of section 6211 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_2a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adverse result defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adverse result defined For purposes of this section the term “adverse result” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>