<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/57b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_57b_1"><akn:num>57b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil investigative demands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 57b–1. Civil investigative demands(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The terms “civil investigative demand” and “demand” mean any demand issued by the commission under subsection (c)(1).

(2) The term “Commission investigation” means any inquiry conducted by a Commission investigator for the purpose of ascertaining whether any person is or has been engaged in any unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce (within the meaning of section 45(a)(1) of this title) or in any antitrust violations.

(3) The term “Commission investigator” means any attorney or investigator employed by the Commission who is charged with the duty of enforcing or carrying into effect any provisions relating to unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce (within the meaning of section 45(a)(1) of this title) or any provisions relating to antitrust violations.

(4) The term “custodian” means the custodian or any deputy custodian designated under section 57b–2(b)(2)(A) of this title.

(5) The term “documentary material” includes the original or any copy of any book, record, report, memorandum, paper, communication, tabulation, chart, or other document.

(6) The term “person” means any natural person, partnership, corporation, association, or other legal entity, including any person acting under color or authority of State law.

(7) The term “violation” means any act or omission constituting an unfair or deceptive act or practice in or affecting commerce (within the meaning of section 45(a)(1) of this title) or any antitrust violation.

(8) The term “antitrust violation” means—(A) any unfair method of competition (within the meaning of section 45(a)(1) of this title);

(B) any violation of the Clayton Act [15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.] or of any other Federal statute that prohibits, or makes available to the Commission a civil remedy with respect to, any restraint upon or monopolization of interstate or foreign trade or commerce;

(C) with respect to th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions conducted by Commission respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Actions conducted by Commission respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce For the purpose of investigations performed pursuant to this section with respect to unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce (within the meaning of section 45(a)(1) of this title); all actions of the Commission taken under section 46 and section 49 of this title shall be conducted pursuant to subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of demand; contents; service; verified return; sworn certificate; answers; taking of oral testimony</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of demand; contents; service; verified return; sworn certificate; answers; taking of oral testimony</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for demand material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedures for demand material Materials received as a result of a civil investigative demand shall be subject to the procedures established in section 57b–2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Petition for enforcement Whenever any person fails to comply with any civil investigative demand duly served upon him under this section, or whenever satisfactory copying or reproduction of material requested pursuant to the demand cannot be accomplished and such person refuses to surrender such material, the Commission, through such officers or attorneys as it may designate, may file, in the district court of the United States for any judicial district in which such person resides, is found, or transacts business, and serve upon such person, a petition for an order of such court for the enforcement of this section. All process of any court to which application may be made as provided in this subsection may be served in any judicial district.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for order modifying or setting aside demand</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Petition for order modifying or setting aside demand</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Custodial control of documentary material, tangible things, reports, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Custodial control of documentary material, tangible things, reports, etc. At any time during which any custodian is in custody or control of any documentary material, tangible things, reports, answers to questions, or transcripts of oral testimony given by any person in compliance with any civil investigative demand, such person may file, in the district court of the United States for the judicial district within which the office of such custodian is situated, and serve upon such custodian, a petition for an order of such court requiring the performance by such custodian of any duty imposed upon him by this section or section 57b–2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Jurisdiction of court Whenever any petition is filed in any district court of the United States under this section, such court shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine the matter so presented, and to enter such order or orders as may be required to carry into effect the provisions of this section. Any final order so entered shall be subject to appeal pursuant to section 1291 of title 28. Any disobedience of any final order entered under this section by any court shall be punished as a contempt of such court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission authority to issue subpoenas or make demand for information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Commission authority to issue subpoenas or make demand for information Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commission shall have no authority to issue a subpoena or make a demand for information, under authority of this subchapter or any other provision of law, unless such subpoena or demand for information is signed by a Commissioner acting pursuant to a Commission resolution. The Commission shall not delegate the power conferred by this section to sign subpoenas or demands for information to any other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57b_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Applicability of this section The provisions of this section shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>