<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6004"><akn:num>6004</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6004. Standards(a) In generalBicycle helmets manufactured 9 months or more after June 16, 1994, shall conform to—(1) any interim standard described under subsection (b), pending the establishment of a final standard pursuant to subsection (c); and

(2) the final standard, once it has been established under subsection (c).


(b) Interim standardsThe interim standards are as follows:(1) The American National Standards Institute standard designated as “Z90.4–1984”.

(2) The Snell Memorial Foundation standard designated as “B–90”.

(3) The American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) standard designated as “F 1447”.

(4) Any other standard that the Commission determines is appropriate.


(c) Final standardNot later than 60 days after June 16, 1994, the Commission shall begin a proceeding under section 553 of title 5 to—(1) review the requirements of the interim standards set forth in subsection (a) and establish a final standard based on such requirements;

(2) include in the final standard a provision to protect against the risk of helmets coming off the heads of bicycle riders;

(3) include in the final standard provisions that address the risk of injury to children; and

(4) include additional provisions as appropriate.


Sections 7, 9, and 30(d) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2056, 2058, 2079(d)) shall not apply to the proceeding under this subsection and section 11 of such Act (15 U.S.C. 2060) shall not apply with respect to any standard issued under such proceeding. The final standard shall take effect 1 year from the date it is issued.

(d) Failure to meet standards(1) Failure to meet interim standardUntil the final standard takes effect, a bicycle helmet that does not conform to an interim standard as required under subsection (a)(1) shall be considered in violation of a consumer product safety standard promulgated under the Consumer Product Safety Act [15 U.S.C. 2051 et seq.].


(2) Status of final sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Bicycle helmets manufactured 9 months or more after June 16, 1994, shall conform to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interim standards The interim standards are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6004_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Final standard Not later than 60 days after June 16, 1994, the Commission shall begin a proceeding under section 553 of title 5 to— Sections 7, 9, and 30(d) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Consumer Product Safety Act (15 U.S.C. 2056, 2058, 2079(d)) shall not apply to the proceeding under this subsection and section 11 of such Act (15 U.S.C. 2060) shall not apply with respect to any standard issued under such proceeding. The final standard shall take effect 1 year from the date it is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6004_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to meet standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>