<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6152"><akn:num>6152</akn:num><akn:heading>Telemarketing Sales Rule; do-not-call registry fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6152. Telemarketing Sales Rule; do-not-call registry fees(a) In generalThe Federal Trade Commission shall assess and collect an annual fee pursuant to this section in order to implement and enforce the “do-not-call” registry as provided for in section 310.4(b)(1)(iii) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other regulation issued by the Commission under section 6102 of this title.


(b) Annual fees(1) In generalThe Commission shall charge each person who accesses the “do-not-call” registry an annual fee that is equal to the lesser of—(A) $54 for each area code of data accessed from the registry; or

(B) $14,850 for access to every area code of data contained in the registry.


(2) ExceptionThe Commission shall not charge a fee to any person—(A) for accessing the first 5 area codes of data; or

(B) for accessing area codes of data in the registry if the person is permitted to access, but is not required to access, the “do-not-call” registry under section 11 So in original. Probably should be “part”. 310 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, section 64.1200 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other Federal regulation or law.


(3) Duration of access(A) In generalThe Commission shall allow each person who pays the annual fee described in paragraph (1), each person excepted under paragraph (2) from paying the annual fee, and each person excepted from paying an annual fee under section 310.4(b)(1)(iii)(B) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, to access the area codes of data in the “do-not-call” registry for which the person has paid during that person’s annual period.


(B) Annual periodIn this paragraph, the term “annual period” means the 12-month period beginning on the first day of the month in which a person pays the fee described in paragraph (1).




(c) Additional fees(1) In generalThe Commission shall charge a person required to pay an annual fee under subsection (b) an additional fee for each additional area code of data the per</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Federal Trade Commission shall assess and collect an annual fee pursuant to this section in order to implement and enforce the “do-not-call” registry as provided for in section 310.4(b)(1)(iii) of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations, or any other regulation issued by the Commission under section 6102 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustment of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against fee sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition against fee sharing No person may enter into or participate in an arrangement (as such term is used in section 310.8(c) of the Commission’s regulations (16 C.F.R. 310.8(c))) to share any fee required by subsection (b) or (c), including any arrangement to divide the costs to access the registry among various clients of a telemarketer or service provider.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6152_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Handling of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Handling of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>