<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6301"><akn:num>6301</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6301. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter:(1) BoxerThe term “boxer” means an individual who fights in a professional boxing match.


(2) Boxing commission(A) 11 So in original. No subpar. (B) has been enacted. The term “boxing commission” means an entity authorized under State law to regulate professional boxing matches.


(3) Boxer registryThe term “boxer registry” means any entity certified by the Association of Boxing Commissions for the purposes of maintaining records and identification of boxers.


(4) LicenseeThe term “licensee” means an individual who serves as a trainer, second, or cut man for a boxer.


(5) ManagerThe term “manager” means a person who receives compensation for service as an agent or representative of a boxer.


(6) MatchmakerThe term “matchmaker” means a person that proposes, selects, and arranges the boxers to participate in a professional boxing match.


(7) PhysicianThe term “physician” means a doctor of medicine legally authorized to practice medicine by the State in which the physician performs such function or action.


(8) Professional boxing matchThe term “professional boxing match” means a boxing contest held in the United States between individuals for financial compensation. Such term does not include a boxing contest that is regulated by an amateur sports organization.


(9) PromoterThe term “promoter” means the person primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing a professional boxing match. The term “promoter” does not include a hotel, casino, resort, or other commercial establishment hosting or sponsoring a professional boxing match unless—(A) the hotel, casino, resort, or other commercial establishment is primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing the match; and

(B) there is no other person primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing the match.


(10) StateThe term “State” means each of the 50 States, Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, and any territory or p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boxer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Boxer The term “boxer” means an individual who fights in a professional boxing match.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boxing commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Boxing commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boxer registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Boxer registry The term “boxer registry” means any entity certified by the Association of Boxing Commissions for the purposes of maintaining records and identification of boxers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Licensee The term “licensee” means an individual who serves as a trainer, second, or cut man for a boxer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manager</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Manager The term “manager” means a person who receives compensation for service as an agent or representative of a boxer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matchmaker</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Matchmaker The term “matchmaker” means a person that proposes, selects, and arranges the boxers to participate in a professional boxing match.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physician</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Physician The term “physician” means a doctor of medicine legally authorized to practice medicine by the State in which the physician performs such function or action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional boxing match</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Professional boxing match The term “professional boxing match” means a boxing contest held in the United States between individuals for financial compensation. Such term does not include a boxing contest that is regulated by an amateur sports organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Promoter The term “promoter” means the person primarily responsible for organizing, promoting, and producing a professional boxing match. The term “promoter” does not include a hotel, casino, resort, or other commercial establishment hosting or sponsoring a professional boxing match unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State The term “State” means each of the 50 States, Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States, including the Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>