<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6309"><akn:num>6309</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6309. Enforcement(a) InjunctionsWhenever the Attorney General of the United States has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaged in a violation of this chapter, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate district court of the United States requesting such relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, against the person, as the Attorney General determines to be necessary to restrain the person from continuing to engage in, sanction, promote, or otherwise participate in a professional boxing match in violation of this chapter.


(b) Criminal penalties(1) Managers, promoters, matchmakers, and licenseesAny manager, promoter, matchmaker, and licensee who knowingly violates, or coerces or causes any other person to violate, any provision of this chapter, other than section 6307a(b),11 So in original. Section 6307a does not contain a subsec. (b). 6307b, 6307c, 6307d, 6307e, 6307f, or 6307h of this title, shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than $20,000, or both.


(2) Violation of antiexploitation, sanctioning organization, or disclosure provisionsAny person who knowingly violates any provision of section 6307a(b),1 6307b, 6307c, 6307d, 6307e, 6307f, or 6307h of this title shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than—(A) $100,000; and

(B) if a violation occurs in connection with a professional boxing match the gross revenues for which exceed $2,000,000, an additional amount which bears the same ratio to $100,000 as the amount of such revenues compared to $2,000,000, or both.


(3) Conflict of interestAny member or employee of a boxing commission, any person who administers or enforces State boxing laws, and any member of the Association of Boxing Commissions who knowingly violates section 6308(a) of this title shall, upon conviction, be imprisoned for not more than 1 year or fined not more than $20,000, or bot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6309_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Injunctions Whenever the Attorney General of the United States has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaged in a violation of this chapter, the Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate district court of the United States requesting such relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, against the person, as the Attorney General determines to be necessary to restrain the person from continuing to engage in, sanction, promote, or otherwise participate in a professional boxing match in violation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6309_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criminal penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6309_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Actions by States Whenever the chief law enforcement officer of any State has reason to believe that a person or organization is engaging in practices which violate any requirement of this chapter, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of its residents in an appropriate district court of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6309_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private right of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Private right of action Any boxer who suffers economic injury as a result of a violation of any provision of this chapter may bring an action in the appropriate Federal or State court and recover the damages suffered, court costs, and reasonable attorneys fees and expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6309_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement against Federal Trade Commission, State Attorneys General, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement against Federal Trade Commission, State Attorneys General, etc. Nothing in this chapter authorizes the enforcement of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>