<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_631"><akn:num>631</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 631. Declaration of policy(a) Aid, counsel, assistance, etc., to small business concernsThe essence of the American economic system of private enterprise is free competition. Only through full and free competition can free markets, free entry into business, and opportunities for the expression and growth of personal initiative and individual judgment be assured. The preservation and expansion of such competition is basic not only to the economic well-being but to the security of this Nation. Such security and well-being cannot be realized unless the actual and potential capacity of small business is encouraged and developed. It is the declared policy of the Congress that the Government should aid, counsel, assist, and protect, insofar as is possible, the interests of small-business concerns in order to preserve free competitive enterprise, to insure that a fair proportion of the total purchases and contracts or subcontracts for property and services for the Government (including but not limited to contracts or subcontracts for maintenance, repair, and construction) be placed with small-business enterprises, to insure that a fair proportion of the total sales of Government property be made to such enterprises, and to maintain and strengthen the overall economy of the Nation.


(b) Assistance to compete in international markets(1) It is the declared policy of the Congress that the Federal Government, through the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, acting through the Associate Administrator for International Trade, and in cooperation with the Department of Commerce and other relevant State and Federal agencies, should aid and assist small businesses, as defined under this chapter, to increase their ability to compete in international markets by—(A) enhancing their ability to export;

(B) facilitating technology transfers;

(C) enhancing their ability to compete effectively and efficiently against imports;

(D) increasing the access of small businesses</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aid, counsel, assistance, etc., to small business concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Aid, counsel, assistance, etc., to small business concerns The essence of the American economic system of private enterprise is free competition. Only through full and free competition can free markets, free entry into business, and opportunities for the expression and growth of personal initiative and individual judgment be assured. The preservation and expansion of such competition is basic not only to the economic well-being but to the security of this Nation. Such security and well-being cannot be realized unless the actual and potential capacity of small business is encouraged and developed. It is the declared policy of the Congress that the Government should aid, counsel, assist, and protect, insofar as is possible, the interests of small-business concerns in order to preserve free competitive enterprise, to insure that a fair proportion of the total purchases and contracts or subcontracts for property and services for the Government (including but not limited to contracts or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to compete in international markets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance to compete in international markets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aid for agriculturally related industries; financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Aid for agriculturally related industries; financial assistance It is the declared policy of the Congress that the Government, through the Small Business Administration, should aid and assist small business concerns which are engaged in the production of food and fiber, ranching, and raising of livestock, aquaculture, and all other farming and agricultural related industries; and the financial assistance programs authorized by this chapter are also to be used to assist such concerns.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of assistance programs to establish, preserve, and strengthen small business concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of assistance programs to establish, preserve, and strengthen small business concerns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to victims of floods, etc., and those displaced as result of federally aided construction programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance to victims of floods, etc., and those displaced as result of federally aided construction programs Further, it is the declared policy of the Congress that the Government should aid and assist victims of floods and other catastrophes, and small-business concerns which are displaced as a result of federally aided construction programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Findings; purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to disaster victims under disaster loan program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance to disaster victims under disaster loan program In administering the disaster loan program authorized by section 636 of this title, to the maximum extent possible, the Administration shall provide assistance and counseling to disaster victims in filing applications, providing information relevant to loan processing, and in loan closing and prompt disbursement of loan proceeds and shall give the disaster program a high priority in allocating funds for administrative expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to women owned business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Assistance to women owned business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds for individuals not lawfully within United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition on use of funds for individuals not lawfully within United States None of the funds made available pursuant to this chapter may be used to provide any direct benefit or assistance to any individual in the United States if the Administrator or the official to which the funds are made available receives notification that the individual is not lawfully within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_631_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract bundling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contract bundling In complying with the statement of congressional policy expressed in subsection (a), relating to fostering the participation of small business concerns in the contracting opportunities of the Government, each Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>