<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6312"><akn:num>6312</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional boxing matches conducted on Indian reservations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6312. Professional boxing matches conducted on Indian reservations(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the same meaning as in section 5304(e) of title 25.


(2) ReservationThe term “reservation” means the geographically defined area over which a tribal organization exercises governmental jurisdiction.


(3) Tribal organizationThe term “tribal organization” has the same meaning as in section 5304(l) of title 25.



(b) Requirements(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a tribal organization of an Indian tribe may, upon the initiative of the tribal organization—(A) regulate professional boxing matches held within the reservation under the jurisdiction of that tribal organization; and

(B) carry out that regulation or enter into a contract with a boxing commission to carry out that regulation.


(2) Standards and licensingIf a tribal organization regulates professional boxing matches pursuant to paragraph (1), the tribal organization shall, by tribal ordinance or resolution, establish and provide for the implementation of health and safety standards, licensing requirements, and other requirements relating to the conduct of professional boxing matches that are at least as restrictive as—(A) the otherwise applicable standards and requirements of a State in which the reservation is located; or

(B) the most recently published version of the recommended regulatory guidelines certified and published by the Association of Boxing Commissions.



(Pub. L. 104–272, § 21, formerly § 13, Oct. 9, 1996, 110 Stat. 3313; renumbered § 21, Pub. L. 106–210, § 4(1), May 26, 2000, 114 Stat. 322.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 1997, see section 23 of Pub. L. 104–272, set out as a note under section 6301 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>