<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/633" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/633/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/633/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_633"><akn:num>633</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Business Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 633. Small Business Administration(a) Creation; principal, branch, and regional officesIn order to carry out the policies of this chapter there is created an agency under the name “Small Business Administration” (herein referred to as the Administration), which Administration shall be under the general direction and supervision of the President and shall not be affiliated with or be within any other agency or department of the Federal Government. The principal office of the Administration shall be located in the District of Columbia. The Administration may establish such branch and regional offices in other places in the United States as may be determined by the Administrator of the Administration. As used in this chapter, the term “United States” includes the several States, the Territories and possessions of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the District of Columbia.


(b) Appointment of Administrator, Deputy Administrator, and Associate Administrators; duties of Administrator: preparation of data base and publication of economic indices and annual report; risk management database; computer security and education program(1) The management of the Administration shall be vested in an Administrator who shall be appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall be a person of outstanding qualifications known to be familiar and sympathetic with small-business needs and problems. The Administrator shall not engage in any other business, vocation, or employment than that of serving as Administrator. In carrying out the programs administered by the Small Business Administration including its lending and guaranteeing functions, the Administrator shall not discriminate on the basis of sex or marital status against any person or small business concern applying for or receiving assistance from the Small Business Administration, and the Small Busines</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation; principal, branch, and regional offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation; principal, branch, and regional offices In order to carry out the policies of this chapter there is created an agency under the name “Small Business Administration” (herein referred to as the Administration), which Administration shall be under the general direction and supervision of the President and shall not be affiliated with or be within any other agency or department of the Federal Government. The principal office of the Administration shall be located in the District of Columbia. The Administration may establish such branch and regional offices in other places in the United States as may be determined by the Administrator of the Administration. As used in this chapter, the term “United States” includes the several States, the Territories and possessions of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Administrator, Deputy Administrator, and Associate Administrators; duties of Administrator: preparation of data base and publication of economic indices and annual report; risk management database; computer security and education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment of Administrator, Deputy Administrator, and Associate Administrators; duties of Administrator: preparation of data base and publication of economic indices and annual report; risk management database; computer security and education program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revolving funds; disaster loan fund; business loan and investment fund; payments into funds; appropriations; reports to Congress; business-type budgets; borrowing authority: terms and conditions of notes, interest rate, public debt transactions; payments into miscellaneous receipts; authorization of appropriations for losses and interest subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revolving funds; disaster loan fund; business loan and investment fund; payments into funds; appropriations; reports to Congress; business-type budgets; borrowing authority: terms and conditions of notes, interest rate, public debt transactions; payments into miscellaneous receipts; authorization of appropriations for losses and interest subsidies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation and composition of Loan Policy Board; establishment of policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Creation and composition of Loan Policy Board; establishment of policies There is created the Loan Policy Board of the Small Business Administration, which shall consist of the following members, all ex officio: The Administrator, as Chairman, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Commerce. Either of the said Secretaries may designate an officer of his Department, who has been appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to act in his stead as a member of the Loan Policy Board with respect to any matter or matters. The Loan Policy Board shall establish general policies (particularly with reference to the public interest involved in the granting and denial of applications for financial assistance by the Administration and with reference to the coordination of the functions of the Administration with other activities and policies of the Government), which shall govern the granting and denial of applications for financial assistance by the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on provision of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on provision of assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administration is prohibited from providing any financial or other assistance to any business concern or other person engaged in the production or distribution of any product or service that has been determined to be obscene by a court of competent jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of compliance with child support obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certification of compliance with child support obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business Opportunity Specialists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Business Opportunity Specialists</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial market representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Commercial market representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>