<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/636" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/636/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/636/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_636"><akn:num>636</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 636. Additional powers(a) Loans to small business concerns; allowable purposes; qualified business; restrictions and limitationsThe Administration is empowered to the extent and in such amounts as provided in advance in appropriation Acts to make loans for plant acquisition, construction, conversion, or expansion, including the acquisition of land, material, supplies, equipment, and working capital, and to make loans to any qualified small business concern, including those owned by qualified Indian tribes, for purposes of this chapter. Such financings may be made either directly or in cooperation with banks or other financial institutions through agreements to participate on an immediate or deferred (guaranteed) basis. These powers shall be subject, however, to the following restrictions, limitations, and provisions:(1) In general.—(A) Credit elsewhere.—(i) In general.—The Administrator has the authority to direct, and conduct oversight for, the methods by which lenders determine whether a borrower is able to obtain credit elsewhere. No financial assistance shall be extended pursuant to this subsection if the applicant can obtain credit elsewhere. No immediate participation may be purchased unless it is shown that a deferred participation is not available; and no direct financing may be made unless it is shown that a participation is not available.

(ii) Liquidity.—On and after October 1, 2015, the Administrator may not guarantee a loan under this subsection if the lender determines that the borrower is unable to obtain credit elsewhere solely because the liquidity of the lender depends upon the guaranteed portion of the loan being sold on the secondary market.


(B) Background checks.—Prior to the approval of any loan made pursuant to this subsection, or section 503 of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 [15 U.S.C. 697], the Administrator may verify the applicant’s criminal background, or lack thereof, through the best available means, including, if possibl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to small business concerns; allowable purposes; qualified business; restrictions and limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Loans to small business concerns; allowable purposes; qualified business; restrictions and limitations The Administration is empowered to the extent and in such amounts as provided in advance in appropriation Acts to make loans for plant acquisition, construction, conversion, or expansion, including the acquisition of land, material, supplies, equipment, and working capital, and to make loans to any qualified small business concern, including those owned by qualified Indian tribes, for purposes of this chapter. Such financings may be made either directly or in cooperation with banks or other financial institutions through agreements to participate on an immediate or deferred (guaranteed) basis. These powers shall be subject, however, to the following restrictions, limitations, and provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disaster loans; authorization, scope, terms and conditions, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disaster loans; authorization, scope, terms and conditions, etc. Except as to agricultural enterprises as defined in section 647(b)(1) of this title, the Administration also is empowered to the extent and in such amounts as provided in advance in appropriation Acts— No loan under this subsection, including renewals and extensions thereof, may be made for a period or periods exceeding thirty years: Provided, That the Administrator may consent to a suspension in the payment of principal and interest charges on, and to an extension in the maturity of, the Federal share of any loan under this subsection for a period not to exceed five years, if (A) the borrower under such loan is a homeowner or a small business concern, (B) the loan was made to enable (i) such homeowner to repair or replace his home, or (ii) such concern to repair or replace plant or equipment which was damaged or destroyed as the result of a disaster meeting the requirements of clause (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) of th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private disaster loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Private disaster loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension or renewal of loans; purchase of participations; assumption of obligations; disaster loans; interest rates; loan amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Extension or renewal of loans; purchase of participations; assumption of obligations; disaster loans; interest rates; loan amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for small business development centers under section 648 of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funds for small business development centers under The Administration shall not fund any Small Business Development Center or any variation thereof, except as authorized in section 648 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements for subsection (b) loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional requirements for subsection (b) loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net earnings clauses prohibited for subsection (b) loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Net earnings clauses prohibited for subsection (b) loans In making loans under subsection (b), the Administrator shall not require the borrower to pay any non-amortized amount for the first five years after repayment begins.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to handicapped persons and organizations for handicapped</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Loans to handicapped persons and organizations for handicapped</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to small business concerns located in urban or rural areas with high proportions of unemployed or low-income individuals, or owned by low-income individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Loans to small business concerns located in urban or rural areas with high proportions of unemployed or low-income individuals, or owned by low-income individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance for projects providing technical or management assistance; areas of high concentration of unemployment or low-income; preferences; manner and method of payment; accessible services; program evaluations; establishment of development program; coordination of policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Financial assistance for projects providing technical or management assistance; areas of high concentration of unemployment or low-income; preferences; manner and method of payment; accessible services; program evaluations; establishment of development program; coordination of policies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>