<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/637b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/637b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/637b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_637b"><akn:num>637b</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 637b. Availability of information(a) Requests for informationFor any contract to be let by any Federal agency, such agency shall provide to any small business concern upon its request—(1) a copy of bid sets and specifications with respect to such contract;

(2) the name and telephone number of an employee of such agency to answer questions with respect to such contract; and

(3) adequate citations to each major Federal law or agency rule with which such business concern must comply in performing such contract.


(b) Exempt contractsSubsection (a) shall not apply to any contract or subcontract under such contract which—(1) will be performed entirely outside any State, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; or

(2) is for services which are personal in nature.


(Pub. L. 95–507, title II, § 223, Oct. 24, 1978, 92 Stat. 1772.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Small Business Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_637b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requests for information For any contract to be let by any Federal agency, such agency shall provide to any small business concern upon its request—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_637b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exempt contracts Subsection (a) shall not apply to any contract or subcontract under such contract which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>