<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/644" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/644/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/644/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_644"><akn:num>644</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards or contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 644. Awards or contracts(a) Small business procurements(1) In generalFor purposes of this chapter, small business concerns shall receive any award or contract if such award or contract is, in the determination of the Administrator and the contracting agency, in the interest of—(A) maintaining or mobilizing the full productive capacity of the United States;

(B) war or national defense programs; or

(C) assuring that a fair proportion of the total purchases and contracts for goods and services of the Government in each industry category (as defined under paragraph (2)) are awarded to small business concerns.


(2) Industry category defined(A) In generalIn this subsection, the term “industry category” means a discrete group of similar goods and services, as determined by the Administrator in accordance with the North American Industry Classification System codes used to establish small business size standards, except that the Administrator shall limit an industry category to a greater extent than provided under the North American Industry Classification System codes if the Administrator receives evidence indicating that further segmentation of the industry category is warranted—(i) due to special capital equipment needs;

(ii) due to special labor requirements;

(iii) due to special geographic requirements, except as provided in subparagraph (B);

(iv) due to unique Federal buying patterns or requirements; or

(v) to recognize a new industry.


(B) Exception for geographic requirementsThe Administrator may not further segment an industry category based on geographic requirements unless—(i) the Government typically designates the geographic area where work for contracts for goods or services is to be performed;

(ii) Government purchases comprise the major portion of the entire domestic market for such goods or services; and

(iii) it is unreasonable to expect competition from business concerns located outside of the general geographic area due to the fixed location </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business procurements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Small business procurements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Placement of contracts by contracting procurement agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Placement of contracts by contracting procurement agency With respect to any work to be performed the amount of which would exceed the maximum amount of any contract for which a surety may be guaranteed against loss under section 694b of this title, the contracting procurement agency shall, to the extent practicable, place contracts so as to allow more than one small business concern to perform such work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs for blind and handicapped individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programs for blind and handicapped individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority For purposes of this section priority shall be given to the awarding of contracts and the placement of subcontracts to small business concerns which shall perform a substantial proportion of the production on those contracts and subcontracts within areas of concentrated unemployment or underemployment or within labor surplus areas. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, total labor surplus area set-asides pursuant to Defense Manpower Policy Number 4 (32A C.F.R. Chapter 1) or any successor policy shall be authorized if the Secretary or his designee specifically determines that there is a reasonable expectation that offers will be obtained from a sufficient number of eligible concerns so that awards will be made at reasonable prices. As soon as practicable and to the extent possible, in determining labor surplus areas, consideration shall be given to those persons who would be available for employment were suitable employment available. Until such definition reflects su</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement strategies; contract bundling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procurement strategies; contract bundling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting preference for small business concerns in a major disaster area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contracting preference for small business concerns in a major disaster area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals for participation of small business concerns in procurement contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Goals for participation of small business concerns in procurement contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting on goals for procurement contracts awarded to small business concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reporting on goals for procurement contracts awarded to small business concerns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business set-asides</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Small business set-asides Nothing in this chapter or any other provision of law precludes exclusive small business set-asides for procurements of architectural and engineering services, research, development, test and evaluation, and each Federal agency is authorized to develop such set-asides to further the interests of small business in those areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Small business reservation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>