<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_648b"><akn:num>648b</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for SBDCs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 648b. Grants for SBDCs(a) In generalThe Administrator may make grants to small business development centers under section 648 of this title to provide targeted technical assistance to small business concerns seeking access to capital or credit, Federal procurement opportunities, energy efficiency audits to reduce energy bills, opportunities to export products or provide services to foreign customers, adopting, making innovations in, and using broadband technologies, or other assistance.


(b) Allocation(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), and notwithstanding the requirements of section 648(a)(4)(C)(iii) of this title, the amount appropriated to carry out this section shall be allocated under the formula under section 648(a)(4)(C)(i) of this title.


(2) Minimum fundingThe amount made available under this section to each State shall be not less than $325,000.


(3) Types of usesOf the total amount of the grants awarded by the Administrator under this section—(A) not less than 80 percent shall be used for counseling of small business concerns; and

(B) not more than 20 percent may be used for classes or seminars.



(c) No non-Federal share requiredNotwithstanding section 648(a)(4)(A) of this title, the recipient of a grant made under this section shall not be required to provide non-Federal matching funds.


(d) DistributionNot later than 30 days after the date on which amounts are appropriated to carry out this section, the Administrator shall disburse the total amount appropriated.


(e) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $50,000,000 to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 111–240, title I, § 1402, Sept. 27, 2010, 124 Stat. 2550.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, and not as part of the Small Business Act which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definition of “Administrator” and “small business co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator may make grants to small business development centers under section 648 of this title to provide targeted technical assistance to small business concerns seeking access to capital or credit, Federal procurement opportunities, energy efficiency audits to reduce energy bills, opportunities to export products or provide services to foreign customers, adopting, making innovations in, and using broadband technologies, or other assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No non-Federal share required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No non-Federal share required Notwithstanding section 648(a)(4)(A) of this title, the recipient of a grant made under this section shall not be required to provide non-Federal matching funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distribution Not later than 30 days after the date on which amounts are appropriated to carry out this section, the Administrator shall disburse the total amount appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $50,000,000 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>