<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/648c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_648c"><akn:num>648c</akn:num><akn:heading>SBA and USPTO partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 648c. SBA and USPTO partnerships(a) In generalBeginning not later than 180 days after October 9, 2018, the Administrator, in consultation with the Director, shall develop partnership agreements that—(1) provide for the—(A) development of high-quality training, including in-person or modular training sessions, for small business concerns relating to domestic and international protection of intellectual property;

(B) leveraging of training materials already developed for the education of inventors and small business concerns; and

(C) participation of a nongovernmental organization; and


(2) provide training—(A) through electronic resources, including Internet-based webinars; and

(B) at physical locations, including—(i) a small business development center; and

(ii) the headquarters or a regional office of the USPTO.




(Pub. L. 115–259, § 4, Oct. 9, 2018, 132 Stat. 3664.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017, and not as part of the Small Business Act which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
FindingsPub. L. 115–259, § 3, Oct. 9, 2018, 132 Stat. 3664, provided that: 
“Congress finds that—
“(1) the USPTO and the SBA are positioned to—“(A) build upon several successful intellectual property and training programs aimed at small business concerns; and

“(B) increase the availability of and the participation in the programs described in subparagraph (A) across the United States; and


“(2) any education and training program administered by the USPTO and the SBA should be scalable so that the program is able to reach more small business concerns.”





Definitions
Pub. L. 115–259, § 2, Oct. 9, 2018, 132 Stat. 3664, provided that: 
“In this Act [see Short Title of 2018 Amendment note set out under section 631 of this title]—
“(1) the term ‘Administrator’ means the Administrator of the SBA;

“(2) the term ‘Director’ means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intelle</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_648c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning not later than 180 days after October 9, 2018, the Administrator, in consultation with the Director, shall develop partnership agreements that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>