<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/653" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/653/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/653/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_653"><akn:num>653</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Rural Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 653. Office of Rural Affairs(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established in the Small Business Administration an Office of Rural Affairs (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(b) Appointment of directorThe Office shall be headed by a director who shall be appointed by the Administrator not later than 90 days after November 15, 1990.


(c) FunctionsThe Office shall—(1) strive to achieve an equitable distribution of the financial assistance available from the Administration for small business concerns located in rural areas;

(2) to the extent practicable, compile annual statistics on rural areas, including statistics concerning the population, poverty, job creation and retention, unemployment, business failures, and business startups;

(3) provide information to industries, organizations, and State and local governments concerning the assistance available to rural small business concerns through the Administration and through other Federal departments and agencies;

(4) provide information to industries, organizations, educational institutions, and State and local governments concerning programs administered by private organizations, educational institutions, and Federal, State, and local governments which improve the economic opportunities of rural citizens; and

(5) work with the United States Tourism and Travel Administration to assist small businesses in rural areas with tourism promotion and development.


(Pub. L. 85–536, § 2[26], as added Pub. L. 101–574, title III, § 302, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2827.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Catalog of Programs To Assist Rural Small Business ConcernsPub. L. 101–574, title III, § 304, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2829, required the Small Business Administration to compile a catalog of programs administered by Federal and State departments and agencies which offer assistance to small business concerns in rural areas by no later than 180 days after Nov. 15, 1990, and to issue updates of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_653_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established in the Small Business Administration an Office of Rural Affairs (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_653_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment of director The Office shall be headed by a director who shall be appointed by the Administrator not later than 90 days after November 15, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_653_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions The Office shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>