<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/654" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/654/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/654/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_654"><akn:num>654</akn:num><akn:heading>Paul D. Coverdell drug-free workplace program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 654. Paul D. Coverdell drug-free workplace program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Drug-free workplace programThe term “drug-free workplace program” means a program that includes—(A) a written policy, including a clear statement of expectations for workplace behavior, prohibitions against reporting to work or working under the influence of illegal drugs or alcohol, prohibitions against the use or possession of illegal drugs in the workplace, and the consequences of violating those expectations and prohibitions;

(B) drug and alcohol abuse prevention training for a total of not less than 2 hours for each employee, and additional voluntary drug and alcohol abuse prevention training for employees who are parents;

(C) employee illegal drug testing, with analysis conducted by a drug testing laboratory certified by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, or approved by the College of American Pathologists for forensic drug testing, and a review of each positive test result by a medical review officer;

(D) employee access to an employee assistance program, including confidential assessment, referral, and short-term problem resolution; and

(E) continuing alcohol and drug abuse prevention education.


(2) Eligible intermediaryThe term “eligible intermediary” means an organization—(A) that has not less than 2 years of experience in carrying out drug-free workplace programs;

(B) that has a drug-free workplace policy in effect;

(C) that is located in a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory of the United States; and

(D)(i) the purpose of which is—(I) to develop comprehensive drug-free workplace programs or to supply drug-free workplace services; or

(II) to provide other forms of assistance and services to small business concerns; or


(ii) that is eligible to receive a grant under chapter 2 of the National Narcotics Leadership Act of 1988 (21 U.S.C. 1521 et seq.).



(3) EmployeeThe term “employee” includes any—(A) applicant for employ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of effective practices of eligible intermediaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Promotion of effective practices of eligible intermediaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation and coordination Not later than 18 months after October 21, 1998, the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of National Drug Control Policy, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contract authority In carrying out this section, the Administrator may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction Nothing in this section may be construed to require an employer who attends a program offered by an intermediary to contract for any service offered by the intermediary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>