<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/656" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/656/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/656/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_656"><akn:num>656</akn:num><akn:heading>Women’s Business Center program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 656. Women’s Business Center program(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “Assistant Administrator” means the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Women’s Business Ownership established under subsection (g);

(2) the term “private nonprofit organization” means an entity that is described in section 501(c) of title 26 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title;

(3) the term “small business concern owned and controlled by women”, either startup or existing, includes any small business concern—(A) that is not less than 51 percent owned by 1 or more women; and

(B) the management and daily business operations of which are controlled by 1 or more women; and


(4) the term “women’s business center site” means the location of—(A) a women’s business center; or

(B) 1 or more women’s business centers, established in conjunction with another women’s business center in another location within a State or region—(i) that reach a distinct population that would otherwise not be served;

(ii) whose services are targeted to women; and

(iii) whose scope, function, and activities are similar to those of the primary women’s business center or centers in conjunction with which it was established.




(b) AuthorityThe Administration may provide financial assistance to private nonprofit organizations to conduct 5-year projects for the benefit of small business concerns owned and controlled by women. The projects shall provide—(1) financial assistance, including training and counseling in how to apply for and secure business credit and investment capital, preparing and presenting financial statements, and managing cash flow and other financial operations of a business concern;

(2) management assistance, including training and counseling in how to plan, organize, staff, direct, and control each major activity and function of a small business concern; and

(3) marketing assistance, including training and counseling in identifying and segmenting domestic and in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority The Administration may provide financial assistance to private nonprofit organizations to conduct 5-year projects for the benefit of small business concerns owned and controlled by women. The projects shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions of participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contract authority A women’s business center may enter into a contract with a Federal department or agency to provide specific assistance to women and other underserved small business concerns. Performance of such contract should not hinder the women’s business centers in carrying out the terms of the grant received by the women’s business centers from the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of 5-year plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Submission of 5-year plan Each applicant organization initially shall submit a 5-year plan to the Administration on proposed fundraising and training activities, and a recipient organization may receive financial assistance under this program for a maximum of 5 years per women’s business center site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Criteria The Administration shall evaluate and rank applicants in accordance with predetermined selection criteria that shall be stated in terms of relative importance. Such criteria and their relative importance shall be made publicly available and stated in each solicitation for applications made by the Administration. The criteria shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Women’s Business Ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Office of Women’s Business Ownership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Program examination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Contract authority The authority of the Administrator to enter into contracts shall be in effect for each fiscal year only to the extent and in the amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts. After the Administrator has entered into a contract, either as a grant or a cooperative agreement, with any applicant under this section, it shall not suspend, terminate, or fail to renew or extend any such contract unless the Administrator provides the applicant with written notification setting forth the reasons therefore 1 and affords the applicant an opportunity for a hearing, appeal, or other administrative proceeding under chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_656_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Management report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>