<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_657p"><akn:num>657p</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach regarding health insurance options available to children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 657p. Outreach regarding health insurance options available to children(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the terms “Administration” and “Administrator” means the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof, respectively;

(2) the term “certified development company” means a development company participating in the program under title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (15 U.S.C. 695 et seq.);

(3) the term “Medicaid program” means the program established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.);

(4) the term “Service Corps of Retired Executives” means the Service Corps of Retired Executives authorized by section 637(b)(1) of this title;

(5) the term “small business concern” has the meaning given that term in section 632 of this title;

(6) the term “small business development center” means a small business development center described in section 648 of this title;

(7) the term “State” has the meaning given that term for purposes of title XXI of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.);

(8) the term “State Children’s Health Insurance Program” means the State Children’s Health Insurance Program established under title XXI of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.);

(9) the term “task force” means the task force established under subsection (b)(1); and

(10) the term “women’s business center” means a women’s business center described in section 656 of this title.


(b) Establishment of task force(1) EstablishmentThere is established a task force to conduct a nationwide campaign of education and outreach for small business concerns regarding the availability of coverage for children through private insurance options, the Medicaid program, and the State Children’s Health Insurance Program.


(2) MembershipThe task force shall consist of the Administrator, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of the Treasury.


(3) ResponsibilitiesThe campai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of task force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of task force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>