<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_657q"><akn:num>657q</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of contract requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 657q. Consolidation of contract requirements(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “Chief Acquisition Officer” means the employee of a Federal agency appointed or designated as the Chief Acquisition Officer for the Federal agency under section 1702(a) of title 41;

(2) the term “consolidation of contract requirements”, with respect to contract requirements of a Federal agency, means a use of a solicitation to obtain offers for a single contract or a multiple award contract—(A) to satisfy 2 or more requirements of the Federal agency for goods or services that have been provided to or performed for the Federal agency under 2 or more separate contracts lower in cost than the total cost of the contract for which the offers are solicited; or

(B) to satisfy requirements of the Federal agency for construction projects to be performed at 2 or more discrete sites; and


(3) the term “senior procurement executive” means an official designated under section 1702(c) of title 41 as the senior procurement executive for a Federal agency.


(b) PolicyThe head of each Federal agency shall ensure that the decisions made by the Federal agency regarding consolidation of contract requirements of the Federal agency are made with a view to providing small business concerns with appropriate opportunities to participate as prime contractors and subcontractors in the procurements of the Federal agency.


(c) Limitation on use of acquisition strategies involving consolidation(1) In generalThe head of a Federal agency may not carry out an acquisition strategy that includes a consolidation of contract requirements of the Federal agency with a total value of more than $2,000,000, unless the senior procurement executive or Chief Acquisition Officer for the Federal agency, before carrying out the acquisition strategy—(A) conducts market research;

(B) identifies any alternative contracting approaches that would involve a lesser degree of consolidation of contract requirements;

(C) makes a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Policy The head of each Federal agency shall ensure that the decisions made by the Federal agency regarding consolidation of contract requirements of the Federal agency are made with a view to providing small business concerns with appropriate opportunities to participate as prime contractors and subcontractors in the procurements of the Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of acquisition strategies involving consolidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on use of acquisition strategies involving consolidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>