<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_657r"><akn:num>657r</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor-protege programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 657r. Mentor-protege programs(a) Administration program(1) AuthorityThe Administrator is authorized to establish a mentor-protege program for all small business concerns.


(2) Model for programThe mentor-protege program established under paragraph (1) shall be identical to the mentor-protege program of the Administration for small business concerns that participate in the program under section 637(a) of this title (as in effect on January 2, 2013), except that the Administrator may modify the program to the extent necessary given the types of small business concerns included as proteges.


(3) Puerto Rico businessesDuring the period beginning on August 13, 2018, and ending on the date on which the Oversight Board established under section 2121 of title 48 terminates, the Administrator shall identify potential incentives to a covered mentor that awards a subcontract to its covered protege, including—(A) positive consideration in any past performance evaluation of the covered mentor; and

(B) the application of costs incurred for providing training to such covered protege to the subcontracting plan (as required under paragraph (4) or (5) of section 637(d) of this title) of the covered mentor.


(4) Covered territory businessesDuring the period beginning on January 1, 2021, and ending on the date that is 4 years after such date, the Administrator shall identify potential incentives to a covered territory mentor that awards a subcontract to its covered territory protege, including—(A) positive consideration in any past performance evaluation of the covered territory mentor; and

(B) the application of costs incurred for providing training to such covered territory protege to the subcontracting plan (as required under paragraph (4) or (5) of section 637(d) of this title) of the covered territory mentor.



(b) Programs of other agencies(1) Approval requiredExcept as provided in paragraph (4), a Federal department or agency may not carry out a mentor-protege program fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Programs of other agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current mentor protege agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Current mentor protege agreements Mentors and proteges with approved agreement in a program operating pursuant to subsection (b)(4)(C) shall be permitted to continue their relationship according to the terms specified in their agreement until the expiration date specified in the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of agency plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Submission of agency plans Agencies operating mentor protege programs pursuant to subsection (b)(4)(C) shall submit the plans specified in subsection (b)(1)(A) to the Administrator within 6 months of the promulgation of rules required by subsection (b)(3). The Administrator shall provide initial comments on each plan within 60 days of receipt, and final approval or denial of each plan within 180 days after receipt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>