<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/657t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_657t"><akn:num>657t</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Credit Risk Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 657t. Office of Credit Risk Management(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Administration the Office of Credit Risk Management (in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(b) DutiesThe Office shall be responsible for supervising—(1) any lender making loans under section 7(a) [15 U.S.C. 636(a)] (in this section referred to as a “7(a) lender”);

(2) any Lending Partner or Intermediary participant of the Administration in a lending program of the Office of Capital Access of the Administration; and

(3) any small business lending company or a non-Federally regulated lender without regard to the requirements of section 650 of this title.


(c) Director(1) In generalThe Office shall be headed by the Director of the Office of Credit Risk Management (in this section referred to as the “Director”), who shall be a career appointee in the Senior Executive Service (as defined in section 3132 of title 5).


(2) DutiesThe Director shall be responsible for oversight of the lenders and participants described in subsection (b), including by conducting periodic reviews of the compliance and performance of such lenders and participants.



(d) Supervision duties for 7(a) lenders(1) ReviewsWith respect to 7(a) lenders, an employee of the Office shall—(A) be present for and supervise any such review that is conducted by a contractor of the Office on the premise 11 So in original. Probably should be “premises”. of the 7(a) lender; and

(B) supervise any such review that is not conducted on the premise 1 of the 7(a) lender.


(2) Review report timeline(A) In generalNotwithstanding any other requirements of the Office or the Administrator, the Administrator shall develop and implement a review report timeline which shall—(i) require the Administrator to—(I) deliver a written report of the review to the 7(a) lender not later than 60 business days after the date on which the review is concluded; or

(II) if the Administrator expects to submit the report after the end of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Administration the Office of Credit Risk Management (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Office shall be responsible for supervising—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision duties for 7(a) lenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supervision duties for 7(a) lenders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement authority against 7(a) lenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement authority against 7(a) lenders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations Not later than 1 year after June 21, 2018, the Administrator shall issue regulations, after opportunity for notice and comment, to carry out subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicing and liquidation responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Servicing and liquidation responsibilities During any period during which a 7(a) lender is suspended or otherwise prohibited from making loans under section 7(a) [15 U.S.C. 636(a)], the 7(a) lender shall remain obligated to maintain all servicing and liquidation activities delegated to the lender by the Administrator, unless otherwise specified by the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portfolio risk analysis of 7(a) loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Portfolio risk analysis of 7(a) loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657t_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget submission and justification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Budget submission and justification The Director shall annually provide, in writing, a fiscal year budget submission for the Office and a justification for such submission to the Administrator. Such submission and justification shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>