<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6603"><akn:num>6603</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6603. Application of chapter(a) General ruleThis chapter applies to any Y2K action brought after January 1, 1999, for a Y2K failure occurring before January 1, 2003, or for a potential Y2K failure that could occur or has allegedly caused harm or injury before January 1, 2003, including any appeal, remand, stay, or other judicial, administrative, or alternative dispute resolution proceeding in such an action.


(b) No new cause of action createdNothing in this chapter creates a new cause of action, and, except as otherwise explicitly provided in this chapter, nothing in this chapter expands any liability otherwise imposed or limits any defense otherwise available under Federal or State law.


(c) Claims for personal injury or wrongful death excludedThis chapter does not apply to a claim for personal injury or for wrongful death.


(d) Warranty and contract preservation(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), in any Y2K action any written contractual term, including a limitation or an exclusion of liability, or a disclaimer of warranty, shall be strictly enforced unless the enforcement of that term would manifestly and directly contravene applicable State law embodied in any statute in effect on January 1, 1999, specifically addressing that term.


(2) Interpretation of contractIn any Y2K action in which a contract to which paragraph (1) applies is silent as to a particular issue, the interpretation of the contract as to that issue shall be determined by applicable law in effect at the time the contract was executed.


(3) UnconscionabilityNothing in paragraph (1) shall prevent enforcement of State law doctrines of unconscionability, including adhesion, recognized as of January 1, 1999, in controlling judicial precedent by the courts of the State whose law applies to the Y2K action.



(e) Preemption of State lawThis chapter supersedes State law to the extent that it establishes a rule of law applicable to a Y2K action that is inconsistent with State law, but nothing</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule This chapter applies to any Y2K action brought after January 1, 1999, for a Y2K failure occurring before January 1, 2003, or for a potential Y2K failure that could occur or has allegedly caused harm or injury before January 1, 2003, including any appeal, remand, stay, or other judicial, administrative, or alternative dispute resolution proceeding in such an action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No new cause of action created</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No new cause of action created Nothing in this chapter creates a new cause of action, and, except as otherwise explicitly provided in this chapter, nothing in this chapter expands any liability otherwise imposed or limits any defense otherwise available under Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims for personal injury or wrongful death excluded</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Claims for personal injury or wrongful death excluded This chapter does not apply to a claim for personal injury or for wrongful death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warranty and contract preservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Warranty and contract preservation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption of State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preemption of State law This chapter supersedes State law to the extent that it establishes a rule of law applicable to a Y2K action that is inconsistent with State law, but nothing in this chapter implicates, alters, or diminishes the ability of a State to defend itself against any claim on the basis of sovereign immunity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application with Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application with Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act Nothing in this chapter supersedes any provision of the Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to actions brought by a government entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application to actions brought by a government entity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer protection from Y2K failures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consumer protection from Y2K failures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6603_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to securities litigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability to securities litigation In any Y2K action in which the underlying claim arises under the securities laws (as defined in section 78c(a) of this title), the provisions of this chapter, other than section 6612(b) of this title, shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>