<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6605"><akn:num>6605</akn:num><akn:heading>Proportionate liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6605. Proportionate liability(a) In generalExcept in a Y2K action that is a contract action, and except as provided in subsections (b) through (g), a person against whom a final judgment is entered in a Y2K action shall be liable solely for the portion of the judgment that corresponds to the relative and proportionate responsibility of that person. In determining the percentage of responsibility of any defendant, the trier of fact shall determine that percentage as a percentage of the total fault of all persons, including the plaintiff, who caused or contributed to the total loss incurred by the plaintiff.


(b) Proportionate liability(1) Determination of responsibilityIn any Y2K action that is not a contract action, the court shall instruct the jury to answer special interrogatories, or, if there is no jury, the court shall make findings with respect to each defendant, including defendants who have entered into settlements with the plaintiff or plaintiffs, concerning—(A) the percentage of responsibility, if any, of each defendant, measured as a percentage of the total fault of all persons who caused or contributed to the loss incurred by the plaintiff; and

(B) if alleged by the plaintiff, whether the defendant (other than a defendant who has entered into a settlement agreement with the plaintiff)—(i) acted with specific intent to injure the plaintiff; or

(ii) knowingly committed fraud.



(2) Contents of special interrogatories or findingsThe responses to interrogatories or findings under paragraph (1) shall specify the total amount of damages that the plaintiff is entitled to recover and the percentage of responsibility of each defendant found to have caused or contributed to the loss incurred by the plaintiff.


(3) Factors for considerationIn determining the percentage of responsibility under this subsection, the trier of fact shall consider—(A) the nature of the conduct of each person found to have caused or contributed to the loss incurred by the plaintiff</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except in a Y2K action that is a contract action, and except as provided in subsections (b) through (g), a person against whom a final judgment is entered in a Y2K action shall be liable solely for the portion of the judgment that corresponds to the relative and proportionate responsibility of that person. In determining the percentage of responsibility of any defendant, the trier of fact shall determine that percentage as a percentage of the total fault of all persons, including the plaintiff, who caused or contributed to the total loss incurred by the plaintiff.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proportionate liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proportionate liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint liability for specific intent or fraud</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint liability for specific intent or fraud</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement discharge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Settlement discharge</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>General right of contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) General right of contribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6605_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>More protective State law not preempted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) More protective State law not preempted Nothing in this section preempts or supersedes any provision of State law that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>