<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6606"><akn:num>6606</akn:num><akn:heading>Prelitigation notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6606. Prelitigation notice(a) In generalBefore commencing a Y2K action, except an action that seeks only injunctive relief, a prospective plaintiff in a Y2K action shall send a written notice by certified mail (with either return receipt requested or other means of verification that the notice was sent) to each prospective defendant in that action. The notice shall provide specific and detailed information about—(1) the manifestations of any material defect alleged to have caused harm or loss;

(2) the harm or loss allegedly suffered by the prospective plaintiff;

(3) how the prospective plaintiff would like the prospective defendant to remedy the problem;

(4) the basis upon which the prospective plaintiff seeks that remedy; and

(5) the name, title, address, and telephone number of any individual who has authority to negotiate a resolution of the dispute on behalf of the prospective plaintiff.


(b) Person to whom notice to be sentThe notice required by subsection (a) shall be sent—(1) to the registered agent of the prospective defendant for service of legal process;

(2) if the prospective defendant does not have a registered agent, then to the chief executive officer if the prospective defendant is a corporation, to the managing partner if the prospective defendant is a partnership, to the proprietor if the prospective defendant is a sole proprietorship, or to a similarly-situated person if the prospective defendant is any other enterprise; or

(3) if the prospective defendant has designated a person to receive prelitigation notices on a Year 2000 Internet Website (as defined in section 3(7) of the Year 2000 Information and Readiness Disclosure Act), to the designated person, if the prospective plaintiff has reasonable access to the Internet.


(c) Response to notice(1) In generalWithin 30 days after receipt of the notice specified in subsection (a), each prospective defendant shall send by certified mail with return receipt requested to each prospective plain</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Before commencing a Y2K action, except an action that seeks only injunctive relief, a prospective plaintiff in a Y2K action shall send a written notice by certified mail (with either return receipt requested or other means of verification that the notice was sent) to each prospective defendant in that action. The notice shall provide specific and detailed information about—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person to whom notice to be sent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Person to whom notice to be sent The notice required by subsection (a) shall be sent—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response to notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Response to notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to respond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to respond If a prospective defendant— the prospective plaintiff may immediately commence a legal action against that prospective defendant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remediation period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Remediation period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to provide notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Failure to provide notice If a defendant determines that a plaintiff has filed a Y2K action without providing the notice specified in subsection (a) or without awaiting the expiration of the appropriate waiting period specified in subsection (c), the defendant may treat the plaintiff’s complaint as such a notice by so informing the court and the plaintiff in its initial response to the plaintiff. If any defendant elects to treat the complaint as such a notice—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of contractual or statutory waiting periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect of contractual or statutory waiting periods In cases in which a contract, or a statute enacted before January 1, 1999, requires notice of nonperformance and provides for a period of delay prior to the initiation of suit for breach or repudiation of contract, the period of delay provided by contract or the statute is controlling over the waiting period specified in subsections (c) and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>State law controls alternative methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) State law controls alternative methods Nothing in this section supersedes or otherwise preempts any State law or rule of civil procedure with respect to the use of alternative dispute resolution for Y2K actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisional remedies unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Provisional remedies unaffected Nothing in this section interferes with the right of a litigant to provisional remedies otherwise available under Rule 65 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or any State rule of civil procedure providing extraordinary or provisional remedies in any civil action in which the underlying complaint seeks both injunctive and monetary relief.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6606_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for class actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rule for class actions For the purpose of applying this section to a Y2K action that is maintained as a class action in Federal or State court, the requirements of the preceding subsections of this section apply only to named plaintiffs in the class action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>