<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6701"><akn:num>6701</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6701. Operation of State law(a) State regulation of the business of insuranceThe Act entitled “An Act to express the intent of Congress with reference to the regulation of the business of insurance” and approved March 9, 1945 (15 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.) (commonly referred to as the “McCarran-Ferguson Act”) remains the law of the United States.


(b) Mandatory insurance licensing requirementsNo person shall engage in the business of insurance in a State as principal or agent unless such person is licensed as required by the appropriate insurance regulator of such State in accordance with the relevant State insurance law, subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e).


(c) Affiliations(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, prevent or restrict a depository institution, or an affiliate thereof, from being affiliated directly or indirectly or associated with any person, as authorized or permitted by this Act or any other provision of Federal law.


(2) InsuranceWith respect to affiliations between depository institutions, or any affiliate thereof, and any insurer, paragraph (1) does not prohibit—(A) any State from—(i) collecting, reviewing, and taking actions (including approval and disapproval) on applications and other documents or reports concerning any proposed acquisition of, or a change or continuation of control of, an insurer domiciled in that State; and

(ii) exercising authority granted under applicable State law to collect information concerning any proposed acquisition of, or a change or continuation of control of, an insurer engaged in the business of insurance in, and regulated as an insurer by, such State;


during the 60-day period preceding the effective date of the acquisition or change or continuation of control, so long as the collecting, reviewing, taking actions, or exercising authority by the State does not have the effect of discriminating, intentionally or uninte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State regulation of the business of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State regulation of the business of insurance The Act entitled “An Act to express the intent of Congress with reference to the regulation of the business of insurance” and approved March 9, 1945 (15 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.) (commonly referred to as the “McCarran-Ferguson Act”) remains the law of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory insurance licensing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mandatory insurance licensing requirements No person shall engage in the business of insurance in a State as principal or agent unless such person is licensed as required by the appropriate insurance regulator of such State in accordance with the relevant State insurance law, subject to subsections (c), (d), and (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Affiliations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nondiscrimination Except as provided in any restrictions described in subsection (d)(2)(B), no State may, by statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, regulate the insurance activities authorized or permitted under this Act or any other provision of Federal law of a depository institution, or affiliate thereof, to the extent that such statute, regulation, order, interpretation, or other action—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation Subsections (c) and (d) shall not be construed to affect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>