<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6714" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6714/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6714/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6714"><akn:num>6714</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited and equalized dispute resolution for Federal regulators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6714. Expedited and equalized dispute resolution for Federal regulators(a) Filing in Court of AppealsIn the case of a regulatory conflict between a State insurance regulator and a Federal regulator regarding insurance issues, including whether a State law, rule, regulation, order, or interpretation regarding any insurance sales or solicitation activity is properly treated as preempted under Federal law, the Federal or State regulator may seek expedited judicial review of such determination by the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the State is located or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit by filing a petition for review in such court.


(b) Expedited reviewThe United States Court of Appeals in which a petition for review is filed in accordance with subsection (a) shall complete all action on such petition, including rendering a judgment, before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which such petition is filed, unless all parties to such proceeding agree to any extension of such period.


(c) Supreme Court reviewAny request for certiorari to the Supreme Court of the United States of any judgment of a United States Court of Appeals with respect to a petition for review under this section shall be filed with the Supreme Court of the United States as soon as practicable after such judgment is issued.


(d) Statute of limitationNo petition may be filed under this section challenging an order, ruling, determination, or other action of a Federal regulator or State insurance regulator after the later of—(1) the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the first public notice is made of such order, ruling, determination or other action in its final form; or

(2) the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date on which such order, ruling, determination, or other action takes effect.


(e) Standard of reviewThe court shall decide a petition filed under this section based on its</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6714_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing in Court of Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing in Court of Appeals In the case of a regulatory conflict between a State insurance regulator and a Federal regulator regarding insurance issues, including whether a State law, rule, regulation, order, or interpretation regarding any insurance sales or solicitation activity is properly treated as preempted under Federal law, the Federal or State regulator may seek expedited judicial review of such determination by the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the State is located or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit by filing a petition for review in such court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6714_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expedited review The United States Court of Appeals in which a petition for review is filed in accordance with subsection (a) shall complete all action on such petition, including rendering a judgment, before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date on which such petition is filed, unless all parties to such proceeding agree to any extension of such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6714_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supreme Court review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supreme Court review Any request for certiorari to the Supreme Court of the United States of any judgment of a United States Court of Appeals with respect to a petition for review under this section shall be filed with the Supreme Court of the United States as soon as practicable after such judgment is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6714_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statute of limitation No petition may be filed under this section challenging an order, ruling, determination, or other action of a Federal regulator or State insurance regulator after the later of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6714_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Standard of review The court shall decide a petition filed under this section based on its review on the merits of all questions presented under State and Federal law, including the nature of the product or activity and the history and purpose of its regulation under State and Federal law, without unequal deference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>