<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/6802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6802"><akn:num>6802</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations with respect to disclosures of personal information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6802. Obligations with respect to disclosures of personal information(a) Notice requirementsExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a financial institution may not, directly or through any affiliate, disclose to a nonaffiliated third party any nonpublic personal information, unless such financial institution provides or has provided to the consumer a notice that complies with section 6803 of this title.


(b) Opt out(1) In generalA financial institution may not disclose nonpublic personal information to a nonaffiliated third party unless—(A) such financial institution clearly and conspicuously discloses to the consumer, in writing or in electronic form or other form permitted by the regulations prescribed under section 6804 of this title, that such information may be disclosed to such third party;

(B) the consumer is given the opportunity, before the time that such information is initially disclosed, to direct that such information not be disclosed to such third party; and

(C) the consumer is given an explanation of how the consumer can exercise that nondisclosure option.


(2) ExceptionThis subsection shall not prevent a financial institution from providing nonpublic personal information to a nonaffiliated third party to perform services for or functions on behalf of the financial institution, including marketing of the financial institution’s own products or services, or financial products or services offered pursuant to joint agreements between two or more financial institutions that comply with the requirements imposed by the regulations prescribed under section 6804 of this title, if the financial institution fully discloses the providing of such information and enters into a contractual agreement with the third party that requires the third party to maintain the confidentiality of such information.



(c) Limits on reuse of informationExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a nonaffiliated third party that receives from a financial instit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice requirements Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a financial institution may not, directly or through any affiliate, disclose to a nonaffiliated third party any nonpublic personal information, unless such financial institution provides or has provided to the consumer a notice that complies with section 6803 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opt out</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Opt out</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits on reuse of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limits on reuse of information Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, a nonaffiliated third party that receives from a financial institution nonpublic personal information under this section shall not, directly or through an affiliate of such receiving third party, disclose such information to any other person that is a nonaffiliated third party of both the financial institution and such receiving third party, unless such disclosure would be lawful if made directly to such other person by the financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on the sharing of account number information for marketing purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on the sharing of account number information for marketing purposes A financial institution shall not disclose, other than to a consumer reporting agency, an account number or similar form of access number or access code for a credit card account, deposit account, or transaction account of a consumer to any nonaffiliated third party for use in telemarketing, direct mail marketing, or other marketing through electronic mail to the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General exceptions Subsections (a) and (b) shall not prohibit the disclosure of nonpublic personal information—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>