<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/681" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/681/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/681/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_681"><akn:num>681</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 681. Organization(a) Incorporation and charter under State law, period of succession; area of operationsA small business investment company shall be an incorporated body, a limited liability company, or a limited partnership organized and chartered or otherwise existing under State law solely for the purpose of performing the functions and conducting the activities contemplated under this subchapter, which, if incorporated, has succession for a period of not less than thirty years unless sooner dissolved by its shareholders, and if a limited partnership, has succession for a period of not less than ten years, and possesses the powers reasonably necessary to perform such functions and conduct such activities. The area in which the company is to conduct its operations, and the establishment of branch offices or agencies (if authorized by the articles), shall be subject to the approval of the Administration.


(b) Articles of incorporation; approvalThe articles of any small business investment company shall specify in general terms the objects for which the company is formed, the name assumed by such company, the area or areas in which its operations are to be carried on, the place where its principal office is to be located, and the amount and classes of its shares of capital stock. Such articles may contain any other provisions not inconsistent with this chapter that the company may see fit to adopt for the regulation of its business and the conduct of its affairs. Such articles and any amendments thereto adopted from time to time shall be subject to the approval of the Administration.


(c) Issuance of license(1) Submission of applicationEach applicant for a license to operate as a small business investment company under this chapter shall submit to the Administrator an application, in a form and including such documentation as may be prescribed by the Administrator.


(2) Procedures(A) StatusNot later than 90 days after the initial receipt by the Administrator of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation and charter under State law, period of succession; area of operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Incorporation and charter under State law, period of succession; area of operations A small business investment company shall be an incorporated body, a limited liability company, or a limited partnership organized and chartered or otherwise existing under State law solely for the purpose of performing the functions and conducting the activities contemplated under this subchapter, which, if incorporated, has succession for a period of not less than thirty years unless sooner dissolved by its shareholders, and if a limited partnership, has succession for a period of not less than ten years, and possesses the powers reasonably necessary to perform such functions and conduct such activities. The area in which the company is to conduct its operations, and the establishment of branch offices or agencies (if authorized by the articles), shall be subject to the approval of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Articles of incorporation; approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Articles of incorporation; approval The articles of any small business investment company shall specify in general terms the objects for which the company is formed, the name assumed by such company, the area or areas in which its operations are to be carried on, the place where its principal office is to be located, and the amount and classes of its shares of capital stock. Such articles may contain any other provisions not inconsistent with this chapter that the company may see fit to adopt for the regulation of its business and the conduct of its affairs. Such articles and any amendments thereto adopted from time to time shall be subject to the approval of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of license</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–208, div. D, title II, § 208(b)(3)(A), Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–742</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_681_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>