<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/689l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/689l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/689l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_689l"><akn:num>689l</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctions and other orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 689l. Injunctions and other orders(a) In generalWhenever, in the judgment of the Administrator, a New Markets Venture Capital company or any other person has engaged or is about to engage in any acts or practices which constitute or will constitute a violation of any provision of this chapter, or of any rule or regulation under this chapter, or of any order issued under this chapter, the Administrator may make application to the proper district court of the United States or a United States court of any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States for an order enjoining such acts or practices, or for an order enforcing compliance with such provision, rule, regulation, or order, and such courts shall have jurisdiction of such actions and, upon a showing by the Administrator that such New Markets Venture Capital company or other person has engaged or is about to engage in any such acts or practices, a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, shall be granted without bond.


(b) JurisdictionIn any proceeding under subsection (a), the court as a court of equity may, to such extent as it deems necessary, take exclusive jurisdiction of the New Market Venture Capital company and the assets thereof, wherever located, and the court shall have jurisdiction in any such proceeding to appoint a trustee or receiver to hold or administer under the direction of the court the assets so possessed.


(c) Administrator as trustee or receiver(1) AuthorityThe Administrator may act as trustee or receiver of a New Markets Venture Capital company.


(2) AppointmentUpon request of the Administrator, the court may appoint the Administrator to act as a trustee or receiver of a New Markets Venture Capital company unless the court deems such appointment inequitable or otherwise inappropriate by reason of the special circumstances involved.



(Pub. L. 85–699, title III, § 363, as added Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(8) [§ 1(b)(3)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_689l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Whenever, in the judgment of the Administrator, a New Markets Venture Capital company or any other person has engaged or is about to engage in any acts or practices which constitute or will constitute a violation of any provision of this chapter, or of any rule or regulation under this chapter, or of any order issued under this chapter, the Administrator may make application to the proper district court of the United States or a United States court of any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States for an order enjoining such acts or practices, or for an order enforcing compliance with such provision, rule, regulation, or order, and such courts shall have jurisdiction of such actions and, upon a showing by the Administrator that such New Markets Venture Capital company or other person has engaged or is about to engage in any such acts or practices, a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, shall be granted without bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_689l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Jurisdiction In any proceeding under subsection (a), the court as a court of equity may, to such extent as it deems necessary, take exclusive jurisdiction of the New Market Venture Capital company and the assets thereof, wherever located, and the court shall have jurisdiction in any such proceeding to appoint a trustee or receiver to hold or administer under the direction of the court the assets so possessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_689l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator as trustee or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrator as trustee or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>