<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/690" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/690/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/690/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_690"><akn:num>690</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 690. Definitions
In this part:(1) Operational assistanceThe term “operational assistance” means management, marketing, and other technical assistance that assists a small business concern with business development.


(2) Participation agreementThe term “participation agreement” means an agreement, between the Administrator and a company granted final approval under section 690c(e) of this title, that—(A) details the operating plan and investment criteria of the company; and

(B) requires the company to make investments in smaller enterprises primarily engaged in researching, manufacturing, developing, producing, or bringing to market goods, products, or services that generate or support the production of renewable energy.


(3) Renewable energyThe term “renewable energy” means energy derived from resources that are regenerative or that cannot be depleted, including solar, wind, ethanol, and biodiesel fuels.


(4) Renewable Fuel Capital Investment companyThe term “Renewable Fuel Capital Investment company” means a company—(A) that—(i) has been granted final approval by the Administrator under section 690c(e) of this title; and

(ii) has entered into a participation agreement with the Administrator; or


(B) that has received conditional approval under section 690c(c) of this title.


(5) StateThe term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.


(6) Venture capitalThe term “venture capital” means capital in the form of equity capital investments, as that term is defined in section 683(g)(4) of this title.


(Pub. L. 85–699, title III, § 381, as added Pub. L. 110–140, title XII, § 1207, Dec. 19, 2007, 121 Stat. 1774.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePart effective on the date that is 1 day after Dec. 19, 2007, see section</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Operational assistance The term “operational assistance” means management, marketing, and other technical assistance that assists a small business concern with business development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Participation agreement The term “participation agreement” means an agreement, between the Administrator and a company granted final approval under section 690c(e) of this title, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Renewable energy The term “renewable energy” means energy derived from resources that are regenerative or that cannot be depleted, including solar, wind, ethanol, and biodiesel fuels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable Fuel Capital Investment company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Renewable Fuel Capital Investment company The term “Renewable Fuel Capital Investment company” means a company—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) State The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_690_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venture capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Venture capital The term “venture capital” means capital in the form of equity capital investments, as that term is defined in section 683(g)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>