<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/69e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/69e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/69e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_69e"><akn:num>69e</akn:num><akn:heading>Name guide for fur products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 69e. Name guide for fur products(a) Fur Products Name GuideThe Commission shall, with the assistance and cooperation of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, within six months after August 8, 1951, issue, after holding public hearings, a register setting forth the names of hair, fleece, and fur-bearing animals, which shall be known as the Fur Products Name Guide. The names used shall be the true English names for the animals in question, or in the absence of a true English name for an animal, the name by which such animal can be properly identified in the United States.


(b) Additions and deletions; public hearingThe Commission may, from time to time, with the assistance and cooperation of the Department of Agriculture and Department of the Interior, after holding public hearings, add to or delete from such register the name of any hair, fleece, or fur-bearing animal.


(c) Prevention of confusion or deceptionIf the name of an animal (as set forth in the Fur Products Name Guide) connotes a geographical origin or significance other than the true country or place of origin of such animal, the Commission may require whenever such name is used in setting forth the information required by this subchapter, such qualifying statements as it may deem necessary to prevent confusion or deception.


(Aug. 8, 1951, ch. 298, § 7, 65 Stat. 179.)

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain exceptions, to Chairman of such Commission, see Reorg. Plan No. 8 of 1950, § 1, eff. May 24, 1950, 15 F.R. 3175, 64 Stat. 1264, set out under section 41 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_69e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fur Products Name Guide</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fur Products Name Guide The Commission shall, with the assistance and cooperation of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, within six months after August 8, 1951, issue, after holding public hearings, a register setting forth the names of hair, fleece, and fur-bearing animals, which shall be known as the Fur Products Name Guide. The names used shall be the true English names for the animals in question, or in the absence of a true English name for an animal, the name by which such animal can be properly identified in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_69e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additions and deletions; public hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additions and deletions; public hearing The Commission may, from time to time, with the assistance and cooperation of the Department of Agriculture and Department of the Interior, after holding public hearings, add to or delete from such register the name of any hair, fleece, or fur-bearing animal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_69e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of confusion or deception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prevention of confusion or deception If the name of an animal (as set forth in the Fur Products Name Guide) connotes a geographical origin or significance other than the true country or place of origin of such animal, the Commission may require whenever such name is used in setting forth the information required by this subchapter, such qualifying statements as it may deem necessary to prevent confusion or deception.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>