<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7004"><akn:num>7004</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Federal and State governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7004. Applicability to Federal and State governments(a) Filing and access requirementsSubject to subsection (c)(2), nothing in this subchapter limits or supersedes any requirement by a Federal regulatory agency, self-regulatory organization, or State regulatory agency that records be filed with such agency or organization in accordance with specified standards or formats.


(b) Preservation of existing rulemaking authority(1) Use of authority to interpretSubject to paragraph (2) and subsection (c), a Federal regulatory agency or State regulatory agency that is responsible for rulemaking under any other statute may interpret section 7001 of this title with respect to such statute through—(A) the issuance of regulations pursuant to a statute; or

(B) to the extent such agency is authorized by statute to issue orders or guidance, the issuance of orders or guidance of general applicability that are publicly available and published (in the Federal Register in the case of an order or guidance issued by a Federal regulatory agency).


This paragraph does not grant any Federal regulatory agency or State regulatory agency authority to issue regulations, orders, or guidance pursuant to any statute that does not authorize such issuance.

(2) Limitations on interpretation authorityNotwithstanding paragraph (1), a Federal regulatory agency shall not adopt any regulation, order, or guidance described in paragraph (1), and a State regulatory agency is preempted by section 7001 of this title from adopting any regulation, order, or guidance described in paragraph (1), unless—(A) such regulation, order, or guidance is consistent with section 7001 of this title;

(B) such regulation, order, or guidance does not add to the requirements of such section; and

(C) such agency finds, in connection with the issuance of such regulation, order, or guidance, that—(i) there is a substantial justification for the regulation, order, or guidance;

(ii) the methods selected to carry out that purp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing and access requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing and access requirements Subject to subsection (c)(2), nothing in this subchapter limits or supersedes any requirement by a Federal regulatory agency, self-regulatory organization, or State regulatory agency that records be filed with such agency or organization in accordance with specified standards or formats.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of existing rulemaking authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preservation of existing rulemaking authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7004_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7004_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to exempt from consent provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority to exempt from consent provision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7004_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic letters of agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Electronic letters of agency The Federal Communications Commission shall not hold any contract for telecommunications service or letter of agency for a preferred carrier change, that otherwise complies with the Commission’s rules, to be legally ineffective, invalid, or unenforceable solely because an electronic record or electronic signature was used in its formation or authorization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>