<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70d"><akn:num>70d</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70d. Records(a) Maintenance and preservation by manufacturerEvery manufacturer of textile fiber products subject to this subchapter shall maintain proper records showing the fiber content as required by this subchapter of all such products made by him, and shall preserve such records for at least three years.


(b) Maintenance and preservation by person substituting stamp, tag, etc.Any person substituting a stamp, tag, label, or other identification pursuant to section 70c(b) of this title shall keep such records as will show the information set forth on the stamp, tag, label, or other identification that he removed and the name or names of the person or persons from whom such textile fiber product was received, and shall preserve such records for at least three years.


(c) Neglect or refusal to maintain or preserve recordsThe neglect or refusal to maintain or preserve the records required by this section is unlawful, and any person neglecting or refusing to maintain such records shall be guilty of an unfair method of competition, and an unfair or deceptive act or practice, in commerce, under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].


(Pub. L. 85–897, § 6, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1721.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, 38 Stat. 717, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 58 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and preservation by manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maintenance and preservation by manufacturer Every manufacturer of textile fiber products subject to this subchapter shall maintain proper records showing the fiber content as required by this subchapter of all such products made by him, and shall preserve such records for at least three years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and preservation by person substituting stamp, tag, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance and preservation by person substituting stamp, tag, etc. Any person substituting a stamp, tag, label, or other identification pursuant to section 70c(b) of this title shall keep such records as will show the information set forth on the stamp, tag, label, or other identification that he removed and the name or names of the person or persons from whom such textile fiber product was received, and shall preserve such records for at least three years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Neglect or refusal to maintain or preserve records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Neglect or refusal to maintain or preserve records The neglect or refusal to maintain or preserve the records required by this section is unlawful, and any person neglecting or refusing to maintain such records shall be guilty of an unfair method of competition, and an unfair or deceptive act or practice, in commerce, under the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>