<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/70h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70h"><akn:num>70h</akn:num><akn:heading>Guaranty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70h. Guaranty(a) Avoidance of liability; requirementsNo person shall be guilty of an unlawful act under section 70a of this title if he establishes a guaranty received in good faith, signed by and containing the name and address of the person residing in the United States by whom the textile fiber product guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received, that said product is not misbranded or falsely invoiced under the provisions of this subchapter. Said guaranty shall be (1) a separate guaranty specifically designating the textile fiber product guaranteed, in which case it may be on the invoice or other paper relating to said product; or (2) a continuing guaranty given by seller to the buyer applicable to all textile fiber products sold to or to be sold to buyer by seller in a form as the Commission, by rules and regulations, may prescribe; or (3) a continuing guaranty filed with the Commission applicable to all textile fiber products handled by a guarantor in such form as the Commission by rules and regulations may prescribe.


(b) Furnishing false guarantyThe furnishing of a false guaranty, except where the person furnishing such false guaranty relies on a guaranty to the same effect received in good faith signed by and containing the name and address of the person residing in the United States by whom the product guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received, is unlawful, and shall be an unfair method of competition, and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, in commerce, within the meaning of the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].


(Pub. L. 85–897, § 10, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1722.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, 38 Stat. 717, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 58 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Avoidance of liability; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Avoidance of liability; requirements No person shall be guilty of an unlawful act under section 70a of this title if he establishes a guaranty received in good faith, signed by and containing the name and address of the person residing in the United States by whom the textile fiber product guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received, that said product is not misbranded or falsely invoiced under the provisions of this subchapter. Said guaranty shall be (1) a separate guaranty specifically designating the textile fiber product guaranteed, in which case it may be on the invoice or other paper relating to said product; or (2) a continuing guaranty given by seller to the buyer applicable to all textile fiber products sold to or to be sold to buyer by seller in a form as the Commission, by rules and regulations, may prescribe; or (3) a continuing guaranty filed with the Commission applicable to all textile fiber products handled by a guarantor in such form as the Commission </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing false guaranty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Furnishing false guaranty The furnishing of a false guaranty, except where the person furnishing such false guaranty relies on a guaranty to the same effect received in good faith signed by and containing the name and address of the person residing in the United States by whom the product guaranteed was manufactured or from whom it was received, is unlawful, and shall be an unfair method of competition, and an unfair and deceptive act or practice, in commerce, within the meaning of the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>