<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7101"><akn:num>7101</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Interagency Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7101. Establishment of the Interagency Committee
There is established an interagency committee to be known as the Interagency Committee on Women’s Business Enterprise.
(Pub. L. 100–533, title IV, § 401, as added Pub. L. 103–403, title IV, § 413, Oct. 22, 1994, 108 Stat. 4193.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 401 of Pub. L. 100–533, title IV, Oct. 25, 1988, 102 Stat. 2694, related to the establishment of the National Women’s Business Council, prior to the general amendment of title IV of Pub. L. 100–533 by Pub. L. 103–403. See section 7105 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2000 AmendmentPub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(9) [title VII, § 701], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–701, provided that: “This title [amending sections 7107, 7109, and 7110 of this title and repealing former section 7109 of this title] may be cited as the ‘National Women’s Business Council Reauthorization Act of 2000’.”


Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 12138. National Women’s Business Enterprise Policy and National Program for Women’s Business Enterprise
Ex. Ord. No. 12138, May 18, 1979, 44 F.R. 29637, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12608, Sept. 9, 1987, 52 F.R. 34617, provided:
In response to the findings of the Interagency Task Force on Women Business Owners and congressional findings that recognize:
1. the significant role which small business and women entrepreneurs can play in promoting full employment and balanced growth in our economy;
2. the many obstacles facing women entrepreneurs; and
3. the need to aid and stimulate women’s business enterprise;
By the authority vested in me as President of the United States of America, in order to create a National Women’s Business Enterprise Policy and to prescribe arrangements for developing, coordinating and implementing a national program for women’s business enterprise, it is ordered as follows:

1–1. Responsibilities of the Federal Departments and Agencies1–101. Within the constraints of statuto</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>