<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7102"><akn:num>7102</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Interagency Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7102. Duties of the Interagency Committee(a) In generalThe Interagency Committee shall—(1) monitor, coordinate, and promote the plans, programs, and operations of the departments and agencies of the Federal Government that may contribute to the establishment and growth of women’s business enterprise;

(2) develop and promote new public sector initiatives, policies, programs, and plans designed to foster women’s business enterprise;

(3) review, monitor, and coordinate plans and programs, developed in the public sector, which affect the ability of women-owned businesses to obtain capital and credit;

(4) promote and assist, as appropriate, in the development of surveys of women-owned business; and

(5) design a comprehensive plan for a joint public-private sector effort to facilitate growth and development of women’s business enterprise, which plan shall, not later than 1 year after October 22, 1994, be submitted to the President for review.


(b) MeetingsThe Interagency Committee shall meet not less than biannually at such times as the Interagency Committee determines to be necessary to perform the duties under subsection (a). A majority of the members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum for the approval of recommendations or reports issued pursuant to this section.


(c) Interaction with CouncilIn performing its duties under subsection (a), the Interagency Committee shall consult with the Council. The Interagency Committee may meet jointly with the Council at the discretion of the chairperson of the Interagency Committee and the chairperson of the Council, but not less frequently than twice annually. The chairperson of the Interagency Committee shall serve as chairperson of any joint meetings of the Interagency Committee and the Council.


(Pub. L. 100–533, title IV, § 402, as added Pub. L. 103–403, title IV, § 413, Oct. 22, 1994, 108 Stat. 4193.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 402 of Pub. L. 100–533, title IV, Oct. 25, 1988, 102 Stat. 26</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Interagency Committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Meetings The Interagency Committee shall meet not less than biannually at such times as the Interagency Committee determines to be necessary to perform the duties under subsection (a). A majority of the members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum for the approval of recommendations or reports issued pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interaction with Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interaction with Council In performing its duties under subsection (a), the Interagency Committee shall consult with the Council. The Interagency Committee may meet jointly with the Council at the discretion of the chairperson of the Interagency Committee and the chairperson of the Council, but not less frequently than twice annually. The chairperson of the Interagency Committee shall serve as chairperson of any joint meetings of the Interagency Committee and the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>