<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7106"><akn:num>7106</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7106. Duties of the Council(a) In generalThe Council shall advise and consult with the Interagency Committee on matters relating to the activities, functions, and policies of the Interagency Committee, as provided in this chapter. The Council shall meet jointly with the Interagency Committee at the discretion of the chairperson of the Council and the chairperson of the Interagency Committee, but not less than biannually.


(b) MeetingsThe Council shall meet separately at such times as the Council deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum for the approval of recommendations or reports issued pursuant to this section.


(c) RecommendationsThe Council shall make annual recommendations for consideration by the Interagency Committee. The Council shall also provide reports and make such other recommendations as it deems appropriate to the Interagency Committee, to the President, to the Administrator (through the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Women’s Business Ownership), and to the Committees on Small Business of the Senate and the House of Representatives.


(d) Other dutiesThe Council shall—(1) review, coordinate, and monitor plans and programs developed in the public and private sectors, which affect the ability of women-owned business enterprises to obtain capital and credit;

(2) promote and assist in the development of a women’s business census and other surveys of women-owned businesses;

(3) monitor and promote the plans, programs, and operations of the departments and agencies of the Federal Government which may contribute to the establishment and growth of women’s business enterprise;

(4) develop and promote new initiatives, policies, programs, and plans designed to foster women’s business enterprise;

(5) advise and consult with the Interagency Committee in the design of a comprehensive plan for a joint public-private sector effort to facilitate growth and development of women’s business enterprise; 11 So i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Council shall advise and consult with the Interagency Committee on matters relating to the activities, functions, and policies of the Interagency Committee, as provided in this chapter. The Council shall meet jointly with the Interagency Committee at the discretion of the chairperson of the Council and the chairperson of the Interagency Committee, but not less than biannually.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Meetings The Council shall meet separately at such times as the Council deems necessary. A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum for the approval of recommendations or reports issued pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendations The Council shall make annual recommendations for consideration by the Interagency Committee. The Council shall also provide reports and make such other recommendations as it deems appropriate to the Interagency Committee, to the President, to the Administrator (through the Assistant Administrator of the Office of Women’s Business Ownership), and to the Committees on Small Business of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other duties The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of transmittal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Form of transmittal The information included in each report under subsection (d) that is described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (d)(6), shall be reported verbatim, together with any separate additional, concurring, or dissenting views of the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>