<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_717n"><akn:num>717n</akn:num><akn:heading>Process coordination; hearings; rules of procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 717n. Process coordination; hearings; rules of procedure(a) DefinitionIn this section, the term “Federal authorization”—(1) means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to an application for authorization under section 717b of this title or a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 717f of this title; and

(2) includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to an application for authorization under section 717b of this title or a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 717f of this title.


(b) Designation as lead agency(1) In generalThe Commission shall act as the lead agency for the purposes of coordinating all applicable Federal authorizations and for the purposes of complying with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(2) Other agenciesEach Federal and State agency considering an aspect of an application for Federal authorization shall cooperate with the Commission and comply with the deadlines established by the Commission.



(c) Schedule(1) Commission authority to set scheduleThe Commission shall establish a schedule for all Federal authorizations. In establishing the schedule, the Commission shall—(A) ensure expeditious completion of all such proceedings; and

(B) comply with applicable schedules established by Federal law.


(2) Failure to meet scheduleIf a Federal or State administrative agency does not complete a proceeding for an approval that is required for a Federal authorization in accordance with the schedule established by the Commission, the applicant may pursue remedies under section 717r(d) of this title.



(d) Consolidated recordThe Commission shall, with the cooperation of Federal and State administrative agencies and officials, maintain a complete consolidated record of all decisions made or actions taken by the Commission or by a Federal administ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this section, the term “Federal authorization”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation as lead agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation as lead agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Schedule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consolidated record The Commission shall, with the cooperation of Federal and State administrative agencies and officials, maintain a complete consolidated record of all decisions made or actions taken by the Commission or by a Federal administrative agency or officer (or State administrative agency or officer acting under delegated Federal authority) with respect to any Federal authorization. Such record shall be the record for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings; parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hearings; parties Hearings under this chapter may be held before the Commission, any member or members thereof, or any representative of the Commission designated by it, and appropriate records thereof shall be kept. In any proceeding before it, the Commission in accordance with such rules and regulations as it may prescribe, may admit as a party any interested State, State commission, municipality or any representative of interested consumers or security holders, or any competitor of a party to such proceeding, or any other person whose participation in the proceeding may be in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedure All hearings, investigations, and proceedings under this chapter shall be governed by rules of practice and procedure to be adopted by the Commission, and in the conduct thereof the technical rules of evidence need not be applied. No informality in any hearing, investigation, or proceeding or in the manner of taking testimony shall invalidate any order, decision, rule, or regulation issued under the authority of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>