<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/717y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_717y"><akn:num>717y</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary conversion of natural gas users to heavy fuel oil</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 717y. Voluntary conversion of natural gas users to heavy fuel oil(a) Transfer of contractual interests(1) In order to facilitate voluntary conversion of facilities from the use of natural gas to the use of heavy petroleum fuel oil, the Commission shall, by rule, provide a procedure for the approval by the Commission of any transfer to any person described in paragraph 2(B)(i), (ii), or (iii) of contractual interests involving the receipt of natural gas described in paragraph 2(A).

(2)(A) The rule required under paragraph (1) shall apply to—(i) natural gas—(I) received by the user pursuant to a contract entered into before September 1, 1977, not including any renewal or extension thereof entered into on or after such date other than any such extension or renewal pursuant to the exercise by such user of an option to extend or renew such contract;

(II) other than natural gas the sale for resale or the transportation of which was subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Power Commission under the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.] as of September 1, 1977;

(III) which was used as a fuel in any facility in existence on September 1, 1977.


(ii) natural gas subject to a prohibition order issued under section 717z of this title.


(B) The rule required under paragraph (1) shall permit the transfer of contractual interests—(i) to any interstate pipeline;

(ii) to any local distribution company served by an interstate pipeline; and

(iii) to any person served by an interstate pipeline for a high priority use by such person.



(3) The rule required under paragraph (1) shall provide that any transfer of contractual interests pursuant to such rule shall be under such terms and conditions as the Commission may prescribe. Such rule shall include a requirement for refund of any consideration, received by the person transferring contractual interests pursuant to such rule, to the extent such consideration exceeds the amount by which the costs actually incurred, during t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of contractual interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of contractual interests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commission approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on transfers unenforceable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restrictions on transfers unenforceable Any provision of any contract, which provision prohibits any transfer of any contractual interests thereunder, or any commingling or transportation of natural gas subject to such contract with natural gas the sale for resale or transportation of which is subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.], or terminates such contract on the basis of any such transfer, commingling, or transportation, shall be unenforceable in any court of the United States and in any court of any State if applied with respect to any transfer approved under the rule required under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractual obligations unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contractual obligations unaffected The person acquiring contractual interests transferred pursuant to the rule required under subsection (a)(1) shall assume the contractual obligations which the person transferring such contractual interests has under such contract. This section shall not relieve the person transferring such contractual interests from any contractual obligation of such person under such contract if such obligation is not performed by the person acquiring such contractual interests.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with the Natural Gas Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with the Natural Gas Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717y_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volume limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Volume limitation No supplier of natural gas under any contract, with respect to which contractual interests have been transferred pursuant to the rule required under subsection (a)(1), shall be required to supply natural gas during any relevant period in volume amounts which exceed the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>