<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_719f"><akn:num>719f</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 719f. Congressional review(a) Effectiveness of decision designating transportation system for approval upon enactment of joint resolutionAny decision under section 719e(a) of this title or subsection (b) designating for approval a transportation system for the delivery of Alaska natural gas shall take effect upon enactment of a joint resolution within the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress beginning on the date after the date of receipt by the Senate and House of Representatives of a decision transmitted pursuant to section 719e(b) of this title or subsection (b) of this section.


(b) New decision: statement of reasons for proposal; transmittal to CongressIf the Congress does not enact such a joint resolution within such 60-day period, the President, not later than the end of the 30th day following the expiration of the 60-day period, may propose a new decision and shall provide a detailed statement concerning the reasons for such proposal. The new decision shall be submitted in accordance with section 719e(a) of this title and transmitted to the House of Representatives and the Senate on the same day while both are in session and shall take effect pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. In the event that a resolution respecting the President’s decision was defeated by vote of either House, no new decision may be transmitted pursuant to this subsection unless such decision differs in a material respect from the previous decision.


(c) Sessions of CongressFor purposes of this section—(1) continuity of session of Congress is broken only by an adjournment sine die; and

(2) the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of the 60-day calendar period.


(d) Rules under rulemaking powers of Congress; change of rules; “resolution” defined; referral to Congressional committees; debate limitation; motion for consideration of resolution; de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness of decision designating transportation system for approval upon enactment of joint resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Effectiveness of decision designating transportation system for approval upon enactment of joint resolution Any decision under section 719e(a) of this title or subsection (b) designating for approval a transportation system for the delivery of Alaska natural gas shall take effect upon enactment of a joint resolution within the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress beginning on the date after the date of receipt by the Senate and House of Representatives of a decision transmitted pursuant to section 719e(b) of this title or subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New decision: statement of reasons for proposal; transmittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New decision: statement of reasons for proposal; transmittal to Congress If the Congress does not enact such a joint resolution within such 60-day period, the President, not later than the end of the 30th day following the expiration of the 60-day period, may propose a new decision and shall provide a detailed statement concerning the reasons for such proposal. The new decision shall be submitted in accordance with section 719e(a) of this title and transmitted to the House of Representatives and the Senate on the same day while both are in session and shall take effect pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. In the event that a resolution respecting the President’s decision was defeated by vote of either House, no new decision may be transmitted pursuant to this subsection unless such decision differs in a material respect from the previous decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sessions of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sessions of Congress For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules under rulemaking powers of Congress; change of rules; “resolution” defined; referral to Congressional committees; debate limitation; motion for consideration of resolution; debate on resolution; nondebatable motions and appeals from procedural decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules under rulemaking powers of Congress; change of rules; “resolution” defined; referral to Congressional committees; debate limitation; motion for consideration of resolution; debate on resolution; nondebatable motions and appeals from procedural decisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential finding respecting and supplementation or modification of environmental impact statement; submittal to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Presidential finding respecting and supplementation or modification of environmental impact statement; submittal to Congressional committees The President shall find that any required environmental impact statement relative to the Alaska natural gas transportation system designated for approval by the President has been prepared and that such statement is in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.]. Such finding shall be set forth in the report of the President submitted under section 719e of this title. The President may supplement or modify the environmental impact statements prepared by the Commission or other Federal officers or agencies. Any such environmental impact statement shall be submitted contemporaneously with the transmittal to the Senate and House of Representatives of the President’s decision pursuant to section 719e(b) of this title or subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of Commission: submittal to Congress; Council on Environmental Quality: hearings, report, submittal to Congress; Congressional committee hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report of Commission: submittal to Congress; Council on Environmental Quality: hearings, report, submittal to Congress; Congressional committee hearings Within 20 days of the transmittal of the President’s decision to the Congress under section 719e(b) of this title or under subsection (b) of this section, (1) the Commission shall submit to the Congress a report commenting on the decision and including any information with regard to that decision which the Commission considers appropriate, and (2) the Council on Environmental Quality shall provide an opportunity to any interested person to present oral and written data, views, and arguments on any environmental impact statement submitted by the President relative to any system designated by him for approval which is different from any system reported on by the Commission under section 719c(c) of this title, and shall submit to the Congress a report summarizing any such views received. The committees in each House of Congress to whi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver; submittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Waiver; submittal to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>