<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/719i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_719i"><akn:num>719i</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 719i. Supplemental enforcement authority(a) Compliance order or civil actionIn addition to remedies available under other applicable provisions of law, whenever any Federal officer or agency determines that any person is in violation of any applicable provision of law administered or enforceable by such officer or agency or any rule, regulation, or order under such provision, including any term or condition of any certificate, right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization, issued or granted by such officer or agency, such officer or agency may—(1) issue a compliance order requiring such person to comply with such provision or any rule, regulation, or order thereunder, or

(2) bring a civil action in accordance with subsection (c).


(b) Specificity of compliance orderAny order issued under subsection (a) shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation and a time of compliance, not to exceed 30 days, which the officer or agency, as the case may be, determines is reasonable, taking into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with applicable requirements.


(c) Appropriate relief and jurisdiction of civil actionUpon a request of such officer or agency, as the case may be, the Attorney General may commence a civil action for appropriate relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction or a civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 per day for violations of the compliance order issued under subsection (a). Any action under this subsection may be brought in any district court of the United States for the district in which the defendant is located, resides, or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to restrain such violation, require compliance, or impose such penalty or give ancillary relief.


(Pub. L. 94–586, § 11, Oct. 22, 1976, 90 Stat. 2914.)

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Enforcement functions authorized by, and supplemental enforcement authority created by this chapter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance order or civil action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance order or civil action In addition to remedies available under other applicable provisions of law, whenever any Federal officer or agency determines that any person is in violation of any applicable provision of law administered or enforceable by such officer or agency or any rule, regulation, or order under such provision, including any term or condition of any certificate, right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization, issued or granted by such officer or agency, such officer or agency may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specificity of compliance order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specificity of compliance order Any order issued under subsection (a) shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation and a time of compliance, not to exceed 30 days, which the officer or agency, as the case may be, determines is reasonable, taking into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with applicable requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate relief and jurisdiction of civil action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriate relief and jurisdiction of civil action Upon a request of such officer or agency, as the case may be, the Attorney General may commence a civil action for appropriate relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction or a civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 per day for violations of the compliance order issued under subsection (a). Any action under this subsection may be brought in any district court of the United States for the district in which the defendant is located, resides, or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to restrain such violation, require compliance, or impose such penalty or give ancillary relief.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>