<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7201"><akn:num>7201</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7201. Definitions
Except as otherwise specifically provided in this Act, in this Act, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Appropriate State regulatory authorityThe term “appropriate State regulatory authority” means the State agency or other authority responsible for the licensure or other regulation of the practice of accounting in the State or States having jurisdiction over a registered public accounting firm or associated person thereof, with respect to the matter in question.


(2) AuditThe term “audit” means an examination of the financial statements of any issuer by an independent public accounting firm in accordance with the rules of the Board or the Commission (or, for the period preceding the adoption of applicable rules of the Board under section 7213 of this title, in accordance with then-applicable generally accepted auditing and related standards for such purposes), for the purpose of expressing an opinion on such statements.


(3) Audit committeeThe term “audit committee” means—(A) a committee (or equivalent body) established by and amongst the board of directors of an issuer for the purpose of overseeing the accounting and financial reporting processes of the issuer and audits of the financial statements of the issuer; and

(B) if no such committee exists with respect to an issuer, the entire board of directors of the issuer.


(4) Audit reportThe term “audit report” means a document or other record—(A) prepared following an audit performed for purposes of compliance by an issuer with the requirements of the securities laws; and

(B) in which a public accounting firm either—(i) sets forth the opinion of that firm regarding a financial statement, report, or other document; or

(ii) asserts that no such opinion can be expressed.



(5) BoardThe term “Board” means the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board established under section 7211 of this title.


(6) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.


(7) Is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate State regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate State regulatory authority The term “appropriate State regulatory authority” means the State agency or other authority responsible for the licensure or other regulation of the practice of accounting in the State or States having jurisdiction over a registered public accounting firm or associated person thereof, with respect to the matter in question.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Audit The term “audit” means an examination of the financial statements of any issuer by an independent public accounting firm in accordance with the rules of the Board or the Commission (or, for the period preceding the adoption of applicable rules of the Board under section 7213 of this title, in accordance with then-applicable generally accepted auditing and related standards for such purposes), for the purpose of expressing an opinion on such statements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Audit committee The term “audit committee” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Audit report The term “audit report” means a document or other record—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Board The term “Board” means the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board established under section 7211 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Commission The term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Issuer The term “issuer” means an issuer (as defined in section 78c of this title), the securities of which are registered under section 78l of this title, or that is required to file reports under section 78o(d) of this title, or that files or has filed a registration statement that has not yet become effective under the Securities Act of 1933 (15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.), and that it has not withdrawn.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-audit services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Non-audit services The term “non-audit services” means any professional services provided to an issuer by a registered public accounting firm, other than those provided to an issuer in connection with an audit or a review of the financial statements of an issuer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person associated with a public accounting firm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Person associated with a public accounting firm</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7201_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Professional standards The term “professional standards” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>