<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_720a"><akn:num>720a</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of certificate of public convenience and necessity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 720a. Issuance of certificate of public convenience and necessity(a) Authority of the CommissionNotwithstanding the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Act of 1976 (15 U.S.C. 719 et seq.), the Commission may, in accordance with section 7(c) of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717f(c)), consider and act on an application for the issuance of a certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing the construction and operation of an Alaska natural gas transportation project other than the Alaska natural gas transportation system.


(b) Issuance of certificate(1) In generalThe Commission shall issue a certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing the construction and operation of an Alaska natural gas transportation project under this section if the applicant has satisfied the requirements of section 7(e) of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717f(e)).


(2) ConsiderationsIn considering an application under this section, the Commission shall presume that—(A) a public need exists to construct and operate the proposed Alaska natural gas transportation project; and

(B) sufficient downstream capacity will exist to transport the Alaska natural gas moving through the project to markets in the contiguous United States.



(c) Expedited approval processNot later than 60 days after the date of issuance of the final environmental impact statement under section 720b of this title for an Alaska natural gas transportation project, the Commission shall issue a final order granting or denying any application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity for the project under section 7(c) of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717f(c)) and this section.


(d) Prohibition of certain pipeline routeNo license, permit, lease, right-of-way, authorization, or other approval required under Federal law for the construction of any pipeline to transport natural gas from land within the Prudhoe Bay oil and gas lease area may be granted for any pipeline that follows a route that</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of the Commission Notwithstanding the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Act of 1976 (15 U.S.C. 719 et seq.), the Commission may, in accordance with section 7(c) of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717f(c)), consider and act on an application for the issuance of a certificate of public convenience and necessity authorizing the construction and operation of an Alaska natural gas transportation project other than the Alaska natural gas transportation system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Issuance of certificate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited approval process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expedited approval process Not later than 60 days after the date of issuance of the final environmental impact statement under section 720b of this title for an Alaska natural gas transportation project, the Commission shall issue a final order granting or denying any application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity for the project under section 7(c) of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717f(c)) and this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of certain pipeline route</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of certain pipeline route No license, permit, lease, right-of-way, authorization, or other approval required under Federal law for the construction of any pipeline to transport natural gas from land within the Prudhoe Bay oil and gas lease area may be granted for any pipeline that follows a route that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Open season</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Open season</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects in the contiguous United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Projects in the contiguous United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of in-State needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study of in-State needs The holder of the certificate of public convenience and necessity issued, modified, or amended by the Commission for an Alaska natural gas transportation project shall demonstrate that the holder has conducted a study of Alaska in-State needs, including tie-in points along the Alaska natural gas transportation project for in-State access.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska royalty gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Alaska royalty gas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Commission may issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>