<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/720d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_720d"><akn:num>720d</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 720d. Federal Coordinator(a) EstablishmentThere is established, as an independent office in the executive branch, the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects.


(b) Federal Coordinator(1) AppointmentThe Office shall be headed by a Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, to serve a term to last until 1 year following the completion of the project referred to in section 720a of this title.


(2) CompensationThe Federal Coordinator shall be compensated at the rate prescribed for level III of the Executive Schedule (5 U.S.C. 5314).



(c) DutiesThe Federal Coordinator shall be responsible for—(1) coordinating the expeditious discharge of all activities by Federal agencies with respect to an Alaska natural gas transportation project; and

(2) ensuring the compliance of Federal agencies with the provisions of this chapter.


(d) Reviews and actions of other Federal agencies(1) Expedited reviews and actionsAll reviews conducted and actions taken by any Federal agency relating to an Alaska natural gas transportation project authorized under this section shall be expedited, in a manner consistent with completion of the necessary reviews and approvals by the deadlines under this chapter.


(2) Prohibition of certain terms and conditionsNo Federal agency may include in any certificate, right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization issued to an Alaska natural gas transportation project any term or condition that may be permitted, but is not required, by any applicable law if the Federal Coordinator determines that the term or condition would prevent or impair in any significant respect the expeditious construction and operation, or an expansion, of the Alaska natural gas transportation project.


(3) Prohibition of certain actionsUnless required by law, no Federal agency shall add to, amend, or abrogate any certi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established, as an independent office in the executive branch, the Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal Coordinator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Federal Coordinator shall be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews and actions of other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reviews and actions of other Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Federal Inspector functions and authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of Federal Inspector functions and authority On appointment of the Federal Coordinator by the President, all of the functions and authority of the Office of Federal Inspector of Construction for the Alaska Natural Gas Transportation System vested in the Secretary under section 3012(b) of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (15 U.S.C. 719e note; Public Law 102–486), including all functions and authority described and enumerated in the Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1979 (44 Fed. Reg. 33663), Executive Order No. 12142 of June 21, 1979 (44 Fed. Reg. 36927), and section 5 of the President’s decision, shall be transferred to the Federal Coordinator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Temporary authority The functions, authorities, duties, and responsibilities of the Federal Coordinator shall be vested in the Secretary until the earlier of the appointment of the Federal Coordinator by the President, or 18 months after October 13, 2004.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_720d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>