<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7216" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7216/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7216/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7216"><akn:num>7216</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign public accounting firms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7216. Foreign public accounting firms(a) Applicability to certain foreign firms(1) In generalAny foreign public accounting firm that prepares or furnishes an audit report with respect to any issuer, broker, or dealer, shall be subject to this Act and the rules of the Board and the Commission issued under this Act, in the same manner and to the same extent as a public accounting firm that is organized and operates under the laws of the United States or any State, except that registration pursuant to section 7212 of this title shall not by itself provide a basis for subjecting such a foreign public accounting firm to the jurisdiction of the Federal or State courts, other than with respect to controversies between such firms and the Board.


(2) Board authorityThe Board may, by rule, determine that a foreign public accounting firm (or a class of such firms) that does not issue audit reports nonetheless plays such a substantial role in the preparation and furnishing of such reports for particular issuers, brokers, or dealers, that it is necessary or appropriate, in light of the purposes of this Act and in the public interest or for the protection of investors, that such firm (or class of firms) should be treated as a public accounting firm (or firms) for purposes of registration under, and oversight by the Board in accordance with, this subchapter.



(b) Production of documents(1) Production by foreign firmsIf a foreign public accounting firm performs material services upon which a registered public accounting firm relies in the conduct of an audit or interim review, issues an audit report, performs audit work, or conducts interim reviews, the foreign public accounting firm shall—(A) produce the audit work papers of the foreign public accounting firm and all other documents of the firm related to any such audit work or interim review to the Commission or the Board, upon request of the Commission or the Board; and

(B) be subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to certain foreign firms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability to certain foreign firms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production of documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Production of documents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption authority The Commission, and the Board, subject to the approval of the Commission, may, by rule, regulation, or order, and as the Commission (or Board) determines necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, either unconditionally or upon specified terms and conditions exempt any foreign public accounting firm, or any class of such firms, from any provision of this Act or the rules of the Board or the Commission issued under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of requests or process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service of requests or process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sanctions A willful refusal to comply, in whole in or in part, with any request by the Commission or the Board under this section, shall be deemed a violation of this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other means of satisfying production obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other means of satisfying production obligations Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, the staff of the Commission or the Board may allow a foreign public accounting firm that is subject to this section to meet production obligations under this section through alternate means, such as through foreign counterparts of the Commission or the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7216_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition In this section, the term “foreign public accounting firm” means a public accounting firm that is organized and operates under the laws of a foreign government or political subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>