<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7218"><akn:num>7218</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7218. Accounting standards(a) Omitted

(b) Commission authorityThe Commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations to carry out section 77s(b) of this title as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.


(c) No effect on Commission powersNothing in this Act, including this section and the amendment made by this section, shall be construed to impair or limit the authority of the Commission to establish accounting principles or standards for purposes of enforcement of the securities laws.


(d) Study and report on adopting principles-based accounting(1) Study(A) In generalThe Commission shall conduct a study on the adoption by the United States financial reporting system of a principles-based accounting system.


(B) Study topicsThe study required by subparagraph (A) shall include an examination of—(i) the extent to which principles-based accounting and financial reporting exists in the United States;

(ii) the length of time required for change from a rules-based to a principles-based financial reporting system;

(iii) the feasibility of and proposed methods by which a principles-based system may be implemented; and

(iv) a thorough economic analysis of the implementation of a principles-based system.



(2) ReportNot later than 1 year after July 30, 2002, the Commission shall submit a report on the results of the study required by paragraph (1) to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.



(Pub. L. 107–204, title I, § 108, July 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 768.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is Pub. L. 107–204, July 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 745, known as the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
Section is comprised of section 108 of Pub. L. 107–204. Subsec. (a) of section 108 of Pub. L. 107–204 amended section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commission authority The Commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations to carry out section 77s(b) of this title as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on Commission powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No effect on Commission powers Nothing in this Act, including this section and the amendment made by this section, shall be construed to impair or limit the authority of the Commission to establish accounting principles or standards for purposes of enforcement of the securities laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7218_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report on adopting principles-based accounting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Study and report on adopting principles-based accounting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>