<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7401"><akn:num>7401</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7401. Findings
The Congress finds the following:(1) Revolutionary advancements in computing and communications technology have interconnected government, commercial, scientific, and educational infrastructures—including critical infrastructures for electric power, natural gas and petroleum production and distribution, telecommunications, transportation, water supply, banking and finance, and emergency and government services—in a vast, interdependent physical and electronic network.

(2) Exponential increases in interconnectivity have facilitated enhanced communications, economic growth, and the delivery of services critical to the public welfare, but have also increased the consequences of temporary or prolonged failure.

(3) A Department of Defense Joint Task Force concluded after a 1997 United States information warfare exercise that the results “clearly demonstrated our lack of preparation for a coordinated cyber and physical attack on our critical military and civilian infrastructure”.

(4) Computer security technology and systems implementation lack—(A) sufficient long term research funding;

(B) adequate coordination across Federal and State government agencies and among government, academia, and industry; and

(C) sufficient numbers of outstanding researchers in the field.


(5) Accordingly, Federal investment in computer and network security research and development must be significantly increased to—(A) improve vulnerability assessment and technological and systems solutions;

(B) expand and improve the pool of information security professionals, including researchers, in the United States workforce; and

(C) better coordinate information sharing and collaboration among industry, government, and academic research projects.


(6) While African-Americans, Hispanics, and Native Americans constitute 25 percent of the total United States workforce and 30 percent of the college-age population, members of these minorities comprise less than 7 percent of the Uni</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Revolutionary advancements in computing and communications technology have interconnected government, commercial, scientific, and educational infrastructures—including critical infrastructures for electric power, natural gas and petroleum production and distribution, telecommunications, transportation, water supply, banking and finance, and emergency and government services—in a vast, interdependent physical and electronic network.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Exponential increases in interconnectivity have facilitated enhanced communications, economic growth, and the delivery of services critical to the public welfare, but have also increased the consequences of temporary or prolonged failure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) A Department of Defense Joint Task Force concluded after a 1997 United States information warfare exercise that the results “clearly demonstrated our lack of preparation for a coordinated cyber and physical attack on our critical military and civilian infrastructure”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Computer security technology and systems implementation lack—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Accordingly, Federal investment in computer and network security research and development must be significantly increased to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) While African-Americans, Hispanics, and Native Americans constitute 25 percent of the total United States workforce and 30 percent of the college-age population, members of these minorities comprise less than 7 percent of the United States computer and information science workforce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>