<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7505"><akn:num>7505</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7505. Authorization of appropriations(a) National Science FoundationThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation to carry out the Director’s responsibilities under this chapter—(1) $385,000,000 for fiscal year 2005;

(2) $424,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(3) $449,000,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(4) $476,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(b) Department of EnergyThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out the Secretary’s responsibilities under this chapter—(1) $317,000,000 for fiscal year 2005;

(2) $347,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(3) $380,000,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(4) $415,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(c) National Aeronautics and Space AdministrationThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to carry out the Administrator’s responsibilities under this chapter—(1) $34,100,000 for fiscal year 2005;

(2) $37,500,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(3) $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(4) $42,300,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(d) National Institute of Standards and TechnologyThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to carry out the Director’s responsibilities under this chapter—(1) $68,200,000 for fiscal year 2005;

(2) $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(3) $80,000,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(4) $84,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(e) Environmental Protection AgencyThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out the Administrator’s responsibilities under this chapter—(1) $5,500,000 for fiscal year 2005;

(2) $6,050,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(3) $6,413,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(4) $6,800,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(Pub. L. 108–153, § 6, Dec. 3, 2003, 117 Stat. 1929.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Science Foundation There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Science Foundation to carry out the Director’s responsibilities under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Department of Energy There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out the Secretary’s responsibilities under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Aeronautics and Space Administration There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to carry out the Administrator’s responsibilities under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7505_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Institute of Standards and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National Institute of Standards and Technology There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to carry out the Director’s responsibilities under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7505_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Protection Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental Protection Agency There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out the Administrator’s responsibilities under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>