<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/774" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/774/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/774/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_774"><akn:num>774</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 774. Reports and recommendations(a) Administrator’s initial submittal to President and CongressNot later than one year after the effective date of this chapter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the President and Congress which will provide a complete and independent analysis of actual oil and gas reserves and resources in the United States and its Outer Continental Shelf, as well as of the existing productive capacity and the extent to which such capacity could be increased for crude oil and each major petroleum product each year for the next ten years through full utilization of available technology and capacity. The report shall also contain the Administration’s recommendations for improving the utilization and effectiveness of Federal energy data and its manner of collection. The data collection and analysis portion of this report shall be prepared by the Federal Trade Commission for the Administration. Unless specifically prohibited by law, all Federal agencies shall make available estimates, statistics, data and other information in their files which, in the judgment of the Commission or Administration, are necessary for the purposes of this subsection.


(b) Administrator’s annual report to Congress; contentsThe Administrator shall prepare and submit directly to the Congress and the President every year after May 7, 1974, a report which shall include—(1) a review and analysis of the major actions taken by the Administrator;

(2) an analysis of the impact these actions have had on the Nation’s civilian requirements for energy supplies for materials and commodities;

(3) a projection of the energy supply for the midterm and long term for each of the major types of fuel and the potential size and impact of any anticipated shortages, including recommendations for measures to—(A) minimize deficiencies of energy supplies in relation to needs;

(B) maintain the health and safety of citizens;

(C) maintain production and employment at the highest feasible </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator’s initial submittal to President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrator’s initial submittal to President and Congress Not later than one year after the effective date of this chapter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the President and Congress which will provide a complete and independent analysis of actual oil and gas reserves and resources in the United States and its Outer Continental Shelf, as well as of the existing productive capacity and the extent to which such capacity could be increased for crude oil and each major petroleum product each year for the next ten years through full utilization of available technology and capacity. The report shall also contain the Administration’s recommendations for improving the utilization and effectiveness of Federal energy data and its manner of collection. The data collection and analysis portion of this report shall be prepared by the Federal Trade Commission for the Administration. Unless specifically prohibited by law, all Federal agencies shall make available estimates, statistic</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator’s annual report to Congress; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrator’s annual report to Congress; contents The Administrator shall prepare and submit directly to the Congress and the President every year after May 7, 1974, a report which shall include— In the first annual report submitted after August 14, 1976, the Administrator shall include in such report with respect to the analysis referred to in paragraph (6) a specific discussion of the utility and relative benefits of employing a Btu tax as a means for obtaining national energy goals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen fuel use; summer guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Citizen fuel use; summer guidelines Not later than thirty days after the effective date of this chapter, the Administrator shall issue preliminary summer guidelines for citizen fuel use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator’s interim reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrator’s interim reports to Congress The Administrator shall provide interim reports to the Congress from time to time and when requested by committees of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy needs analysis; time for submission; contents; continuation of analysis after termination of Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Energy needs analysis; time for submission; contents; continuation of analysis after termination of Administration The analysis referred to in subsection (b)(6) shall include, for each of the next five fiscal years following the year in which the annual report is submitted and for the tenth fiscal year following such year— Notwithstanding the termination of this chapter, the President shall designate an appropriate Federal agency to conduct the analysis specified in subsection (b)(6).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>