<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77d"><akn:num>77d</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempted transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77d. Exempted transactions(a) In generalThe provisions of section 77e of this title shall not apply to—(1) transactions by any person other than an issuer, underwriter, or dealer.

(2) transactions by an issuer not involving any public offering.

(3) transactions by a dealer (including an underwriter no longer acting as an underwriter in respect of the security involved in such transaction), except—(A) transactions taking place prior to the expiration of forty days after the first date upon which the security was bona fide offered to the public by the issuer or by or through an underwriter,

(B) transactions in a security as to which a registration statement has been filed taking place prior to the expiration of forty days after the effective date of such registration statement or prior to the expiration of forty days after the first date upon which the security was bona fide offered to the public by the issuer or by or through an underwriter after such effective date, whichever is later (excluding in the computation of such forty days any time during which a stop order issued under section 77h of this title is in effect as to the security), or such shorter period as the Commission may specify by rules and regulations or order, and

(C) transactions as to securities constituting the whole or a part of an unsold allotment to or subscription by such dealer as a participant in the distribution of such securities by the issuer or by or through an underwriter.


With respect to transactions referred to in clause (B), if securities of the issuer have not previously been sold pursuant to an earlier effective registration statement the applicable period, instead of forty days, shall be ninety days, or such shorter period as the Commission may specify by rules and regulations or order.

(4) brokers’ transactions executed upon customers’ orders on any exchange or in the over-the-counter market but not the solicitation of such orders.

(5) transactions involving offers or sa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The provisions of section 77e of this title shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offers and sales exempt under 17 CFR 230.506</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Offers and sales exempt under 17 CFR 230.506 Offers and sales exempt under section 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (as revised pursuant to section 201 of the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act) shall not be deemed public offerings under the Federal securities laws as a result of general advertising or general solicitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Securities offered and sold in compliance with Rule 506 of Regulation D</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain accredited investor transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain accredited investor transactions The transactions referred to in subsection (a)(7) are transactions meeting the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>