<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77eee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77eee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77eee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77eee"><akn:num>77eee</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities required to be registered under Securities Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77eee. Securities required to be registered under Securities Act(a) Information requiredSubject to the provisions of section 77ddd of this title, a registration statement relating to a security shall include the following information and documents, as though such inclusion were required by the provisions of section 7 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77g]—(1) such information and documents as the Commission may by rules and regulations prescribe in order to enable the Commission to determine whether any person designated to act as trustee under the indenture under which such security has been or is to be issued is eligible to act as such under subsection (a) of section 77jjj of this title; and

(2) an analysis of any provisions of such indenture with respect to (A) the definition of what shall constitute a default under such indenture, and the withholding of notice to the indenture security holders of any such default, (B) the authentication and delivery of the indenture securities and the application of the proceeds thereof, (C) the release or the release and substitution of any property subject to the lien of the indenture, (D) the satisfaction and discharge of the indenture, and (E) the evidence required to be furnished by the obligor upon the indenture securities to the trustee as to compliance with the conditions and covenants provided for in such indenture.


The information and documents required by paragraph (1) of this subsection with respect to the person designated to act as indenture trustee shall be contained in a separate part of such registration statement, which part shall be signed by such person. Such part of the registration statement shall be deemed to be a document filed pursuant to this subchapter, and the provisions of sections 11, 12, 17, and 24 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77k, 77l, 77q, 77x] shall not apply to statements therein or omissions therefrom.

(b) Refusal of registration statement(1) Except as may be permitted</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77eee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information required Subject to the provisions of section 77ddd of this title, a registration statement relating to a security shall include the following information and documents, as though such inclusion were required by the provisions of section 7 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77g]— The information and documents required by paragraph (1) of this subsection with respect to the person designated to act as indenture trustee shall be contained in a separate part of such registration statement, which part shall be signed by such person. Such part of the registration statement shall be deemed to be a document filed pursuant to this subchapter, and the provisions of sections 11, 12, 17, and 24 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77k, 77l, 77q, 77x] shall not apply to statements therein or omissions therefrom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77eee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal of registration statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Refusal of registration statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77eee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in prospectus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information required in prospectus A prospectus relating to any such security shall include to the extent the Commission may prescribe by rules and regulations as necessary and appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, as though such inclusion were required by section 10 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77j], a written statement containing the analysis set forth in the registration statement, of any indenture provisions with respect to the matters specified in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) of this section, together with a supplementary analysis, prepared by the Commission, of such provisions and of the effect thereof, if, in the opinion of the Commission, the inclusion of such supplementary analysis is necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, and the Commission so declares by order after notice and, if demanded by the issuer, opportunity for hearing thereon. Such order shall be entered prior to the ef</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77eee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other statutory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of other statutory provisions The provisions of sections 11, 12, 17, and 24 of the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77k, 77l, 77q, 77x], and the provisions of sections 77www and 77yyy of this title, shall not apply to statements in or omissions from any analysis required under the provisions of this section or section 77fff or 77ggg of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>