<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77f"><akn:num>77f</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77f. Registration of securities(a) Method of registrationAny security may be registered with the Commission under the terms and conditions hereinafter provided, by filing a registration statement in triplicate, at least one of which shall be signed by each issuer, its principal executive officer or officers, its principal financial officer, its comptroller or principal accounting officer, and the majority of its board of directors or persons performing similar functions (or, if there is no board of directors or persons performing similar functions, by the majority of the persons or board having the power of management of the issuer), and in case the issuer is a foreign or Territorial person by its duly authorized representative in the United States; except that when such registration statement relates to a security issued by a foreign government, or political subdivision thereof, it need be signed only by the underwriter of such security. Signatures of all such persons when written on the said registration statements shall be presumed to have been so written by authority of the person whose signature is so affixed and the burden of proof, in the event such authority shall be denied, shall be upon the party denying the same. The affixing of any signature without the authority of the purported signer shall constitute a violation of this subchapter. A registration statement shall be deemed effective only as to the securities specified therein as proposed to be offered.


(b) Registration fee(1) Fee payment requiredAt the time of filing a registration statement, the applicant shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate that shall be equal to $92 11 See Adjustment of Registration Fee Rate notes below. per $1,000,000 of the maximum aggregate price at which such securities are proposed to be offered, except that during fiscal year 2003 and any succeeding fiscal year such fee shall be adjusted pursuant to paragraph (2).


(2) Annual adjustmentFor each fiscal year, the Com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Method of registration Any security may be registered with the Commission under the terms and conditions hereinafter provided, by filing a registration statement in triplicate, at least one of which shall be signed by each issuer, its principal executive officer or officers, its principal financial officer, its comptroller or principal accounting officer, and the majority of its board of directors or persons performing similar functions (or, if there is no board of directors or persons performing similar functions, by the majority of the persons or board having the power of management of the issuer), and in case the issuer is a foreign or Territorial person by its duly authorized representative in the United States; except that when such registration statement relates to a security issued by a foreign government, or political subdivision thereof, it need be signed only by the underwriter of such security. Signatures of all such persons when written on the said registration statemen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time registration effective</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time registration effective The filing with the Commission of a registration statement, or of an amendment to a registration statement, shall be deemed to have taken place upon the receipt thereof, but the filing of a registration statement shall not be deemed to have taken place unless it is accompanied by a United States postal money order or a certified bank check or cash for the amount of the fee required under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information available to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information available to public The information contained in or filed with any registration statement shall be made available to the public under such regulations as the Commission may prescribe, and copies thereof, photostatic or otherwise, shall be furnished to every applicant at such reasonable charge as the Commission may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging growth companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Emerging growth companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>