<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77g"><akn:num>77g</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in registration statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77g. Information required in registration statement(a) Information required in registration statement(1) In generalThe registration statement, when relating to a security other than a security issued by a foreign government, or political subdivision thereof, shall contain the information, and be accompanied by the documents, specified in Schedule A of section 77aa of this title, and when relating to a security issued by a foreign government, or political subdivision thereof, shall contain the information, and be accompanied by the documents, specified in Schedule B of section 77aa of this title; except that the Commission may by rules or regulations provide that any such information or document need not be included in respect of any class of issuers or securities if it finds that the requirement of such information or document is inapplicable to such class and that disclosure fully adequate for the protection of investors is otherwise required to be included within the registration statement. If any accountant, engineer, or appraiser, or any person whose profession gives authority to a statement made by him, is named as having prepared or certified any part of the registration statement, or is named as having prepared or certified a report or valuation for use in connection with the registration statement, the written consent of such person shall be filed with the registration statement. If any such person is named as having prepared or certified a report or valuation (other than a public official document or statement) which is used in connection with the registration statement, but is not named as having prepared or certified such report or valuation for use in connection with the registration statement, the written consent of such person shall be filed with the registration statement unless the Commission dispenses with such filing as impracticable or as involving undue hardship on the person filing the registration statement. Any such registration statement sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in registration statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information required in registration statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration statement for blank check companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration statement for blank check companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration statement for asset-backed securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Registration statement for asset-backed securities Not later than 180 days after July 21, 2010, the Commission shall issue rules relating to the registration statement required to be filed by any issuer of an asset-backed security (as that term is defined in section 78c(a)(77) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title) that require any issuer of an asset-backed security—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>