<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77mmm" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77mmm/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77mmm/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77mmm"><akn:num>77mmm</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by indenture trustee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77mmm. Reports by indenture trustee(a) Report to security holders; time; contentsThe indenture trustee shall transmit to the indenture security holders as hereinafter provided, at stated intervals of not more than 12 months, a brief report with respect to any of the following events which may have occurred within the previous 12 months (but if no such event has occurred within such period no report need be transmitted):— 11 So in original. The colon probably should not appear.(1) any change to its eligibility and its qualifications under section 77jjj of this title;

(2) the creation of or any material change to a relationship specified in paragraph 22 So in original. Probably should be “paragraphs”. (1) through (10) of section 77jjj(b) of this title;

(3) the character and amount of any advances made by it, as indenture trustee, which remain unpaid on the date of such report, and for the reimbursement of which it claims or may claim a lien or charge, prior to that of the indenture securities, on the trust estate or on property or funds held or collected by it as such trustee, if such advances so remaining unpaid aggregate more than one-half of 1 per centum of the principal amount of the indenture securities outstanding on such date;

(4) any change to the amount, interest rate, and maturity date of all other indebtedness owing to it in its individual capacity, on the date of such report, by the obligor upon the indenture securities, with a brief description of any property held as collateral security therefor, except an indebtedness based upon a creditor relationship arising in any manner described in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), or (6) of subsection (b) of section 77kkk of this title;

(5) any change to the property and funds physically in its possession as indenture trustee on the date of such report;

(6) any release, or release and substitution, of property subject to the lien of the indenture (and the consideration therefor, if any) which it has not previously </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77mmm_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to security holders; time; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report to security holders; time; contents The indenture trustee shall transmit to the indenture security holders as hereinafter provided, at stated intervals of not more than 12 months, a brief report with respect to any of the following events which may have occurred within the previous 12 months (but if no such event has occurred within such period no report need be transmitted):— 11 So in original. The colon probably should not appear.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77mmm_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reports to security holders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional reports to security holders The indenture trustee shall transmit to the indenture security holders as hereinafter provided, within the times hereinafter specified, a brief report with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77mmm_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional parties to whom reports to be transmitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional parties to whom reports to be transmitted Reports pursuant to this section shall be transmitted by mail—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77mmm_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of report with stock exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filing of report with stock exchanges A copy of each such report shall, at the time of such transmission to indenture security holders, be filed with each stock exchange upon which the indenture securities are listed, and also with the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>