<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77rrr" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77rrr/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/77rrr/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77rrr"><akn:num>77rrr</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of prescribed indenture provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77rrr. Effect of prescribed indenture provisions(a) Imposed duties to controlIf any provision of the indenture to be qualified limits, qualifies, or conflicts with the duties imposed by operation of subsection (c) of this section, the imposed duties shall control.


(b) Additional provisionsThe indenture to be qualified may contain, in addition to provisions specifically authorized under this subchapter to be included therein, any other provisions the inclusion of which is not in contravention of any provision of this subchapter.


(c) Provisions governing qualified indenturesThe provisions of sections 77jjj to and including 77qqq of this title that impose duties on any person (including provisions automatically deemed included in an indenture unless the indenture provides that such provisions are excluded) are a part of and govern every qualified indenture, whether or not physically contained therein, shall be deemed retroactively to govern each indenture heretofore qualified, and prospectively to govern each indenture hereafter qualified under this subchapter and shall be deemed retroactively to amend and supersede inconsistent provisions in each such indenture heretofore qualified. The foregoing provisions of this subsection shall not be deemed to effect the inclusion (by retroactive amendment or otherwise) in the text of any indenture heretofore qualified of any of the optional provisions contemplated by section 77jjj(b)(1), 77kkk(b), 77nnn(d), 77ooo(a), 77ooo(b), 77ooo(d), 77ooo(e), or 77ppp(a)(1) of this title.


(May 27, 1933, ch. 38, title III, § 318, as added Aug. 3, 1939, ch. 411, 53 Stat. 1173; amended Pub. L. 101–550, title IV, § 417, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2731.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1990—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 101–550, § 417(1), added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which read as follows: “The indenture to be qualified shall provide that if any provision thereof limits, qualifies, or conflicts with another provision which is requi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77rrr_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposed duties to control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposed duties to control If any provision of the indenture to be qualified limits, qualifies, or conflicts with the duties imposed by operation of subsection (c) of this section, the imposed duties shall control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77rrr_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional provisions The indenture to be qualified may contain, in addition to provisions specifically authorized under this subchapter to be included therein, any other provisions the inclusion of which is not in contravention of any provision of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77rrr_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions governing qualified indentures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provisions governing qualified indentures The provisions of sections 77jjj to and including 77qqq of this title that impose duties on any person (including provisions automatically deemed included in an indenture unless the indenture provides that such provisions are excluded) are a part of and govern every qualified indenture, whether or not physically contained therein, shall be deemed retroactively to govern each indenture heretofore qualified, and prospectively to govern each indenture hereafter qualified under this subchapter and shall be deemed retroactively to amend and supersede inconsistent provisions in each such indenture heretofore qualified. The foregoing provisions of this subsection shall not be deemed to effect the inclusion (by retroactive amendment or otherwise) in the text of any indenture heretofore qualified of any of the optional provisions contemplated by section 77jjj(b)(1), 77kkk(b), 77nnn(d), 77ooo(a), 77ooo(b), 77ooo(d), 77ooo(e), or 77ppp(a)(1) of this t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>