<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/783" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/783/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/783/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_783"><akn:num>783</akn:num><akn:heading>Hydroelectric generating facilities; lists, transmittal to Congress; construction schedule and cost </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 783. Hydroelectric generating facilities; lists, transmittal to Congress; construction schedule and cost estimates for expedited construction program; prospective accomplishments from expedited completion of facilities; statement of appropriated but not obligated funds
Within ninety days of the effective date of this chapter, the Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army, shall—(1) transmit to the Congress—(A) a list of hydroelectric generating facilities and electric power transmission facilities which have been authorized for construction by the Congress and which are not yet completed, and

(B) a list of opportunities to increase the capacity of existing hydroelectric generating facilities, and


(2) provide, for each such facility which is listed—(A) a construction schedule and cost estimates for an expedited construction program which would make the facility available for service at the earliest practicable date, and

(B) a statement of the accomplishments which could be provided by the expedited completion of each facility and a statement of any funds which have been appropriated but not yet obligated.


(Pub. L. 93–275, § 24, May 7, 1974, 88 Stat. 114.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
Federal Energy Administration terminated and functions vested by law in Administrator thereof transferred to Secretary of Energy (unless otherwise specifically provided) by sections 7151(a) and 7293 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_783_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) transmit to the Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_783_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) provide, for each such facility which is listed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>