<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78bb"><akn:num>78bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on existing law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78bb. Effect on existing law(a) Limitation on judgments(1) In generalNo person permitted to maintain a suit for damages under the provisions of this chapter shall recover, through satisfaction of judgment in 1 or more actions, a total amount in excess of the actual damages to that person on account of the act complained of. Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, nothing in this chapter shall affect the jurisdiction of the securities commission (or any agency or officer performing like functions) of any State over any security or any person insofar as it does not conflict with the provisions of this chapter or the rules and regulations under this chapter.


(2) Rule of constructionExcept as provided in subsection (f), the rights and remedies provided by this chapter shall be in addition to any and all other rights and remedies that may exist at law or in equity.


(3) State bucket shop lawsNo State law which prohibits or regulates the making or promoting of wagering or gaming contracts, or the operation of “bucket shops” or other similar or related activities, shall invalidate—(A) any put, call, straddle, option, privilege, or other security subject to this chapter (except any security that has a pari-mutuel payout or otherwise is determined by the Commission, acting by rule, regulation, or order, to be appropriately subject to such laws), or apply to any activity which is incidental or related to the offer, purchase, sale, exercise, settlement, or closeout of any such security;

(B) any security-based swap between eligible contract participants; or

(C) any security-based swap effected on a national securities exchange registered pursuant to section 78f(b) of this title.


(4) Other State provisionsNo provision of State law regarding the offer, sale, or distribution of securities shall apply to any transaction in a security-based swap or a security futures product, except that this paragraph may not be construed as limiting any State antifraud </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on judgments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on judgments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of disciplinary procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Modification of disciplinary procedures Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to modify existing law with regard to the binding effect (1) on any member of or participant in any self-regulatory organization of any action taken by the authorities of such organization to settle disputes between its members or participants, (2) on any municipal securities dealer or municipal securities broker of any action taken pursuant to a procedure established by the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board to settle disputes between municipal securities dealers and municipal securities brokers, or (3) of any action described in paragraph (1) or (2) on any person who has agreed to be bound thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing validity of disciplinary sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continuing validity of disciplinary sanctions The stay, setting aside, or modification pursuant to section 78s(e) of this title of any disciplinary sanction imposed by a self-regulatory organization on a member thereof, person associated with a member, or participant therein, shall not affect the validity or force of any action taken as a result of such sanction by the self-regulatory organization prior to such stay, setting aside, or modification: Provided, That such action is not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter or the rules or regulations thereunder. The rights of any person acting in good faith which arise out of any such action shall not be affected in any way by such stay, setting aside, or modification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical location of facilities of registered clearing agencies or registered transfer agents not to subject changes in beneficial or record ownership of securities to State or local taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Physical location of facilities of registered clearing agencies or registered transfer agents not to subject changes in beneficial or record ownership of securities to State or local taxes No State or political subdivision thereof shall impose any tax on any change in beneficial or record ownership of securities effected through the facilities of a registered clearing agency or registered transfer agent or any nominee thereof or custodian therefor or upon the delivery or transfer of securities to or through or receipt from such agency or agent or any nominee thereof or custodian therefor, unless such change in beneficial or record ownership or such transfer or delivery or receipt would otherwise be taxable by such State or political subdivision if the facilities of such registered clearing agency, registered transfer agent, or any nominee thereof or custodian therefor were not physically located in the taxing State or political subdivision. No State or political subdivision thereof</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange, broker, and dealer commissions; brokerage and research services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exchange, broker, and dealer commissions; brokerage and research services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78bb_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations on remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>