<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78c"><akn:num>78c</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78c. Definitions and application(a) DefinitionsWhen used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires—(1) The term “exchange” means any organization, association, or group of persons, whether incorporated or unincorporated, which constitutes, maintains, or provides a market place or facilities for bringing together purchasers and sellers of securities or for otherwise performing with respect to securities the functions commonly performed by a stock exchange as that term is generally understood, and includes the market place and the market facilities maintained by such exchange.

(2) The term “facility” when used with respect to an exchange includes its premises, tangible or intangible property whether on the premises or not, any right to the use of such premises or property or any service thereof for the purpose of effecting or reporting a transaction on an exchange (including, among other things, any system of communication to or from the exchange, by ticker or otherwise, maintained by or with the consent of the exchange), and any right of the exchange to the use of any property or service.

(3)(A) The term “member” when used with respect to a national securities exchange means (i) any natural person permitted to effect transactions on the floor of the exchange without the services of another person acting as broker, (ii) any registered broker or dealer with which such a natural person is associated, (iii) any registered broker or dealer permitted to designate as a representative such a natural person, and (iv) any other registered broker or dealer which agrees to be regulated by such exchange and with respect to which the exchange undertakes to enforce compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the rules and regulations thereunder, and its own rules. For purposes of sections 78f(b)(1), 78f(b)(4), 78f(b)(6), 78f(b)(7), 78f(d), 78q(d), 78s(d), 78s(e), 78s(g), 78s(h), and 78u of this title, the term “member” when used with respect to a national secur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions When used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Power to define technical, trade, accounting, and other terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Power to define technical, trade, accounting, and other terms The Commission and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, as to matters within their respective jurisdictions, shall have power by rules and regulations to define technical, trade, accounting, and other terms used in this chapter, consistently with the provisions and purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to governmental departments or agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application to governmental departments or agencies No provision of this chapter shall apply to, or be deemed to include, any executive department or independent establishment of the United States, or any lending agency which is wholly owned, directly or indirectly, by the United States, or any officer, agent, or employee of any such department, establishment, or agency, acting in the course of his official duty as such, unless such provision makes specific reference to such department, establishment, or agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuers of municipal securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuers of municipal securities No issuer of municipal securities or officer or employee thereof acting in the course of his official duties as such shall be deemed to be a “broker”, “dealer”, or “municipal securities dealer” solely by reason of buying, selling, or effecting transactions in the issuer’s securities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Charitable organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consideration of promotion of efficiency, competition, and capital formation Whenever pursuant to this chapter the Commission is engaged in rulemaking, or in the review of a rule of a self-regulatory organization, and is required to consider or determine whether an action is necessary or appropriate in the public interest, the Commission shall also consider, in addition to the protection of investors, whether the action will promote efficiency, competition, and capital formation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Church plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Church plans No church plan described in section 414(e) of title 26, no person or entity eligible to establish and maintain such a plan under title 26, no company or account that is excluded from the definition of an investment company under section 3(c)(14) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 [15 U.S.C. 80a–3(c)(14)], and no trustee, director, officer or employee of or volunteer for such plan, company, account, person, or entity, acting within the scope of that person’s employment or activities with respect to such plan, shall be deemed to be a “broker”, “dealer”, “municipal securities broker”, “municipal securities dealer”, “government securities broker”, “government securities dealer”, “clearing agency”, or “transfer agent” for purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited exemption for funding portals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limited exemption for funding portals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>