<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78d_5"><akn:num>78d–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for completing enforcement investigations and compliance examinations and inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78d–5. Deadline for completing enforcement investigations and compliance examinations and inspections(a) Enforcement investigations(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after the date on which Commission staff provide 11 So in original. Probably should be “provides”. a written Wells notification to any person, the Commission staff shall either file an action against such person or provide notice to the Director of the Division of Enforcement of its intent to not file an action.


(2) Exceptions for certain complex actionsNotwithstanding paragraph (1), if the Director of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission or the Director’s designee determines that a particular enforcement investigation is sufficiently complex such that a determination regarding the filing of an action against a person cannot be completed within the deadline specified in paragraph (1), the Director of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission or the Director’s designee may, after providing notice to the Chairman of the Commission, extend such deadline as needed for one additional 180-day period. If after the additional 180-day period the Director of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission or the Director’s designee determines that a particular enforcement investigation is sufficiently complex such that a determination regarding the filing of an action against a person cannot be completed within the additional 180-day period, the Director of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission or the Director’s designee may, after providing notice to and receiving approval of the Commission, extend such deadline as needed for one or more additional successive 180-day periods.



(b) Compliance examinations and inspections(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after the date on which Commission staff completes the on-site portion of its compliance examination or inspection or receives all records requested from the entity being examined or inspected, whichever is later, Commission staff s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforcement investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance examinations and inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance examinations and inspections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>