<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78d–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78d_6"><akn:num>78d–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Report and certification of internal supervisory controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78d–6. Report and certification of internal supervisory controls(a) Annual reports and certificationNot later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Commission shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on the conduct by the Commission of examinations of registered entities, enforcement investigations, and review of corporate financial securities filings.


(b) Contents of reportsEach report under subsection (a) shall contain—(1) an assessment, as of the end of the most recent fiscal year, of the effectiveness of—(A) the internal supervisory controls of the Commission; and

(B) the procedures of the Commission applicable to the staff of the Commission who perform examinations of registered entities, enforcement investigations, and reviews of corporate financial securities filings;


(2) a certification that the Commission has adequate internal supervisory controls to carry out the duties of the Commission described in paragraph (1)(B); and

(3) a summary by the Comptroller General of the United States of the review carried out under subsection (d).11 So in original. Probably should be “(e).”


(c) Certification(1) SignatureThe certification under subsection (b)(2) shall be signed by the Director of the Division of Enforcement, the Director of the Division of Corporation Finance, and the Director of the Office of Compliance Inspections and Examinations (or the head of any successor division or office).


(2) Content of certificationEach individual described in paragraph (1) shall certify that the individual—(A) is directly responsible for establishing and maintaining the internal supervisory controls of the Division or Office of which the individual is the head;

(B) is knowledgeable about the internal supervisory controls of the Division or Office of which the individual is the head;

(C) has evaluated the effectiveness of the inter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports and certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual reports and certification Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Commission shall submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on the conduct by the Commission of examinations of registered entities, enforcement investigations, and review of corporate financial securities filings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of reports Each report under subsection (a) shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>New Director or Acting Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) New Director or Acting Director Notwithstanding subsection (a), if the Director of the Division of Enforcement, the Director of the Division of Corporate Finance, or the Director of the Office of Compliance Inspections and Examinations has served as Director of the Division or Office for less than 90 days on the date on which a report is required to be submitted under subsection (a), the Commission may submit the report on the date on which the Director has served as Director for 90 days. If there is no Director of the Division of Enforcement, the Division of Corporate Finance, or the Office of Compliance Inspections and Examinations, on the date on which a report is required to be submitted under subsection (a), the Acting Director of the Division or Office may make the certification required under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78d_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by the Comptroller General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review by the Comptroller General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>