<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78ee"><akn:num>78ee</akn:num><akn:heading>Transaction fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78ee. Transaction fees(a) Recovery of costs of annual appropriationThe Commission shall, in accordance with this section, collect transaction fees and assessments that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the annual appropriation to the Commission by Congress.


(b) Exchange-traded securitiesSubject to subsection (j), each national securities exchange shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 11 See Adjustment of Transaction Fee Rate notes below. per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) transacted on such national securities exchange.


(c) Off-exchange trades of exchange registered and last-sale-reported securitiesSubject to subsection (j), each national securities association shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 1 per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) registered on a national securities exchange or subject to prompt last sale reporting pursuant to the rules of the Commission or a registered national securities association.


(d) Assessments on security futures transactionsEach national securities exchange and national securities association shall pay to the Commission an assessment equal to $0.009 for each round turn transaction (treated as including one purchase and one sale of a contract of sale for future delivery) on a security future traded on such national securities exchange or by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange, except that for fiscal year 2007 and each </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of costs of annual appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recovery of costs of annual appropriation The Commission shall, in accordance with this section, collect transaction fees and assessments that are designed to recover the costs to the Government of the annual appropriation to the Commission by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange-traded securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exchange-traded securities Subject to subsection (j), each national securities exchange shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 11 See Adjustment of Transaction Fee Rate notes below. per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) transacted on such national securities exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Off-exchange trades of exchange registered and last-sale-reported securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Off-exchange trades of exchange registered and last-sale-reported securities Subject to subsection (j), each national securities association shall pay to the Commission a fee at a rate equal to $15 1 per $1,000,000 of the aggregate dollar amount of sales transacted by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange of securities (other than bonds, debentures, other evidences of indebtedness, security futures products, and options on securities indexes (excluding a narrow-based security index)) registered on a national securities exchange or subject to prompt last sale reporting pursuant to the rules of the Commission or a registered national securities association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments on security futures transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assessments on security futures transactions Each national securities exchange and national securities association shall pay to the Commission an assessment equal to $0.009 for each round turn transaction (treated as including one purchase and one sale of a contract of sale for future delivery) on a security future traded on such national securities exchange or by or through any member of such association otherwise than on a national securities exchange, except that for fiscal year 2007 and each succeeding fiscal year such assessment shall be equal to $0.0042 for each such transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dates for payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dates for payments The fees and assessments required by subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section shall be paid—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemptions The Commission, by rule, may exempt any sale of securities or any class of sales of securities from any fee or assessment imposed by this section, if the Commission finds that such exemption is consistent with the public interest, the equal regulation of markets and brokers and dealers, and the development of a national market system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Publication The Commission shall publish in the Federal Register notices of the fee and assessment rates applicable under this section for each fiscal year not later than 30 days after the date on which an Act making a regular appropriation to the Commission for such fiscal year is enacted, together with any estimates or projections on which such fees are based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pro rata application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Pro rata application The rates per $1,000,000 required by this section shall be applied pro rata to amounts and balances of less than $1,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Deposit of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78ee_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments to fee rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Adjustments to fee rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>