<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78eee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78eee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78eee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78eee"><akn:num>78eee</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78eee. Protection of customers(a) Determination of need of protection(1) Notice to SIPCIf the Commission or any self-regulatory organization is aware of facts which lead it to believe that any broker or dealer subject to its regulation is in or is approaching financial difficulty, it shall immediately notify SIPC, and, if such notification is by a self-regulatory organization, the Commission.


(2) Action by self-regulatory organizationIf a self-regulatory organization has given notice to SIPC pursuant to subsection (a)(1) with respect to a broker or dealer, and such broker or dealer undertakes to liquidate or reduce its business either pursuant to the direction of a self-regulatory organization or voluntarily, such self-regulatory organization may render such assistance or oversight to such broker or dealer as it considers appropriate to protect the interests of customers of such broker or dealer. The assistance or oversight by a self-regulatory organization shall not be deemed the assumption or adoption by such self-regulatory organization of any obligation or liability to customers, other creditors, shareholders, or partners of the broker or dealer, and shall not prevent or act as a bar to any action by SIPC.


(3) Action by SIPC(A) In generalSIPC may, upon notice to a member of SIPC, file an application for a protective decree with any court of competent jurisdiction specified in section 78u(e) or 78aa of this title, except that no such application shall be filed with respect to a member, the only customers of which are persons whose claims could not be satisfied by SIPC advances pursuant to section 78fff–3 of this title, if SIPC determines that—(A) 11 So in original. Probably should be “(i)”. the member (including any person who was a member within one hundred eighty days prior to such determination) has failed or is in danger of failing to meet its obligations to customers; and

(B) 22 So in original. Probably should be “(ii)”. one or more of the conditions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78eee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of need of protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of need of protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78eee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Court action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78eee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>SEC participation in proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) SEC participation in proceedings The Commission may, on its own motion, file notice of its appearance in any proceeding under this chapter and may thereafter participate as a party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78eee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>SIPC participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) SIPC participation SIPC shall be deemed to be a party in interest as to all matters arising in a liquidation proceeding, with the right to be heard on all such matters, and shall be deemed to have intervened with respect to all such matters with the same force and effect as if a petition for such purpose had been allowed by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>