<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78g"><akn:num>78g</akn:num><akn:heading>Margin requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78g. Margin requirements(a) Rules and regulations for extension of credit; standard for initial extension; undermargined accountsFor the purpose of preventing the excessive use of credit for the purchase or carrying of securities, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, prior to October 1, 1934, and from time to time thereafter, prescribe rules and regulations with respect to the amount of credit that may be initially extended and subsequently maintained on any security (other than an exempted security or a security futures product). For the initial extension of credit, such rules and regulations shall be based upon the following standard: An amount not greater than whichever is the higher of—(1) 55 per centum of the current market price of the security, or

(2) 100 per centum of the lowest market price of the security during the preceding thirty-six calendar months, but not more than 75 per centum of the current market price.


Such rules and regulations may make appropriate provision with respect to the carrying of undermargined accounts for limited periods and under specified conditions; the withdrawal of funds or securities; the substitution or additional purchases of securities; the transfer of accounts from one lender to another; special or different margin requirements for delayed deliveries, short sales, arbitrage transactions, and securities to which paragraph (2) of this subsection does not apply; the bases and the methods to be used in calculating loans, and margins and market prices; and similar administrative adjustments and details. For the purposes of paragraph (2) of this subsection, until July 1, 1936, the lowest price at which a security has sold on or after July 1, 1933, shall be considered as the lowest price at which such security has sold during the preceding thirty-six calendar months.

(b) Lower and higher margin requirementsNotwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Board of Governors of the F</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations for extension of credit; standard for initial extension; undermargined accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations for extension of credit; standard for initial extension; undermargined accounts For the purpose of preventing the excessive use of credit for the purchase or carrying of securities, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall, prior to October 1, 1934, and from time to time thereafter, prescribe rules and regulations with respect to the amount of credit that may be initially extended and subsequently maintained on any security (other than an exempted security or a security futures product). For the initial extension of credit, such rules and regulations shall be based upon the following standard: An amount not greater than whichever is the higher of— Such rules and regulations may make appropriate provision with respect to the carrying of undermargined accounts for limited periods and under specified conditions; the withdrawal of funds or securities; the substitution or additional purchases of securities; the transfer of accounts from one lender</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lower and higher margin requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Lower and higher margin requirements Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a) of this section, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, may, from time to time, with respect to all or specified securities or transactions, or classes of securities, or classes of transactions, by such rules and regulations (1) prescribe such lower margin requirements for the initial extension or maintenance of credit as it deems necessary or appropriate for the accommodation of commerce and industry, having due regard to the general credit situation of the country, and (2) prescribe such higher margin requirements for the initial extension or maintenance of credit as it may deem necessary or appropriate to prevent the excessive use of credit to finance transactions in securities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful credit extension to customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unlawful credit extension to customers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful credit extension in violation of rules and regulations; exceptions to application of rules, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unlawful credit extension in violation of rules and regulations; exceptions to application of rules, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of this section and rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date of this section and rules and regulations The provisions of this section or the rules and regulations thereunder shall not apply on or before July 1, 1937, to any loan or extension of credit made prior to June 6, 1934, or to the maintenance, renewal, or extension of any such loan or credit, except to the extent that the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may by rules and regulations prescribe as necessary to prevent the circumvention of the provisions of this section or the rules and regulations thereunder by means of withdrawals of funds or securities, substitutions of securities, or additional purchases or by any other device.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful receipt of credit; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unlawful receipt of credit; exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of bona fide agreement for delayed delivery of mortgage related security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect of bona fide agreement for delayed delivery of mortgage related security Subject to such rules and regulations as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may adopt in the public interest and for the protection of investors, no member of a national securities exchange or broker or dealer shall be deemed to have extended or maintained credit or arranged for the extension or maintenance of credit for the purpose of purchasing a security, within the meaning of this section, by reason of a bona fide agreement for delayed delivery of a mortgage related security or a small business related security against full payment of the purchase price thereof upon such delivery within one hundred and eighty days after the purchase, or within such shorter period as the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe by rule or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>