<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78i"><akn:num>78i</akn:num><akn:heading>Manipulation of security prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78i. Manipulation of security prices(a) Transactions relating to purchase or sale of securityIt shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, by the use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce, or of any facility of any national securities exchange, or for any member of a national securities exchange—(1) For the purpose of creating a false or misleading appearance of active trading in any security other than a government security, or a false or misleading appearance with respect to the market for any such security, (A) to effect any transaction in such security which involves no change in the beneficial ownership thereof, or (B) to enter an order or orders for the purchase of such security with the knowledge that an order or orders of substantially the same size, at substantially the same time, and at substantially the same price, for the sale of any such security, has been or will be entered by or for the same or different parties, or (C) to enter any order or orders for the sale of any such security with the knowledge that an order or orders of substantially the same size, at substantially the same time, and at substantially the same price, for the purchase of such security, has been or will be entered by or for the same or different parties.

(2) To effect, alone or with 1 or more other persons, a series of transactions in any security registered on a national securities exchange, any security not so registered, or in connection with any security-based swap or security-based swap agreement with respect to such security creating actual or apparent active trading in such security, or raising or depressing the price of such security, for the purpose of inducing the purchase or sale of such security by others.

(3) If a dealer, broker, security-based swap dealer, major security-based swap participant, or other person selling or offering for sale or purchasing or offering to purchase the security, a security-based swap, or a s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions relating to purchase or sale of security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transactions relating to purchase or sale of security It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, by the use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce, or of any facility of any national securities exchange, or for any member of a national securities exchange—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions relating to puts, calls, straddles, options, futures, or security-based swaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transactions relating to puts, calls, straddles, options, futures, or security-based swaps It shall be unlawful for any person to effect, in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Endorsement or guarantee of puts, calls, straddles, or options</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Endorsement or guarantee of puts, calls, straddles, or options It shall be unlawful for any broker, dealer, or member of a national securities exchange directly or indirectly to endorse or guarantee the performance of any put, call, straddle, option, or privilege in relation to any security other than a government security, in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions relating to short sales of securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transactions relating to short sales of securities It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, by the use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce, or of any facility of any national securities exchange, or for any member of a national securities exchange to effect, alone or with one or more other persons, a manipulative short sale of any security. The Commission shall issue such other rules as are necessary or appropriate to ensure that the appropriate enforcement options and remedies are available for violations of this subsection in the public interest or for the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registered warrant, right, or convertible security not included in “put”, “call”, “straddle”, or “option”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Registered warrant, right, or convertible security not included in “put”, “call”, “straddle”, or “option” The terms “put”, “call”, “straddle”, “option”, or “privilege” as used in this section shall not include any registered warrant, right, or convertible security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons liable; suits at law or in equity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Persons liable; suits at law or in equity Any person who willfully participates in any act or transaction in violation of subsections (a), (b), or (c) of this section, shall be liable to any person who shall purchase or sell any security at a price which was affected by such act or transaction, and the person so injured may sue in law or in equity in any court of competent jurisdiction to recover the damages sustained as a result of any such act or transaction. In any such suit the court may, in its discretion, require an undertaking for the payment of the costs of such suit, and assess reasonable costs, including reasonable attorneys’ fees, against either party litigant. Every person who becomes liable to make any payment under this subsection may recover contribution as in cases of contract from any person who, if joined in the original suit, would have been liable to make the same payment. No action shall be maintained to enforce any liability created under this section, unless </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsection (a) not applicable to exempted securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subsection (a) not applicable to exempted securities The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to an exempted security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign currencies and security futures products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Foreign currencies and security futures products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on practices that affect market volatility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitations on practices that affect market volatility It shall be unlawful for any person, by the use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce or of any facility of any national securities exchange, to use or employ any act or practice in connection with the purchase or sale of any equity security in contravention of such rules or regulations as the Commission may adopt, consistent with the public interest, the protection of investors, and the maintenance of fair and orderly markets— In adopting rules under paragraph (2), the Commission shall, consistent with the purposes of this subsection, minimize the impact on the normal operations of the market and a natural person’s freedom to buy or sell any equity security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78i_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two subsecs. (j) have been enacted. Limitation on Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The authority of the Commission under this section with respect to security-based swap agreements shall be subject to the restrictions and limitations of section 78c–1(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>