<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78l"><akn:num>78l</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration requirements for securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78l. Registration requirements for securities(a) General requirement of registrationIt shall be unlawful for any member, broker, or dealer to effect any transaction in any security (other than an exempted security) on a national securities exchange unless a registration is effective as to such security for such exchange in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and the rules and regulations thereunder. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply in respect of a security futures product traded on a national securities exchange.


(b) Procedure for registration; informationA security may be registered on a national securities exchange by the issuer filing an application with the exchange (and filing with the Commission such duplicate originals thereof as the Commission may require), which application shall contain—(1) Such information, in such detail, as to the issuer and any person directly or indirectly controlling or controlled by, or under direct or indirect common control with, the issuer, and any guarantor of the security as to principal or interest or both, as the Commission may by rules and regulations require, as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, in respect of the following:(A) the organization, financial structure, and nature of the business;

(B) the terms, position, rights, and privileges of the different classes of securities outstanding;

(C) the terms on which their securities are to be, and during the preceding three years have been, offered to the public or otherwise;

(D) the directors, officers, and underwriters, and each security holder of record holding more than 10 per centum of any class of any equity security of the issuer (other than an exempted security), their remuneration and their interests in the securities of, and their material contracts with, the issuer and any person directly or indirectly controlling or controlled by, or under direct or indirect common control with, th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirement of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirement of registration It shall be unlawful for any member, broker, or dealer to effect any transaction in any security (other than an exempted security) on a national securities exchange unless a registration is effective as to such security for such exchange in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and the rules and regulations thereunder. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply in respect of a security futures product traded on a national securities exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for registration; information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure for registration; information A security may be registered on a national securities exchange by the issuer filing an application with the exchange (and filing with the Commission such duplicate originals thereof as the Commission may require), which application shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional or alternative information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional or alternative information If in the judgment of the Commission any information required under subsection (b) is inapplicable to any specified class or classes of issuers, the Commission shall require in lieu thereof the submission of such other information of comparable character as it may deem applicable to such class of issuers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of registration; withdrawal of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date of registration; withdrawal of registration If the exchange authorities certify to the Commission that the security has been approved by the exchange for listing and registration, the registration shall become effective thirty days after the receipt of such certification by the Commission or within such shorter period of time as the Commission may determine. A security registered with a national securities exchange may be withdrawn or stricken from listing and registration in accordance with the rules of the exchange and, upon such terms as the Commission may deem necessary to impose for the protection of investors, upon application by the issuer or the exchange to the Commission; whereupon the issuer shall be relieved from further compliance with the provisions of this section and section 78m of this title and any rules or regulations under such sections as to the securities so withdrawn or stricken. An unissued security may be registered only in accordance with suc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from provisions of section for period ending not later than July 1, 1935</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption from provisions of section for period ending not later than Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section, the Commission may by such rules and regulations as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, permit securities listed on any exchange at the time the registration of such exchange as a national securities exchange becomes effective, to be registered for a period ending not later than July 1, 1935, without complying with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlisted trading privileges for security originally listed on another national exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unlisted trading privileges for security originally listed on another national exchange</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of securities by issuer; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Registration of securities by issuer; exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption by rules and regulations from certain provisions of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemption by rules and regulations from certain provisions of section The Commission may by rules and regulations, or upon application of an interested person, by order, after notice and opportunity for hearing, exempt in whole or in part any issuer or class of issuers from the provisions of subsection (g) of this section or from section 78m, 78n, or 78o(d) of this title or may exempt from section 78p of this title any officer, director, or beneficial owner of securities of any issuer, any security of which is required to be registered pursuant to subsection (g) hereof, upon such terms and conditions and for such period as it deems necessary or appropriate, if the Commission finds, by reason of the number of public investors, amount of trading interest in the securities, the nature and extent of the activities of the issuer, income or assets of the issuer, or otherwise, that such action is not inconsistent with the public interest or the protection of investors. The Commission may,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities issued by banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Securities issued by banks In respect of any securities issued by banks and savings associations the deposits of which are insured in accordance with the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.], the powers, functions, and duties vested in the Commission to administer and enforce this section and sections 78j–1(m), 78m, 78n(a), 78n(c), 78n(d), 78n(f), and 78p of this title, and sections 7241, 7242, 7243, 7244, 7261(b), 7262, 7264, and 7265 of this title, (1) with respect to national banks and Federal savings associations, the accounts of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation 33 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. are vested in the Comptroller of the Currency, (2) with respect to all other member banks of the Federal Reserve System are vested in the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and (3) with respect to all other insured banks and State savings associations, the accounts of which are insured by the Federal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78l_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial, suspension, or revocation of registration; notice and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Denial, suspension, or revocation of registration; notice and hearing The Commission is authorized, by order, as it deems necessary or appropriate for the protection of investors to deny, to suspend the effective date of, to suspend for a period not exceeding twelve months, or to revoke the registration of a security, if the Commission finds, on the record after notice and opportunity for hearing, that the issuer, of such security has failed to comply with any provision of this chapter or the rules and regulations thereunder. No member of a national securities exchange, broker, or dealer shall make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce to effect any transaction in, or to induce the purchase or sale of, any security the registration of which has been and is suspended or revoked pursuant to the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>