<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78lll" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78lll/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78lll/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78lll"><akn:num>78lll</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78lll. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter, including the application of the Bankruptcy Act to a liquidation proceeding:(1) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.


(2) Customer(A) In generalThe term “customer” of a debtor means any person (including any person with whom the debtor deals as principal or agent) who has a claim on account of securities received, acquired, or held by the debtor in the ordinary course of its business as a broker or dealer from or for the securities accounts of such person for safekeeping, with a view to sale, to cover consummated sales, pursuant to purchases, as collateral, security, or for purposes of effecting transfer.


(B) Included personsThe term “customer” includes—(i) any person who has deposited cash with the debtor for the purpose of purchasing securities;

(ii) any person who has a claim against the debtor for cash, securities, futures contracts, or options on futures contracts received, acquired, or held in a portfolio margining account carried as a securities account pursuant to a portfolio margining program approved by the Commission; and

(iii) any person who has a claim against the debtor arising out of sales or conversions of such securities.


(C) Excluded personsThe term “customer” does not include any person, to the extent that—(i) the claim of such person arises out of transactions with a foreign subsidiary of a member of SIPC; or

(ii) such person has a claim for cash or securities which by contract, agreement, or understanding, or by operation of law, is part of the capital of the debtor, or is subordinated to the claims of any or all creditors of the debtor, notwithstanding that some ground exists for declaring such contract, agreement, or understanding void or voidable in a suit between the claimant and the debtor.



(3) Customer name securitiesThe term “customer name securities” means securities which were held for the account of a customer on the filing date by or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Commission The term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Customer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customer name securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Customer name securities The term “customer name securities” means securities which were held for the account of a customer on the filing date by or on behalf of the debtor and which on the filing date were registered in the name of the customer, or were in the process of being so registered pursuant to instructions from the debtor, but does not include securities registered in the name of the customer which, by endorsement or otherwise, were in negotiable form.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customer property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Customer property The term “customer property” means cash and securities (except customer name securities delivered to the customer) at any time received, acquired, or held by or for the account of a debtor from or for the securities accounts of a customer, and the proceeds of any such property transferred by the debtor, including property unlawfully converted. The term “customer property” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debtor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Debtor The term “debtor” means a member of SIPC with respect to whom an application for a protective decree has been filed under section 78eee(a)(3) of this title or a direct payment procedure has been instituted under section 78fff–4(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examining authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Examining authority The term “examining authority” means, with respect to any member of SIPC (A) the self-regulatory organization which inspects or examines such member of SIPC, or (B) the Commission if such member of SIPC is not a member of or participant in any self-regulatory organization or if the Commission has designated itself examining authority for such member pursuant to section 78iii(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Filing date The term “filing date” means the date on which an application for a protective decree is filed under section 78eee(a)(3) of this title, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign subsidiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Foreign subsidiary The term “foreign subsidiary” means any subsidiary of a member of SIPC which has its principal place of business in a foreign country or which is organized under the laws of a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross revenues from the securities business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Gross revenues from the securities business The term “gross revenues from the securities business” means the sum of (but without duplication)— Such term includes revenues earned by a broker or dealer in connection with a transaction in the portfolio margining account of a customer carried as securities accounts pursuant to a portfolio margining program approved by the Commission. Such term does not include revenues received by a broker or dealer in connection with the distribution of shares of a registered open end investment company or unit investment trust or revenues derived by a broker or dealer from the sale of variable annuities or from the conduct of the business of insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78lll_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Liquidation proceeding The term “liquidation proceeding” means any proceeding for the liquidation of a debtor under this chapter in which a trustee has been appointed under section 78eee(b)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>