<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78m"><akn:num>78m</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodical and other reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78m. Periodical and other reports(a) Reports by issuer of security; contentsEvery issuer of a security registered pursuant to section 78l of this title shall file with the Commission, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate for the proper protection of investors and to insure fair dealing in the security—(1) such information and documents (and such copies thereof) as the Commission shall require to keep reasonably current the information and documents required to be included in or filed with an application or registration statement filed pursuant to section 78l of this title, except that the Commission may not require the filing of any material contract wholly executed before July 1, 1962.

(2) such annual reports (and such copies thereof), certified if required by the rules and regulations of the Commission by independent public accountants, and such quarterly reports (and such copies thereof), as the Commission may prescribe.


Every issuer of a security registered on a national securities exchange shall also file a duplicate original of such information, documents, and reports with the exchange. In any registration statement, periodic report, or other reports to be filed with the Commission, an emerging growth company need not present selected financial data in accordance with section 229.301 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, for any period prior to the earliest audited period presented in connection with its first registration statement that became effective under this chapter or the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.] and, with respect to any such statement or reports, an emerging growth company may not be required to comply with any new or revised financial accounting standard until such date that a company that is not an issuer (as defined under section 7201 of this title) is required to comply with such new or revised accounting standard, if such standard applies to compan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by issuer of security; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports by issuer of security; contents Every issuer of a security registered pursuant to section 78l of this title shall file with the Commission, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate for the proper protection of investors and to insure fair dealing in the security— Every issuer of a security registered on a national securities exchange shall also file a duplicate original of such information, documents, and reports with the exchange. In any registration statement, periodic report, or other reports to be filed with the Commission, an emerging growth company need not present selected financial data in accordance with section 229.301 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, for any period prior to the earliest audited period presented in connection with its first registration statement that became effective under this chapter or the Securities Act of 1933 [15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.] and, with respect to any such state</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of report; books, records, and internal accounting; directives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form of report; books, records, and internal accounting; directives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative reports If in the judgment of the Commission any report required under subsection (a) is inapplicable to any specified class or classes of issuers, the Commission shall require in lieu thereof the submission of such reports of comparable character as it may deem applicable to such class or classes of issuers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by persons acquiring more than five per centum of certain classes of securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports by persons acquiring more than five per centum of certain classes of securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of securities by issuer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Purchase of securities by issuer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by institutional investment managers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports by institutional investment managers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of equity security ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Statement of equity security ownership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Large trader reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Large trader reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accuracy of financial reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Accuracy of financial reports Each financial report that contains financial statements, and that is required to be prepared in accordance with (or reconciled to) generally accepted accounting principles under this chapter and filed with the Commission shall reflect all material correcting adjustments that have been identified by a registered public accounting firm in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and the rules and regulations of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Off-balance sheet transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Off-balance sheet transactions Not later than 180 days after July 30, 2002, the Commission shall issue final rules providing that each annual and quarterly financial report required to be filed with the Commission shall disclose all material off-balance sheet transactions, arrangements, obligations (including contingent obligations), and other relationships of the issuer with unconsolidated entities or other persons, that may have a material current or future effect on financial condition, changes in financial condition, results of operations, liquidity, capital expenditures, capital resources, or significant components of revenues or expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>