<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78m–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78m_1"><akn:num>78m–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and recordkeeping for certain security-based swaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78m–1. Reporting and recordkeeping for certain security-based swaps(a) Required reporting of security-based swaps not accepted by any clearing agency or derivatives clearing organization(1) In generalEach security-based swap that is not accepted for clearing by any clearing agency or derivatives clearing organization shall be reported to—(A) a security-based swap data repository described in section 78m(n) of this title; or

(B) in the case in which there is no security-based swap data repository that would accept the security-based swap, to the Commission pursuant to this section within such time period as the Commission may by rule or regulation prescribe.


(2) Transition rule for preenactment security-based swaps(A) Security-based swaps entered into before July 21, 2010Each security-based swap entered into before July 21, 2010, the terms of which have not expired as of July 21, 2010, shall be reported to a registered security-based swap data repository or the Commission by a date that is not later than—(i) 30 days after issuance of the interim final rule; or

(ii) such other period as the Commission determines to be appropriate.


(B) Commission rulemakingThe Commission shall promulgate an interim final rule within 90 days of July 21, 2010, providing for the reporting of each security-based swap entered into before July 21, 2010, as referenced in subparagraph (A).


(C) Effective dateThe reporting provisions described in this section shall be effective upon July 21, 2010.



(3) Reporting obligations(A) Security-based swaps in which only 1 counterparty is a security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participantWith respect to a security-based swap in which only 1 counterparty is a security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participant, the security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participant shall report the security-based swap as required under paragraphs (1) and (2).


(B) Security-based swaps in which 1 counterparty </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required reporting of security-based swaps not accepted by any clearing agency or derivatives clearing organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required reporting of security-based swaps not accepted by any clearing agency or derivatives clearing organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of certain individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of certain individuals Any individual or entity that enters into a security-based swap shall meet each requirement described in subsection (c) if the individual or entity did not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements An individual or entity described in subsection (b) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78m_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identical data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identical data In prescribing rules under this section, the Commission shall require individuals and entities described in subsection (b) to submit to the Commission a report that contains data that is not less comprehensive than the data required to be collected by security-based swap data repositories under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>