<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78n–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78n–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78n–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78n_1"><akn:num>78n–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder approval of executive compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78n–1. Shareholder approval of executive compensation(a) Separate resolution required(1) In generalNot less frequently than once every 3 years, a proxy or consent or authorization for an annual or other meeting of the shareholders for which the proxy solicitation rules of the Commission require compensation disclosure shall include a separate resolution subject to shareholder vote to approve the compensation of executives, as disclosed pursuant to section 229.402 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto.


(2) Frequency of voteNot less frequently than once every 6 years, a proxy or consent or authorization for an annual or other meeting of the shareholders for which the proxy solicitation rules of the Commission require compensation disclosure shall include a separate resolution subject to shareholder vote to determine whether votes on the resolutions required under paragraph (1) will occur every 1, 2, or 3 years.


(3) Effective dateThe proxy or consent or authorization for the first annual or other meeting of the shareholders occurring after the end of the 6-month period beginning on July 21, 2010, shall include—(A) the resolution described in paragraph (1); and

(B) a separate resolution subject to shareholder vote to determine whether votes on the resolutions required under paragraph (1) will occur every 1, 2, or 3 years.



(b) Shareholder approval of golden parachute compensation(1) DisclosureIn any proxy or consent solicitation material (the solicitation of which is subject to the rules of the Commission pursuant to subsection (a)) for a meeting of the shareholders occurring after the end of the 6-month period beginning on July 21, 2010, at which shareholders are asked to approve an acquisition, merger, consolidation, or proposed sale or other disposition of all or substantially all the assets of an issuer, the person making such solicitation shall disclose in the proxy or consent solicitation material, in a clear and simple form i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78n_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate resolution required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Separate resolution required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78n_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder approval of golden parachute compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Shareholder approval of golden parachute compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78n_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction The shareholder vote referred to in subsections (a) and (b) shall not be binding on the issuer or the board of directors of an issuer, and may not be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78n_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of votes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure of votes Every institutional investment manager subject to section 78m(f) of this title shall report at least annually how it voted on any shareholder vote pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), unless such vote is otherwise required to be reported publicly by rule or regulation of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78n_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>