<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78nn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78nn/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78nn/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78nn"><akn:num>78nn</akn:num><akn:heading>Tennessee Valley Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78nn. Tennessee Valley Authority(a) In generalCommencing with the issuance by the Tennessee Valley Authority of an annual report on Commission Form 10–K (or any successor thereto) for fiscal year 2006 and thereafter, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall file with the Commission, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission has prescribed or may prescribe, such periodic, current, and supplementary information, documents, and reports as would be required pursuant to section 78m of this title if the Tennessee Valley Authority were an issuer of a security registered pursuant to section 78l of this title. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall not be required to register any securities under this chapter, and shall not be deemed to have registered any securities under this chapter.


(b) Limited treatment as issuerCommencing with the issuance by the Tennessee Valley Authority of an annual report on Commission Form 10–K (or any successor thereto) for fiscal year 2006 and thereafter, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall be deemed to be an issuer for purposes of section 78j–1 of this title, other than for subsection (m)(1) or (m)(3) of section 78j–1 of this title. The Tennessee Valley Authority shall not be required by this subsection to comply with the rules issued by any national securities exchange or national securities association in response to rules issued by the Commission pursuant to section 78j–1(m)(1) of this title.


(c) No effect on TVA authorityNothing in this section shall be construed to diminish, impair, or otherwise affect the authority of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority to carry out its statutory functions under the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 [16 U.S.C. 831 et seq.].


(June 6, 1934, ch. 404, title I, § 37, as added Pub. L. 108–447, div. H, title V, § 520(2), Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 3267.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78nn_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Commencing with the issuance by the Tennessee Valley Authority of an annual report on Commission Form 10–K (or any successor thereto) for fiscal year 2006 and thereafter, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall file with the Commission, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission has prescribed or may prescribe, such periodic, current, and supplementary information, documents, and reports as would be required pursuant to section 78m of this title if the Tennessee Valley Authority were an issuer of a security registered pursuant to section 78l of this title. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall not be required to register any securities under this chapter, and shall not be deemed to have registered any securities under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78nn_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited treatment as issuer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limited treatment as issuer Commencing with the issuance by the Tennessee Valley Authority of an annual report on Commission Form 10–K (or any successor thereto) for fiscal year 2006 and thereafter, the Tennessee Valley Authority shall be deemed to be an issuer for purposes of section 78j–1 of this title, other than for subsection (m)(1) or (m)(3) of section 78j–1 of this title. The Tennessee Valley Authority shall not be required by this subsection to comply with the rules issued by any national securities exchange or national securities association in response to rules issued by the Commission pursuant to section 78j–1(m)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78nn_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on TVA authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No effect on TVA authority Nothing in this section shall be construed to diminish, impair, or otherwise affect the authority of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority to carry out its statutory functions under the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 [16 U.S.C. 831 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>