<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78o"><akn:num>78o</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and regulation of brokers and dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78o. Registration and regulation of brokers and dealers(a) Registration of all persons utilizing exchange facilities to effect transactions; exemptions(1) It shall be unlawful for any broker or dealer which is either a person other than a natural person or a natural person not associated with a broker or dealer which is a person other than a natural person (other than such a broker or dealer whose business is exclusively intrastate and who does not make use of any facility of a national securities exchange) to make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce to effect any transactions in, or to induce or attempt to induce the purchase or sale of, any security (other than an exempted security or commercial paper, bankers’ acceptances, or commercial bills) unless such broker or dealer is registered in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.

(2) The Commission, by rule or order, as it deems consistent with the public interest and the protection of investors, may conditionally or unconditionally exempt from paragraph (1) of this subsection any broker or dealer or class of brokers or dealers specified in such rule or order.


(b) Manner of registration of brokers and dealers(1) A broker or dealer may be registered by filing with the Commission an application for registration in such form and containing such information and documents concerning such broker or dealer and any persons associated with such broker or dealer as the Commission, by rule, may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors. Within forty-five days of the date of the filing of such application (or within such longer period as to which the applicant consents), the Commission shall—(A) by order grant registration, or

(B) institute proceedings to determine whether registration should be denied. Such proceedings shall include notice of the grounds for denial under consideration and opportunity for hearing and shall b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of all persons utilizing exchange facilities to effect transactions; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration of all persons utilizing exchange facilities to effect transactions; exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of registration of brokers and dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Manner of registration of brokers and dealers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of manipulative or deceptive devices; contravention of rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of manipulative or deceptive devices; contravention of rules and regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary and periodic information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supplementary and periodic information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notices to customers regarding securities lending</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notices to customers regarding securities lending Every registered broker or dealer shall provide notice to its customers that they may elect not to allow their fully paid securities to be used in connection with short sales. If a broker or dealer uses a customer’s securities in connection with short sales, the broker or dealer shall provide notice to its customer that the broker or dealer may receive compensation in connection with lending the customer’s securities. The Commission, by rule, as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest and for the protection of investors, may prescribe the form, content, time, and manner of delivery of any notice required under this paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with this chapter by members not required to be registered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compliance with this chapter by members not required to be registered The Commission, by rule, as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest and for the protection of investors or to assure equal regulation, may require any member of a national securities exchange not required to register under this section and any person associated with any such member to comply with any provision of this chapter (other than subsection (a)) or the rules or regulations thereunder which by its terms regulates or prohibits any act, practice, or course of business by a “broker or dealer” or “registered broker or dealer” or a “person associated with a broker or dealer,” respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of misuse of material, nonpublic information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prevention of misuse of material, nonpublic information Every registered broker or dealer shall establish, maintain, and enforce written policies and procedures reasonably designed, taking into consideration the nature of such broker’s or dealer’s business, to prevent the misuse in violation of this chapter, or the rules or regulations thereunder, of material, nonpublic information by such broker or dealer or any person associated with such broker or dealer. The Commission, as it deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, shall adopt rules or regulations to require specific policies or procedures reasonably designed to prevent misuse in violation of this chapter (or the rules or regulations thereunder) of material, nonpublic information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for transactions in penny stocks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Requirements for transactions in penny stocks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitations on State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>44 So in original. There are two subsecs. designated (j). Rulemaking to extend requirements to new hybrid products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>