<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–10" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–10/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–10/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78o_10"><akn:num>78o–10</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and regulation of security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78o–10. Registration and regulation of security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participants(a) Registration(1) Security-based swap dealersIt shall be unlawful for any person to act as a security-based swap dealer unless the person is registered as a security-based swap dealer with the Commission.


(2) Major security-based swap participantsIt shall be unlawful for any person to act as a major security-based swap participant unless the person is registered as a major security-based swap participant with the Commission.



(b) Requirements(1) In generalA person shall register as a security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participant by filing a registration application with the Commission.


(2) Contents(A) In generalThe application shall be made in such form and manner as prescribed by the Commission, and shall contain such information, as the Commission considers necessary concerning the business in which the applicant is or will be engaged.


(B) Continual reportingA person that is registered as a security-based swap dealer or major security-based swap participant shall continue to submit to the Commission reports that contain such information pertaining to the business of the person as the Commission may require.



(3) ExpirationEach registration under this section shall expire at such time as the Commission may prescribe by rule or regulation.


(4) RulesExcept as provided in subsections (d) and (e), the Commission may prescribe rules applicable to security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participants, including rules that limit the activities of non-bank security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participants.


(5) TransitionNot later than 1 year after July 21, 2010, the Commission shall issue rules under this section to provide for the registration of security-based swap dealers and major security-based swap participants.


(6) Statutory disqualificationExcept to the extent otherwise specifica</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dual registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital and margin requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Capital and margin requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting and recordkeeping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Daily trading records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Daily trading records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business conduct standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Business conduct standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Documentation standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_10_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Duties Each registered security-based swap dealer and major security-based swap participant shall, at all times, comply with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>