<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78o_11"><akn:num>78o–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit risk retention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78o–11. Credit risk retention(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “Federal banking agencies” means the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;

(2) the term “insured depository institution” has the same meaning as in section 1813(c) of title 12;

(3) the term “securitizer” means—(A) an issuer of an asset-backed security; or

(B) a person who organizes and initiates an asset-backed securities transaction by selling or transferring assets, either directly or indirectly, including through an affiliate, to the issuer; and


(4) the term “originator” means a person who—(A) through the extension of credit or otherwise, creates a financial asset that collateralizes an asset-backed security; and

(B) sells an asset directly or indirectly to a securitizer.



(b) Regulations required(1) In generalNot later than 270 days after July 21, 2010, the Federal banking agencies and the Commission shall jointly prescribe regulations to require any securitizer to retain an economic interest in a portion of the credit risk for any asset that the securitizer, through the issuance of an asset-backed security, transfers, sells, or conveys to a third party.


(2) Residential mortgagesNot later than 270 days after July 21, 2010, the Federal banking agencies, the Commission, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Federal Housing Finance Agency, shall jointly prescribe regulations to require any securitizer to retain an economic interest in a portion of the credit risk for any residential mortgage asset that the securitizer, through the issuance of an asset-backed security, transfers, sells, or conveys to a third party.



(c) Standards for regulations(1) StandardsThe regulations prescribed under subsection (b) shall—(A) prohibit a securitizer from directly or indirectly hedging or otherwise transferring the credit risk that the securitizer is required to retain wit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Standards for regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Originators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Originators In determining how to allocate risk retention obligations between a securitizer and an originator under subsection (c)(1)(E)(iv), the Federal banking agencies and the Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions, exceptions, and adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemptions, exceptions, and adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enforcement The regulations issued under this section shall be enforced by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authority of Commission The authority of the Commission under this section shall be in addition to the authority of the Commission to otherwise enforce the securities laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to coordinate on rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authority to coordinate on rulemaking The Chairperson of the Financial Stability Oversight Council shall coordinate all joint rulemaking required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_11_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effective date of regulations The regulations issued under this section shall become effective—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>