<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78o–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78o_4"><akn:num>78o–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Municipal securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78o–4. Municipal securities(a) Registration of municipal securities dealers(1)(A) It shall be unlawful for any municipal securities dealer (other than one registered as a broker or dealer under section 78o of this title) to make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce to effect any transaction in, or to induce or attempt to induce the purchase or sale of, any municipal security unless such municipal securities dealer is registered in accordance with this subsection.

(B) It shall be unlawful for a municipal advisor to provide advice to or on behalf of a municipal entity or obligated person with respect to municipal financial products or the issuance of municipal securities, or to undertake a solicitation of a municipal entity or obligated person, unless the municipal advisor is registered in accordance with this subsection.


(2) A municipal securities dealer or municipal advisor may be registered by filing with the Commission an application for registration in such form and containing such information and documents concerning such municipal securities dealer or municipal advisor and any persons associated with such municipal securities dealer or municipal advisor as the Commission, by rule, may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors. Within forty-five days of the date of the filing of such application (or within such longer period as to which the applicant consents), the Commission shall—(A) by order grant registration, or

(B) institute proceedings to determine whether registration should be denied. Such proceedings shall include notice of the grounds for denial under consideration and opportunity for hearing and shall be concluded within one hundred twenty days of the date of the filing of the application for registration. At the conclusion of such proceedings the Commission, by order, shall grant or deny such registration. The Commission may extend the time for the conclus</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of municipal securities dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration of municipal securities dealers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board; rules and regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discipline of municipal securities dealers; censure; suspension or revocation of registration; other sanctions; investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discipline of municipal securities dealers; censure; suspension or revocation of registration; other sanctions; investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of municipal securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuance of municipal securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78o_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>