<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78oo" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78oo/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78oo/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78oo"><akn:num>78oo</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal National Mortgage Association, Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, Federal Home Loan Ban</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78oo. Federal National Mortgage Association, Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, Federal Home Loan Banks(a) Federal National Mortgage Association and Federal Home Loan Mortgage CorporationNo class of equity securities of the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall be treated as an exempted security for purposes of section 78l, 78m, 78n, or 78p of this title.


(b) Federal Home Loan Banks(1) RegistrationEach Federal Home Loan Bank shall register a class of its common stock under section 78l(g) of this title, not later than 120 days after July 30, 2008, and shall thereafter maintain such registration and be treated for purposes of this chapter as an “issuer”, the securities of which are required to be registered under section 78l of this title, regardless of the number of members holding such stock at any given time.


(2) Standards relating to audit committeesEach Federal Home Loan Bank shall comply with the rules issued by the Commission under section 78j–1(m) of this title.



(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Federal Home Loan Bank; memberThe terms “Federal Home Loan Bank” and “member”, have the same meanings as in section 1422 of title 12.


(2) Federal National Mortgage AssociationThe term “Federal National Mortgage Association” means the corporation created by the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act [12 U.S.C. 1716 et seq.].


(3) Federal Home Loan Mortgage CorporationThe term “Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation” means the corporation created by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act [12 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.].



(June 6, 1934, ch. 404, title I, § 38, as added Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1112, July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2677.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), was in the original “this title”. See References in Text note set out under section 78a of this title and Codification </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78oo_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal National Mortgage Association and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal National Mortgage Association and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation No class of equity securities of the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall be treated as an exempted security for purposes of section 78l, 78m, 78n, or 78p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78oo_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Home Loan Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal Home Loan Banks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78oo_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>