<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78pp" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78pp/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78pp/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78pp"><akn:num>78pp</akn:num><akn:heading>Investor Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78pp. Investor Advisory Committee(a) Establishment and purpose(1) EstablishmentThere is established within the Commission the Investor Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the “Committee”).


(2) PurposeThe Committee shall—(A) advise and consult with the Commission on—(i) regulatory priorities of the Commission;

(ii) issues relating to the regulation of securities products, trading strategies, and fee structures, and the effectiveness of disclosure;

(iii) initiatives to protect investor interest; and

(iv) initiatives to promote investor confidence and the integrity of the securities marketplace; and


(B) submit to the Commission such findings and recommendations as the Committee determines are appropriate, including recommendations for proposed legislative changes.



(b) Membership(1) In generalThe members of the Committee shall be—(A) the Investor Advocate;

(B) a representative of State securities commissions;

(C) a representative of the interests of senior citizens; and

(D) not fewer than 10, and not more than 20, members appointed by the Commission, from among individuals who—(i) represent the interests of individual equity and debt investors, including investors in mutual funds;

(ii) represent the interests of institutional investors, including the interests of pension funds and registered investment companies;

(iii) are knowledgeable about investment issues and decisions; and

(iv) have reputations of integrity.



(2) TermEach member of the Committee appointed under paragraph (1)(B) shall serve for a term of 4 years.


(3) Members not Commission employeesMembers appointed under paragraph (1)(B) shall not be deemed to be employees or agents of the Commission solely because of membership on the Committee.



(c) Chairman; vice chairman; secretary; assistant secretary(1) In generalThe members of the Committee shall elect, from among the members of the Committee—(A) a chairman, who may not be employed by an issuer;

(B) a vice chairman, w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman; vice chairman; secretary; assistant secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairman; vice chairman; secretary; assistant secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation and travel expenses Each member of the Committee who is not a full-time employee of the United States shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Staff The Commission shall make available to the Committee such staff as the chairman of the Committee determines are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review by Commission The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Committee findings Nothing in this section shall require the Commission to agree to or act upon any finding or recommendation of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply with respect to the Committee and its activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78pp_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>