<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78q"><akn:num>78q</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78q. Records and reports(a) Rules and regulations(1) Every national securities exchange, member thereof, broker or dealer who transacts a business in securities through the medium of any such member, registered securities association, registered broker or dealer, registered municipal securities dealer municipal advisor,,11 So in original. registered securities information processor, registered transfer agent, nationally recognized statistical rating organization, and registered clearing agency and the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board shall make and keep for prescribed periods such records, furnish such copies thereof, and make and disseminate such reports as the Commission, by rule, prescribes as necessary or appropriate in the public interest, for the protection of investors, or otherwise in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter. Any report that a nationally recognized statistical rating organization is required by Commission rules under this paragraph to make and disseminate to the Commission shall be deemed furnished to the Commission.

(2) Every registered clearing agency shall also make and keep for prescribed periods such records, furnish such copies thereof, and make and disseminate such reports, as the appropriate regulatory agency for such clearing agency, by rule, prescribes as necessary or appropriate for the safeguarding of securities and funds in the custody or control of such clearing agency or for which it is responsible.

(3) Every registered transfer agent shall also make and keep for prescribed periods such rec­ords, furnish such copies thereof, and make such reports as the appropriate regulatory agency for such transfer agent, by rule, prescribes as necessary or appropriate in furtherance of the purposes of section 78q–1 of this title.


(b) Records subject to examination(1) Procedures for cooperation with other agenciesAll records of persons described in subsection (a) of this section are subject at any time, or from time to time, to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records subject to examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Records subject to examination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copies of reports filed with other regulatory agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Copies of reports filed with other regulatory agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-regulatory organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Self-regulatory organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Balance sheet and income statement; other financial statements and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Balance sheet and income statement; other financial statements and information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missing, lost, counterfeit, and stolen securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Missing, lost, counterfeit, and stolen securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons extending credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Persons extending credit Any broker, dealer, or other person extending credit who is subject to the rules and regulations prescribed by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System pursuant to this chapter shall make such reports to the Board as it may require as necessary or appropriate to enable it to perform the functions conferred upon it by this chapter. If any such broker, dealer, or other person shall fail to make any such report or fail to furnish full information therein, or, if in the judgment of the Board it is otherwise necessary, such broker, dealer, or other person shall permit such inspections to be made by the Board with respect to the business operations of such broker, dealer, or other person as the Board may deem necessary to enable it to obtain the required information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk assessment for holding company systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Risk assessment for holding company systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to limit disclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authority to limit disclosure of information Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commission shall not be compelled to disclose any information required to be reported under subsection (h) or (i) 6 or any information supplied to the Commission by any domestic or foreign regulatory agency that relates to the financial or operational condition of any associated person of a broker or dealer, investment bank holding company, or any affiliate of an investment bank holding company. Nothing in this subsection shall authorize the Commission to withhold information from Congress, or prevent the Commission from complying with a request for information from any other Federal department or agency or any self-regulatory organization requesting the information for purposes within the scope of its jurisdiction, or complying with an order of a court of the United States in an action brought by the United States or the Commission. For purposes of section 552 of title 5, this subsection s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of examining authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination of examining authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>