<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78q–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78q_1"><akn:num>78q–1</akn:num><akn:heading>National system for clearance and settlement of securities transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78q–1. National system for clearance and settlement of securities transactions(a) Congressional findings; facilitating establishment of system(1) The Congress finds that—(A) The prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of securities transactions, including the transfer of record ownership and the safeguarding of securities and funds related thereto, are necessary for the protection of investors and persons facilitating transactions by and acting on behalf of investors.

(B) Inefficient procedures for clearance and settlement impose unnecessary costs on investors and persons facilitating transactions by and acting on behalf of investors.

(C) New data processing and communications techniques create the opportunity for more efficient, effective, and safe procedures for clearance and settlement.

(D) The linking of all clearance and settlement facilities and the development of uniform standards and procedures for clearance and settlement will reduce unnecessary costs and increase the protection of investors and persons facilitating transactions by and acting on behalf of investors.


(2)(A) The Commission is directed, therefore, having due regard for the public interest, the protection of investors, the safeguarding of securities and funds, and maintenance of fair competition among brokers and dealers, clearing agencies, and transfer agents, to use its authority under this chapter—(i) to facilitate the establishment of a national system for the prompt and accurate clearance and settlement of transactions in securities (other than exempt securities); and

(ii) to facilitate the establishment of linked or coordinated facilities for clearance and settlement of transactions in securities, securities options, contracts of sale for future delivery and options thereon, and commodity options;


in accordance with the findings and to carry out the objectives set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection.

(B) The Commission shall use its authority under this chapter to as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings; facilitating establishment of system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings; facilitating establishment of system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of clearing agencies; application; determinations by Commission requisite to registration of applicant as clearing agency; denial of participation; discipline; summary proceedings; exemption; facilities for handling derivatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration of clearing agencies; application; determinations by Commission requisite to registration of applicant as clearing agency; denial of participation; discipline; summary proceedings; exemption; facilities for handling derivatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of transfer agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration of transfer agents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities of clearing agencies and transfer agents; enforcement by appropriate regulatory agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities of clearing agencies and transfer agents; enforcement by appropriate regulatory agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical movement of securities certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Physical movement of securities certificates The Commission shall use its authority under this chapter to end the physical movement of securities certificates in connection with the settlement among brokers and dealers of transactions in securities consummated by means of the mails or any means or instrumentalities of interstate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules concerning transfer of securities and rights and obligations of involved or affected parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules concerning transfer of securities and rights and obligations of involved or affected parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>33 So in original. Two subsecs. (g) have been enacted. Due diligence for the delivery of dividends, interest, and other valuable property rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>3 Registration requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) It shall be unlawful for a clearing agency, unless registered with the Commission, directly or indirectly to make use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce to perform the functions of a clearing agency with respect to a security-based swap.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Voluntary registration A person that clears agreements, contracts, or transactions that are not required to be cleared under this chapter may register with the Commission as a clearing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78q_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for clearing agencies clearing security-based swap transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Standards for clearing agencies clearing security-based swap transactions To be registered and to maintain registration as a clearing agency that clears security-based swap transactions, a clearing agency shall comply with such standards as the Commission may establish by rule. In establishing any such standards, and in the exercise of its oversight of such a clearing agency pursuant to this chapter, the Commission may conform such standards or oversight to reflect evolving United States and international standards. Except where the Commission determines otherwise by rule or regulation, a clearing agency shall have reasonable discretion in establishing the manner in which it complies with any such standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>