<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78u_7"><akn:num>78u–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation and transition provisions for whistleblower protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78u–7. Implementation and transition provisions for whistleblower protection(a) Implementing rulesThe Commission shall issue final regulations implementing the provisions of section 78u–6 of this title, as added by this subtitle, not later than 270 days after July 21, 2010.


(b) Original informationInformation provided to the Commission in writing by a whistleblower shall not lose the status of original information (as defined in section 78u–6(a)(3) of this title, as added by this subtitle) solely because the whistleblower provided the information prior to the effective date of the regulations, if the information is provided by the whistleblower after July 21, 2010.


(c) AwardsA whistleblower may receive an award pursuant to section 78u–6 of this title, as added by this subtitle, regardless of whether any violation of a provision of the securities laws, or a rule or regulation thereunder, underlying the judicial or administrative action upon which the award is based, occurred prior to July 21, 2010.


(d) Administration and enforcementThe Securities and Exchange Commission shall establish a separate office within the Commission to administer and enforce the provisions of section 78u–6 of this title (as add 11 So in original. Probably should be “added”. by section 922(a)).22 See References in Text note below. Such office shall report annually to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on its activities, whistleblower complaints, and the response of the Commission to such complaints.


(Pub. L. 111–203, title IX, § 924, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1850.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subtitle, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c), means subtitle B (§§ 921–929Z) of title IX of Pub. L. 111–203.
Section 922(a), referred to in subsec. (d), means section 922(a) of Pub. L. 111–203.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Investor Protection and Securities Re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementing rules The Commission shall issue final regulations implementing the provisions of section 78u–6 of this title, as added by this subtitle, not later than 270 days after July 21, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Original information Information provided to the Commission in writing by a whistleblower shall not lose the status of original information (as defined in section 78u–6(a)(3) of this title, as added by this subtitle) solely because the whistleblower provided the information prior to the effective date of the regulations, if the information is provided by the whistleblower after July 21, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Awards A whistleblower may receive an award pursuant to section 78u–6 of this title, as added by this subtitle, regardless of whether any violation of a provision of the securities laws, or a rule or regulation thereunder, underlying the judicial or administrative action upon which the award is based, occurred prior to July 21, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration and enforcement The Securities and Exchange Commission shall establish a separate office within the Commission to administer and enforce the provisions of section 78u–6 of this title (as add 11 So in original. Probably should be “added”. by section 922(a)).22 See References in Text note below. Such office shall report annually to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on its activities, whistleblower complaints, and the response of the Commission to such complaints.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>