<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78u_6"><akn:num>78u–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities whistleblower incentives and protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78u–6. Securities whistleblower incentives and protection(a) DefinitionsIn this section the following definitions shall apply:(1) Covered judicial or administrative actionThe term “covered judicial or administrative action” means any judicial or administrative action brought by the Commission under the securities laws that results in monetary sanctions exceeding $1,000,000.


(2) FundThe term “Fund” means the Securities and Exchange Commission Investor Protection Fund.


(3) Original informationThe term “original information” means information that—(A) is derived from the independent knowledge or analysis of a whistleblower;

(B) is not known to the Commission from any other source, unless the whistleblower is the original source of the information; and

(C) is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or administrative hearing, in a governmental report, hearing, audit, or investigation, or from the news media, unless the whistleblower is a source of the information.


(4) Monetary sanctionsThe term “monetary sanctions”, when used with respect to any judicial or administrative action, means—(A) any monies, including penalties, disgorgement, and interest, ordered to be paid; and

(B) any monies deposited into a disgorgement fund or other fund pursuant to section 308(b) of the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 (15 U.S.C. 7246(b)), as a result of such action or any settlement of such action.


(5) Related actionThe term “related action”, when used with respect to any judicial or administrative action brought by the Commission under the securities laws, means any judicial or administrative action brought by an entity described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of subsection (h)(2)(D)(i) that is based upon the original information provided by a whistleblower pursuant to subsection (a) that led to the successful enforcement of the Commission action.


(6) WhistleblowerThe term “whistleblower” means any individual who provides, or 2 or more individuals acting j</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount of award; denial of award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of amount of award; denial of award</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Representation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No contract necessary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No contract necessary No contract with the Commission is necessary for any whistleblower to receive an award under subsection (b), unless otherwise required by the Commission by rule or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appeals Any determination made under this section, including whether, to whom, or in what amount to make awards, shall be in the discretion of the Commission. Any such determination, except the determination of the amount of an award if the award was made in accordance with subsection (b), may be appealed to the appropriate court of appeals of the United States not more than 30 days after the determination is issued by the Commission. The court shall review the determination made by the Commission in accordance with section 706 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investor Protection Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Investor Protection Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Fund 11 So in original. Probably should be designated “(2)”.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of Fund The Fund shall be available to the Commission, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, for paying awards to whistleblowers as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of whistleblowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Protection of whistleblowers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_6_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of false information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Provision of false information A whistleblower shall not be entitled to an award under this section if the whistleblower—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>