<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78u_1"><akn:num>78u–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties for insider trading</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78u–1. Civil penalties for insider trading(a) Authority to impose civil penalties(1) Judicial actions by Commission authorizedWhenever it shall appear to the Commission that any person has violated any provision of this chapter or the rules or regulations thereunder by purchasing or selling a security or security-based swap agreement while in possession of material, nonpublic information in, or has violated any such provision by communicating such information in connection with, a transaction on or through the facilities of a national securities exchange or from or through a broker or dealer, and which is not part of a public offering by an issuer of securities other than standardized options or security futures products, the Commission—(A) may bring an action in a United States district court to seek, and the court shall have jurisdiction to impose, a civil penalty to be paid by the person who committed such violation; and

(B) may, subject to subsection (b)(1), bring an action in a United States district court to seek, and the court shall have jurisdiction to impose, a civil penalty to be paid by a person who, at the time of the violation, directly or indirectly controlled the person who committed such violation.


(2) Amount of penalty for person who committed violationThe amount of the penalty which may be imposed on the person who committed such violation shall be determined by the court in light of the facts and circumstances, but shall not exceed three times the profit gained or loss avoided as a result of such unlawful purchase, sale, or communication.


(3) Amount of penalty for controlling personThe amount of the penalty which may be imposed on any person who, at the time of the violation, directly or indirectly controlled the person who committed such violation, shall be determined by the court in light of the facts and circumstances, but shall not exceed the greater of $1,000,000, or three times the amount of the profit gained or loss avoided as a resu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to impose civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to impose civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority of Commission The Commission, by such rules, regulations, and orders as it considers necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors, may exempt, in whole or in part, either unconditionally or upon specific terms and conditions, any person or transaction or class of persons or transactions from this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedures for collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definition For purposes of this section, “profit gained” or “loss avoided” is the difference between the purchase or sale price of the security and the value of that security as measured by the trading price of the security a reasonable period after public dissemination of the nonpublic information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on Commission authority The authority of the Commission under this section with respect to security-based swap agreements shall be subject to the restrictions and limitations of section 78c–1(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Members and employees of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Duty of Members and employees of Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of other Federal officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Duty of other Federal officials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in initial public offerings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Participation in initial public offerings An individual described in section 13103(f) of title 5 may not purchase securities that are the subject of an initial public offering (within the meaning given such term in section 78l(f)(1)(G)(i) of this title) in any manner other than is available to members of the public generally.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>