<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78u–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78u_3"><akn:num>78u–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Cease-and-desist proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78u–3. Cease-and-desist proceedings(a) Authority of CommissionIf the Commission finds, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that any person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter, or any rule or regulation thereunder, the Commission may publish its findings and enter an order requiring such person, and any other person that is, was, or would be a cause of the violation, due to an act or omission the person knew or should have known would contribute to such violation, to cease and desist from committing or causing such violation and any future violation of the same provision, rule, or regulation. Such order may, in addition to requiring a person to cease and desist from committing or causing a violation, require such person to comply, or to take steps to effect compliance, with such provision, rule, or regulation, upon such terms and conditions and within such time as the Commission may specify in such order. Any such order may, as the Commission deems appropriate, require future compliance or steps to effect future compliance, either permanently or for such period of time as the Commission may specify, with such provision, rule, or regulation with respect to any security, any issuer, or any other person.


(b) HearingThe notice instituting proceedings pursuant to subsection (a) shall fix a hearing date not earlier than 30 days nor later than 60 days after service of the notice unless an earlier or a later date is set by the Commission with the consent of any respondent so served.


(c) Temporary order(1) In generalWhenever the Commission determines that the alleged violation or threatened violation specified in the notice instituting proceedings pursuant to subsection (a), or the continuation thereof, is likely to result in significant dissipation or conversion of assets, significant harm to investors, or substantial harm to the public interest, including, but not limited to, losses to the Securities Investor Protecti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Commission If the Commission finds, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that any person is violating, has violated, or is about to violate any provision of this chapter, or any rule or regulation thereunder, the Commission may publish its findings and enter an order requiring such person, and any other person that is, was, or would be a cause of the violation, due to an act or omission the person knew or should have known would contribute to such violation, to cease and desist from committing or causing such violation and any future violation of the same provision, rule, or regulation. Such order may, in addition to requiring a person to cease and desist from committing or causing a violation, require such person to comply, or to take steps to effect compliance, with such provision, rule, or regulation, upon such terms and conditions and within such time as the Commission may specify in such order. Any such order may, as the Commission deems appropriate, require </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearing The notice instituting proceedings pursuant to subsection (a) shall fix a hearing date not earlier than 30 days nor later than 60 days after service of the notice unless an earlier or a later date is set by the Commission with the consent of any respondent so served.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of temporary orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of temporary orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter order requiring accounting and disgorgement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to enter order requiring accounting and disgorgement In any cease-and-desist proceeding under subsection (a), the Commission may enter an order requiring accounting and dis­gorgement, including reasonable interest. The Commission is authorized to adopt rules, regulations, and orders concerning payments to investors, rates of interest, periods of accrual, and such other matters as it deems appropriate to implement this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78u_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Commission to prohibit persons from serving as officers or directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority of the Commission to prohibit persons from serving as officers or directors In any cease-and-desist proceeding under subsection (a), the Commission may issue an order to prohibit, conditionally or unconditionally, and permanently or for such period of time as it shall determine, any person who has violated section 78j(b) of this title or the rules or regulations thereunder, from acting as an officer or director of any issuer that has a class of securities registered pursuant to section 78l of this title, or that is required to file reports pursuant to section 78o(d) of this title, if the conduct of that person demonstrates unfitness to serve as an officer or director of any such issuer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>