<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78x" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78x/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/78x/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_78x"><akn:num>78x</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 78x. Public availability of information(a) “Records” definedFor purposes of section 552 of title 5 the term “records” includes all applications, statements, reports, contracts, correspondence, notices, and other documents filed with or otherwise obtained by the Commission pursuant to this chapter or otherwise.


(b) Disclosure or personal useIt shall be unlawful for any member, officer, or employee of the Commission to disclose to any person other than a member, officer, or employee of the Commission, or to use for personal benefit, any information contained in any application, statement, report, contract, correspondence, notice, or other document filed with or otherwise obtained by the Commission (1) in contravention of the rules and regulations of the Commission under section 552 of title 5, or (2) in circumstances where the Commission has determined pursuant to such rules to accord confidential treatment to such information.


(c) Confidential disclosuresThe Commission may, in its discretion and upon a showing that such information is needed, provide all “records” (as defined in subsection (a)) and other information in its possession to such persons, both domestic and foreign, as the Commission by rule deems appropriate if the person receiving such records or information provides such assurances of confidentiality as the Commission deems appropriate.


(d) Records obtained from foreign securities authoritiesExcept as provided in subsection (g), the Commission shall not be compelled to disclose records obtained from a foreign securities authority if (1) the foreign securities authority has in good faith determined and represented to the Commission that public disclosure of such records would violate the laws applicable to that foreign securities authority, and (2) the Commission obtains such records pursuant to (A) such procedure as the Commission may authorize for use in connection with the administration or enforcement of the securities laws, or (B) a memorand</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Records” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Records” defined For purposes of section 552 of title 5 the term “records” includes all applications, statements, reports, contracts, correspondence, notices, and other documents filed with or otherwise obtained by the Commission pursuant to this chapter or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure or personal use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure or personal use It shall be unlawful for any member, officer, or employee of the Commission to disclose to any person other than a member, officer, or employee of the Commission, or to use for personal benefit, any information contained in any application, statement, report, contract, correspondence, notice, or other document filed with or otherwise obtained by the Commission (1) in contravention of the rules and regulations of the Commission under section 552 of title 5, or (2) in circumstances where the Commission has determined pursuant to such rules to accord confidential treatment to such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidential disclosures The Commission may, in its discretion and upon a showing that such information is needed, provide all “records” (as defined in subsection (a)) and other information in its possession to such persons, both domestic and foreign, as the Commission by rule deems appropriate if the person receiving such records or information provides such assurances of confidentiality as the Commission deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records obtained from foreign securities authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Records obtained from foreign securities authorities Except as provided in subsection (g), the Commission shall not be compelled to disclose records obtained from a foreign securities authority if (1) the foreign securities authority has in good faith determined and represented to the Commission that public disclosure of such records would violate the laws applicable to that foreign securities authority, and (2) the Commission obtains such records pursuant to (A) such procedure as the Commission may authorize for use in connection with the administration or enforcement of the securities laws, or (B) a memorandum of understanding. For purposes of section 552 of title 5, this subsection shall be considered a statute described in subsection (b)(3)(B) of such section 552.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Freedom of Information Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Freedom of Information Act For purposes of section 552(b)(8) of title 5 (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing privileged information with other authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sharing privileged information with other authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_78x_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Savings provision Nothing in this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>