<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/790a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/790a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/790a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_790a"><akn:num>790a</akn:num><akn:heading>National Energy Information System; information required to be maintained</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 790a. National Energy Information System; information required to be maintained(a) It shall be the duty of the Director to establish a National Energy Information System (hereinafter referred to in this chapter as the “System”), which shall be operated and maintained by the Office. The System shall contain such information as is required to provide a description of and facilitate analysis of energy supply and consumption within and affecting the United States on the basis of such geographic areas and economic sectors as may be appropriate to meet adequately the needs of—(1) the Federal Energy Administration in carrying out its lawful functions;

(2) the Congress;

(3) other officers and employees of the United States in whom have been vested, or to whom have been delegated energy-related policy decisionmaking responsibilities; and

(4) the States to the extent required by the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.] and the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.].


(b) At a minimum, the System shall contain such energy information as is necessary to carry out the Administration’s statistical and forecasting activities, and shall include, at the earliest date and to the maximum extent practical subject to the resources available and the Director’s ordering of those resources to meet the responsibilities of his Office, such energy information as is required to define and permit analysis of—(1) the institutional structure of the energy supply system including patterns of ownership and control of mineral fuel and nonmineral energy resources and the production, distribution, and marketing of mineral fuels and electricity;

(2) the consumption of mineral fuels, nonmineral energy resources, and electricity by such classes, sectors, and regions as may be appropriate for the purposes of this chapter;

(3) the sensitivity of energy resource reserves, exploration, development, production, transportation, and consumption to economic factors, environmental constraints, tech</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_790a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) It shall be the duty of the Director to establish a National Energy Information System (hereinafter referred to in this chapter as the “System”), which shall be operated and maintained by the Office. The System shall contain such information as is required to provide a description of and facilitate analysis of energy supply and consumption within and affecting the United States on the basis of such geographic areas and economic sectors as may be appropriate to meet adequately the needs of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_790a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) At a minimum, the System shall contain such energy information as is necessary to carry out the Administration’s statistical and forecasting activities, and shall include, at the earliest date and to the maximum extent practical subject to the resources available and the Director’s ordering of those resources to meet the responsibilities of his Office, such energy information as is required to define and permit analysis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>