<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/792" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/792/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/792/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_792"><akn:num>792</akn:num><akn:heading>Coal conversion and allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 792. Coal conversion and allocation(a) Powerplant and fuel burning installationsThe Federal Energy Administrator—(1) shall, by order, prohibit any powerplant, and

(2) may, by order, prohibit any major fuel burning installation, other than a powerplant,


from burning natural gas or petroleum products as its primary energy source, if the requirements of subsection (b) are met and if (A) the Federal Energy Administrator determines such powerplant or installation on June 22, 1974, had, or thereafter acquires or is designed with, the capability and necessary plant equipment to burn coal, or (B) such powerplant or installation is required to meet a design or construction requirement under subsection (c).

(b) Prerequisites to issuance or effectiveness of orders prohibiting use of natural gas or petroleum products as primary energy sourceThe requirements referred to in subsection (a) are as follows:(1) An order under subsection (a) may not be issued with respect to a powerplant or installation unless the Federal Energy Administrator finds (A) that the burning of coal by such plant or installation, in lieu of petroleum products or natural gas, is practicable and consistent with the purposes of this chapter, (B) that coal and coal transportation facilities will be available during the period the order is in effect, and (C) in the case of a powerplant, that the prohibition under subsection (a) will not impair the reliability of service in the area served by such plant. Such an order shall be rescinded or modified to the extent the Federal Energy Administrator determines that any requirement described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of this paragraph is no longer met; and such an order may at any time be modified if the Federal Energy Administrator determines that such order, as modified, complies with the requirements of this section.

(2)(A) Before issuing an order under subsection (a) which is applicable to a powerplant or installation for a period ending on or before </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powerplant and fuel burning installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powerplant and fuel burning installations The Federal Energy Administrator— from burning natural gas or petroleum products as its primary energy source, if the requirements of subsection (b) are met and if (A) the Federal Energy Administrator determines such powerplant or installation on June 22, 1974, had, or thereafter acquires or is designed with, the capability and necessary plant equipment to burn coal, or (B) such powerplant or installation is required to meet a design or construction requirement under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites to issuance or effectiveness of orders prohibiting use of natural gas or petroleum products as primary energy source</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prerequisites to issuance or effectiveness of orders prohibiting use of natural gas or petroleum products as primary energy source The requirements referred to in subsection (a) are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and design of powerplants or other major fuel burning installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Construction and design of powerplants or other major fuel burning installations The Federal Energy Administrator may require that any powerplant or other major fuel burning installation in the early planning process (other than a combustion gas turbine or combined cycle unit) be designed and constructed so as to be capable of using coal as its primary energy source. No powerplant or other major fuel burning installation may be required under this subsection to be so designed and constructed, if the Administrator determines that (1) in the case of a powerplant to do so is likely to result in an impairment of reliability or adequacy of service, or (2) an adequate and reliable supply of coal is not expected to be available. In considering whether to impose a design and construction requirement under this subsection, the Federal Energy Administrator shall consider the existence and effects of any contractual commitment for the construction of such facilities and the capability of the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of coal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation of coal The Federal Energy Administrator may, by rule or order, allocate coal (1) to any powerplant or major fuel-burning installation to which an order under subsection (a) has been issued, or (2) to any other person to the extent necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration of authority; effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expiration of authority; effective dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>