<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/7a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7a"><akn:num>7a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7a. Definitions
In sections 7a to 7a–3 of this title:(1) Antitrust DivisionThe term “Antitrust Division” means the United States Department of Justice Antitrust Division.


(2) Antitrust leniency agreementThe term “antitrust leniency agreement,” or “agreement,” means a leniency letter agreement, whether conditional or final, between a person and the Antitrust Division pursuant to the Corporate Leniency Policy of the Antitrust Division in effect on the date of execution of the agreement.


(3) Antitrust leniency applicantThe term “antitrust leniency applicant,” or “applicant,” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, the person that has entered into the agreement.


(4) ClaimantThe term “claimant” means a person or class, that has brought, or on whose behalf has been brought, a civil action alleging a violation of section 1 or 3 of this title or any similar State law, except that the term does not include a State or a subdivision of a State with respect to a civil action brought to recover damages sustained by the State or subdivision.


(5) Cooperating individualThe term “cooperating individual” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, a current or former director, officer, or employee of the antitrust leniency applicant who is covered by the agreement.


(6) PersonThe term “person” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of section 12 of this title.


(Pub. L. 108–237, title II, § 212, June 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 666; Pub. L. 111–190, § 2, June 9, 2010, 124 Stat. 1275; Pub. L. 116–159, div. D, title III, § 4303(b)(2), Oct. 1, 2020, 134 Stat. 742.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 7a to 7a–3 of this title, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle A (§§ 211–216) of title II of Pub. L. 108–237, June 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 666, which enacted this section and sections 7a–1 to 7a–3 of this title, amended sections 1, 2, and 3 of this title, and enacted provisions formerly set out in a note under se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust Division</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Antitrust Division The term “Antitrust Division” means the United States Department of Justice Antitrust Division.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust leniency agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Antitrust leniency agreement The term “antitrust leniency agreement,” or “agreement,” means a leniency letter agreement, whether conditional or final, between a person and the Antitrust Division pursuant to the Corporate Leniency Policy of the Antitrust Division in effect on the date of execution of the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust leniency applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Antitrust leniency applicant The term “antitrust leniency applicant,” or “applicant,” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, the person that has entered into the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claimant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Claimant The term “claimant” means a person or class, that has brought, or on whose behalf has been brought, a civil action alleging a violation of section 1 or 3 of this title or any similar State law, except that the term does not include a State or a subdivision of a State with respect to a civil action brought to recover damages sustained by the State or subdivision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperating individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Cooperating individual The term “cooperating individual” means, with respect to an antitrust leniency agreement, a current or former director, officer, or employee of the antitrust leniency applicant who is covered by the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Person The term “person” has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of section 12 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>