<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8005"><akn:num>8005</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum State law requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8005. Minimum State law requirements(a) In general(1) Safety standardsA State meets the minimum State law requirements of this section if—(A) the State requires by statute—(i) the enclosure of all outdoor residential pools and spas by barriers to entry that will effectively prevent small children from gaining unsupervised and unfettered access to the pool or spa; and

(ii) that pools and spas built more than 1 year after the date of the enactment of such statute have—(I) more than 1 drain;

(II) 1 or more unblockable drains; or

(III) no main drain; and



(B) the State meets such additional State law requirements for pools and spas as the Commission may establish after public notice and a 30-day public comment period.


(2) Use of minimum State law requirementsThe Commission—(A) shall use the minimum State law requirements under paragraph (1) solely for the purpose of determining the eligibility of a covered entity for a grant under section 8004 of this title; and

(B) may not enforce any requirement under paragraph (1) except for the purpose of determining the eligibility of a covered entity for a grant under section 8004 of this title.


(3) Requirements to reflect national performance standards and Commission guidelinesIn establishing minimum State law requirements under paragraph (1)(B), the Commission shall—(A) consider current or revised national performance standards on pool and spa barrier protection and entrapment prevention; and

(B) ensure that any such requirements are consistent with the guidelines contained in the Commission’s publication 362, entitled “Safety Barrier Guidelines for Home Pools”, the Commission’s publication entitled “Guidelines for Entrapment Hazards: Making Pools and Spas Safer”, and any other pool safety guidelines established by the Commission.



(b) StandardsNothing in this section prevents the Commission from promulgating standards regulating pool and spa safety or from relying on an applicable national performance standard.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards Nothing in this section prevents the Commission from promulgating standards regulating pool and spa safety or from relying on an applicable national performance standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic access-related safety devices and equipment requirements to be considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Basic access-related safety devices and equipment requirements to be considered In establishing minimum State law requirements for swimming pools and spas under subsection (a)(1), the Commission shall consider the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entrapment, entanglement, and evisceration prevention standards to be required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Entrapment, entanglement, and evisceration prevention standards to be required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8005_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State defined In this section, the term “State” includes an Indian Tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>