<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–32" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–32/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–32/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80a_32"><akn:num>80a–32</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of documents with Commission in civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80a–32. Filing of documents with Commission in civil actions
Every registered investment company which is a party and every affiliated person of such company who is a party defendant to any action or claim by a registered investment company or a security holder thereof in a derivative or representative capacity against an officer, director, investment adviser, trustee, or depositor of such company, shall file with the Commission, unless already so filed, (1) a copy of all pleadings, verdicts, or judgments filed with the court or served in connection with such action or claim, (2) a copy of any proposed settlement, compromise, or discontinuance of such action, and (3) a copy of such motions, transcripts, or other documents filed in or issued by the court or served in connection with such action or claim as may be requested in writing by the Commission. If any document referred to in clause (1) or (2)—(A) is delivered to such company or party defendant, such document shall be filed with the Commission not later than ten days after the receipt thereof; or

(B) is filed in such court or delivered by such company or party defendant, such documents shall be filed with the Commission not later than five days after such filing or delivery.

(Aug. 22, 1940, ch. 686, title I, § 33, 54 Stat. 839; Pub. L. 91–547, § 19, Dec. 14, 1970, 84 Stat. 1428.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1970—Pub. L. 91–547 inserted provision for party acting in representative capacity and substituted provisions for prompt filing with the Commission of copies of all pleadings, verdicts, judgments, settlements, compromises, or discontinuances served or filed in suits by a registered investment company or a security holder thereof against an officer, director, investment adviser, trustee, or depositor of such company and of copies of motions, transcripts, or other documents if the Commission requests them for prior requirement that registered companies and their affiliated persons who are defendants in der</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_32_A"><akn:num>(A)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(A) is delivered to such company or party defendant, such document shall be filed with the Commission not later than ten days after the receipt thereof; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_32_B"><akn:num>(B)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(B) is filed in such court or delivered by such company or party defendant, such documents shall be filed with the Commission not later than five days after such filing or delivery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>