<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–29" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–29/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–29/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80a_29"><akn:num>80a–29</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and financial statements of investment companies and affiliated persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80a–29. Reports and financial statements of investment companies and affiliated persons(a) Annual report by companyEvery registered investment company shall file annually with the Commission such information, documents, and reports as investment companies having securities registered on a national securities exchange are required to file annually pursuant to section 13(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78m(a)] and the rules and regulations issued thereunder.


(b) Semi-annual or quarterly filing of information; copies of periodic or interim reports sent to security holdersEvery registered investment company shall file with the Commission—(1) such information, documents, and reports (other than financial statements), as the Commission may require to keep reasonably current the information and documents contained in the registration statement of such company filed under this subchapter; and

(2) copies of every periodic or interim report or similar communication containing financial statements and transmitted to any class of such company’s security holders, such copies to be filed not later than ten days after such transmission.


Any information or documents contained in a report or other communication to security holders filed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection may be incorporated by reference in any report subsequently or concurrently filed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.

(c) Minimizing reporting burdens(1) The Commission shall take such action as it deems necessary or appropriate, consistent with the public interest and the protection of investors, to avoid unnecessary reporting by, and minimize the compliance burdens on, registered investment companies and their affiliated persons in exercising its authority—(A) under subsection (f); and

(B) under subsection (b)(1), if the Commission requires the filing of information, documents, and reports under that subsection on a basis more frequently than semiannually.


(2) Ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report by company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report by company Every registered investment company shall file annually with the Commission such information, documents, and reports as investment companies having securities registered on a national securities exchange are required to file annually pursuant to section 13(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78m(a)] and the rules and regulations issued thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semi-annual or quarterly filing of information; copies of periodic or interim reports sent to security holders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Semi-annual or quarterly filing of information; copies of periodic or interim reports sent to security holders Every registered investment company shall file with the Commission— Any information or documents contained in a report or other communication to security holders filed pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection may be incorporated by reference in any report subsequently or concurrently filed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimizing reporting burdens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Minimizing reporting burdens</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports under this section in lieu of reports under other provisions of law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports under this section in lieu of reports under other provisions of law The Commission shall issue rules and regulations permitting the filing with the Commission, and with any national securities exchange concerned, of copies of periodic reports, or of extracts therefrom, filed by any registered investment company pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), in lieu of any reports and documents required of such company under section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78m or 78o(d)].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual reports to stockholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Semiannual reports to stockholders Every registered investment company shall transmit to its stockholders, at least semiannually, reports containing such of the following information and financial statements or their equivalent, as of a reasonably current date, as the Commission may prescribe by rules and regulations for the protection of investors, which reports shall not be misleading in any material respect in the light of the reports required to be filed pursuant to subsections (a) and (b):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional information The Commission may, by rule, require that semiannual reports containing the information set forth in subsection (e) include such other information as the Commission deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of independent public accountants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certificate of independent public accountants Financial statements contained in annual reports required pursuant to subsections (a) and (e), if required by the rules and regulations of the Commission, shall be accompanied by a certificate of independent public accountants. The certificate of such independent public accountants shall be based upon an audit not less in scope or procedures followed than that which independent public accountants would ordinarily make for the purpose of presenting comprehensive and dependable financial statements, and shall contain such information as the Commission may prescribe, by rules and regulations in the public interest or for the protection of investors, as to the nature and scope of the audit and the findings and opinion of the accountants. Each such report shall state that such independent public accountants have verified securities owned, either by actual examination, or by receipt of a certificate from the custodian, as the Commission may p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and liabilities of affiliated persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Duties and liabilities of affiliated persons Every person who is directly or indirectly the beneficial owner of more than 10 per centum of any class of outstanding securities (other than short-term paper) of which a registered closed-end company is the issuer or who is an officer, director, member of an advisory board, investment adviser, or affiliated person of an investment adviser of such a company shall in respect of his transactions in any securities of such company (other than short-term paper) be subject to the same duties and liabilities as those imposed by section 16 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78p] upon certain beneficial owners, directors, and officers in respect of their transactions in certain equity securities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to church plan participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure to church plan participants A person that maintains a church plan that is excluded from the definition of an investment company solely by reason of section 80a–3(c)(14) of this title shall provide disclosure to plan participants, in writing, and not less frequently than annually, and for new participants joining such a plan after May 31, 1996, as soon as is practicable after joining such plan, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_29_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notice to Commission The Commission may issue rules and regulations to require any person that maintains a church plan that is excluded from the definition of an investment company solely by reason of section 80a–3(c)(14) of this title to file a notice with the Commission containing such information and in such form as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or consistent with the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>