<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–17" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–17/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80a–17/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80a_17"><akn:num>80a–17</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions of certain affiliated persons and underwriters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80a–17. Transactions of certain affiliated persons and underwriters(a) Prohibited transactionsIt shall be unlawful for any affiliated person or promoter of or principal underwriter for a registered investment company (other than a company of the character described in section 80a–12(d)(3)(A) and (B) of this title), or any affiliated person of such a person, promoter, or principal underwriter, acting as principal—(1) knowingly to sell any security or other property to such registered company or to any company controlled by such registered company, unless such sale involves solely (A) securities of which the buyer is the issuer, (B) securities of which the seller is the issuer and which are part of a general offering to the holders of a class of its securities, or (C) securities deposited with the trustee of a unit investment trust or periodic payment plan by the depositor thereof;

(2) knowingly to purchase from such registered company, or from any company controlled by such registered company, any security or other property (except securities of which the seller is the issuer);

(3) to borrow money or other property from such registered company or from any company controlled by such registered company (unless the borrower is controlled by the lender) except as permitted in section 80a–21(b) of this title; or

(4) to loan money or other property to such registered company, or to any company controlled by such registered company, in contravention of such rules, regulations, or orders as the Commission may, after consultation with and taking into consideration the views of the Federal banking agencies (as defined in section 1813 of title 12), prescribe or issue consistent with the protection of investors.


(b) Application for exemption of proposed transaction from certain restrictionsNotwithstanding subsection (a), any person may file with the Commission an application for an order exempting a proposed transaction of the applicant from one or more provisions of said</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibited transactions It shall be unlawful for any affiliated person or promoter of or principal underwriter for a registered investment company (other than a company of the character described in section 80a–12(d)(3)(A) and (B) of this title), or any affiliated person of such a person, promoter, or principal underwriter, acting as principal—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for exemption of proposed transaction from certain restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application for exemption of proposed transaction from certain restrictions Notwithstanding subsection (a), any person may file with the Commission an application for an order exempting a proposed transaction of the applicant from one or more provisions of said subsection. The Commission shall grant such application and issue such order of exemption if evidence establishes that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale or purchase of merchandise from any company or furnishing of services incident to lessor-lessee relationship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale or purchase of merchandise from any company or furnishing of services incident to lessor-lessee relationship Notwithstanding subsection (a), a person may, in the ordinary course of business, sell to or purchase from any company merchandise or may enter into a lessor-lessee relationship with any person and furnish the services incident thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint or joint and several participation with company in transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Joint or joint and several participation with company in transactions It shall be unlawful for any affiliated person of or principal underwriter for a registered investment company (other than a company of the character described in section 80a–12(d)(3) (A) and (B) of this title), or any affiliated person of such a person or principal underwriter, acting as principal to effect any transaction in which such registered company, or a company controlled by such registered company, is a joint or a joint and several participant with such person, principal underwriter, or affiliated person, in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe for the purpose of limiting or preventing participation by such registered or controlled company on a basis different from or less advantageous than that of such other participant. Nothing contained in this subsection shall be deemed to preclude any affiliated person from acting as manager of any underwriting syndicate or ot</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of compensation, commissions, fees, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acceptance of compensation, commissions, fees, etc. It shall be unlawful for any affiliated person of a registered investment company, or any affiliated person of such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Custody of securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Custody of securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonding of officers and employees having access to securities or funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bonding of officers and employees having access to securities or funds The Commission is authorized to require by rules and regulations or orders for the protection of investors that any officer or employee of a registered management investment company who may singly, or jointly with others, have access to securities or funds of any registered company, either directly or through authority to draw upon such funds or to direct generally the disposition of such securities (unless the officer or employee has such access solely through his position as an officer or employee of a bank) be bonded by a reputable fidelity insurance company against larceny and embezzlement in such reasonable minimum amounts as the Commission may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions in charter, by-laws, etc., protecting against liability for willful misfeasance, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Provisions in charter, by-laws, etc., protecting against liability for willful misfeasance, etc. After one year from the effective date of this subchapter, neither the charter, certificate of incorporation, articles of association, indenture of trust, nor the by-laws of any registered investment company, nor any other instrument pursuant to which such a company is organized or administered, shall contain any provision which protects or purports to protect any director or officer of such company against any liability to the company or to its security holders to which he would otherwise be subject by reason of willful misfeasance, bad faith, gross negligence or reckless disregard of the duties involved in the conduct of his office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions in contracts protecting against willful misfeasance, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Provisions in contracts protecting against willful misfeasance, etc. After one year from the effective date of this subchapter no contract or agreement under which any person undertakes to act as investment adviser of, or principal underwriter for, a registered investment company shall contain any provision which protects or purports to protect such person against any liability to such company or its security holders to which he would otherwise be subject by reason of willful misfeasance, bad faith, or gross negligence, in the performance of his duties, or by reason of his reckless disregard of his obligations and duties under such contract or agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80a_17_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations prohibiting fraudulent, deceptive or manipulative courses of conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rules and regulations prohibiting fraudulent, deceptive or manipulative courses of conduct It shall be unlawful for any affiliated person of or principal underwriter for a registered investment company or any affiliated person of an investment adviser of or principal underwriter for a registered investment company, to engage in any act, practice, or course of business in connection with the purchase or sale, directly or indirectly, by such person of any security held or to be acquired by such registered investment company in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission may adopt to define, and prescribe means reasonably necessary to prevent, such acts, practices, or courses of business as are fraudulent, deceptive or manipulative. Such rules and regulations may include requirements for the adoption of codes of ethics by registered investment companies and investment advisers of, and principal underwriters for, such investment companies establishing such standards a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>