<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80b_11"><akn:num>80b–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules, regulations, and orders of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80b–11. Rules, regulations, and orders of Commission(a) Power of CommissionThe Commission shall have authority from time to time to make, issue, amend, and rescind such rules and regulations and such orders as are necessary or appropriate to the exercise of the functions and powers conferred upon the Commission elsewhere in this subchapter, including rules and regulations defining technical, trade, and other terms used in this subchapter, except that the Commission may not define the term “client” for purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 80b–6 of this title to include an investor in a private fund managed by an investment adviser, if such private fund has entered into an advisory contract with such adviser. For the purposes of its rules or regulations the Commission may classify persons and matters within its jurisdiction and prescribe different requirements for different classes of persons or matters.


(b) Effective date of regulationsSubject to the provisions of chapter 15 of title 44 and regulations prescribed under the authority thereof, the rules and regulations of the Commission under this subchapter, and amendments thereof, shall be effective upon publication in the manner which the Commission shall prescribe, or upon such later date as may be provided in such rules and regulations.


(c) Orders of Commission after notice and hearing; type of noticeOrders of the Commission under this subchapter shall be issued only after appropriate notice and opportunity for hearing. Notice to the parties to a proceeding before the Commission shall be given by personal service upon each party or by registered mail or certified mail or confirmed telegraphic notice to the party’s last known business address. Notice to interested persons, if any, other than parties may be given in the same manner or by publication in the Federal Register.


(d) Good faith compliance with rules and regulationsNo provision of this subchapter imposing any liability shall apply to any a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Power of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Power of Commission The Commission shall have authority from time to time to make, issue, amend, and rescind such rules and regulations and such orders as are necessary or appropriate to the exercise of the functions and powers conferred upon the Commission elsewhere in this subchapter, including rules and regulations defining technical, trade, and other terms used in this subchapter, except that the Commission may not define the term “client” for purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 80b–6 of this title to include an investor in a private fund managed by an investment adviser, if such private fund has entered into an advisory contract with such adviser. For the purposes of its rules or regulations the Commission may classify persons and matters within its jurisdiction and prescribe different requirements for different classes of persons or matters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective date of regulations Subject to the provisions of chapter 15 of title 44 and regulations prescribed under the authority thereof, the rules and regulations of the Commission under this subchapter, and amendments thereof, shall be effective upon publication in the manner which the Commission shall prescribe, or upon such later date as may be provided in such rules and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orders of Commission after notice and hearing; type of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Orders of Commission after notice and hearing; type of notice Orders of the Commission under this subchapter shall be issued only after appropriate notice and opportunity for hearing. Notice to the parties to a proceeding before the Commission shall be given by personal service upon each party or by registered mail or certified mail or confirmed telegraphic notice to the party’s last known business address. Notice to interested persons, if any, other than parties may be given in the same manner or by publication in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good faith compliance with rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Good faith compliance with rules and regulations No provision of this subchapter imposing any liability shall apply to any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any rule, regulation, or order of the Commission, notwithstanding that such rule, regulation, or order may, after such act or omission, be amended or rescinded or be determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure rules on private funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure rules on private funds The Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall, after consultation with the Council but not later than 12 months after July 21, 2010, jointly promulgate rules to establish the form and content of the reports required to be filed with the Commission under subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 80b–4(b) of this title and with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission by investment advisers that are registered both under this subchapter and the Commodity Exchange Act [7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. No subsec. (f) has been enacted. Standard of conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Other matters The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_11_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harmonization of enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Harmonization of enforcement The enforcement authority of the Commission with respect to violations of the standard of conduct applicable to an investment adviser shall include— the Commission shall seek to prosecute and sanction violators of the standard of conduct applicable to an investment adviser under this subchapter to same extent as the Commission prosecutes and sanctions violators of the standard of conduct applicable to a broker or dealer providing personalized investment advice about securities to a retail customer under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>