<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80b_4"><akn:num>80b–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by investment advisers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80b–4. Reports by investment advisers(a) In generalEvery investment adviser who makes use of the mails or of any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce in connection with his or its business as an investment adviser (other than one specifically exempted from registration pursuant to section 80b–3(b) of this title), shall make and keep for prescribed periods such records (as defined in section 78c(a)(37) of this title), furnish such copies thereof, and make and disseminate such reports as the Commission, by rule, may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors. All records (as so defined) of such investment advisers are subject at any time, or from time to time, to such reasonable periodic, special, or other examinations by representatives of the Commission as the Commission deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.


(b) Records and reports of private funds(1) In generalThe Commission may require any investment adviser registered under this subchapter—(A) to maintain such records of, and file with the Commission such reports regarding, private funds advised by the investment adviser, as necessary and appropriate in the public interest and for the protection of investors, or for the assessment of systemic risk by the Financial Stability Oversight Council (in this subsection referred to as the “Council”); and

(B) to provide or make available to the Council those reports or records or the information contained therein.


(2) Treatment of recordsThe records and reports of any private fund to which an investment adviser registered under this subchapter provides investment advice shall be deemed to be the records and reports of the investment adviser.


(3) Required informationThe records and reports required to be maintained by an investment adviser and subject to inspection by the Commission under this subsection shall include, for each private fund advised by</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Every investment adviser who makes use of the mails or of any means or instrumentality of interstate commerce in connection with his or its business as an investment adviser (other than one specifically exempted from registration pursuant to section 80b–3(b) of this title), shall make and keep for prescribed periods such records (as defined in section 78c(a)(37) of this title), furnish such copies thereof, and make and disseminate such reports as the Commission, by rule, may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors. All records (as so defined) of such investment advisers are subject at any time, or from time to time, to such reasonable periodic, special, or other examinations by representatives of the Commission as the Commission deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports of private funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Records and reports of private funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing depositories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Filing depositories The Commission may, by rule, require an investment adviser—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to disciplinary and other information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to disciplinary and other information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records of persons with custody or use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Records of persons with custody or use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data standards for reports filed under this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Data standards for reports filed under this section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>