<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–3a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–3a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80b–3a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80b_3a"><akn:num>80b–3a</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Federal responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80b–3a. State and Federal responsibilities(a) Advisers subject to State authorities(1) In generalNo investment adviser that is regulated or required to be regulated as an investment adviser in the State in which it maintains its principal office and place of business shall register under section 80b–3 of this title, unless the investment adviser—(A) has assets under management of not less than $25,000,000, or such higher amount as the Commission may, by rule, deem appropriate in accordance with the purposes of this subchapter; or

(B) is an adviser to an investment company registered under subchapter I of this chapter.


(2) Treatment of mid-sized investment advisers(A) In generalNo investment adviser described in subparagraph (B) shall register under section 80b–3 of this title, unless the investment adviser is an adviser to an investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940 [15 U.S.C. 80a–1 et seq.], or a company which has elected to be a business development company pursuant to section 54 of the Investment Company Act of 1940 [15 U.S.C. 80a–53], and has not withdrawn the election, except that, if by effect of this paragraph an investment adviser would be required to register with 15 or more States, then the adviser may register under section 80b–3 of this title.


(B) Covered personsAn investment adviser described in this subparagraph is an investment adviser that—(i) is required to be registered as an investment adviser with the securities commissioner (or any agency or office performing like functions) of the State in which it maintains its principal office and place of business and, if registered, would be subject to examination as an investment adviser by any such commissioner, agency, or office; and

(ii) has assets under management between—(I) the amount specified under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), as such amount may have been adjusted by the Commission pursuant to that subparagraph; and

(II) $100,000,000, or such higher amou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_3a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisers subject to State authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Advisers subject to State authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_3a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisers subject to Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisers subject to Commission authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_3a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemptions Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Commission, by rule or regulation upon its own motion, or by order upon application, may permit the registration with the Commission of any person or class of persons to which the application of subsection (a) would be unfair, a burden on interstate commerce, or otherwise inconsistent with the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_3a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State assistance Upon request of the securities commissioner (or any agency or officer performing like functions) of any State, the Commission may provide such training, technical assistance, or other reasonable assistance in connection with the regulation of investment advisers by the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>