<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/80c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80c_1"><akn:num>80c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual government-business forum on capital formation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80c–1. Annual government-business forum on capital formation(a) Responsibility of Securities and Exchange CommissionPursuant to the consultation called for in section 80c of this title, the Securities and Exchange Commission (acting through the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and in consultation with the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee) shall conduct an annual Government-business forum to review the current status of problems and programs relating to small business capital formation.


(b) Participation in forum planningThe Commission shall invite other Federal agencies, such as the Department of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Small Business Administration, organizations representing State securities commissioners, and leading small business and professional organizations concerned with capital formation, to participate in the planning for such forums.


(c) Preparation of statements and reportsThe Commission may request any of the Federal departments, agencies, or organizations such as those specified in subsection (b), or other groups or individuals, to prepare statements and reports to be delivered at such forums. Such departments and agencies shall cooperate in this effort.


(d) Transmittal of proceedings and findingsA summary of the proceedings of such forums and any findings or recommendations thereof shall be prepared and transmitted to the participants, appropriate committees of the Congress, and others who may be interested in the subject matter.


(e) Review of findings and recommendationsThe Commission shall—(1) review the findings and recommendations of the forum; and

(2) each time the forum submits a finding or recommendation to the Commission, promptly issue a public statement—(A) assessing the finding or recommendation of the forum; and

(B) disclosing the action, if any, the Commission intends to take with respect to the finding or recommendation.



(Pub. L.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility of Securities and Exchange Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Responsibility of Securities and Exchange Commission Pursuant to the consultation called for in section 80c of this title, the Securities and Exchange Commission (acting through the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and in consultation with the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee) shall conduct an annual Government-business forum to review the current status of problems and programs relating to small business capital formation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in forum planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participation in forum planning The Commission shall invite other Federal agencies, such as the Department of the Treasury, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Small Business Administration, organizations representing State securities commissioners, and leading small business and professional organizations concerned with capital formation, to participate in the planning for such forums.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of statements and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preparation of statements and reports The Commission may request any of the Federal departments, agencies, or organizations such as those specified in subsection (b), or other groups or individuals, to prepare statements and reports to be delivered at such forums. Such departments and agencies shall cooperate in this effort.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmittal of proceedings and findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transmittal of proceedings and findings A summary of the proceedings of such forums and any findings or recommendations thereof shall be prepared and transmitted to the participants, appropriate committees of the Congress, and others who may be interested in the subject matter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80c_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of findings and recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review of findings and recommendations The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>