<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8221"><akn:num>8221</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of credit for reinsurance and reinsurance agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8221. Regulation of credit for reinsurance and reinsurance agreements(a) Credit for reinsuranceIf the State of domicile of a ceding insurer is an NAIC-accredited State, or has financial solvency requirements substantially similar to the requirements necessary for NAIC accreditation, and recognizes credit for reinsurance for the insurer’s ceded risk, then no other State may deny such credit for reinsurance.


(b) Additional preemption of extraterritorial application of State lawIn addition to the application of subsection (a), all laws, regulations, provisions, or other actions of a State that is not the domiciliary State of the ceding insurer, except those with respect to taxes and assessments on insurance companies or insurance income, are preempted to the extent that they—(1) restrict or eliminate the rights of the ceding insurer or the assuming insurer to resolve disputes pursuant to contractual arbitration to the extent such contractual provision is not inconsistent with the provisions of title 9;

(2) require that a certain State’s law shall govern the reinsurance contract, disputes arising from the reinsurance contract, or requirements of the reinsurance contract;

(3) attempt to enforce a reinsurance contract on terms different than those set forth in the reinsurance contract, to the extent that the terms are not inconsistent with this subchapter; or

(4) otherwise apply the laws of the State to reinsurance agreements of ceding insurers not domiciled in that State.


(Pub. L. 111–203, title V, § 531, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1595.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for reinsurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Credit for reinsurance If the State of domicile of a ceding insurer is an NAIC-accredited State, or has financial solvency requirements substantially similar to the requirements necessary for NAIC accreditation, and recognizes credit for reinsurance for the insurer’s ceded risk, then no other State may deny such credit for reinsurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional preemption of extraterritorial application of State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional preemption of extraterritorial application of State law In addition to the application of subsection (a), all laws, regulations, provisions, or other actions of a State that is not the domiciliary State of the ceding insurer, except those with respect to taxes and assessments on insurance companies or insurance income, are preempted to the extent that they—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>