<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8222" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8222/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8222/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8222"><akn:num>8222</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of reinsurer solvency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8222. Regulation of reinsurer solvency(a) Domiciliary State regulationIf the State of domicile of a reinsurer is an NAIC-accredited State or has financial solvency requirements substantially similar to the requirements necessary for NAIC accreditation, such State shall be solely responsible for regulating the financial solvency of the reinsurer.


(b) Nondomiciliary States(1) Limitation on financial information requirementsIf the State of domicile of a reinsurer is an NAIC-accredited State or has financial solvency requirements substantially similar to the requirements necessary for NAIC accreditation, no other State may require the reinsurer to provide any additional financial information other than the information the reinsurer is required to file with its domiciliary State.


(2) Receipt of informationNo provision of this section shall be construed as preventing or prohibiting a State that is not the State of domicile of a reinsurer from receiving a copy of any financial statement filed with its domiciliary State.



(Pub. L. 111–203, title V, § 532, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1595.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8222_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domiciliary State regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Domiciliary State regulation If the State of domicile of a reinsurer is an NAIC-accredited State or has financial solvency requirements substantially similar to the requirements necessary for NAIC accreditation, such State shall be solely responsible for regulating the financial solvency of the reinsurer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8222_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondomiciliary States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nondomiciliary States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>