<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8305"><akn:num>8305</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against Federal Government bailouts of swaps entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8305. Prohibition against Federal Government bailouts of swaps entities(a) Prohibition on Federal assistanceNotwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), no Federal assistance may be provided to any swaps entity with respect to any swap, security-based swap, or other activity of the swaps entity.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Federal assistanceThe term “Federal assistance” means the use of any advances from any Federal Reserve credit facility or discount window that is not part of a program or facility with broad-based eligibility under section 343(3)(A) of title 12, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation insurance or guarantees for the purpose of—(A) making any loan to, or purchasing any stock, equity interest, or debt obligation of, any swaps entity;

(B) purchasing the assets of any swaps entity;

(C) guaranteeing any loan or debt issuance of any swaps entity; or

(D) entering into any assistance arrangement (including tax breaks), loss sharing, or profit sharing with any swaps entity.


(2) Swaps entity(A) In generalThe term “swaps entity” means any swap dealer, security-based swap dealer, major swap participant, major security-based swap participant, that is registered under—(i) the Commodity Exchange Act (7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.); or

(ii) the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.).


(B) ExclusionThe term “swaps entity” does not include any major swap participant or major security-based swap participant that is an 11 So in original. Probably should be “a”. covered depository institution.



(3) Covered depository institution


The term “covered depository institution” means—
(A) an insured depository institution, as that term is defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (12 U.S.C. 1813); and

(B) a United States uninsured branch or agency of a foreign bank.


(c) Affiliates of covered depository institutionsThe prohibition on Federal assistance contained in subsection (a) does not apply to and shall no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on Federal assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations), no Federal assistance may be provided to any swaps entity with respect to any swap, security-based swap, or other activity of the swaps entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section: The term “covered depository institution” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliates of covered depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Affiliates of covered depository institutions The prohibition on Federal assistance contained in subsection (a) does not apply to and shall not prevent a covered depository institution from having or establishing an affiliate which is a swaps entity, as long as such covered depository institution is part of a bank holding company, savings and loan holding company, or foreign banking organization (as such term is defined under Regulation K of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (12 CFR 211.21(o))), that is supervised by the Federal Reserve and such swaps entity affiliate complies with sections 371c and 371c–1 of title 12 and such other requirements as the Commodity Futures Trading Commission or the Securities Exchange Commission, as appropriate, and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, may determine to be necessary and appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Only bona fide hedging and traditional bank activities permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Only bona fide hedging and traditional bank activities permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing swaps and security-based swaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Existing swaps and security-based swaps The prohibition in subsection (a) shall only apply to swaps or security-based swaps entered into by a covered depository institution after the end of the transition period described in subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transition period To the extent a covered depository institution qualifies as a “swaps entity” and would be subject to the Federal assistance prohibition in subsection (a), the appropriate Federal banking agency, after consulting with and considering the views of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission or the Securities Exchange Commission, as appropriate, shall permit the covered depository institution up to 24 months to divest the swaps entity or cease the activities that require registration as a swaps entity. In establishing the appropriate transition period to effect such divestiture or cessation of activities, which may include making the swaps entity an affiliate of the covered depository institution, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall take into account and make written findings regarding the potential impact of such divestiture or cessation of activities on the covered depository institution’s (1) mortgage lending, (2) small business lending, (3) job creation, an</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excluded entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Excluded entities For purposes of this section, the term “swaps entity” shall not include any insured depository institution under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.] or a covered financial company under title II which is in a conservatorship, receivership, or a bridge bank operated by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date The prohibition in subsection (a) shall be effective 2 years following the date on which this Act is effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Liquidation required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8305_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on unregulated combination of swaps entities and banking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Prohibition on unregulated combination of swaps entities and banking At no time following adoption of the rules in subsection (k) may a bank or bank holding company be permitted to be or become a swap entity unless it conducts its swap or security-based swap activity in compliance with such minimum standards set by its prudential regulator as are reasonably calculated to permit the swaps entity to conduct its swap or security-based swap activities in a safe and sound manner and mitigate systemic risk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>