<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8501"><akn:num>8501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8501. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) SeasonalThe term “seasonal” means the time range between 3 months and 2 years.


(2) StateThe term “State” means a State, a territory, or possession of the United States, including a Commonwealth, or the District of Columbia.


(3) SubseasonalThe term “subseasonal” means the time range between 2 weeks and 3 months.


(4) Under SecretaryThe term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.


(5) Weather industry and weather enterpriseThe terms “weather industry” and “weather enterprise” are interchangeable in this chapter, and include individuals and organizations from public, private, and academic sectors that contribute to the research, development, and production of weather forecast products, and primary consumers of these weather forecast products.


(Pub. L. 115–25, § 2, Apr. 18, 2017, 131 Stat. 92.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 115–25, April 18, 2017, 131 Stat. 91, known as the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2022 AmendmentPub. L. 117–229, div. D, § 1, Dec. 16, 2022, 136 Stat. 2313, provided that: “This Act [enacting subchapter IV of this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act’ or the ‘PRECIP Act’.”


Short Title of 2019 AmendmentPub. L. 115–423, § 1, Jan. 7, 2019, 132 Stat. 5454, provided that: “This Act [enacting section 8550 of this title and section 4010 of Title 33, Navigation and Navigable Waters, amending sections 313d, 8512, 8518 to 8521, 8531, and 8532 of this title and sections 4001 to 4002 and 4009 of Title 33, enacting provisions set out as a note under section 4001 of Title 33, and amending provisions set out as a note under section 313d </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seasonal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Seasonal The term “seasonal” means the time range between 3 months and 2 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) State The term “State” means a State, a territory, or possession of the United States, including a Commonwealth, or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subseasonal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Subseasonal The term “subseasonal” means the time range between 2 weeks and 3 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Under Secretary The term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weather industry and weather enterprise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Weather industry and weather enterprise The terms “weather industry” and “weather enterprise” are interchangeable in this chapter, and include individuals and organizations from public, private, and academic sectors that contribute to the research, development, and production of weather forecast products, and primary consumers of these weather forecast products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>