<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8702"><akn:num>8702</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8702. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter:(1) Block machineThe term “block machine” means a piece of equipment that utilizes vibration and compaction to form concrete masonry products.


(2) BoardThe term “Board” means the Concrete Masonry Products Board established under section 8704 of this title.


(3) CavityThe term “cavity” means the open space in the mold of a block machine capable of forming a single concrete masonry unit having nominal plan dimensions of 8 inches by 16 inches.


(4) Concrete masonry productsThe term “concrete masonry products” refers to a broader class of products, including concrete masonry units as well as hardscape products such as concrete pavers and segmental retaining wall units, manufactured on a block machine using dry-cast concrete.


(5) Concrete masonry unitThe term “concrete masonry unit”—(A) means a concrete masonry product that is a manmade masonry unit having an actual width of 3 inches or greater and manufactured from dry-cast concrete using a block machine; and

(B) includes concrete block and related concrete units used in masonry applications.


(6) Conflict of interestThe term “conflict of interest” means, with respect to a member or employee of the Board, a situation in which such member or employee has a direct or indirect financial or other interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, for anything of economic value.


(7) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Commerce.


(8) Dry-cast concreteThe term “dry-cast concrete” means a composite material that is composed essentially of aggregates embedded in a binding medium composed of a mixture of cementitious materials (including hydraulic cement, pozzolans, or other cementitious materials) and water of such a consistency to maintain its shape after forming in a block machine.


(9) EducationThe term “education” means programs that will educate or communicate the benefits of concrete masonry products in safe </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Block machine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Block machine The term “block machine” means a piece of equipment that utilizes vibration and compaction to form concrete masonry products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Board The term “Board” means the Concrete Masonry Products Board established under section 8704 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cavity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Cavity The term “cavity” means the open space in the mold of a block machine capable of forming a single concrete masonry unit having nominal plan dimensions of 8 inches by 16 inches.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concrete masonry products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Concrete masonry products The term “concrete masonry products” refers to a broader class of products, including concrete masonry units as well as hardscape products such as concrete pavers and segmental retaining wall units, manufactured on a block machine using dry-cast concrete.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concrete masonry unit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Concrete masonry unit The term “concrete masonry unit”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Conflict of interest The term “conflict of interest” means, with respect to a member or employee of the Board, a situation in which such member or employee has a direct or indirect financial or other interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, for anything of economic value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dry-cast concrete</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Dry-cast concrete The term “dry-cast concrete” means a composite material that is composed essentially of aggregates embedded in a binding medium composed of a mixture of cementitious materials (including hydraulic cement, pozzolans, or other cementitious materials) and water of such a consistency to maintain its shape after forming in a block machine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Education The term “education” means programs that will educate or communicate the benefits of concrete masonry products in safe and environmentally sustainable development, advancements in concrete masonry product technology and development, and other information and programs designed to generate increased demand for commercial, residential, multifamily, and institutional projects using concrete masonry products and to generally enhance the image of concrete masonry products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Machine cavities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Machine cavities The term “machine cavities” means the cavities with which a block machine could be equipped.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>