<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8706"><akn:num>8706</akn:num><akn:heading>Referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8706. Referenda(a) Initial referendum(1) Referendum requiredDuring the 60-day period immediately preceding the proposed effective date of the order issued under section 8703 of this title, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among manufacturers eligible under subsection (b)(2) subject to assessments under section 8705 of this title.


(2) Approval of order neededThe order shall become effective only if the Secretary determines that the order has been approved by a majority of manufacturers voting who also represent a majority of the machine cavities in operation of those manufacturers voting in the referendum.



(b) Votes permitted(1) In generalEach manufacturer eligible to vote in a referendum conducted under this section shall be entitled to cast 1 vote.


(2) EligibilityFor purposes of paragraph (1), a manufacturer shall be considered to be eligible to vote if the manufacturer has manufactured concrete masonry products during a period of at least 180 days prior to the first day of the period during which voting in the referendum will occur.



(c) Manner of conducting referenda(1) In generalReferenda conducted pursuant to this section shall be conducted in a manner determined by the Secretary.


(2) Advance registrationA manufacturer who chooses to vote in any referendum conducted under this section shall register with the Secretary prior to the voting period, after receiving notice from the Secretary concerning the referendum under paragraph (4).


(3) VotingThe Secretary shall establish procedures for voting in any referendum conducted under this section. The ballots and other information or reports that reveal or tend to reveal the identity or vote of voters shall be strictly confidential.


(4) NoticeNot later than 30 days before a referendum is conducted under this section with respect to an order, the Secretary shall notify all manufacturers, in such a manner as determined by the Secretary, of the period during which voting in the referendum will oc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial referendum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial referendum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Votes permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Votes permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of conducting referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Manner of conducting referenda</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subsequent referenda If an order is approved in a referendum conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall conduct a subsequent referendum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension or termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension or termination If, as a result of a referendum conducted under subsection (d), the Secretary determines that suspension or termination of the order is favored by a majority of all votes cast in the referendum as provided in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs of referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Costs of referenda The Board established under an order with respect to which a referendum is conducted under this section shall reimburse the Secretary from assessments for any expenses incurred by the Secretary to conduct the referendum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>