<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8842" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8842/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/8842/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8842"><akn:num>8842</akn:num><akn:heading>Multidisciplinary centers for quantum research and education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8842. Multidisciplinary centers for quantum research and education(a) In generalThe Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall award grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia thereof) to establish at least 2, but not more than 5, Multidisciplinary Centers for Quantum Research and Education (referred to in this section as “Centers”).


(b) CollaborationsA collaboration receiving an award under this subsection may include institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and private sector entities.


(c) PurposeThe purpose of the Centers shall be to conduct basic research and education activities in support of the goals and priorities established under section 8813(d)(2) of this title, including by—(1) continuing to advance quantum information science and engineering;

(2) supporting curriculum and workforce development in quantum information science and engineering; and

(3) fostering innovation by bringing industry perspectives to quantum research and workforce development, including by leveraging industry knowledge and resources.


(d) Requirements(1) In generalAn institution of higher education or an eligible nonprofit organization (or a consortium thereof) seeking funding under this section shall submit an application to the Director of the National Science Foundation at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require.


(2) ApplicationsEach application under paragraph (1) shall include a description of—(A) how the Center will work with other research institutions and industry partners to leverage expertise in quantum science, education and curriculum development, and technology transfer;

(B) how the Center will promote active collaboration among researchers in multiple disciplines involved in quantum research, including physics, engineering, mathematics, computer science, chemi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall award grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia thereof) to establish at least 2, but not more than 5, Multidisciplinary Centers for Quantum Research and Education (referred to in this section as “Centers”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collaborations A collaboration receiving an award under this subsection may include institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and private sector entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose The purpose of the Centers shall be to conduct basic research and education activities in support of the goals and priorities established under section 8813(d)(2) of this title, including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection and duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Selection and duration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8842_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding The Director of the National Science Foundation shall allocate up to $10,000,000 for each Center established under this section for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, subject to the availability of appropriations. Amounts made available to carry out this section shall be derived from amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the National Science Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>