<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9011" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9011/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9011/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9011"><akn:num>9011</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidy for certain loan payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9011. Subsidy for certain loan payments(a) Definition of covered loanIn this section, the term “covered loan” means a loan that is—(1) guaranteed by the Administration under—(A) section 636(a) of this title—(i) including a loan made under the Community Advantage Pilot Program of the Administration; and

(ii) excluding a loan made under paragraph (36) of such section 636(a) of this title, as added by section 1102; or


(B) title V of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (15 U.S.C. 695 et seq.); or


(2) made by an intermediary to a small business concern using loans or grants received under section 636(m) of this title.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(1) all borrowers are adversely affected by COVID–19;

(2) relief payments by the Administration are appropriate for all borrowers; and

(3) in addition to the relief provided under this Act, the Administration should encourage lenders to provide payment deferments, when appropriate, and to extend the maturity of covered loans, so as to avoid balloon payments or any requirement for increases in debt payments resulting from deferments provided by lenders during the period of the national emergency declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) with respect to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19).


(c) Principal and interest payments(1) In generalSubject to the other provisions of this section, the Administrator shall pay the principal, interest, and any associated fees that are owed on a covered loan in a regular servicing status, without regard to the date on which the covered loan is fully disbursed, and subject to availability of funds, as follows:(A) With respect to a covered loan made before March 27, 2020, and not on deferment, the Administrator shall make those payments as follows:(i) The Administrator shall make those payments for the 6-month period beginning with the next payment due on the covered loan.

(ii) In addition to the payments u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of covered loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of covered loan In this section, the term “covered loan” means a loan that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal and interest payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Principal and interest payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other requirements The Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator to make payments pursuant to subsection (c) with respect to a covered loan solely because the covered loan has been sold in the secondary market.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for new loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligibility for new loans For each individual lending program under this section, the Administrator may establish a minimum loan maturity period, taking into consideration the normal underwriting requirements for each such program, with the goal of preventing abuse under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on assistance A borrower may not receive assistance under subsection (c) for more than 1 covered loan of the borrower described in paragraph (1)(C) of that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reporting and outreach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9011_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $17,000,000,000 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>