<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9024" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9024/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9024/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9024"><akn:num>9024</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary full Federal funding of the first week of compensable regular unemployment for States with</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9024. Temporary full Federal funding of the first week of compensable regular unemployment for States with no waiting week(a) Federal-State agreementsAny State which desires to do so may enter into and participate in an agreement under this section with the Secretary of Labor (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”). Any State which is a party to an agreement under this section may, upon providing 30 days’ written notice to the Secretary, terminate such agreement.


(b) Requirement that State law does not apply a waiting weekA State is eligible to enter into an agreement under this section if the State law (including a waiver of State law) provides that compensation is paid to individuals for their first week of regular unemployment without a waiting week. An agreement under this section shall not apply (or shall cease to apply) with respect to a State upon a determination by the Secretary that the State law no longer meets the requirement under the preceding sentence.


(c) Payments to States(1) Full reimbursementExcept as provided in paragraph (3), there shall be paid to each State which has entered into an agreement under this section an amount equal to 100 percent of—(A) the total amount of regular compensation paid to individuals by the State for their first week of regular unemployment; and

(B) any additional administrative expenses incurred by the State by reason of such agreement (as determined by the Secretary).


(2) Terms of paymentsSums payable to any State by reason of such State’s having an agreement under this section shall be payable, either in advance or by way of reimbursement (as determined by the Secretary), in such amounts as the Secretary estimates the State will be entitled to receive under this section for each calendar month, reduced or increased, as the case may be, by any amount by which the Secretary finds that his estimates for any prior calendar month were greater or less than the amounts which should have been paid to the St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal-State agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal-State agreements Any State which desires to do so may enter into and participate in an agreement under this section with the Secretary of Labor (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”). Any State which is a party to an agreement under this section may, upon providing 30 days’ written notice to the Secretary, terminate such agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement that State law does not apply a waiting week</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement that State law does not apply a waiting week A State is eligible to enter into an agreement under this section if the State law (including a waiver of State law) provides that compensation is paid to individuals for their first week of regular unemployment without a waiting week. An agreement under this section shall not apply (or shall cease to apply) with respect to a State upon a determination by the Secretary that the State law no longer meets the requirement under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability An agreement entered into under this section shall apply to weeks of unemployment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraud and overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fraud and overpayments The provisions of section 9025(e) of this title shall apply with respect to compensation paid under an agreement under this section to the same extent and in the same manner as in the case of pandemic emergency unemployment compensation under such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9024_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section, the terms “regular compensation”, “State”, “State agency”, “State law”, and “week” have the respective meanings given such terms under section 205 of the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 (26 U.S.C. 3304 note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>