<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9025/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9025/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9025"><akn:num>9025</akn:num><akn:heading>Pandemic emergency unemployment compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9025. Pandemic emergency unemployment compensation(a) Federal-State agreements(1) In generalAny State which desires to do so may enter into and participate in an agreement under this section with the Secretary of Labor (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”). Any State which is a party to an agreement under this section may, upon providing 30 days’ written notice to the Secretary, terminate such agreement.


(2) Provisions of agreementAny agreement under paragraph (1) shall provide that the State agency of the State will make payments of pandemic emergency unemployment compensation to individuals who—(A) have exhausted all rights to regular compensation under the State law or under Federal law with respect to a benefit year (excluding any benefit year that ended before July 1, 2019);

(B) have no rights to regular compensation with respect to a week under such law or any other State unemployment compensation law or to compensation under any other Federal law;

(C) are not receiving compensation with respect to such week under the unemployment compensation law of Canada; and

(D) are able to work, available to work, and actively seeking work.


(3) Exhaustion of benefitsFor purposes of paragraph (2)(A), an individual shall be deemed to have exhausted such individual’s rights to regular compensation under a State law when—(A) no payments of regular compensation can be made under such law because such individual has received all regular compensation available to such individual based on employment or wages during such individual’s base period; or

(B) such individual’s rights to such compensation have been terminated by reason of the expiration of the benefit year with respect to which such rights existed.


(4) Weekly benefit amount, etc.For purposes of any agreement under this section—(A) the amount of pandemic emergency unemployment compensation which shall be payable to any individual for any week of total unemployment shall be equal to—(i) the amount of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal-State agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal-State agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pandemic emergency unemployment compensation account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pandemic emergency unemployment compensation account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States having agreements for the payment of pandemic emergency unemployment compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to States having agreements for the payment of pandemic emergency unemployment compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Financing provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraud and overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fraud and overpayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section, the terms “compensation”, “regular compensation”, “extended compensation”, “benefit year”, “base period”, “State”, “State agency”, “State law”, and “week” have the respective meanings given such terms under section 205 of the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 (26 U.S.C. 3304 note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9025_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applicability An agreement entered into under this section shall apply to weeks of unemployment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>