<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9026" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9026/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9026/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9026"><akn:num>9026</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary financing of short-time compensation payments in States with programs in law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9026. Temporary financing of short-time compensation payments in States with programs in law(a) Payments to States(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (3), there shall be paid to a State an amount equal to 100 percent of the amount of short-time compensation paid under a short-time compensation program (as defined in section 3306(v) of title 26) under the provisions of the State law.


(2) Terms of paymentsPayments made to a State under paragraph (1) shall be payable by way of reimbursement in such amounts as the Secretary estimates the State will be entitled to receive under this section for each calendar month, reduced or increased, as the case may be, by any amount by which the Secretary finds that the Secretary’s estimates for any prior calendar month were greater or less than the amounts which should have been paid to the State. Such estimates may be made on the basis of such statistical, sampling, or other method as may be agreed upon by the Secretary and the State agency of the State involved.


(3) Limitations on payments(A) General payment limitationsNo payments shall be made to a State under this section for short-time compensation paid to an individual by the State during a benefit year in excess of 26 times the amount of regular compensation (including dependents’ allowances) under the State law payable to such individual for a week of total unemployment.


(B) Employer limitationsNo payments shall be made to a State under this section for benefits paid to an individual by the State under a short-time compensation program if such individual is employed by the participating employer on a seasonal, temporary, or intermittent basis.




(b) ApplicabilityPayments to a State under subsection (a) shall be available for weeks of unemployment—(1) beginning on or after March 27, 2020; and

(2) ending on or before September 6, 2021.


(c) New programsSubject to subsection (b)(2), if at any point after March 27, 2020, the State enacts a State law providing for the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9026_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9026_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability Payments to a State under subsection (a) shall be available for weeks of unemployment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9026_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>New programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) New programs Subject to subsection (b)(2), if at any point after March 27, 2020, the State enacts a State law providing for the payment of short-time compensation under a short-time compensation program that meets the definition of such a program under section 3306(v) of title 26, the State shall be eligible for payments under this section after the effective date of such enactment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9026_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding and certifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding and certifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9026_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>