<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9031" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9031/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9031/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9031"><akn:num>9031</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for the DOL Office of Inspector General for oversight of unemployment provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9031. Funding for the DOL Office of Inspector General for oversight of unemployment provisions
There are appropriated, out of moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Labor, $25,000,000 to carry out audits, investigations, and other oversight activities authorized under the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) 11 See References in Text note below. that are related to the provisions of, and amendments made by, this subtitle, to remain available without fiscal year limitation.
(Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title II, § 2115, Mar. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 334.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Inspector General Act of 1978, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 95–452, Oct. 12, 1978, 92 Stat. 1101, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was substantially repealed and restated in chapter 4 (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 5 by Pub. L. 117–286, §§ 3(b), 7, Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4206, 4361. For disposition of sections of the Act into chapter 4 of Title 5, see Disposition Table preceding section 101 of Title 5.
This subtitle, referred to in text, is subtitle A (§ 2101 et seq.) of title II of div. A of Pub. L. 116–136, Mar. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 313, known as the Relief for Workers Affected by Coronavirus Act. For complete classification of subtitle A to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 9001 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>