<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9042" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9042/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9042/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9042"><akn:num>9042</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency relief and taxpayer protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9042. Emergency relief and taxpayer protections(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, to provide liquidity to eligible businesses, States, and municipalities related to losses incurred as a result of coronavirus, the Secretary is authorized to make loans, loan guarantees, and other investments in support of eligible businesses, States, and municipalities that do not, in the aggregate, exceed $0 and provide the subsidy amounts necessary for such loans, loan guarantees, and other investments in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (2 U.S.C. 661 et seq.).


(b) Loans, loan guarantees, and other investmentsLoans, loan guarantees, and other investments made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made available as follows:(1) Not more than $0 shall be available to make loans and loan guarantees for passenger air carriers, eligible businesses that are certified under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and approved to perform inspection, repair, replace, or overhaul services, and ticket agents (as defined in section 40102 of title 49).

(2) Not more than 0 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by a dollar sign. shall be available to make loans and loan guarantees for cargo air carriers.

(3) Not more than 0 1 shall be available to make loans and loan guarantees for businesses critical to maintaining national security.

(4) Not more than the sum of $0 and any amounts available under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) that are not used as provided under those paragraphs shall be available to make loans and loan guarantees to, and other investments in, programs or facilities established by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System for the purpose of providing liquidity to the financial system that supports lending to eligible businesses, States, or municipalities by—(A) purchasing obligations or other interests directly from issuers of such obligations or other interests;

(B) purchasing obligat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, to provide liquidity to eligible businesses, States, and municipalities related to losses incurred as a result of coronavirus, the Secretary is authorized to make loans, loan guarantees, and other investments in support of eligible businesses, States, and municipalities that do not, in the aggregate, exceed $0 and provide the subsidy amounts necessary for such loans, loan guarantees, and other investments in accordance with the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (2 U.S.C. 661 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans, loan guarantees, and other investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Loans, loan guarantees, and other investments Loans, loan guarantees, and other investments made pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made available as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial protection of government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Financial protection of government</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deposit of proceeds Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts collected under subsection (b) shall be deposited in the following order of priority:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative provisions Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may use not greater than 61,000,000 1 of the funds made available under section 9061 of this title to pay costs and administrative expenses associated with the loans, loan guarantees, and other investments authorized under this section. The Secretary is authorized to take such actions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the authorities in this part, including, without limitation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Financial agents The Secretary is authorized to designate financial institutions, including but not limited to, depositories, brokers, dealers, and other institutions, as financial agents of the United States. Such institutions shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9042_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans made by or guaranteed by the Department of the Treasury treated as indebtedness for tax purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Loans made by or guaranteed by the Department of the Treasury treated as indebtedness for tax purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>