<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9058a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9058a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9058a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9058a"><akn:num>9058a</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency rental assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9058a. Emergency rental assistance(a) Appropriation(1) In generalOut of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated for making payments to eligible grantees under this section, $25,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2021.


(2) Reservation of funds for the territories and tribal communitiesOf the amount appropriated under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall reserve—(A) $400,000,000 of such amount for making payments under this section to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa; and

(B) $800,000,000 of such amount for making payments under this section to eligible grantees described in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (k)(2); and

(C) $15,000,000 for administrative expenses of the Secretary described in subsection (h).



(b) Payments for rental assistance(1) Allocation and payments to states and units of local government(A) In generalThe amount appropriated under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) that remains after the application of paragraph (2) of such subsection shall be allocated and paid to eligible grantees described in subparagraph (B) in the same manner as the amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) of section 801 of title 42 is allocated and paid to States and units of local government under subsections (b) and (c) of such section, and shall be subject to the same requirements, except that—(i) the deadline for payments under section 801(b)(1) of such title shall, for purposes of payments under this section, be deemed to be not later than 30 days after December 27, 2020;

(ii) the amount referred to in paragraph (3) of section 801(c) of such title shall be deemed to be the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) of subsection (a) of this Act 11 So in original. Probably should be “this section”. that remains after the application of paragraph (2) of such subsection;

(iii) section 801(c) of title 42 s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for rental assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments for rental assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation of unused funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallocation of unused funds Beginning on September 30, 2021, the Secretary shall recapture excess funds, as determined by the Secretary, not obligated by a grantee for the purposes described under subsection (c) and the Secretary shall reallocate and repay such amounts to eligible grantees who, at the time of such reallocation, have obligated at least 65 percent of the amount originally allocated and paid to such grantee under subsection (b)(1), only for the allowable uses described under subsection (c). The amount of any such reallocation shall be determined based on demonstrated need within a grantee’s jurisdiction, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for assistance by landlords and owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application for assistance by landlords and owners</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrative expenses of the Secretary Of the funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a), not more than $15,000,000 may be used for administrative expenses of the Secretary in administering this section, including technical assistance to grantees in order to facilitate effective use of funds provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General Oversight; Recoupment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Inspector General Oversight; Recoupment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9058a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Treatment of assistance Assistance provided to a household from a payment made under this section shall not be regarded as income and shall not be regarded as a resource for purposes of determining the eligibility of the household or any member of the household for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>