<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9098" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9098/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9098/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9098"><akn:num>9098</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxpayer protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9098. Taxpayer protection(a) CARES Act assistance recipientsWith respect to a recipient of financial assistance under section 4113 of the CARES Act (15 U.S.C. 9073) that receives financial assistance under this part, the Secretary may receive warrants, options, preferred stock, debt securities, notes, or other financial instruments issued by such recipient that are, to the maximum extent practicable, in the same form and amount, and under the same terms and conditions, as agreed to by the Secretary and such recipient to provide appropriate compensation to the Federal Government for the provision of the financial assistance under this part.


(b) Other applicantsWith respect to a recipient of financial assistance under this part that did not receive financial assistance under section 4113 of the CARES Act (15 U.S.C. 9073), the Secretary may receive warrants, options, preferred stock, debt securities, notes, or other financial instruments issued by such recipient in a form and amount that are, to the maximum extent practicable, under the same terms and conditions as agreed to by the Secretary and similarly situated recipients of financial assistance under such section to provide appropriate compensation to the Federal Government for the provision of the financial assistance under this part.


(Pub. L. 116–260, div. N, title IV, § 408, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2059.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe CARES Act, referred to in subsec. (a), also known as the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act, is Pub. L. 116–136, Mar. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 281, which enacted this chapter and enacted, amended, and repealed numerous other sections and notes in the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 9001 of this title and Tables.
This part, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle A (§§ 401–412) of title IV of div. N of Pub. L. 116–260, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2052, wh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9098_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>CARES Act assistance recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) CARES Act assistance recipients With respect to a recipient of financial assistance under section 4113 of the CARES Act (15 U.S.C. 9073) that receives financial assistance under this part, the Secretary may receive warrants, options, preferred stock, debt securities, notes, or other financial instruments issued by such recipient that are, to the maximum extent practicable, in the same form and amount, and under the same terms and conditions, as agreed to by the Secretary and such recipient to provide appropriate compensation to the Federal Government for the provision of the financial assistance under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9098_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other applicants With respect to a recipient of financial assistance under this part that did not receive financial assistance under section 4113 of the CARES Act (15 U.S.C. 9073), the Secretary may receive warrants, options, preferred stock, debt securities, notes, or other financial instruments issued by such recipient in a form and amount that are, to the maximum extent practicable, under the same terms and conditions as agreed to by the Secretary and similarly situated recipients of financial assistance under such section to provide appropriate compensation to the Federal Government for the provision of the financial assistance under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>