<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9401"><akn:num>9401</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9401. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Advisory CommitteeThe term “Advisory Committee” means the National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee established under section 9414(a) of this title.


(2) Agency headThe term “agency head” means the head of any Executive agency (as defined in section 105 of title 5).


(3) Artificial intelligenceThe term “artificial intelligence” means a machine-based system that can, for a given set of human-defined objectives, make predictions, recommendations or decisions influencing real or virtual environments. Artificial intelligence systems use machine and human-based inputs to—(A) perceive real and virtual environments;

(B) abstract such perceptions into models through analysis in an automated manner; and

(C) use model inference to formulate options for information or action.


(4) Community collegeThe term “community college” means a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year Tribal Colleges or Universities under section 1059c of title 20 and public 2-year State institutions of higher education.


(5) InitiativeThe term “Initiative” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative established under section 9411(a) of this title.


(6) Initiative OfficeThe term “Initiative Office” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Office established under section 9412(a) of this title.


(7) InstituteThe term “Institute” means an Artificial Intelligence Research Institute described in section 9431(b)(2) of this title.


(8) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001 and section 1002(c) of title 20.


(9) Interagency CommitteeThe term “Interagency Committee” means the interagency committee established under section 9413(a) of this title.


(10) K-12 educationThe term “K-12 education” means elementary school and secondary school educa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Advisory Committee The term “Advisory Committee” means the National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee established under section 9414(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency head</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agency head The term “agency head” means the head of any Executive agency (as defined in section 105 of title 5).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Artificial intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Artificial intelligence The term “artificial intelligence” means a machine-based system that can, for a given set of human-defined objectives, make predictions, recommendations or decisions influencing real or virtual environments. Artificial intelligence systems use machine and human-based inputs to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community college</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Community college The term “community college” means a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year Tribal Colleges or Universities under section 1059c of title 20 and public 2-year State institutions of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Initiative The term “Initiative” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative established under section 9411(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiative Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Initiative Office The term “Initiative Office” means the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Office established under section 9412(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Institute The term “Institute” means an Artificial Intelligence Research Institute described in section 9431(b)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001 and section 1002(c) of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Interagency Committee The term “Interagency Committee” means the interagency committee established under section 9413(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9401_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>K-12 education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) K-12 education The term “K-12 education” means elementary school and secondary school education provided by local educational agencies, as such agencies are defined in section 7801 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>