<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9411"><akn:num>9411</akn:num><akn:heading>National Artificial Intelligence Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9411. National Artificial Intelligence Initiative(a) Establishment; purposesThe President shall establish and implement an initiative to be known as the “National Artificial Intelligence Initiative”. The purposes of the Initiative shall be to—(1) ensure continued United States leadership in artificial intelligence research and development;

(2) lead the world in the development and use of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems in the public and private sectors;

(3) prepare the present and future United States workforce for the integration of artificial intelligence systems across all sectors of the economy and society; and

(4) coordinate ongoing artificial intelligence research, development, and demonstration activities among the civilian agencies, the Department of Defense and the Intelligence Community to ensure that each informs the work of the others.


(b) Initiative activitiesIn carrying out the Initiative, the President, acting through the Initiative Office, the Interagency Committee, and agency heads as the President considers appropriate, shall carry out activities that include the following:(1) Sustained and consistent support for artificial intelligence research and development through grants, cooperative agreements, testbeds, and access to data and computing resources.

(2) Support for K-12 education and postsecondary educational programs, including workforce training and career and technical education programs, and informal education programs to prepare the American workforce and the general public to be able to create, use, and interact with artificial intelligence systems.

(3) Support for interdisciplinary research, education, and workforce training programs for students and researchers that promote learning in the methods and systems used in artificial intelligence and foster interdisciplinary perspectives and collaborations among subject matter experts in relevant fields, including computer science, mathematics, statistics, engineering, so</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; purposes The President shall establish and implement an initiative to be known as the “National Artificial Intelligence Initiative”. The purposes of the Initiative shall be to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiative activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initiative activities In carrying out the Initiative, the President, acting through the Initiative Office, the Interagency Committee, and agency heads as the President considers appropriate, shall carry out activities that include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation The Initiative shall not impact sources and methods, as determined by the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules of construction Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sunset The Initiative established in this chapter shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after January 1, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>