<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9414"><akn:num>9414</akn:num><akn:heading>National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9414. National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee(a) In generalThe Secretary of Commerce shall, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Director of National Intelligence establish an advisory committee to be known as the “National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee”.


(b) QualificationsThe Advisory Committee shall consist of members, appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, who are representing broad and interdisciplinary expertise and perspectives, including from academic institutions, companies across diverse sectors, nonprofit and civil society entities, including civil rights and disability rights organizations, and Federal laboratories, who are representing geographic diversity, and who are qualified to provide advice and information on science and technology research, development, ethics, standards, education, technology transfer, commercial application, security, and economic competitiveness related to artificial intelligence.


(c) Membership considerationIn selecting the members of the Advisory Committee, the Secretary of Commerce shall seek and give consideration to recommendations from Congress, industry, nonprofit organizations, the scientific community (including the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, scientific professional societies, and academic institutions), the defense and law enforcement communities, and other appropriate organizations.


(d) DutiesThe Advisory Committee shall advise the President and the Initiative Office on matters related to the Initiative, including recommendations related to—(1) the current state of United States competitiveness and leadership in artificial intelligence, including the scope and scale of United States investments in artificial intelligence research and development in the international context;

(2) the progress made in impl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Commerce shall, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Director of National Intelligence establish an advisory committee to be known as the “National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications The Advisory Committee shall consist of members, appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, who are representing broad and interdisciplinary expertise and perspectives, including from academic institutions, companies across diverse sectors, nonprofit and civil society entities, including civil rights and disability rights organizations, and Federal laboratories, who are representing geographic diversity, and who are qualified to provide advice and information on science and technology research, development, ethics, standards, education, technology transfer, commercial application, security, and economic competitiveness related to artificial intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership consideration In selecting the members of the Advisory Committee, the Secretary of Commerce shall seek and give consideration to recommendations from Congress, industry, nonprofit organizations, the scientific community (including the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, scientific professional societies, and academic institutions), the defense and law enforcement communities, and other appropriate organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties The Advisory Committee shall advise the President and the Initiative Office on matters related to the Initiative, including recommendations related to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittee on artificial intelligence and law enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subcommittee on artificial intelligence and law enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports Not later than 1 year after January 1, 2021, and not less frequently than once every 3 years thereafter, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the President, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, a report on the Advisory Committee’s findings and recommendations under subsection (d) and subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel expenses of non-Federal members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Travel expenses of non-Federal members Non-Federal members of the Advisory Committee, while attending meetings of the Advisory Committee or while otherwise serving at the request of the head of the Advisory Committee away from their homes or regular places of business, may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized by section 5703 of title 5 for individuals in the Government serving without pay. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit members of the Advisory Committee who are officers or employees of the United States from being allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with existing law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>FACA exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) FACA exemption The Secretary of Commerce shall charter the Advisory Committee in accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.),1 except that the Advisory Committee shall be exempt from section 14 of such Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>