<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9451"><akn:num>9451</akn:num><akn:heading>Artificial intelligence research and education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9451. Artificial intelligence research and education(a) In generalthe 11 So in original. Director of the National Science Foundation shall fund research and education activities in artificial intelligence systems and related fields, including competitive awards or grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia thereof).


(b) Uses of fundsIn carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Director of the National Science Foundation shall—(1) support research, including interdisciplinary research, on artificial intelligence systems and related areas, including fields and research areas that will contribute to the development and deployment of trustworthy artificial intelligence systems, and fields and research areas that address the application of artificial intelligence systems to scientific discovery and societal challenges;

(2) use the existing programs of the National Science Foundation, in collaboration with other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate to—(A) improve the teaching and learning of topics related to artificial intelligence systems in K-12 education and postsecondary educational programs, including workforce training and career and technical education programs, undergraduate and graduate education programs, and in informal settings; and

(B) increase participation in artificial intelligence related fields, including by individuals identified in sections 1885a and 1885b of title 42;


(3) support partnerships among institutions of higher education, Federal laboratories, nonprofit organizations, State, local, and Tribal governments, industry, and potential users of artificial intelligence systems that facilitate collaborative research, personnel exchanges, and workforce development and identify emerging research needs with respect to artificial intelligence systems;

(4) ensure adequate access to research and education infrastructure with respect to artificial intelligence systems, which</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general the 11 So in original. Director of the National Science Foundation shall fund research and education activities in artificial intelligence systems and related fields, including competitive awards or grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia thereof).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses of funds In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Director of the National Science Foundation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Engineering support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Engineering support In general, the Director shall permit applicants to include in their proposed budgets funding for software engineering support to assist with the proposed research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ethics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ethics</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Foundation pilot program of grants for research in rapidly evolving, high priority topics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National Science Foundation pilot program of grants for research in rapidly evolving, high priority topics</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9451_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>