<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9461" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9461/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9461/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9461"><akn:num>9461</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy artificial intelligence research program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9461. Department of Energy artificial intelligence research program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out a cross-cutting research and development program to advance artificial intelligence tools, systems, capabilities, and workforce needs and to improve the reliability of artificial intelligence methods and solutions relevant to the mission of the Department. In carrying out this program, the Secretary shall coordinate across all relevant offices and programs at the Department, including the Office of Science, the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, the Office of Nuclear Energy, the Office of Fossil Energy, the Office of Electricity, the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response, the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, and any other relevant office determined by the Secretary.


(b) Research areasIn carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall award financial assistance to eligible entities to carry out research projects on topics including—(1) the application of artificial intelligence systems to improve large-scale simulations of natural and other phenomena;

(2) the study of applied mathematics, computer science, and statistics, including foundations of methods and systems of artificial intelligence, causal and statistical inference, and the development of algorithms for artificial intelligence systems;

(3) the analysis of existing large-scale datasets from science and engineering experiments and simulations, including energy simulations and other priorities at the Department as determined by the Secretary using artificial intelligence tools and techniques;

(4) the development of operation and control systems that enhance automated, intelligent decisionmaking capabilities;

(5) the development of advanced computing hardware and computer architecture tailored to artificial intelligence systems, including the codesign of networks and computational hardware;

(6) the development of standardiz</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall carry out a cross-cutting research and development program to advance artificial intelligence tools, systems, capabilities, and workforce needs and to improve the reliability of artificial intelligence methods and solutions relevant to the mission of the Department. In carrying out this program, the Secretary shall coordinate across all relevant offices and programs at the Department, including the Office of Science, the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, the Office of Nuclear Energy, the Office of Fossil Energy, the Office of Electricity, the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response, the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, and any other relevant office determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research areas In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall award financial assistance to eligible entities to carry out research projects on topics including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technology transfer In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall support technology transfer of artificial intelligence systems for the benefit of society and United States economic competitiveness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility use and upgrades</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Facility use and upgrades In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on ethics statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on ethics statements Not later than 6 months after publication of the study described in section 9451(d)(1)(C) of this title, the Secretary shall report to Congress on options for requiring an ethics or risk statement as part of all or a subset of applications for research activities funded by the Department of Energy and performed at Department of Energy national laboratories and user facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Risk management The Secretary shall review agency policies for risk management in artificial intelligence related projects and issue as necessary policies and principles that are consistent with the framework developed under section 278h–1(c) of this title (as added by section 5301 of this division).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data privacy and sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Data privacy and sharing The Secretary shall review agency policies for data sharing with other public and private sector organizations and issue as necessary policies and principles that are consistent with the standards and guidelines submitted under section 278h–1(e) of this title (as added by section 5301 of this division). In addition, the Secretary shall establish a streamlined mechanism for approving research projects or partnerships that require sharing sensitive public or private data with the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships with other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Partnerships with other Federal agencies The Secretary may request, accept, and provide funds from other Federal departments and agencies, State, United States territory, local, or Tribal government agencies, private sector for-profit entities, and nonprofit entities, to be available to the extent provided by appropriations Acts, to support a research project or partnership carried out under this section. The Secretary may not give any special consideration to any agency or entity in return for a donation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stakeholder engagement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Stakeholder engagement In carrying out the activities authorized in this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9461_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>