<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9524" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9524/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9524/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9524"><akn:num>9524</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9524. Grants and cooperative agreements(a) RequirementsAn MBDA Business Center (referred to in this part as a “Center”), with respect to the Federal financial assistance award made to operate the Center under the MBDA Business Center Program—(1) shall—(A) provide to minority business enterprises programs and services determined to be appropriate by the Under Secretary, which may include—(i) referral services to meet the needs of minority business enterprises; and

(ii) programs and services to accomplish the goals described in section ___101(1); 11 So in original. See References in Text note below.


(B) develop, cultivate, and maintain a network of strategic partnerships with organizations that foster access by minority business enterprises to economic markets, capital, or contracts;

(C) continue to upgrade and modify the services provided by the Center, as necessary, in order to meet the changing and evolving needs of the business community;

(D) establish or continue a referral relationship with not less than 1 community-based organization; and

(E) collaborate with other Centers; and


(2) in providing programs and services under the applicable MBDA Business Center agreement, may—(A) operate on a fee-for-service basis; or

(B) generate income through the collection of—(i) client fees;

(ii) membership fees; and

(iii) any other appropriate fees proposed by the Center in the application submitted by the Center under subsection (e).




(b) TermSubject to subsection (g)(3), the term of an MBDA Business Center agreement shall be not less than 3 years.


(c) Financial assistance(1) In generalThe amount of financial assistance provided by the Under Secretary under an MBDA Business Center agreement shall be not less than $250,000 for the term of the agreement.


(2) Matching requirement(A) In generalA Center shall match not less than ⅓ of the amount of the financial assistance awarded to the Center under the terms of the applicable MBDA Business Center agreement, u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements An MBDA Business Center (referred to in this part as a “Center”), with respect to the Federal financial assistance award made to operate the Center under the MBDA Business Center Program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term Subject to subsection (g)(3), the term of an MBDA Business Center agreement shall be not less than 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for selection The Under Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applications An eligible entity desiring to enter into an MBDA Business Center agreement shall submit to the Under Secretary an application that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification If the Under Secretary grants an application of an eligible entity submitted under subsection (e), the Under Secretary shall notify the eligible entity that the application has been granted not later than 150 days after the last day on which an application may be submitted under that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program examination; accreditation; extensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program examination; accreditation; extensions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>MBDA involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) MBDA involvement The Under Secretary may take actions to ensure that the Agency is substantially involved in the activities of Centers in carrying out subsection (a), including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9524_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Under Secretary shall issue and publish regulations that establish minimum standards regarding verification of minority business enterprise status for clients of entities operating under the MBDA Business Center Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>