<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9572"><akn:num>9572</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9572. Composition and term(a) CompositionThe Council shall be composed of 9 members of the private sector and 1 representative from each of not fewer than 10 Federal agencies that support or otherwise have duties that relate to business formation, including duties relating to labor development, monetary policy, national security, energy, agriculture, transportation, and housing.


(b) ChairThe Under Secretary shall designate 1 of the private sector members of the Council as the Chair of the Council for a 1-year term.


(c) TermThe Council shall meet at the request of the Under Secretary and members shall serve for a term of 2 years. Members of the Council may be reappointed.


(Pub. L. 117–58, div. K, title V, § 100502, Nov. 15, 2021, 135 Stat. 1463.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Composition The Council shall be composed of 9 members of the private sector and 1 representative from each of not fewer than 10 Federal agencies that support or otherwise have duties that relate to business formation, including duties relating to labor development, monetary policy, national security, energy, agriculture, transportation, and housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chair The Under Secretary shall designate 1 of the private sector members of the Council as the Chair of the Council for a 1-year term.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9572_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term The Council shall meet at the request of the Under Secretary and members shall serve for a term of 2 years. Members of the Council may be reappointed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>