<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9704"><akn:num>9704</akn:num><akn:heading>Service coordination hydrologists at River Forecast Centers of the National Weather Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9704. Service coordination hydrologists at River Forecast Centers of the National Weather Service(a) Designation of service coordination hydrologists(1) In generalThe Director of the National Weather Service (in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall designate at least 1 service coordination hydrologist at each River Forecast Center of the National Weather Service.


(2) Performance by other employeesPerformance of the responsibilities outlined in this section is not limited to the service coordination hydrologist position.



(b) Primary role of service coordination hydrologistsThe primary role of the service coordination hydrologist shall be to carry out the responsibilities required by this section.


(c) Responsibilities(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), consistent with the analysis described in section 409 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (Public Law 115–25; 131 Stat. 112), and in order to increase impact-based decision support services, each service coordination hydrologist designated under subsection (a) shall, with respect to hydrology—(A) be responsible for providing service to the geographic area of responsibility covered by the River Forecast Center at which the service coordination hydrologist is employed to help ensure that users of products and services of the National Weather Service can respond effectively to improve outcomes from flood events;

(B) liaise with users of products and services of the National Weather Service, such as the public, academia, media outlets, users in the hydropower, transportation, recreation, and agricultural communities, and forestry, land, fisheries, and water management interests, to evaluate the adequacy and usefulness of the products and services of the National Weather Service;

(C) collaborate with such River Forecast Centers and Weather Forecast Offices and Federal, State, local, and Tribal government agencies as the Director considers appropriate in developing, propo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of service coordination hydrologists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of service coordination hydrologists</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary role of service coordination hydrologists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Primary role of service coordination hydrologists The primary role of the service coordination hydrologist shall be to carry out the responsibilities required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>