<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9705"><akn:num>9705</akn:num><akn:heading>Improving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration communication of future flood risks and ha</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9705. Improving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration communication of future flood risks and hazardous flash flood events(a) Assessment of flash flood watches and warnings(1) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 27, 2022, the Administrator shall—(A) conduct an assessment of—(i) the flash flood watches and warnings of the National Weather Service; and

(ii) the information delivery to support preparation and responses to floods; and


(B) submit to Congress a report on the findings of the Administrator with respect to the assessment required by subparagraph (A).


(2) ElementsThe assessment required by paragraph (1)(A) shall include the following:(A) An evaluation of whether the watches, warnings, and information described in paragraph (1)(A) effectively—(i) communicate risk to the general public;

(ii) inform action to prevent loss of life and property;

(iii) inform action to support flood preparation and response; and

(iv) deliver information in a manner designed to lead to appropriate action.


(B) Subject to subsection (b)(2), such recommendations as the Administrator may have for—(i) legislative and administrative action to improve the watches and warnings described in paragraph (1)(A)(i); and

(ii) such research as the Administrator considers necessary to address the focus areas described in paragraph (3).



(3) Focus areasThe assessment required by paragraph (1)(A) shall focus on the following areas:(A) Ways to communicate the risks posed by hazardous flash flood events to the public that are most likely to result in informed decision making regarding the mitigation of those risks.

(B) Ways to provide actionable geographic information to the recipient of a watch or warning for a flash flood, including partnering with emergency response agencies, as appropriate.

(C) Evaluation of information delivery to support the preparation for and response to floods.


(4) ConsultationIn conducting the assessment required by paragraph (1)(A), th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of flash flood watches and warnings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment of flash flood watches and warnings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvements to flash flood watches and warnings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Improvements to flash flood watches and warnings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>