<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9708"><akn:num>9708</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Committee on Water Management and Infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9708. Interagency Committee on Water Management and Infrastructure(a) EstablishmentThere is established a committee, to be known as the “Interagency Committee on Water Management and Infrastructure” (in this section referred to as the “Water Policy Committee”).


(b) MembershipThe Water Policy Committee shall be composed of the following members:(1) The Administrator.

(2) The Secretary of the Interior.

(3) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.

(4) The Secretary of Agriculture.

(5) The Secretary of Commerce.

(6) The Secretary of Energy.

(7) The Secretary of the Army.

(8) The heads of such other agencies as the co-chairs consider appropriate.


(c) Co-chairsThe Water Policy Committee shall be co-chaired by the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(d) MeetingsThe Water Policy Committee shall meet not less frequently than 6 times each year, at the call of the co-chairs.


(e) General purpose and dutiesThe Water Policy Committee shall ensure that agencies and departments across the Federal Government that engage in water-related matters, including water storage and supplies, water quality and restoration activities, water infrastructure, transportation on United States rivers and inland waterways, and water forecasting, work together where such agencies and departments have joint or overlapping responsibilities to—(1) improve interagency coordination among Federal agencies and departments on water resource management and water infrastructure issues;

(2) coordinate existing water-related Federal task forces, working groups, and other formal cross-agency initiatives, as appropriate;

(3) prioritize managing the water resources of the United States and promoting resilience of the water-related infrastructure of the United States, including—(A) increasing water storage, water supply reliability, and drought resiliency;

(B) improving water quality, source water protection, and nutrient managem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a committee, to be known as the “Interagency Committee on Water Management and Infrastructure” (in this section referred to as the “Water Policy Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Water Policy Committee shall be composed of the following members:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Co-chairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Co-chairs The Water Policy Committee shall be co-chaired by the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings The Water Policy Committee shall meet not less frequently than 6 times each year, at the call of the co-chairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General purpose and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General purpose and duties The Water Policy Committee shall ensure that agencies and departments across the Federal Government that engage in water-related matters, including water storage and supplies, water quality and restoration activities, water infrastructure, transportation on United States rivers and inland waterways, and water forecasting, work together where such agencies and departments have joint or overlapping responsibilities to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9708_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross-agency priority research needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross-agency priority research needs Not later than 1 year after December 27, 2022, the Water Policy Committee shall develop and submit to Congress a list of research needs that includes needs for cross-agency research and coordination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>