<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/15/9710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9710"><akn:num>9710</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and support of consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological i</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9710. Identification and support of consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological information(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Extreme weatherThe term “extreme weather” includes observed or anticipated severe and unseasonable atmospheric conditions, including drought, heavy precipitation, hurricanes, tornadoes and other windstorms (including derechos), large hail, extreme heat, extreme cold, flooding, sustained temperatures or precipitation that deviate substantially from historical averages, and any other weather event that the Administrator determines qualifies as extreme weather.


(2) Long-termThe term “long-term” shall have such meaning as the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Administrator, considers appropriate for purposes of this section.


(3) Other environmental trendsThe term “other environmental trends” means wildfires, coastal flooding, inland flooding, land subsidence, rising sea levels, and any other challenges relating to changes in environmental systems over time that the Administrator determines qualify as environmental challenges other than extreme weather.



(b) Identification and support of consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological informationThe Administrator shall identify, and support research that enables, a consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological information that models future extreme weather events, other environmental trends, projections, and up-to-date observations, including mesoscale information as determined appropriate by the Administrator.


(Pub. L. 117–316, § 15, Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4417.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and support of consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification and support of consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological information The Administrator shall identify, and support research that enables, a consistent, Federal set of forward-looking, long-term meteorological information that models future extreme weather events, other environmental trends, projections, and up-to-date observations, including mesoscale information as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>