<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_112"><akn:num>112</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of certain policies, procedures, and directives in effect on July 1, 1949</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 112. Applicability of certain policies, procedures, and directives in effect on July 1, 1949(a) In General.—A policy, procedure, or directive described in subsection (b) remains in effect until superseded or amended under this subtitle or other appropriate authority.

(b) Description.—A policy, procedure, or directive referred to in subsection (a) is one that was in effect on July 1, 1949, and that was prescribed by—(1) the Director of the Bureau of Federal Supply or the Secretary of the Treasury and that related to a function transferred to or vested in the Administrator of General Services on June 30, 1949, by the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949; 11 See References in Text note below.

(2) an officer of the Federal Government under authority of the Surplus Property Act of 1944 (ch. 479, 58 Stat. 765) or other authority related to surplus property or foreign excess property;

(3) the Federal Works Administrator or the head of a constituent agency of the Federal Works Agency; or

(4) the Archivist of the United States or another officer or body whose functions were transferred on June 30, 1949, by title I 1 of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949.


(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1065.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


11240:473.June 30, 1949, ch. 288, title VI, § 601, formerly title V, § 501, 63 Stat. 399; renumbered Sept. 5, 1950, ch. 849, § 6(a), (b), 64 Stat. 583.



Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), (4), is act June 30, 1949, ch. 288, 63 Stat. 377, which was substantially repealed and restated in this chapter, chapters 3 to 11 of this title, and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of Title 41, Public Contracts, by Pub. L. 107–217, §§ 1, 6(b), Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062, 1304, wh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A policy, procedure, or directive described in subsection (b) remains in effect until superseded or amended under this subtitle or other appropriate authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A policy, procedure, or directive referred to in subsection (a) is one that was in effect on July 1, 1949, and that was prescribed by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>