<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/11301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/11301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/11301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11301"><akn:num>11301</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11301. Responsibility of Director
In fulfilling the responsibility to administer the functions assigned under chapter 35 of title 44, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall comply with this chapter with respect to the specific matters covered by this chapter.
(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1237.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


1130140:1411.Pub. L. 104–106, div. E, title LI, § 5111, Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 680.



Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Advancing American Artificial IntelligencePub. L. 117–263, div. G, title LXXII, subtitle B, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3668, provided that:
“SEC. 7221. SHORT TITLE.“This subtitle may be cited as the ‘Advancing American AI Act’.


“SEC. 7222. PURPOSES.“The purposes of this subtitle are to—“(1) encourage agency artificial intelligence-related programs and initiatives that enhance the competitiveness of the United States and foster an approach to artificial intelligence that builds on the strengths of the United States in innovation and entrepreneurialism;

“(2) enhance the ability of the Federal Government to translate research advances into artificial intelligence applications to modernize systems and assist agency leaders in fulfilling their missions;

“(3) promote adoption of modernized business practices and advanced technologies across the Federal Government that align with the values of the United States, including the protection of privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties; and

“(4) test and harness applied artificial intelligence to enhance mission effectiveness, agency program integrity, and business practice efficiency.


“SEC. 7223. DEFINITIONS.“In this subtitle:“(1) Agency.—The term ‘agency’ has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.

“(2) Appropriate congressional committees.—The term ‘appropriate congressional committees’ means—“(A) the Committee on Homeland Secur</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>