<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_121"><akn:num>121</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 121. Administrative(a) Policies Prescribed by the President.—The President may prescribe policies and directives that the President considers necessary to carry out this subtitle. The policies must be consistent with this subtitle.

(b) Accounting Principles and Standards.—(1) Prescription.—The Comptroller General, after considering the needs and requirements of executive agencies, shall prescribe principles and standards of accounting for property.

(2) Property accounting systems.—The Comptroller General shall cooperate with the Administrator of General Services and with executive agencies in the development of property accounting systems and approve the systems when they are adequate and in conformity with prescribed principles and standards.

(3) Compliance review.—From time to time the Comptroller General shall examine the property accounting systems established by executive agencies to determine the extent of compliance with prescribed principles and standards and approved systems. The Comptroller General shall report to Congress any failure to comply with the principles and standards or to adequately account for property.


(c) Regulations by Administrator.—(1) General authority.—The Administrator may prescribe regulations to carry out this subtitle.

(2) Required regulations and orders.—The Administrator shall prescribe regulations that the Administrator considers necessary to carry out the Administrator’s functions under this subtitle and the head of each executive agency shall issue orders and directives that the agency head considers necessary to carry out the regulations.


(d) Delegation of Authority by Administrator.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Administrator may delegate authority conferred on the Administrator by this subtitle to an official in the General Services Administration or to the head of another federal agency. The Administrator may authorize successive redelegation of authority conferred by this subtitle.

(2)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policies Prescribed by the President.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President may prescribe policies and directives that the President considers necessary to carry out this subtitle. The policies must be consistent with this subtitle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting Principles and Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations by Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of Authority by Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of Functions by Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator may establish advisory committees to provide advice on any function of the Administrator under this subtitle. Members of the advisory committees shall serve without compensation but are entitled to transportation and not more than $25 a day instead of expenses under section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation With Federal Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator shall advise and consult with interested federal agencies and seek their advice and assistance to accomplish the purposes of this subtitle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_121_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering Oaths.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In carrying out investigative duties, an officer or employee of the Administration, if authorized by the Administrator, may administer an oath to an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>