<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/1304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/1304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/1304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1304"><akn:num>1304</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of federal property to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1304. Transfer of federal property to States(a) Obsolete Buildings and Sites.—(1) In general.—The Administrator of General Services, in the Administrator’s discretion, on terms the Administrator considers proper, and under regulations the Administrator may prescribe, may sell property described in paragraph (2) to a State or a political subdivision of a State for public use if the Administrator considers the sale to be in the best interest of the Federal Government.

(2) Applicable property.—The property referred to in paragraph (1) is any federal building, building site, or part of a building site under the Administrator’s control that has been replaced by a new structure and that the Administrator determines is no longer needed by the Government.

(3) Price.—The purchase price for a sale under this section must be at least 50 percent of the value of the land as appraised by the Administrator.

(4) Proceeds of sale.—The proceeds of a sale under this section shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.

(5) Payment terms.—The Administrator may enter into a long term contract for the payment of the purchase price in installments that the Administrator considers fair and reasonable. The Administrator may waive any requirement for interest charges on deferred payment.

(6) Conveyance.—The Administrator may convey property sold under this section by the usual quitclaim deed.


(b) Widening of Public Roads.—(1) Definition.—In this subsection, the term “executive agency” means an executive department or independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government, including any wholly owned Government corporation.

(2) In general.—When a State or a political subdivision of a State applies for a conveyance or transfer of real property of the Government in connection with an authorized widening of a public highway, street, or alley, the head of the executive agency that controls the affected real property may convey or transfer to the State or poli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obsolete Buildings and Sites.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Widening of Public Roads.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>