<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14323"><akn:num>14323</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14323. Congressional notification(a) In General.—In the case of a project described in subsection (b), the Appalachian Regional Commission shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate notice of the award of a grant or other financial assistance not less than 3 full business days before awarding the grant or other financial assistance.

(b) Projects Described.—A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project that the Appalachian Regional Commission has selected to receive a grant or other financial assistance under this subtitle in an amount not less than $50,000.

(Added Pub. L. 117–58, div. A, title I, § 11506(c)(1), Nov. 15, 2021, 135 Stat. 584.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 2021, see section 10003 of Pub. L. 117–58, set out as an Effective Date of 2021 Amendment note under section 101 of Title 23, Highways.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In the case of a project described in subsection (b), the Appalachian Regional Commission shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate notice of the award of a grant or other financial assistance not less than 3 full business days before awarding the grant or other financial assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A project referred to in subsection (a) is a project that the Appalachian Regional Commission has selected to receive a grant or other financial assistance under this subtitle in an amount not less than $50,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>