<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14502"><akn:num>14502</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration health projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14502. Demonstration health projects(a) Purpose.—To demonstrate the value of adequate health facilities and services to the economic development of the Appalachian region, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may make grants for the planning, construction, equipment, and operation of multi-county demonstration health, nutrition, and child care projects, including hospitals, regional health diagnostic and treatment centers, and other facilities and services necessary for the purposes of this section.

(b) Planning Grants.—(1) Authority to provide amounts and make grants.—The Secretary may provide amounts to the Appalachian Regional Commission for the support of its Health Advisory Committee and may make grants for expenses of planning necessary for the development and operation of demonstration health projects for the region.

(2) Limitation on available amounts.—The amount of a grant under this section for planning shall not be more than 75 percent of expenses.

(3) Sources of assistance.—The federal contribution may be provided entirely from amounts authorized under this section or in combination with amounts provided under other federal or federal grant programs.

(4) Federal share.—Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the federal share in those other programs, amounts appropriated to carry out this section may be used to increase the federal share to the maximum percentage cost of a grant authorized by this subsection.


(c) Construction and Equipment Grants.—(1) Additional uses for construction grants.—Grants under this section for construction may also be used for—(A) the acquisition of privately owned facilities—(i) not operated for profit; or

(ii) previously operated for profit if the Commission finds that health services would not otherwise be provided in the area served by the facility if the acquisition is not made; and


(B) initial equipment.


(2) Standards for making grants.—Grants under this section for construction shall be made in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To demonstrate the value of adequate health facilities and services to the economic development of the Appalachian region, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may make grants for the planning, construction, equipment, and operation of multi-county demonstration health, nutrition, and child care projects, including hospitals, regional health diagnostic and treatment centers, and other facilities and services necessary for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and Equipment Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Sources and Use of Grants in Computing Allotments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grants under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Commission Contribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14502_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emphasis on Occupational Diseases From Coal Mining.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) To provide for the further development of the Appalachian region’s human resources, grants under this section shall give special emphasis to programs and research for the early detection, diagnosis, and treatment of occupational diseases arising from coal mining, such as black lung.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>