<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14509"><akn:num>14509</akn:num><akn:heading>High-speed broadband deployment initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14509. High-speed broadband deployment initiative(a) In General.—The Appalachian Regional Commission may provide technical assistance, make grants, enter into contracts, or otherwise provide amounts to individuals or entities in the Appalachian region for projects and activities to increase affordable access to broadband networks throughout the Appalachian region.

(b) Eligible Projects and Activities.—A project or activity eligible to be carried out under this section is a project or activity—(1) to conduct research, analysis, and training to increase broadband adoption efforts in the Appalachian region; or

(2) for the construction and deployment of broadband service-related infrastructure in the Appalachian region.


(c) Limitation on Available Amounts.—Of the cost of any activity eligible for a grant under this section—(1) not more than 50 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section; and

(2) notwithstanding paragraph (1)—(A) in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which a distressed county designation is in effect under section 14526, not more than 80 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section; and

(B) in the case of a project to be carried out in a county for which an at-risk designation is in effect under section 14526, not more than 70 percent may be provided from amounts appropriated to carry out this section.



(d) Sources of Assistance.—Subject to subsection (c), a grant provided under this section may be provided from amounts made available to carry out this section in combination with amounts made available—(1) under any other Federal program; or

(2) from any other source.


(e) Federal Share.—Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the Federal share under any other Federal program, amounts made available to carry out this section may be used to increase that Federal share, as the Appalachian Regional Commission determines to be appropriate.

(f) Request for D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Appalachian Regional Commission may provide technical assistance, make grants, enter into contracts, or otherwise provide amounts to individuals or entities in the Appalachian region for projects and activities to increase affordable access to broadband networks throughout the Appalachian region.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Projects and Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A project or activity eligible to be carried out under this section is a project or activity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Available Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Of the cost of any activity eligible for a grant under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subject to subsection (c), a grant provided under this section may be provided from amounts made available to carry out this section in combination with amounts made available—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the Federal share under any other Federal program, amounts made available to carry out this section may be used to increase that Federal share, as the Appalachian Regional Commission determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Before making a grant for a project or activity described in subsection (b)(2), the Appalachian Regional Commission shall request from the Federal Communications Commission, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the Economic Development Administration, and the Department of Agriculture data on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For each fiscal year, not less than 65 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section shall be used for grants for projects and activities described in subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>