<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14525" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14525/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/14525/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14525"><akn:num>14525</akn:num><akn:heading>State development planning process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14525. State development planning process(a) State Development Plan.—Pursuant to policies the Appalachian Regional Commission establishes, each state member shall submit a development plan for the area of the State within the Appalachian region. The plan shall—(1) be submitted according to a schedule the Commission prescribes;

(2) reflect the goals, objectives, and priorities identified in the regional development plan and in any subregional development plan that may be approved for the subregion of which the State is a part;

(3) describe the state organization and continuous process for Appalachian development planning, including—(A) the procedures established by the State for the participation of local development districts in the process;

(B) how the process is related to overall statewide planning and budgeting processes; and

(C) the method of coordinating planning and projects in the region under this subtitle, the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 3121 et seq.), and other federal, state, and local programs;


(4) set forth the goals, objectives, and priorities of the State for the region, as established by the Governor, and identify the needs on which the goals, objectives, and priorities are based; and

(5) describe the development strategies for achieving the goals, objectives, and priorities, including funding sources, and recommendations for specific projects to receive assistance under this subtitle.


(b) Areawide Action Programs.—The Commission shall encourage the preparation and execution of areawide action programs that specify interrelated projects and schedules of actions, the necessary agency funding, and other commitments to implement the programs. The programs shall make appropriate use of existing plans affecting the area.

(c) Local Development Districts.—Local development districts certified by the State as described in section 14102(a)(2) of this title provide the linkage between state and substate planning an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14525_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Development Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pursuant to policies the Appalachian Regional Commission establishes, each state member shall submit a development plan for the area of the State within the Appalachian region. The plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14525_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Areawide Action Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Commission shall encourage the preparation and execution of areawide action programs that specify interrelated projects and schedules of actions, the necessary agency funding, and other commitments to implement the programs. The programs shall make appropriate use of existing plans affecting the area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14525_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local Development Districts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local development districts certified by the State as described in section 14102(a)(2) of this title provide the linkage between state and substate planning and development. The districts shall assist the States in the coordination of areawide programs and projects and may prepare and adopt areawide plans or action programs. In carrying out the development planning process, including the selection of programs and projects for assistance, States shall consult with local development districts, local units of government, and citizen groups and shall consider the goals, objectives, priorities, and recommendations of those bodies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14525_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To the maximum extent practicable, federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities undertaking or providing financial assistance for programs or projects in the region shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>