<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/15902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/15902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/15902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15902"><akn:num>15902</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration health projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15902. Demonstration health projects(a) Purpose.—To demonstrate the value of adequate health facilities and services to the economic development of the region, a Commission may make grants for the planning, construction, equipment, and operation of demonstration health, nutrition, and child care projects to serve distressed areas (referred to in this section as a “demonstration health project”), including hospitals, regional health diagnostic and treatment centers, and other facilities and services necessary for the purposes of this section.

(b) Eligible Entities.—An entity eligible to receive a grant under this section is—(1) an entity described in section 15501(a);

(2) an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1001(a)));

(3) a hospital (as defined in section 1861 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395x)); or

(4) a critical access hospital (as defined in that section).


(c) Planning Grants.—(1) In general.—A Commission may make grants for planning expenses necessary for the development and operation of demonstration health projects for the region served by the Commission.

(2) Maximum commission contribution.—The maximum Commission contribution for a demonstration health project that receives a grant under paragraph (1) shall be made in accordance with section 15501(d).

(3) Sources of assistance.—A grant under paragraph (1) may be provided entirely from amounts made available to carry out this section or in combination with amounts provided under other Federal grant programs.

(4) Federal share for grants under other federal grant programs.—Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting the Federal share in other Federal grant programs, amounts made available to carry out this subsection may be used to increase the Federal share of another Federal grant up to the maximum contribution described in paragraph (2).


(d) Construction and Equipment Grants.—(1) In general.—A grant under this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To demonstrate the value of adequate health facilities and services to the economic development of the region, a Commission may make grants for the planning, construction, equipment, and operation of demonstration health, nutrition, and child care projects to serve distressed areas (referred to in this section as a “demonstration health project”), including hospitals, regional health diagnostic and treatment centers, and other facilities and services necessary for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An entity eligible to receive a grant under this section is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and Equipment Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority Health Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If a Commission elects to make grants under this section, the Commission shall establish specific regional health priorities for such grants that address—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>