<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/17507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/17507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/17507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17507"><akn:num>17507</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17507. Savings(a) Actions by President Required.—The President shall establish, for each executive agency, goals to reduce outlays for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles in order to reduce, by fiscal year 1988, the total amount of outlays by all executive agencies for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles to an amount which is $150,000,000 less than the amount for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles requested by the President in the budget submitted under section 1105 of title 31 for fiscal year 1986.

(b) Monitoring of Compliance.—The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall monitor compliance by executive agencies with the goals established by the President under subsection (a) and shall include, in each summary and analysis required under section 17505 of this title, a statement specifying the reductions in expenditures by executive agencies, including the Department of Defense, achieved under those goals.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1285.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


1750740:908.Pub. L. 99–272, title XV, § 15308, Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 337.



Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Federal Vehicle Repair Cost SavingsPub. L. 114–65, Oct. 7, 2015, 129 Stat. 551, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.“This Act may be cited as the ‘Federal Vehicle Repair Cost Savings Act of 2015’.


“SEC. 2. FINDINGS.“Congress finds that, in March 2013, the Government Accountability Office issued a report that confirmed that—“(1) there are approximately 588,000 vehicles in the civilian Federal fleet;

“(2) Federal agencies spent approximately $975,000,000 on repair and maintenance of the Federal fleet in 2011;

“(3) remanufactured vehicle components, such as engines, starters, alternators, steering racks, and clutches, tend to be less expensi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by President Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President shall establish, for each executive agency, goals to reduce outlays for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles in order to reduce, by fiscal year 1988, the total amount of outlays by all executive agencies for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles to an amount which is $150,000,000 less than the amount for the operation, maintenance, leasing, acquisition, and disposal of motor vehicles requested by the President in the budget submitted under section 1105 of title 31 for fiscal year 1986.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall monitor compliance by executive agencies with the goals established by the President under subsection (a) and shall include, in each summary and analysis required under section 17505 of this title, a statement specifying the reductions in expenditures by executive agencies, including the Department of Defense, achieved under those goals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>