<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3101"><akn:num>3101</akn:num><akn:heading>Public buildings under control of Administrator of General Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3101. Public buildings under control of Administrator of General Services
All public buildings outside of the District of Columbia and outside of military reservations purchased or erected out of any appropriation under the control of the Administrator of General Services, and the sites of the public buildings, are under the exclusive jurisdiction and control, and in the custody of, the Administrator. The Administrator may take possession of the buildings and assign and reassign rooms in the buildings to federal officials, clerks, and employees that the Administrator believes should be furnished with offices or rooms in the buildings.
(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1143.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


310140:285.July 1, 1898, ch. 546, § 1 (6th complete par. on p. 614), 30 Stat. 614.


The word “subtreasuries” in the 6th complete paragraph on p. 614 of section 1 of the Act of July 1, 1898 (ch. 546, 30 Stat. 614), is omitted because section 1 (words in par. under heading “Independent Treasury”) of the Act of May 29, 1914 (ch. 214, 41 Stat. 654) discontinued subtreasuries. The word “post-offices” in section 1 is omitted because section 1 of Executive Order No. 6166 (eff. June 10, 1933) transferred administration of post office buildings to the Post Office Department. The words “courthouses, customhouses, appraiser’s stores, barge offices, and other” are omitted as unnecessary. The words “or are in course of construction” are omitted as obsolete. The words “Administrator of General Services” are substituted for “Treasury Department” and “Secretary of the Treasury” [subsequently changed to “Federal Works Agency” and “Federal Works Administrator” because of sections 301 and 303, respectively, of Reorganization Plan No. I of 1939 (eff. July 1, 1939, 53 Stat. 1426, 1427)] because of section 103(a) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (ch. 288, 63 Stat. 380), wh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>