<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_311"><akn:num>311</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 311. Personnel(a) Appointment and Compensation.—The Administrator of General Services, subject to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, may appoint and fix the compensation of personnel necessary to carry out chapters 1, 3, and 5 of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.

(b) Temporary Employment.—The Administrator may procure the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants under section 3109 of title 5 to the extent the Administrator finds necessary to carry out chapters 1, 3, and 5 of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.

(c) Personnel From Other Agencies.—Notwithstanding section 973 of title 10 or any other law, in carrying out functions under this subtitle the Administrator may use the services of personnel (including armed services personnel) from an executive agency other than the General Services Administration with the consent of the head of the agency.

(d) Detail of Field Personnel to District of Columbia.—The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion, may detail field personnel of the Administration to the District of Columbia for temporary duty for a period of not more than 30 days in any one case. Subsistence or similar expenses may not be allowed for an employee on temporary duty in the District of Columbia under this paragraph.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1072; Pub. L. 111–350, § 5(l)(5), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3851.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


311(a)–(c)40:758.June 30, 1949, ch. 288, title II, § 208, 63 Stat. 391; Sept. 5, 1950, ch. 849, § 7(b), (c), 64 Stat. 590.
311(d)40:253.June 23, 1913, ch. 3, § 1 (proviso on p. 17), 38 Stat. 17.


In subsections (a) and (b), the words “and title III of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (41 U.S.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of General Services, subject to chapters 33 and 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, may appoint and fix the compensation of personnel necessary to carry out chapters 1, 3, and 5 of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary Employment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator may procure the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants under section 3109 of title 5 to the extent the Administrator finds necessary to carry out chapters 1, 3, and 5 of this title and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel From Other Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding section 973 of title 10 or any other law, in carrying out functions under this subtitle the Administrator may use the services of personnel (including armed services personnel) from an executive agency other than the General Services Administration with the consent of the head of the agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of Field Personnel to District of Columbia.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administrator, in the Administrator’s discretion, may detail field personnel of the Administration to the District of Columbia for temporary duty for a period of not more than 30 days in any one case. Subsistence or similar expenses may not be allowed for an employee on temporary duty in the District of Columbia under this paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>