<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3134"><akn:num>3134</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers for certain contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3134. Waivers for certain contracts(a) Military.—The Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of the Air Force, or the Secretary of Transportation may waive this subchapter with respect to cost-plus-a-fixed fee and other cost-type contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of any public building or public work of the Federal Government and with respect to contracts for manufacturing, producing, furnishing, constructing, altering, repairing, processing, or assembling vessels, aircraft, munitions, materiel, or supplies for the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Coast Guard, respectively, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title.

(b) Transportation.—The Secretary of Transportation may waive this subchapter with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels when the contract is made under sections 1535 and 1536 of title 31 or subtitle V of title 46, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title.

(c) National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.—The Secretary of Commerce may waive this subchapter with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title, when the contract is made under the Act entitled “An Act to define the functions and duties of the Coast and Geodetic Survey, and for other purposes”, approved August 6, 1947 (33 U.S.C. 883a et seq.).

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1149; Pub. L. 109–304, § 17(g)(2), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1709; Pub. L. 115–91, div. C, title XXXV, § 3502(b)(2), Dec. 12, 2017, 131 Stat. 1910; Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3515(c), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 2313.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


3134(a)40:270e.Apr. 29, 1941, ch. 81, § 1, 55 Stat. 147; June 3, 1955, ch. 129, 69 Stat. 83.
3134(b)40:270f.Apr. 29, 1941, ch. 81, § 2, as added Pub. L. 91–469, § 39, O</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of the Air Force, or the Secretary of Transportation may waive this subchapter with respect to cost-plus-a-fixed fee and other cost-type contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of any public building or public work of the Federal Government and with respect to contracts for manufacturing, producing, furnishing, constructing, altering, repairing, processing, or assembling vessels, aircraft, munitions, materiel, or supplies for the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Coast Guard, respectively, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation may waive this subchapter with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels when the contract is made under sections 1535 and 1536 of title 31 or subtitle V of title 46, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Commerce may waive this subchapter with respect to contracts for the construction, alteration, or repair of vessels, regardless of the terms of the contracts as to payment or title, when the contract is made under the Act entitled “An Act to define the functions and duties of the Coast and Geodetic Survey, and for other purposes”, approved August 6, 1947 (33 U.S.C. 883a et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>