<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3303"><akn:num>3303</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing investigation and survey of public buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3303. Continuing investigation and survey of public buildings(a) Conducted by Administrator.—The Administrator of General Services shall—(1) make a continuing investigation and survey of the public buildings needs of the Federal Government so that the Administrator may carry out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter; and

(2) submit to Congress prospectuses of proposed projects in accordance with section 3307(a) and (b) of this title.


(b) Cooperation with Federal Agencies.—(1) Duties of administrator.—In carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter, the Administrator—(A) shall cooperate with all federal agencies in order to keep informed of their needs;

(B) shall advise each federal agency of the program with respect to the agency; and

(C) may request the cooperation and assistance of each federal agency in carrying out duties under this chapter.


(2) Duty of federal agencies.—Each federal agency shall cooperate with, advise, and assist the Administrator in carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter as determined necessary by the Administrator to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(c) Request for Identification of Existing Buildings of Historical, Architectural, or Cultural Significance.—When the Administrator undertakes a survey of the public buildings needs of the Government within a geographical area, the Administrator shall request that, within 60 days, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation established by section 304101 of title 54 identify any existing buildings in the geographical area that—(1) are of historical, architectural, or cultural significance (as defined in section 3306(a) of this title); and

(2) whether or not in need of repair, alteration, or addition, would be suitable for acquisition to meet the public buildings needs of the Government.


(d) Standard for Construction and Acquisition of Public Buildings.—In carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conducted by Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of General Services shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with Federal Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for Identification of Existing Buildings of Historical, Architectural, or Cultural Significance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When the Administrator undertakes a survey of the public buildings needs of the Government within a geographical area, the Administrator shall request that, within 60 days, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation established by section 304101 of title 54 identify any existing buildings in the geographical area that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard for Construction and Acquisition of Public Buildings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out the duties of the Administrator under this chapter, the Administrator shall provide for the construction and acquisition of public buildings equitably throughout the United States with due regard to the comparative urgency of the need for each particular building. In developing plans for new buildings, the Administrator shall give due consideration to excellence of architecture and design.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>