<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3306"><akn:num>3306</akn:num><akn:heading>Accommodating federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3306. Accommodating federal agencies(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) Commercial activities.—The term “commercial activities” includes the operations of restaurants, food stores, craft stores, dry goods stores, financial institutions, and display facilities.

(2) Cultural activities.—The term “cultural activities” includes film, dramatic, dance, and musical presentations, and fine art exhibits, whether or not those activities are intended to make a profit.

(3) Educational activities.—The terms “educational activities” includes the operations of libraries, schools, day care centers, laboratories, and lecture and demonstration facilities.

(4) Historical, architectural, or cultural significance.—The term “historical, architectural, or cultural significance” includes buildings listed or eligible to be listed on the National Register established under chapter 3021 of title 54.

(5) Recreational activities.—The term “recreational activities” includes the operations of gymnasiums and related facilities.

(6) Unit of general local government.—The term “unit of general local government” means a city, county, town, parish, village, or other general-purpose political subdivision of a State.


(b) Duties of Administrator.—To carry out the duties of the Administrator of General Services under sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5) of this title and under any other authority with respect to constructing, operating, maintaining, altering, and otherwise managing or acquiring space necessary to accommodate federal agencies and to accomplish the purposes of sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5), the Administrator shall—(1) acquire and utilize space in suitable buildings of historical, architectural, or cultural significance, unless use of the space would not prove feasible and prudent compared with available alternatives;

(2) encourage the location of commercial, cultural, educational, and recreational facilities and activities in public b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To carry out the duties of the Administrator of General Services under sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5) of this title and under any other authority with respect to constructing, operating, maintaining, altering, and otherwise managing or acquiring space necessary to accommodate federal agencies and to accomplish the purposes of sections 581(h), 584(b), 3303(c), and 3307(b)(3) and (5), the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and Solicitation of Comments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>