<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3307"><akn:num>3307</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional approval of proposed projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3307. Congressional approval of proposed projects(a) Resolutions Required Before Appropriations May Be Made.—The following appropriations may be made only if the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives adopt resolutions approving the purpose for which the appropriation is made:(1) An appropriation to construct, alter, or acquire any building to be used as a public building which involves a total expenditure in excess of $1,500,000, so that the equitable distribution of public buildings throughout the United States with due regard for the comparative urgency of need for the buildings, except as provided in section 3305(b) of this title, is ensured.

(2) An appropriation to lease any space at an average annual rental in excess of $1,500,000 for use for public purposes.

(3) An appropriation to alter any building, or part of the building, which is under lease by the Federal Government for use for a public purpose if the cost of the alteration will exceed $750,000.


(b) Transmission to Congress of Prospectus of Proposed Project.—To secure consideration for the approval referred to in subsection (a), the Administrator of General Services (referred to in this section as the “Administrator”) shall transmit to Congress a prospectus of the proposed facility, including—(1) a brief description of the building to be constructed, altered, or acquired, or the space to be leased, under this chapter;

(2) the location of the building or space to be leased and an estimate of the maximum cost to the Government of the facility to be constructed, altered, or acquired, or the space to be leased;

(3) a comprehensive plan for providing space for all Government officers and employees in the locality of the proposed facility or the space to be leased, having due regard for suitable space which may continue to be available in existing Government-owned or occupied buildings, especially t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolutions Required Before Appropriations May Be Made.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The following appropriations may be made only if the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives adopt resolutions approving the purpose for which the appropriation is made:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission to Congress of Prospectus of Proposed Project.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To secure consideration for the approval referred to in subsection (a), the Administrator of General Services (referred to in this section as the “Administrator”) shall transmit to Congress a prospectus of the proposed facility, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase of Estimated Maximum Cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The estimated maximum cost of any project approved under this section as set forth in any prospectus may be increased by an amount equal to any percentage increase, as determined by the Administrator, in construction or alteration costs from the date the prospectus is transmitted to Congress. The increase authorized by this subsection may not exceed 10 percent of the estimated maximum cost. The Administrator shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of any increase of more than 5 percent of an estimated maximum cost or of any increase or decrease in the scope or size of a project of 5 or more percent. Such notification shall include an explanation regarding any such increase or decrease. The scope or size of a project shall not increase or decrease by more than 10 percent unless an amended prospectus is submitted and approved pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rescission of Approval.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If an appropriation is not made within one year after the date a project for construction, alteration, or acquisition is approved under subsection (a), the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate or the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives by resolution may rescind its approval before an appropriation is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency Leases by the Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section does not prevent the Administrator from entering into emergency leases during any period declared by the President to require emergency leasing authority. An emergency lease may not be for more than 180 days without approval of a prospectus for the lease in accordance with subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Performance Requirements for Leased Space.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) With respect to space to be leased, the Administrator shall include, to the maximum extent practicable, minimum performance requirements requiring energy efficiency and the use of renewable energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Leasing Certain Space.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dollar Amount Adjustment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Administrator annually may adjust any dollar amount referred to in this section to reflect a percentage increase or decrease in construction costs during the prior calendar year, as determined by the composite index of construction costs of the Department of Commerce. Any adjustment shall be expeditiously reported to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) For each project approved under this section, the Administrator shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of any project milestones that are accomplished, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration of Committee Resolutions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>