<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3313"><akn:num>3313</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3313. Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Administrator.—The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.

(2) Lighting system.—The term “lighting system” means the elements required to maintain a desired light level, including lamps, light fixtures, fixture distribution, sensors and control technologies, interior design elements, and daylighting sources.


(b) Procurement.—(1) In general.—To the maximum extent practicable, the Administrator shall—(A) procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems; and

(B) ensure that procurements after the date of enactment of the BRIGHT Act of lighting systems or the individual components of lighting systems maximize life-cycle cost effectiveness and energy efficiency.


(2) Use.—Each public building constructed, altered, acquired, or leased by the Administrator shall be equipped, to the maximum extent practicable as determined by the Administrator, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems for each application.


(c) Maintenance of Public Buildings.—Each individual component of a lighting system, including a lamp or fixture, that is replaced by the Administrator in the normal course of maintenance of public buildings shall be replaced, to the maximum extent practicable, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system possible for the application.

(d) Considerations.—(1) Contracting options.—In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consider appropriate contracting options for the procurement of the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems.

(2) Procurement and use.—In making a determination under this section concerning the practicability of procuring and installing the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system, the Administrator shall consider—(A) the compatibility</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of Public Buildings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each individual component of a lighting system, including a lamp or fixture, that is replaced by the Administrator in the normal course of maintenance of public buildings shall be replaced, to the maximum extent practicable, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system possible for the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life-Cycle Cost Effective.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall use the procedures and methods established under section 544(a) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (42 U.S.C. 8254(a)) in determining whether a lighting system is life-cycle cost effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Star.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A lighting system shall be treated as being energy efficient for purposes of this section if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Energy Efficient Lighting Designations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Energy shall give priority to establishing Energy Star performance criteria or Federal Energy Management Program designations for additional lighting product categories that are appropriate for procurement and use in public buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Administrator shall develop guidelines for the procurement and use of energy efficient lighting technologies that contain mercury in child care centers in public buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Buy American Act.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Acquisitions carried out pursuant to this section shall be subject to the requirements of the Buy American Act 11 See References in Text note below. (41 U.S.C. 10c et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>