<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/3703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3703"><akn:num>3703</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of violations and withholding of amounts for unpaid wages and liquidated damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3703. Report of violations and withholding of amounts for unpaid wages and liquidated damages(a) Reports of Inspectors.—An officer or individual designated as an inspector of the work to be performed under a contract described in section 3701 of this title, or to aid in the enforcement or fulfillment of the contract, on observation or after investigation immediately shall report to the proper officer of the Federal Government, a territory of the United States, or the District of Columbia all violations of this chapter occurring in the performance of the work, together with the name of each laborer or mechanic who was required or permitted to work in violation of this chapter and the day the violation occurred.

(b) Withholding Amounts.—(1) Determining amount.—The amount of unpaid wages and liquidated damages owing under this chapter shall be determined administratively.

(2) Amount directed to be withheld.—The officer or individual whose duty it is to approve the payment of money by the Government, territory, or District of Columbia in connection with the performance of the contract work shall direct the amount of—(A) liquidated damages to be withheld for the use and benefit of the Government, territory, or District; and

(B) unpaid wages to be withheld for the use and benefit of the laborers and mechanics who were not compensated as required under this chapter.


(3) Payment.—The Secretary of Labor shall pay the amount administratively determined to be due directly to the laborers and mechanics from amounts withheld on account of underpayments of wages if the amount withheld is adequate. If the amount withheld is not adequate, the Secretary of Labor shall pay an equitable proportion of the amount due.


(c) Right of Action and Intervention Against Contractors and Sureties.—If the accrued payments withheld under the terms of the contract are insufficient to reimburse all the laborers and mechanics who have not been paid the wages required under this chapter, the l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports of Inspectors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An officer or individual designated as an inspector of the work to be performed under a contract described in section 3701 of this title, or to aid in the enforcement or fulfillment of the contract, on observation or after investigation immediately shall report to the proper officer of the Federal Government, a territory of the United States, or the District of Columbia all violations of this chapter occurring in the performance of the work, together with the name of each laborer or mechanic who was required or permitted to work in violation of this chapter and the day the violation occurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of Action and Intervention Against Contractors and Sureties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If the accrued payments withheld under the terms of the contract are insufficient to reimburse all the laborers and mechanics who have not been paid the wages required under this chapter, the laborers and mechanics, in the case of a department or agency of the Government, have the same right of action and intervention against the contractor and the contractor’s sureties as is conferred by law on persons furnishing labor or materials. In those proceedings it is not a defense that the laborers and mechanics accepted or agreed to accept less than the required rate of wages or voluntarily made refunds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>