<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/5104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/5104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/5104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5104"><akn:num>5104</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5104. Unlawful activities(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) Act of physical violence.—The term “act of physical violence” means any act involving—(A) an assault or other infliction or threat of infliction of death or bodily harm on an individual; or

(B) damage to, or destruction of, real or personal property.


(2) Dangerous weapon.—The term “dangerous weapon” includes—(A) all articles enumerated in section 14(a) of the Act of July 8, 1932 (ch. 465, 47 Stat. 654); and

(B) a device designed to expel or hurl a projectile capable of causing injury to individuals or property, a dagger, a dirk, a stiletto, and a knife having a blade over three inches in length.


(3) Explosives.—The term “explosives” has the meaning given that term in section 841(d) of title 18.

(4) Firearm.—The term “firearm” has the meaning given that term in section 921(3) 11 So in original. Probably should be “921(a)(3)”. of title 18.


(b) Obstruction of Roads.—A person may not occupy the roads in the United States Capitol Grounds in a manner that obstructs or hinders their proper use, or use the roads in the area of the Grounds, south of Constitution Avenue and B Street and north of Independence Avenue and B Street, to convey goods or merchandise, except to or from the United States Capitol on Federal Government service.

(c) Sale of Articles, Display of Signs, and Solicitations.—A person may not carry out any of the following activities in the Grounds:(1) offer or expose any article for sale.

(2) display a sign, placard, or other form of advertisement.

(3) solicit fares, alms, subscriptions, or contributions.


(d) Injuries to Property.—A person may not step or climb on, remove, or in any way injure any statue, seat, wall, fountain, or other erection or architectural feature, or any tree, shrub, plant, or turf, in the Grounds.

(e) Capitol Grounds and Buildings Security.—(1) Firearms, dangerous weapons, explosives, or incendiary devices.—An individual or group of individuals—(A) except as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obstruction of Roads.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person may not occupy the roads in the United States Capitol Grounds in a manner that obstructs or hinders their proper use, or use the roads in the area of the Grounds, south of Constitution Avenue and B Street and north of Independence Avenue and B Street, to convey goods or merchandise, except to or from the United States Capitol on Federal Government service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of Articles, Display of Signs, and Solicitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A person may not carry out any of the following activities in the Grounds:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injuries to Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A person may not step or climb on, remove, or in any way injure any statue, seat, wall, fountain, or other erection or architectural feature, or any tree, shrub, plant, or turf, in the Grounds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitol Grounds and Buildings Security.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parades, Assemblages, and Display of Flags.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Except as provided in section 5106 of this title, a person may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>