<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/545" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/545/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/545/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_545"><akn:num>545</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 545. Procedure for disposal(a) Public Advertising for Bids.—(1) Requirement.—(A) In general.—Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Administrator of General Services may make or authorize a disposal or a contract for disposal of surplus property only after public advertising for bids, under regulations the Administrator prescribes.

(B) Exceptions.—This subsection does not apply to disposal or a contract for disposal of surplus property—(i) under subsection (b) or (d); or

(ii) by abandonment, destruction, or donation or through a contract broker.



(2) Time, method, and terms.—The time, method, and terms and conditions of advertisement must permit full and free competition consistent with the value and nature of the property involved.

(3) Public disclosure.—Bids must be publicly disclosed at the time and place stated in the advertisement.

(4) Awards.—An award shall be made with reasonable promptness by notice to the responsible bidder whose bid, conforming to the invitation for bids, is most advantageous to the Federal Government, price and other factors considered. However, all bids may be rejected if it is in the public interest to do so.


(b) Negotiated Disposal.—Under regulations the Administrator prescribes, disposals and contracts for disposal may be negotiated without regard to subsection (a), but subject to obtaining competition that is feasible under the circumstances, if—(1) necessary in the public interest—(A) during the period of a national emergency declared by the President or Congress, with respect to a particular lot of personal property; or

(B) for a period not exceeding three months, with respect to a specifically described category of personal property as determined by the Administrator;


(2) the public health, safety, or national security will be promoted by a particular disposal of personal property;

(3) public exigency will not allow delay incident to advertising certain personal property;

(4) the nature and quantity of personal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Advertising for Bids.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiated Disposal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations the Administrator prescribes, disposals and contracts for disposal may be negotiated without regard to subsection (a), but subject to obtaining competition that is feasible under the circumstances, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposal Through Contract Brokers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disposals and contracts for disposal of surplus real and related personal property through contract realty brokers employed by the Administrator shall be made in the manner followed in similar commercial transactions under regulations the Administrator prescribes. The regulations must require that brokers give wide public notice of the availability of the property for disposal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiated Sale at Fixed Price.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explanatory Statements for Negotiated Disposals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_545_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Other Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Section 6101(b)–(d) of title 41 does not apply to a disposal or contract for disposal made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>