<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_571"><akn:num>571</akn:num><akn:heading>General rules for deposit and use of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 571. General rules for deposit and use of proceeds(a) Deposit in Treasury as Miscellaneous Receipts.—(1) In general.—Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, proceeds described in paragraph (2) shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.

(2) Proceeds.—The proceeds referred to in paragraph (1) are proceeds under this chapter from a—(A) transfer of excess property to a federal agency for agency use; or

(B) sale, lease, or other disposition of surplus property.



(b) Payment of Expenses of Sale Before Deposit.—Subject to regulations under this subtitle, the expenses of the sale of old material, condemned stores, supplies, or other public property may be paid from the proceeds of sale so that only the net proceeds are deposited in the Treasury. This subsection applies whether proceeds are deposited as miscellaneous receipts or to the credit of an appropriation as authorized by law.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1104; Pub. L. 114–287, § 20(a), Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1477; Pub. L. 114–318, § 7(c)(1), Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1616.)

Amendment of SectionPub. L. 114–287, § 20, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1477, which Act is set out as a note under section 1303 of this title, provided that, effective upon the termination of the Public Buildings Reform Board pursuant to section 10 of Pub. L. 114–287 and not applicable to proceeds from transactions conducted under section 14 of Pub. L. 114–287, this section is amended by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:
(a) Proceeds From Transfer or Sale of Real Property.—
(1) Deposit of net proceeds.—Net proceeds described in subsection (c) shall be deposited into the appropriate real property account of the agency that had custody and accountability for the real property at the time the real property is determined to be excess.
(2) Expenditure of net proceeds.—The net proceeds deposited pursuant to paragraph (1) may only be expended, as authorized in annual appropriation</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_571_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit in Treasury as Miscellaneous Receipts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_571_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Expenses of Sale Before Deposit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to regulations under this subtitle, the expenses of the sale of old material, condemned stores, supplies, or other public property may be paid from the proceeds of sale so that only the net proceeds are deposited in the Treasury. This subsection applies whether proceeds are deposited as miscellaneous receipts or to the credit of an appropriation as authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>