<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_572"><akn:num>572</akn:num><akn:heading>Real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 572. Real property(a) In General.—(1) Separate fund.—Except as provided in subsection (b), proceeds of the disposition of surplus real and related personal property by the Administrator of General Services shall be set aside in a separate fund in the Treasury.

(2) Payment of expenses from the fund.—(A) Authority.—From the fund described in paragraph (1), the Administrator may obligate an amount to pay the following direct expenses incurred for the use of excess property and the disposal of surplus property under this subtitle:(i) Fees of appraisers, auctioneers, and realty brokers, in accordance with the scale customarily paid in similar commercial transactions.

(ii) Costs of environmental and historic preservation services, highest and best use of property studies, utilization of property studies, deed compliance inspection, and the expenses incurred in a relocation.

(iii) Advertising and surveying.


(B) Limitations.—(i) Percentage limitation.—In each fiscal year, no more than 12 percent of the proceeds of all dispositions of surplus real and related personal property may be paid to meet direct expenses incurred in connection with the dispositions.

(ii) Determination of maximum amount.—The Director of the Office of Management and Budget each quarter shall determine the maximum amount that may be obligated under this paragraph.


(C) Direct payment or reimbursement.—An amount obligated under this paragraph may be used to pay an expense directly or to reimburse a fund or appropriation that initially paid the expense.


(3) Transfer to miscellaneous receipts.—At least once each year, excess amounts beyond current operating needs shall be transferred from the fund described in paragraph (1) to miscellaneous receipts.

(4) Report.—A report of receipts, disbursements, and transfers to miscellaneous receipts under this subsection shall be made annually, in connection with the budget estimate, to the Director and to Congress.


(b) Real Property Under Control of a M</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Real Property Under Control of a Military Department.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>