<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/581" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/581/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/581/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_581"><akn:num>581</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority of Administrator of General Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 581. General authority of Administrator of General Services[(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1706(a)(1), Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2316.]

(b) Personnel and Equipment.—The Administrator of General Services may—(1) employ and pay personnel at per diem rates approved by the Administrator, not exceeding rates currently paid by private industry for similar services in the place where the services are performed; and

(2) purchase, repair, and clean uniforms for civilian employees of the General Services Administration who are required by law or regulation to wear uniform clothing.


(c) Acquisition and Management of Property.—(1) Real estate.—The Administrator may acquire, by purchase, condemnation, or otherwise, real estate and interests in real estate.

(2) Ground rent.—The Administrator may pay ground rent for buildings owned by the Federal Government or occupied by federal agencies, and pay the rent in advance if required by law or if the Administrator determines that advance payment is in the public interest.

(3) Rent and repairs under a lease.—The Administrator may pay rent and make repairs, alterations, and improvements under the terms of a lease entered into by, or transferred to, the Administration for the housing of a federal agency.

(4) Repairs that are economically advantageous.—The Administrator may repair, alter, or improve rented premises if the Administrator determines that doing so is advantageous to the Government in terms of economy, efficiency, or national security. The Administrator’s determination must—(A) set forth the circumstances that make the repair, alteration, or improvement advantageous; and

(B) show that the total cost (rental, repair, alteration, and improvement) for the expected life of the lease is less than the cost of alternative space not needing repair, alteration, or improvement.


(5) Insurance proceeds for defense industrial reserve.—At the direction of the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator may use insurance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 107–296, title XVII, § 1706(a)(1), Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2316.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel and Equipment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator of General Services may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and Management of Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease of Federal Building Sites.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to the Inaugural Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator may provide direct assistance and special services for the Inaugural Committee (as defined in section 501 of title 36) during an inaugural period in connection with Presidential inaugural operations and functions. Assistance and services under this subsection may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilities for Defense Industrial Reserve and Surplus Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obtaining Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_581_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Use of Public Buildings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>