<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/592" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/592/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/592/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_592"><akn:num>592</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Buildings Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 592. Federal Buildings Fund(a) Existence.—There is in the Treasury a fund known as the Federal Buildings Fund.

(b) Deposits.—(1) In general.—The following revenues and collections shall be deposited into the Fund:(A) User charges under section 586(b) of this title, payable in advance or otherwise.

(B) Proceeds from the lease of federal building sites or additions under section 581(d) of this title.

(C) Receipts from carriers and others for loss of, or damage to, property belonging to the Fund.


(2) Reimbursements for special services.—This subchapter does not preclude the Administrator of General Services from providing special services, not included in the standard level user charge, on a reimbursable basis. The reimbursements may be credited to the Fund.

(3) Transfer of surplus amounts.—To prevent the accumulation of excessive surpluses in the Fund, in any fiscal year an amount specified in an appropriation law may be transferred out of the Fund and deposited as miscellaneous receipts in the Treasury.


(c) Uses.—(1) In general.—Deposits in the Fund are available for real property management and related activities in the amounts specified in annual appropriation laws without regard to fiscal year limitations.

(2) Salaries and expenses related to construction projects or planning programs.—Deposits in the Fund that are available pursuant to annual appropriation laws may be transferred and consolidated on the books of the Treasury into a special account in accordance with, and for the purposes specified in, section 3176 of this title.

(3) Repayment of general services administration borrowing from federal financing bank.—The Administrator, in accordance with rules and procedures that the Office of Management and Budget and the Secretary of the Treasury establish, may transfer from the Fund an amount necessary to repay the principal amount of a General Services Administration borrowing from the Federal Financing Bank, if the borrowing is a legal obligation o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is in the Treasury a fund known as the Federal Buildings Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Management Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recycling Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_592_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Authority Related to Energy Management and Recycling Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Fund may receive, in the form of rebates, cash incentives or otherwise, any revenues, collections, or other income related to energy savings or recycling efforts. Amounts received under this subsection remain in the Fund until expended and remain available for federal energy management improvement programs, recycling programs, or employee programs that are authorized by law or that the Administrator considers appropriate. The Administration may use amounts received under this subsection, in addition to amounts received as New Obligational Authority, in activities of the Fund as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>