<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6301"><akn:num>6301</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6301. Definition
In this chapter, the term “specified buildings and grounds” means—(1) Smithsonian institution.—The Smithsonian Institution and its grounds, which include the following:(A) Smithsonian buildings and grounds on the national mall.—The Smithsonian Building, the Arts and Industries Building, the Freer Gallery of Art, the National Air and Space Museum, the National Museum of Natural History, the National Museum of American History, the National Museum of the American Indian, the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, the Arthur M. Sackler Gallery, the National Museum of African Art, the S. Dillon Ripley Center, and all other buildings of the Smithsonian Institution within the Mall, including the entrance walks, unloading areas, and other pertinent service roads and parking areas.

(B) National zoological park.—The National Zoological Park comprising all the buildings, streets, service roads, walks, and other areas within the boundary fence of the National Zoological Park in the District of Columbia and including the public space between that fence and the face of the curb lines of the adjacent city streets.

(C) Other smithsonian buildings and grounds.—All other buildings, service roads, walks, and other areas within the exterior boundaries of any real estate or land or interest in land (including temporary use) that the Smithsonian Institution acquires and that the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution determines to be necessary for the adequate protection of individuals or property in the Smithsonian Institution and suitable for administration as a part of the Smithsonian Institution.


(2) National gallery of art.—(A) The National Gallery of Art and its grounds, which extend—(i) to the line of the face of the south curb of Constitution Avenue Northwest, between Seventh Street Northwest, and Fourth Street Northwest, to the line of the face of the west curb of Fourth Street Northwest, between Constitution Avenue Northwest, and Madison Drive Northwes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smithsonian institution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The Smithsonian Institution and its grounds, which include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>National gallery of art.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>John f. kennedy center for the performing arts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, which extends to the line of the west face of the west retaining walls and curbs of the Inner Loop Freeway on the east, the north face of the north retaining walls and curbs of the Theodore Roosevelt Bridge approaches on the south, the east face of the east retaining walls and curbs of Rock Creek Parkway on the west, and the south curbs of New Hampshire Avenue and F Street on the north, as generally depicted on the map entitled “Transfer of John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts”, numbered 844/82563 and dated April 20, 1994 (as amended by the map entitled “Transfer of John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts”, numbered 844/82563A and dated May 22, 1997), which shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the National Capital Region, National Park Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>