<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6306"><akn:num>6306</akn:num><akn:heading>Policing of buildings and grounds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6306. Policing of buildings and grounds(a) Designation of Employees as Special Police.—Subject to section 5375 of title 5, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (or their designees) may designate employees of their respective agencies as special police, without additional compensation, for duty in connection with the policing of their respective specified buildings and grounds.

(b) Powers.—The employees designated as special police under subsection (a)—(1) may, within the specified buildings and grounds, enforce, and make arrests for violations of, sections 6302 and 6303 of this title, any regulation prescribed under section 6304 of this title, federal or state law, or any regulation prescribed under federal or state law; and

(2) may enforce concurrently with the United States Park Police the laws and regulations applicable to the National Capital Parks, and may make arrests for violations of sections 6302 and 6303 of this title, within the several areas located within the exterior boundaries of the face of the curb lines of the squares within which the specified buildings and grounds are located.


(c) Uniforms and Other Equipment.—The employees designated as special police under subsection (a) may be provided, without charge, with uniforms and other equipment as may be necessary for the proper performance of their duties, including badges, revolvers, and ammunition.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1186.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6306(a)40:193n.Oct. 24, 1951, ch. 559, § 1, 65 Stat. 634; Pub. L. 91–34, § 2(c), June 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 41; Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(c) [title II, proviso in 1st par. under heading “John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts”], Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321–193, renumbered as title I by Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a), M</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Employees as Special Police.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to section 5375 of title 5, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, the Trustees of the National Gallery of Art, and the Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts (or their designees) may designate employees of their respective agencies as special police, without additional compensation, for duty in connection with the policing of their respective specified buildings and grounds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The employees designated as special police under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniforms and Other Equipment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The employees designated as special police under subsection (a) may be provided, without charge, with uniforms and other equipment as may be necessary for the proper performance of their duties, including badges, revolvers, and ammunition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>