<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6505"><akn:num>6505</akn:num><akn:heading>Structural and mechanical care and security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6505. Structural and mechanical care and security(a) Structural and Mechanical Care.—The Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the Commission for the Judiciary Office Building—(1) is responsible for the structural and mechanical care and maintenance of the Thurgood Marshall Federal Judiciary Building and improvements, including the care and maintenance of the grounds of the Building, in the same manner and to the same extent as for the structural and mechanical care and maintenance of the Supreme Court Building under section 6111 of this title; and

(2) shall perform all other duties and work required for the operation and domestic care of the Building and improvements.


(b) Security.—(1) Capitol police.—The United States Capitol Police—(A) are responsible for all exterior security of the Building and other improvements constructed under this chapter; and

(B) may police the Building and other improvements, including the interior and exterior, and may make arrests within the interior and exterior of the Building and other improvements for any violation of federal or state law or the laws of the District of Columbia, or any regulation prescribed under any of those laws.


(2) Marshal of the supreme court.—This chapter does not interfere with the obligation of the Marshal of the Supreme Court to protect justices, officers, employees, or other personnel of the Supreme Court who may occupy the Building and other improvements.

(3) Reimbursement.—The Architect shall transfer from the account described in section 6507 of this title amounts necessary to reimburse the United States Capitol Police for expenses incurred in providing exterior security under this subsection. The Capitol Police may accept amounts the Architect transfers under this paragraph. Those amounts shall be credited to the appropriation account charged by the Capitol Police in carrying out security duties.


(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1190.)











Historical and Revision</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Structural and Mechanical Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the Commission for the Judiciary Office Building—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>