<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/6901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6901"><akn:num>6901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6901. Definition
In this subchapter, the term “Union Station complex” means real property, air rights, and improvements the Secretary of the Interior leased under sections 101–110 of the National Visitors Center Facilities Act of 1968 (Public Law 90–264, 82 Stat. 43) and property acquired and improvements made in accordance with this subchapter.
(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1201.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


690140:811(a) (last sentence).Pub. L. 90–264, title I, § 111(a) (last sentence), as added Pub. L. 97–125, § 3(3), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1668.



Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 101–110 of the National Visitors Center Facilities Act of 1968, referred to in text, are sections 101 to 110 of Pub. L. 90–264, title I, Mar. 12, 1968, 82 Stat. 43–45, which were classified principally to part A (§ 801 et seq.) of subchapter I of chapter 18 of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 107–217, § 6(b), Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1304. Section 104 of the Act was classified as a note under section 804 of former Title 40 prior to repeal by Pub. L. 107–217. Section 108 of the Act was not classified to the Code.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Sale of Air RightsPub. L. 105–33, title IX, § 9102, Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 670, provided that:
“(a) In General.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator of General Services shall sell, at fair market value and in a manner to be determined by the Administrator, the air rights adjacent to Washington Union Station described in subsection (b), including air rights conveyed to the Administrator under subsection (d). The Administrator shall complete the sale by such date as is necessary to ensure that the proceeds from the sale will be deposited in accordance with subsection (c).

“(b) Description.—The air rights referred to in subsection (a) total approximately 16.5 acr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>