<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8101"><akn:num>8101</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of public buildings and grounds in District of Columbia not otherwise provided for by la</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8101. Supervision of public buildings and grounds in District of Columbia not otherwise provided for by law(a) In General.—Under regulations the President prescribes, the Administrator of General Services shall have charge of the public buildings and grounds in the District of Columbia, except those buildings and grounds which otherwise are provided for by law.

(b) Notice of Unlawful Occupancy.—If the Administrator, or the officer under the direction of the Administrator who is in immediate charge of those public buildings and grounds, decides that an individual is unlawfully occupying any part of that public land, the Administrator or officer in charge shall notify the United States marshal for the District of Columbia in writing of the unlawful occupation.

(c) Ejection of Trespasser.—The marshal shall have the trespasser ejected from the public land and shall restore possession of the land to the officer charged by law with the custody of the land.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1204.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


810140:19.R.S. § 1797; Apr. 28, 1902, ch. 594, [§] 1 (6th par. on p. 152), 32 Stat. 152.


In this chapter, the words “Administrator of General Services” are substituted for “Chief of Engineers” [subsequently changed to “Director of Public Buildings and Public Parks of the National Capital” because of section 3 of the Act of February 26, 1925 (ch. 339, 43 Stat. 983), “Director of the National Park Service” because of section 2 of Executive Order No. 6166 (eff. June 10, 1933) and the Act of March 2, 1934 (ch. 38, 48 Stat. 389), and “Public Buildings Administrator” because of sections 301 and 303 of Reorganization Plan No. I of 1939 (eff. July 1, 1939, 53 Stat. 1426, 1427)] because of section 103(a) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (ch. 288, 63 Stat. 380), which is restated as section 303(c) [303(b)] of the revised title.
In subsection</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations the President prescribes, the Administrator of General Services shall have charge of the public buildings and grounds in the District of Columbia, except those buildings and grounds which otherwise are provided for by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Unlawful Occupancy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If the Administrator, or the officer under the direction of the Administrator who is in immediate charge of those public buildings and grounds, decides that an individual is unlawfully occupying any part of that public land, the Administrator or officer in charge shall notify the United States marshal for the District of Columbia in writing of the unlawful occupation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ejection of Trespasser.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The marshal shall have the trespasser ejected from the public land and shall restore possession of the land to the officer charged by law with the custody of the land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>