<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/40/8164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8164"><akn:num>8164</akn:num><akn:heading>E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8164. E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse(a) Operation, Maintenance, and Repair.—The operation, maintenance, and repair of the E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse, used by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, is under the control of the Administrator of General Services.

(b) Allocation of Space.—The allocation of space in the Courthouse is vested in the chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the chief judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.

(Pub. L. 107–217, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1209.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


8164(a)40:129a.May 14, 1948, ch. 290, 62 Stat. 235.
 40:130 (words before last comma).
 40:130a.
8164(b)40:130 (words after last comma).


In this section, the words “United States District Court for the District of Columbia” are substituted for “District Court of the United States for the District of Columbia” because of section 32(b) of the Act of June 25, 1948 (ch. 646, 62 Stat. 991), as amended by section 127 of the Act of May 24, 1949 (ch. 139, 63 Stat. 107).
In subsection (a), the words “the E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse” are substituted for “the completed building” because of section 2 of the Act of July 1, 1996 (Public Law 104–151, 110 Stat. 1383). The words “Administrator of General Services” are substituted for “Public Buildings Administration, in the Federal Works Agency” because of 103(a) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 (ch. 288, 63 Stat. 380), which is restated as section 303(c) [303(b)] of the revised title. The text of 40:129a (words before last proviso) is omitted as obsolete. The text of 40:129a (last proviso) is omitted because of section 173(a)(1) of the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation, Maintenance, and Repair.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The operation, maintenance, and repair of the E. Barrett Prettyman United States Courthouse, used by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, is under the control of the Administrator of General Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of Space.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The allocation of space in the Courthouse is vested in the chief judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia and the chief judge of the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>